all right the time still 30-some I make an attempt to to put something on the
an attempt to to put something on the website half an hour ago
website half an hour ago so the lecture from last Tuesday and
so the lecture from last Tuesday and today's lecture must be there okay
today's lecture must be there okay the rest is available starters I'm going
the rest is available starters I'm going to be collecting what I had coming okay
to be collecting what I had coming okay and I think probably two more on will
and I think probably two more on will email those register some topics from
email those register some topics from books to read
books to read let's see another announcement we're
let's see another announcement we're going to post an early homework but it's
going to post an early homework but it's nobody need you for another three weeks
nobody need you for another three weeks or so but I want you to just know what
or so but I want you to just know what is coming and just not reading and in
is coming and just not reading and in the process of the homework we're going
the process of the homework we're going to have recitation tomorrow
to have recitation tomorrow so should we can introduce you to
so should we can introduce you to yesterday we did move what you have done
yesterday we did move what you have done introducing led me to some programming
introducing led me to some programming aspects cocoa from vista graphical focus
aspects cocoa from vista graphical focus because I think the Wake is preparing
because I think the Wake is preparing the homeworks he wants you to start
the homeworks he wants you to start building little libraries that
building little libraries that eventually lead to large-scale problems
eventually lead to large-scale problems now if you don't want us to develop this
now if you don't want us to develop this libraries in homework 1 we're gonna pass
libraries in homework 1 we're gonna pass the solutions so you can use from the
the solutions so you can use from the second part hours but lastly whatever we
second part hours but lastly whatever we post does it means the right thing I
post does it means the right thing I mean we are also students and we post
mean we are also students and we post whatever so hopefully you can do better
whatever so hopefully you can do better than than us and hopefully there are
than than us and hopefully there are solutions we post are your solutions
solutions we post are your solutions that's why I want you to factor right up
that's why I want you to factor right up and paste okay
and paste okay and what was the other announcement and
and what was the other announcement and so in this process of we will have a
so in this process of we will have a recitation this Friday but as I told me
recitation this Friday but as I told me very station the same ways the lectures
very station the same ways the lectures are not
are not thorry so if you don't like to see me
thorry so if you don't like to see me you don't have to come you know there
you don't have to come you know there are video lectures everything is online
are video lectures everything is online you can watch me from your kitchen
you can watch me from your kitchen basically we're getting a cup of coffee
basically we're getting a cup of coffee but there's gondola station at the same
but there's gondola station at the same time of driving and again net1 Authority
time of driving and again net1 Authority because hold information will be posted
because hold information will be posted and so the homework the Lexus okay so
and so the homework the Lexus okay so you will notice when you reveal the
you will notice when you reveal the slides from let's do one there are some
slides from let's do one there are some topics that are not covered okay now
topics that are not covered okay now those topics are really some little bit
those topics are really some little bit more examples from the concepts that was
more examples from the concepts that was trying to communicate some of them are
trying to communicate some of them are going to come in this lecture so I don't
going to come in this lecture so I don't have to do them some lady 3d will cover
have to do them some lady 3d will cover on Friday some we have to read them on
on Friday some we have to read them on your own okay and but if there is
your own okay and but if there is anything essential I will go back to it
anything essential I will go back to it okay if I don't cover it means we don't
okay if I don't cover it means we don't really need it for the shell code so for
really need it for the shell code so for example there is a big case study of
example there is a big case study of publicity graphical model related to the
publicity graphical model related to the biology and as you guys know there is
biology and as you guys know there is nobody from biology actually I was asked
nobody from biology actually I was asked yesterday polygamy I said we have any
yesterday polygamy I said we have any students in biology doing this type of
students in biology doing this type of things like not sorry you know so I
things like not sorry you know so I don't know if I stopped working for 20
don't know if I stopped working for 20 minutes in biology and I did clicker on
minutes in biology and I did clicker on the slide maybe a third of humans
the slide maybe a third of humans reached biology and that is not gonna be
reached biology and that is not gonna be good right
good right pointing all the way around okay
we're going to start discussing a limit about conditional independence relations
about conditional independence relations and graphs but the context of
and graphs but the context of theoretical aspects of this conditional
theoretical aspects of this conditional independence relations not the graphs
independence relations not the graphs represent this is sort of an impure much
represent this is sort of an impure much so we will probably go back to it again
so we will probably go back to it again and again for the next 23 weeks so we
and again for the next 23 weeks so we have a very reduced understanding so -
have a very reduced understanding so - you can take the concepts today the
you can take the concepts today the lecture scrolling up you'd be easy but
lecture scrolling up you'd be easy but you know you don't have from the stir
you know you don't have from the stir everything ok this is if you have
everything ok this is if you have variables are showing absolutely zero
variables are showing absolutely zero independence relations this is an
independence relations this is an appreciation of the visionary all right
appreciation of the visionary all right so look at it carefully
so look at it carefully all right not x1 x2 given x1 x2 be given
all right not x1 x2 given x1 x2 be given x2 x1 several different positions like
x2 x1 several different positions like that because for example I can start
that because for example I can start with x2 and the next one you will
with x2 and the next one you will experience x3 given you know x1 and x3
experience x3 given you know x1 and x3 etc etc so in essence you have very
etc etc so in essence you have very shove those and in some ways are not
shove those and in some ways are not symmetric right the way that I write
symmetric right the way that I write them so same sort of symmetry sphere ok
them so same sort of symmetry sphere ok this expansion is very expensive to do
this expansion is very expensive to do so just nibble on this if we have you
so just nibble on this if we have you say K values for its variable X and you
say K values for its variable X and you have both no so this will require a
have both no so this will require a table of the order of KT power V and
table of the order of KT power V and this is the reason really we started
this is the reason really we started probabilistic graphical models because
probabilistic graphical models because we be asking a question structures can
we be asking a question structures can you actually simplify this conditional
you actually simplify this conditional distributions accountable for some
distributions accountable for some independence relations other ways you
independence relations other ways you know looking at this is well explore
know looking at this is well explore given x1 depends on x2 and x3 telling
given x1 depends on x2 and x3 telling the trend of x2 and x3 the answer is yes
the trend of x2 and x3 the answer is yes we would
we would factorization that is very efficient so
factorization that is very efficient so the discount that I did here it does not
the discount that I did here it does not account for normalization of each of
account for normalization of each of these probabilities which is really it
these probabilities which is really it doesn't remove much of the cost and so
doesn't remove much of the cost and so when you want a perfect one
when you want a perfect one you can okay numbers to describe it k
you can okay numbers to describe it k square to describe excellent even x1
square to describe excellent even x1 take you to describe this and take the
take you to describe this and take the power bill escape to describe now we'll
power bill escape to describe now we'll study machine learning right if you have
study machine learning right if you have missed admission like that and if you
missed admission like that and if you want to visit in the context in the self
want to visit in the context in the self classification problems there's a lot of
classification problems there's a lot of text you can do but you don't have to
text you can do but you don't have to deal with complexity of K to the me and
deal with complexity of K to the me and so here's one example I'm going to
so here's one example I'm going to making tables for each of this
making tables for each of this conditional probability distributions
conditional probability distributions but inverse you replace them with
but inverse you replace them with logistic regression ordinates looks like
logistic regression ordinates looks like that
alright so delicious that you see here it's so tight and we're from the field
it's so tight and we're from the field itself in here it depends on all the
itself in here it depends on all the previous axis so I try to fit this
previous axis so I try to fit this distribution of science enjoyed a
distribution of science enjoyed a function with a rival of somewhat it's
function with a rival of somewhat it's doubly times the vector X for a for the
doubly times the vector X for a for the previous ones and then we may have not
previous ones and then we may have not seen this but yeah vs. are different
seen this but yeah vs. are different there's no no services sigmoid function
there's no no services sigmoid function and the focus of a label to take the K
and the focus of a label to take the K component of the argument and there is a
component of the argument and there is a nice model for this provision from a
nice model for this provision from a movie
movie of them and you won't have to fix a
of them and you won't have to fix a thing with to describe them okay now
thing with to describe them okay now it's not but the question is normally
it's not but the question is normally and I have the calculation here so if
and I have the calculation here so if anybody has any places from the power I
anybody has any places from the power I get it it's actually still taller than
get it it's actually still taller than they want you to do the odds of those
they want you to do the odds of those different against yourself so it comes
different against yourself so it comes out of the the the post of this is K
out of the the the post of this is K times miss Claire before the possible
times miss Claire before the possible straight to the power of me you know
straight to the power of me you know it's okay to whisper so it's really I
it's okay to whisper so it's really I mean depends offensively is but they
mean depends offensively is but they they significantly reduce from above
they significantly reduce from above course okay however this method is not
course okay however this method is not very useful because each of this
very useful because each of this conditional distributions depends on the
conditional distributions depends on the values of all the other previous
values of all the other previous variables so you want to be able to do
variables so you want to be able to do maths very sort of business in the
maths very sort of business in the college software plus fire so if you
college software plus fire so if you want people mixtures and you want five
want people mixtures and you want five modules you know account for evidence
modules you know account for evidence and things like that you won't be able
and things like that you won't be able to do the algebra using this module okay
to do the algebra using this module okay but again there is more than this one we
but again there is more than this one we have the tables nice fried this had some
have the tables nice fried this had some function alright and in this case a few
function alright and in this case a few this matrix not many once you have it
this matrix not many once you have it then this could be an easy problem
then this could be an easy problem figure in the context of classification
figure in the context of classification so what I want to do this in this course
so what I want to do this in this course we won't do something better some basic
we won't do something better some basic things probability integral syndrome
conditional independence so I have 1 divided by XY and Z can be scalar K
divided by XY and Z can be scalar K vector so I say that x and y are
vector so I say that x and y are conditionally independent given Z 1 FX 2
conditionally independent given Z 1 FX 2 the y and z is equal to B FX given C ok
the y and z is equal to B FX given C ok so tom is a normal something of Drive
so tom is a normal something of Drive make a difference when it comes to the
make a difference when it comes to the value of x okay so this is one way to
value of x okay so this is one way to I'd the traditional dependent of X for y
I'd the traditional dependent of X for y double Z this important that's why you
double Z this important that's why you say conditional because there is an
say conditional because there is an argument either now cosmas if you think
argument either now cosmas if you think this is a definition let me say the
this is a definition let me say the simple algebra right I can write this
simple algebra right I can write this more effectively y and z and then P of Y
more effectively y and z and then P of Y given Z so those are this I can write
given Z so those are this I can write this as P of X given Z P of Y given C so
this as P of X given Z P of Y given C so we can advances in the Commission to
we can advances in the Commission to life as an alternative way that when
life as an alternative way that when this conditional distribution for price
this conditional distribution for price is like knob Direction Y an independent
is like knob Direction Y an independent commission along Z okay so sometimes
commission along Z okay so sometimes this will be convenient sometimes this
this will be convenient sometimes this they are exactly the same thing that's
they are exactly the same thing that's good
okay dependence relationship also in terms of sets of random variables so we
terms of sets of random variables so we can either assent affection for
can either assent affection for environments is developing once that
environments is developing once that wagon easy when texas independent of Y
wagon easy when texas independent of Y given Z for every X in the set X and
given Z for every X in the set X and everyone in the sidewalk okay
everyone in the sidewalk okay and actually this Zia can make it also
and actually this Zia can make it also set so I maybe that we have been even
set so I maybe that we have been even more generalized reversals in there now
more generalized reversals in there now for example we say this set of the very
for example we say this set of the very most is independent that given that set
most is independent that given that set variable so this basically will follow
variable so this basically will follow this definition here
the repellents we listen to this sort of orthogonality condition but in some
orthogonality condition but in some probability looks mr. personality
probability looks mr. personality condition may imply something else
condition may imply something else usually defined in terms of expectations
usually defined in terms of expectations okay
okay but for us this is the notation we're
but for us this is the notation we're going to use muscle independence
going to use muscle independence basically you know we take this
basically you know we take this definition for example means of
definition for example means of perfection y is given p FX he apply okay
perfection y is given p FX he apply okay I was just looking at this slide right
I was just looking at this slide right you can stab it sometimes because you
you can stab it sometimes because you see for example have I'm using the
see for example have I'm using the notation carrying them in a violent way
notation carrying them in a violent way but hopefully we can still get the
but hopefully we can still get the message for example you know here I lose
message for example you know here I lose capital X and wife on the bottom was
capital X and wife on the bottom was here in little x and y then effectively
here in little x and y then effectively the same force but you know
the same force but you know traditionally this would be the lot of
traditionally this would be the lot of the volume or this will be the values
the volume or this will be the values that are the vitamin can take but you
that are the vitamin can take but you know we're okay right we're not gonna
know we're okay right we're not gonna see you know sorry you with a little X
see you know sorry you with a little X you know it's gonna tell you I type this
you know it's gonna tell you I type this slide at least we have some slides to
slide at least we have some slides to talk about the wrong papers you know
talk about the wrong papers you know it's good idea to sort of be careful and
it's good idea to sort of be careful and consistent because much than you're
consistent because much than you're consistent okay so this mess intent of
consistent okay so this mess intent of this conditional and marginal
this conditional and marginal independence okay so I am saying here
independence okay so I am saying here that this whole time is independent of
that this whole time is independent of the type of the car okay
[Music]
I mean the you know they say the probability of a is higher is you know I
probability of a is higher is you know I mean they you know would be exactly the
mean they you know would be exactly the opposite effect from the first example
opposite effect from the first example okay so so this is the motion again so
okay so so this is the motion again so we're gonna verse here you know I'm
we're gonna verse here you know I'm writing this is a standard are gonna
writing this is a standard are gonna spend actually two or three lectures
spend actually two or three lectures discussing about this kindle market or
discussing about this kindle market or in the State Park Estate state-space
in the State Park Estate state-space models but this is a Markov chain so we
models but this is a Markov chain so we can imagine you know you have some state
can imagine you know you have some state body moves but and you know the values
body moves but and you know the values of it
of it Connie so x1 is the volume of dynomonics
Connie so x1 is the volume of dynomonics - thank you it cetera so the unusually a
- thank you it cetera so the unusually a monomial assumption here where the model
monomial assumption here where the model effects of high BP depends only on the
effects of high BP depends only on the value of I'm XT minus 1 so prepared this
value of I'm XT minus 1 so prepared this expression show expecially we can
expression show expecially we can remember this pretty does this long
remember this pretty does this long expression compared list right with this
expression compared list right with this Markovian model that is very simplified
Markovian model that is very simplified because extra doesn't depend on XT minus
because extra doesn't depend on XT minus 2 XT minus 3 etc ok so this is this
2 XT minus 3 etc ok so this is this moment they see various cues the
moment they see various cues the independence relations in particular but
independence relations in particular but XP is independent X 2 minus 1 is in the
XP is independent X 2 minus 1 is in the parent of all the various values XT
parent of all the various values XT minus 2 X 1 on this course or something
minus 2 X 1 on this course or something if I highlighted from lecture 1 which is
if I highlighted from lecture 1 which is the parent of the node right so in this
the parent of the node right so in this case if we look at no business to
case if we look at no business to parents okay and so here's a fundamental
fairness conditionally previous relations for this directed graph and so
relations for this directed graph and so what it says x-ray is independent from
what it says x-ray is independent from the main the segments of a negative
the main the segments of a negative spiral so this is out there
spiral so this is out there Tamara trenched to emphasize the
Tamara trenched to emphasize the depositor given this will highlight in
depositor given this will highlight in that movie
that movie alright so
alright so the parlance it stays that the value of
the parlance it stays that the value of V is independent through the name of the
V is independent through the name of the sender so photographer at the political
sender so photographer at the political order the wrong descendants will have
order the wrong descendants will have numbers but they are basically
numbers but they are basically everything about the values of the
everything about the values of the parents basically in the order okay
parents basically in the order okay these are the non descendants right so
these are the non descendants right so point on the values of the parents
point on the values of the parents excuse you the fella from the
excuse you the fella from the non-descendants eye or anything like
non-descendants eye or anything like that right so view at this point I just
that right so view at this point I just want you to visualize as to what this
want you to visualize as to what this means because we love I think we should
means because we love I think we should highlight that which is not very
highlight that which is not very difficult but once you have this the
difficult but once you have this the composition for probability defined on
composition for probability defined on this graph you move rains pushing too
this graph you move rains pushing too hard okay so we will able to take
hard okay so we will able to take advantage of this relation so and no
advantage of this relation so and no Pascal will ensure that only
Pascal will ensure that only distillation of the fertilizer in this
distillation of the fertilizer in this graph satisfies this relation and around
graph satisfies this relation and around this dilution on the graph this relation
this dilution on the graph this relation is also satisfied you know I mean you
is also satisfied you know I mean you can see sorry
can see sorry alright so both ways this will be okay
that the capitalization of the joint of immunity on the restive graph is written
immunity on the restive graph is written as the product over all the nodes of the
as the product over all the nodes of the graph of the conditional probabilities
graph of the conditional probabilities of X I excite the volume of you know the
of X I excite the volume of you know the I given the violence apart this is an
I given the violence apart this is an amazing between position if you think
amazing between position if you think about it right so you know
about it right so you know in this case the conditional probability
in this case the conditional probability corresponding to its no and this
corresponding to its no and this function is the condition of the way the
function is the condition of the way the effects are given its forests so mr.
effects are given its forests so mr. Bastian that factorization with this
Bastian that factorization with this graph the personal missile dependent
graph the personal missile dependent relation that we introduced which is
relation that we introduced which is certified ethical justification for
certified ethical justification for deewana and discuss its Lewis okay so I
deewana and discuss its Lewis okay so I will have exactly tricentennial examples
will have exactly tricentennial examples and some a little bit more complicated
and some a little bit more complicated but I'll ask you to know mrs. Blaine and
but I'll ask you to know mrs. Blaine and electric artworks and washing us if we
electric artworks and washing us if we can prove it
[Music]
Rises and this factors here these functions are the condition for
functions are the condition for committees of X i given sparks when we
committees of X i given sparks when we have this complicated factorization from
have this complicated factorization from the product rule well we only have the
the product rule well we only have the parents we have taught the settlers and
parents we have taught the settlers and the co parents and the novice and
the co parents and the novice and everything else is coming here but
everything else is coming here but because of this independent relationship
because of this independent relationship the the only partition here this X i
the the only partition here this X i given the parents of
so I'm actually so sure what I'm doing I am taking a directed graph with my body
am taking a directed graph with my body moves the first equation writes the the
moves the first equation writes the the product rule so no independence
product rule so no independence assumptions I am love assuming nothing
assumptions I am love assuming nothing and then I am applying sort of this
and then I am applying sort of this equation right I'm applying this
equation right I'm applying this equation that says that business
equation that says that business innovation is factorized this way and
innovation is factorized this way and another thing at this the predominate
another thing at this the predominate affects one because it's one has no
affects one because it's one has no parents all right the prevent effects
parents all right the prevent effects still given x1 that's the only part I
still given x1 that's the only part I could still get enough only x1 x4 given
could still get enough only x1 x4 given 2 and 3 and X 5 given 3 so remember you
2 and 3 and X 5 given 3 so remember you can see the appearance relations that
effectively whether says the probability is equal to naught which means the level
is equal to naught which means the level x3 expires in the penitent water I mean
x3 expires in the penitent water I mean looking at this 2 equation there never
looking at this 2 equation there never expiry
expiry x5 is independent off that's 124 right
x5 is independent off that's 124 right there it's here given x2 x3 x4 is
there it's here given x2 x3 x4 is independent of X 1 given X 1 X 3 in
independent of X 1 given X 1 X 3 in terms of X 2 etc you may say I know but
terms of X 2 etc you may say I know but how do I know this independence relation
how do I know this independence relation well we will spend a lecture or two and
well we will spend a lecture or two and we will
cases
it's okay you know this if let's say is the number of parents to the power left
the number of parents to the power left to describe this times times
in principle actually somebody can say take the power a plus one
take the power a plus one
you sit up but you know it's like if you're comfortable a normalization and
you're comfortable a normalization and everything so that's approximately of
everything so that's approximately of the order wine is take aid to affect
reverse right these are going to take a values and we're taking K values all
values and we're taking K values all right so okay less rough
yes NZ's enemy remembrances lesser dismissed
dismissed mara independence relations okay and
mara independence relations okay and this is not very interesting so this is
this is not very interesting so this is something very just the Ascension this
something very just the Ascension this you can appreciate the necessary I'm
you can appreciate the necessary I'm showing that this function is a
showing that this function is a probability right because you say 116
probability right because you say 116 points along that mystical did you okay
the distributions okay next one to experience equal to one which is nice
experience equal to one which is nice so obviously it's individual on
so obviously it's individual on normalizing expect that this will be the
normalizing expect that this will be the case and apparently this the composition
case and apparently this the composition here you can show that the national
here you can show that the national experience is actually it comes home
experience is actually it comes home service functions is really the
service functions is really the conditional distribution which is what I
conditional distribution which is what I tell you you need to remember okay this
tell you you need to remember okay this functions are very more general and they
functions are very more general and they don't even have to be preferable if this
don't even have to be preferable if this but right now from directed graphs this
but right now from directed graphs this is the case and I say the proof and it
is the case and I say the proof and it works on extremely busy slide all right
works on extremely busy slide all right that's why I want you to type your
that's why I want you to type your homework because this rule was the lazy
homework because this rule was the lazy person typing the slide my secretary the
person typing the slide my secretary the novelist which imaginary person alright
novelist which imaginary person alright so it was me okay because I can't
so it was me okay because I can't imagine asking anybody that I've
imagine asking anybody that I've destroyed so it was this I want you to
destroyed so it was this I want you to to need some type and by typing fails so
that because you will need to do this for specific distribution your homework
for specific distribution your homework to do things like that so the first part
to do things like that so the first part of the theorem was methods and responses
of the theorem was methods and responses individually
[Music]
the secrets wirelessly was one of the signals along okay sort of calculation
signals along okay sort of calculation that is going to make the relations of
that is going to make the relations of the article of all those extremely
the article of all those extremely efficient okay define in terms of the
efficient okay define in terms of the notes and the values of the parents
notes and the values of the parents minds within the operations rather in
minds within the operations rather in this case the marginalization is a local
this case the marginalization is a local operation right and this allows us to to
operation right and this allows us to to see immediately the distance
it's his Michigan the normalized properly okay okay mr. as I say those
properly okay okay mr. as I say those any functions like that take the
any functions like that take the permanent zone distribution well I'm
permanent zone distribution well I'm going to show you know that this and
going to show you know that this and some of the various I write lists as the
some of the various I write lists as the joint effects k plus 1 and the quality k
joint effects k plus 1 and the quality k plus 1 divided by the powers of k plus 1
plus 1 divided by the powers of k plus 1 and then I I calculate the numerator
and then I I calculate the numerator denominator using the appropriate
denominator using the appropriate marginalization of the composition of
marginalization of the composition of the joint of a new distribution
expansion sure whatever done
okay okay okay so this is the okay mr. Lucius okay because that's positive
Lucius okay because that's positive wearing dark shirt and whatever else on
wearing dark shirt and whatever else on the proctors so let's take this one and
the proctors so let's take this one and the partnership give you some k plus and
and because I have to forensic aware that if L doesn't create the pilots of k
that if L doesn't create the pilots of k plus 1 is inside before camp yesterday
plus 1 is inside before camp yesterday right so I don't have to worry about the
right so I don't have to worry about the parent and mr. McCann needed to learn
parent and mr. McCann needed to learn outside the estimation because I don't
outside the estimation because I don't samel XK plus one or departments and you
samel XK plus one or departments and you notice from here to there I have to
notice from here to there I have to sound and the professionals from 1 to K
sound and the professionals from 1 to K except the parts of campus where
except the parts of campus where elements will be possible
elements will be possible explain right there without a freshwater
because this is something extremely important right because I'm doing I'm
important right because I'm doing I'm pushing the summations inside I have a
pushing the summations inside I have a context that the potentials are okay
context that the potentials are okay according to my induction argument
according to my induction argument they're really the conditional
they're really the conditional distributions and then I have this
distributions and then I have this summation of the other factors that have
summation of the other factors that have no clear benefit so if you do this and
no clear benefit so if you do this and we move this on the local what you have
we move this on the local what you have to summon XK plus 1 because there's no X
to summon XK plus 1 because there's no X 2 plus 1 so this whole transformation
2 plus 1 so this whole transformation constants numerator denominator D
constants numerator denominator D summation constants and this
summation constants and this factorization by definition is 1 because
factorization by definition is 1 because this functions are normalized so what I
this functions are normalized so what I get is this conditional distribution is
get is this conditional distribution is equal to my factor FK plus 1 so as you
compose in revenue distribution in terms of conditionals the proof is not
of conditionals the proof is not shortened to contagious is like traffic
shortened to contagious is like traffic AIDS
AIDS ok actually most books the parties
ok actually most books the parties consider a logician there's no proof
consider a logician there's no proof okay inaudible any questions on this
okay inaudible any questions on this thing's right if another story
thing's right if another story our interest is really the decomposition
our interest is really the decomposition in terms of these local conscious that
in terms of these local conscious that their conditional the values of exodus
their conditional the values of exodus 12 given its parents the resumption
12 given its parents the resumption topology will here the destructor
topology will here the destructor fundamental to the type of things we do
fundamental to the type of things we do this with directed graph and the part
this with directed graph and the part that we have it illogical or derivative
that we have it illogical or derivative is decelerations and insulation
is decelerations and insulation don't imagine that they have to sound x1
don't imagine that they have to sound x1 an actual appears in all of these
an actual appears in all of these functions
myself but the tractor fixed islands only on the bottom here exclusively
only on the bottom here exclusively there right so obviously in this
there right so obviously in this problems you can start some you provide
problems you can start some you provide to the left all right
to the left all right and if examples as you see this so
and if examples as you see this so that's important and then you'll notice
that's important and then you'll notice you have some operations to put rods and
you have some operations to put rods and notes where we sum up although the rest
notes where we sum up although the rest of the body most this is so focused on
of the body most this is so focused on the operation we we have to do with a
the operation we we have to do with a glass with left of model stressing the
glass with left of model stressing the context of why not kids like the
context of why not kids like the different there is a problem to the
different there is a problem to the complex all right I'm
complex all right I'm I always like the opposite of the normal
I always like the opposite of the normal case right I remember you know I said
case right I remember you know I said maybe this joke some time ago I was
maybe this joke some time ago I was trying to give a whole action on some
trying to give a whole action on some topic and some people ask me can you
topic and some people ask me can you start to give an example and I have not
start to give an example and I have not been introduced what the topic was
been introduced what the topic was okay you know she'll never leave my case
okay you know she'll never leave my case alive to give you the period when the
alive to give you the period when the examples come later on he do the
examples come later on he do the examples on your own so yes sort of the
examples on your own so yes sort of the people in one day so extra depends on X
people in one day so extra depends on X 1 X 2 X 2 etc so you can see I say okay
1 X 2 X 2 etc so you can see I say okay of the write this as a product of the
of the write this as a product of the functions but intellectual inspires this
functions but intellectual inspires this is nothing then experian the partner
is nothing then experian the partner physics wonder next year and the
physics wonder next year and the pharmacist our experience it's for the
pharmacist our experience it's for the next three so the other ones you can
next three so the other ones you can show you at least the service functions
show you at least the service functions they are nothing else or the the
they are nothing else or the the function of P of X clinics still is when
function of P of X clinics still is when the condition of x3 given x2 and
the condition of x3 given x2 and I think mr. composition right and I I
I think mr. composition right and I I you know the country first I have to
you know the country first I have to calculate the joint if X to X T divided
calculate the joint if X to X T divided by T FX still so then the other thing I
by T FX still so then the other thing I have to some obviously to marginalize
have to some obviously to marginalize it's all X 1 X 2 X 4 or X 1 and X 4 and
it's all X 1 X 2 X 4 or X 1 and X 4 and you can see some of the things we'll
you can see some of the things we'll organization can see long distance
organization can see long distance inside the trial and these parenthesis
inside the trial and these parenthesis and visible practice comes too long to
and visible practice comes too long to learn good idea to is f 3 or X 3 and X 3
learn good idea to is f 3 or X 3 and X 3 just is like a turbulent completed
just is like a turbulent completed version of the theorem
version of the theorem okay the best possible functions right
okay the best possible functions right and this conscience turn out to be pro
and this conscience turn out to be pro communities is only for directed graphs
communities is only for directed graphs we said anything for undirected graphs
we said anything for undirected graphs the case to be very well general
the case to be very well general management of sanity can position at
management of sanity can position at least in the context of this Markov
least in the context of this Markov chain about adoption being a bit more
chain about adoption being a bit more powerful so this is an example from one
powerful so this is an example from one of the textbook similar in machine
of the textbook similar in machine learning so one of the notes is the
learning so one of the notes is the glass is left one of the knowledge is
glass is left one of the knowledge is the support which can be on the left the
the support which can be on the left the other one is a know that is raining
other one is a know that is raining which can be on earth
which can be on earth and everyone is that it's cloudy
and everyone is that it's cloudy I am a strong basically the dependencies
I am a strong basically the dependencies look like the hot all right and let's
look like the hot all right and let's follow the fuel that I described the
follow the fuel that I described the junket ability of drama straight away
junket ability of drama straight away the grass right is basically returnest
the grass right is basically returnest same time
same time first even see we're forgiven see what
first even see we're forgiven see what not really given us an hour and
not really given us an hour and everything you can see by comparing this
everything you can see by comparing this with examining the composition using the
with examining the composition using the product community to share is implies
product community to share is implies basically fundamental national
basically fundamental national independence relations right and as a
independence relations right and as a measure of the elections okay right that
measure of the elections okay right that you can this you can expect this
you can this you can expect this independence relations all right and
independence relations all right and then from this you can say oh that's why
then from this you can say oh that's why the composition I mean in Pascal the new
the composition I mean in Pascal the new activist problem and you have this graph
activist problem and you have this graph like that smells you already have a
like that smells you already have a negative in the graphics independence
negative in the graphics independence relations so this decomposition is
relations so this decomposition is automatic you don't have to clear
automatic you don't have to clear anything right so we are going to define
anything right so we are going to define this distribution so effectively the
this distribution so effectively the trial value well because of an
trial value well because of an organization to define this is from his
organization to define this is from his first loudest row so if I do he wanted
first loudest row so if I do he wanted as long as the other one is one line is
as long as the other one is one line is nervously than one value let's say this
nervously than one value let's say this is the probability of the specular the
is the probability of the specular the hell are they so I am writing is
hell are they so I am writing is probability well the cloud is a false
probability well the cloud is a false argument or a tool
argument or a tool to describe this well actually I have no
to describe this well actually I have no money from this I have to fill this I
money from this I have to fill this I have different Lee's and if I take this
have different Lee's and if I take this little mini be how isn't it okay we come
little mini be how isn't it okay we come from the normalization because for a lot
from the normalization because for a lot of skilled problem it doesn't make a
of skilled problem it doesn't make a sense to say - wah - wah
sense to say - wah - wah yeah we can subtract - fish - a problem
yeah we can subtract - fish - a problem with million borrowers we will make a
with million borrowers we will make a difference
difference okay so no bother so I spent the card
okay so no bother so I spent the card for this problem is the times to the
for this problem is the times to the carry case the number of points below
carry case the number of points below and this environment variables that's
and this environment variables that's why you see it through there
why you see it through there actually I don't know why I different
actually I don't know why I different from before before using were using K
from before before using were using K from the number of values that are
from the number of values that are available can take here I just a for
available can take here I just a for another opponent the game you guys are
another opponent the game you guys are adult and vaccinated so you can figure
adult and vaccinated so you can figure out in which life what the context is
out in which life what the context is right so so I don't have to go back and
right so so I don't have to go back and change the story that's already there
change the story that's already there and I was sure that everybody responds
and I was sure that everybody responds what this equation makes or let's the
what this equation makes or let's the the correlation rate across today from
the correlation rate across today from directly ghost makes a little sense
directly ghost makes a little sense there was nothing else okay all right
so this 11 example I think I'm gonna I may have to give this because there's
unpleasant dependence relations from this example as applications in the
this example as applications in the slides so this is prevalence of you know
slides so this is prevalence of you know to come you know sometime in the near
to come you know sometime in the near part of a future so there are such
part of a future so there are such variables and best on with the
variables and best on with the discussion of in the composition this is
discussion of in the composition this is what I have right x1 x2 given x1 x3
what I have right x1 x2 given x1 x3 given X 1 X 5 etc X tix given X 2 X 5
given X 1 X 5 etc X tix given X 2 X 5 protected right and and you say in this
protected right and and you say in this example a nice graphical representation
example a nice graphical representation of the table society to this conditional
of the table society to this conditional distribution is corresponding to each
distribution is corresponding to each tsunami so x1 it's a long experience
tsunami so x1 it's a long experience given x1 so it's a baby like this
given x1 so it's a baby like this exports given x2 table like this exist
exports given x2 table like this exist given two values okay it's a table like
given two values okay it's a table like that and like that I have to actually
that and like that I have to actually program I'm assuming and I'm saying this
program I'm assuming and I'm saying this that show the kid and take note and
that show the kid and take note and destroy that we assign you some homework
destroy that we assign you some homework problems when we don't do the question
problems when we don't do the question all right you have something only
all right you have something only computer program to do this for you
don't eat this don't eat this already did this Antoni gaud
okay guys there's a time for them how's that possible
that possible I don't have the power you know why not
I don't have the power you know why not a very good machine ever left of their
a very good machine ever left of their other thing you guys left me because
other thing you guys left me because you'll never never go almost papers
you'll never never go almost papers right that's the 30 minutes all right
right that's the 30 minutes all right let's see necessarily put so I'm going
let's see necessarily put so I'm going to my past
and okay so which of the sexist is coming all right so then this is our
coming all right so then this is our independent of each other and that's the
independent of each other and that's the concept of the latest Paris fire okay so
concept of the latest Paris fire okay so so it's my NRI all right this are
so it's my NRI all right this are independent if I didn't know why they're
independent if I didn't know why they're nervous values of X 1 and X 4 whatever I
nervous values of X 1 and X 4 whatever I get they depend on each other this is
get they depend on each other this is sort of a song another problem will
sort of a song another problem will reduce you know in in sort of mixed
reduce you know in in sort of mixed models but many other settings as well
models but many other settings as well okay
two things - one and two long is this Belgium to mislead Gaussian so if I
Belgium to mislead Gaussian so if I wrote a little bit of white for it sex
wrote a little bit of white for it sex the this exercising defendant and so
the this exercising defendant and so effectively you know this is the problem
effectively you know this is the problem engine roaring tons of the divinity of
engine roaring tons of the divinity of the world X given Y and the lamented
the world X given Y and the lamented world X living who soldier sex is given
world X living who soldier sex is given Y can be factorized over the data right
Y can be factorized over the data right because of this assumption that the X is
because of this assumption that the X is having a fairly given Y ok so so this is
having a fairly given Y ok so so this is something very important
something very important laughter moment of birth under the name
laughter moment of birth under the name of naive Bayes classifier i mean i
of naive Bayes classifier i mean i satisfy a fear you know i know this but
satisfy a fear you know i know this but additionally basically has been this is
additionally basically has been this is that that's fine to say become from now
that that's fine to say become from now someone and thousand through so that's
someone and thousand through so that's what the name plus pi or take this
what the name plus pi or take this complexed and say the sections are
complexed and say the sections are linearly independent given y and you
linearly independent given y and you notice on this paragraph if you see on
notice on this paragraph if you see on the birthday all right
the birthday all right I started fatal dependencies between the
I started fatal dependencies between the exes okay so this is the display the
exes okay so this is the display the printed my Vegas was fired okay to come
printed my Vegas was fired okay to come up with your own little algorithms and
up with your own little algorithms and this if you search in the literature you
this if you search in the literature you will find very particular algorithm it's
will find very particular algorithm it's for leveling this demented name they
for leveling this demented name they discussed fire okay yes well I just know
discussed fire okay yes well I just know if you remember that name basements that
if you remember that name basements that these types of sex
these types of sex running right and independent so you
running right and independent so you have a nice proposition that looks like
have a nice proposition that looks like this okay
this okay and constants with dependencies between
and constants with dependencies between the extras and because the balance is
the extras and because the balance is still maintained some pay structure that
still maintained some pay structure that you can do is the difference but the
you can do is the difference but the custom what you see on the top okay
it's prevalent conditional independence relations National Defense relations so
relations National Defense relations so these actions right so this is all right
these actions right so this is all right this is the length of appearances this
this is the length of appearances this is referred directly best luck sir okay
is referred directly best luck sir okay and the party dependencies we have this
and the party dependencies we have this one we introduced the Vegas more longer
one we introduced the Vegas more longer in about two legs from now so you can
in about two legs from now so you can work from something from collective one
work from something from collective one connected personal between the first
okay there is nothing new there
but I am descendants even the parents then the descendants even the parents
then the descendants even the parents and
accept the fact the fundamental property of directed graphs the different
of directed graphs the different position from the parable sprouts to
position from the parable sprouts to convince your sensitive actually again
convince your sensitive actually again the fulfilled never step two is this
the fulfilled never step two is this marginalization that we did in two
marginalization that we did in two examples before and then you can treat
examples before and then you can treat this decomposition is correct
[Music]
one extreme
experts in the time of x1 x2 and there's not wrong exterior to this efficient
right
- okay listen tada your life is perfect when it's the
your life is perfect when it's the expected by P of X 1 is 50 ok by you
expected by P of X 1 is 50 ok by you alpha plus X 1 X 2 X 3 X 4 is that what
alpha plus X 1 X 2 X 3 X 4 is that what happens to X 5 and X 6 fear of insulin
happens to X 5 and X 6 fear of insulin what happened to X 5 minus X 6
what happened to X 5 minus X 6 well I mean the question of attack the
well I mean the question of attack the black is words you know when you
black is words you know when you somewhere X 5 and X 6 this is 0.1 of
somewhere X 5 and X 6 this is 0.1 of this equal to 1 so they disappear you
this equal to 1 so they disappear you see that when you analyze to the joint
see that when you analyze to the joint the next 5 minutes because this how
the next 5 minutes because this how conditional distinguishes the summation
conditional distinguishes the summation is giving the advantage okay so so this
is giving the advantage okay so so this is the joint of X 1 X 2 X 3 X 4 and then
is the joint of X 1 X 2 X 3 X 4 and then if you wanted to join the pitch 1 X 2 X
if you wanted to join the pitch 1 X 2 X 3 we have to something that's clear but
3 we have to something that's clear but when someone experimenting disappearing
when someone experimenting disappearing because summation of expelling everyone
because summation of expelling everyone all right
all right yeah well this consus without this
yeah well this consus without this concept evolved already but you get this
concept evolved already but you get this perfect score given X 2 okay so this is
perfect score given X 2 okay so this is kinda filled this independence relation
kinda filled this independence relation but I wrestle to remember the ideas that
but I wrestle to remember the ideas that Assad isn't behind all of this and say
Assad isn't behind all of this and say all there is an independence relations
all there is an independence relations but to heaven all the groups of this
but to heaven all the groups of this graph and he says this graph implies
graph and he says this graph implies none of this independence relations
none of this independence relations so whatever distribution that population
so whatever distribution that population the graph has been tamarkan satisfy of
the graph has been tamarkan satisfy of this relationship
this relationship okay a stupid idea so we're not going to
okay a stupid idea so we're not going to do the algebra but we lived
do the algebra but we lived that vision server browser arguments
that vision server browser arguments implants University what is relationship
and here is an over in the Paris relation X 1 given X 6 is the head of X
relation X 1 given X 6 is the head of X 3 X 3 this is like in the in this case
3 X 3 this is like in the in this case of disease that say cancer and why is
of disease that say cancer and why is somehow kind of a disease you know some
somehow kind of a disease you know some of molecule blood or other things so why
of molecule blood or other things so why is the disease right but the memory
is the disease right but the memory access many diseases and you have
access many diseases and you have something that can be derived from any
something that can be derived from any diseases so you can see this as a little
diseases so you can see this as a little from X to Y so exist another thing the -
from X to Y so exist another thing the - you can see this is awareness problem
you can see this is awareness problem that if you have an alternate and let's
that if you have an alternate and let's say a blood test you ask the members
say a blood test you ask the members area and so this graph that you see in
area and so this graph that you see in spitzer discuss you know this isn't
spitzer discuss you know this isn't about the narrative rondelle the joint
about the narrative rondelle the joint affection Y as the probable effects
affection Y as the probable effects knives the probability of Y given X so
knives the probability of Y given X so reliable addressed you know this you
reliable addressed you know this you know the parent effects may be will
know the parent effects may be will define it by
right right okay
[Music]
delicious from X to Y but that doesn't allow you can be any friends res or
allow you can be any friends res or something for y and say what desserts
something for y and say what desserts okay
they delivered the next two slides we will discuss and rain
okay right okay so this is the right
[Music]
dress is wet but let me let you know whether Dre
this has already explained that the grass is wet
grass is wet okay we will formally serve this with a
okay we will formally serve this with a derivation okay but in essence if this
derivation okay but in essence if this example all right
no problems maybe today
with little names let's say you have two points the students are doing the kind
points the students are doing the kind of it thank you go gents you know come
of it thank you go gents you know come to get doesn't depend on anything so
to get doesn't depend on anything so they're putting the feather corns let's
they're putting the feather corns let's say this and this right so let's
say this and this right so let's Alchemist is right this is zero okay so
Alchemist is right this is zero okay so this has exploratory they so right so
this has exploratory they so right so this is Center for the experiment a
this is Center for the experiment a phenomenal
I was reporting this in the slides you know losing the game in the
know losing the game in the factorization which we miss you can
factorization which we miss you can actually compute an audience and do the
actually compute an audience and do the algebra nothing Ranger so this is the
algebra nothing Ranger so this is the factorization we started so you can
factorization we started so you can actually prove all the questions that
actually prove all the questions that you saw in the previous slides
my ass Douglas relation so let me just say what's going easier so remember we
say what's going easier so remember we sent that you know X of the royal
sent that you know X of the royal descendants okay so basically the board
descendants okay so basically the board is independent of anything else okay the
is independent of anything else okay the SAT score or what rate is clearing out
SAT score or what rate is clearing out that cetera
that cetera question on the doctor okay it says
parasocial was given them the difficulty of an exam all right
of an exam all right it's also kind of hell okay that's not
it's also kind of hell okay that's not what I wrote it
however informational says about its descendants
well so long I just want the sentence against not breathing with an equation
against not breathing with an equation any information about the descendants
any information about the descendants contains beliefs about this invention
contains beliefs about this invention reasoning process so another race if you
reasoning process so another race if you know what happened was still there it
know what happened was still there it has got there okay
has got there okay it changes the picture okay even who
it changes the picture okay even who says the difficulty on the intelligence
says the difficulty on the intelligence of the Skinner right if the evidence is
of the Skinner right if the evidence is the difficulty of in Excel and even
the difficulty of in Excel and even peasants sugar still smells but the
peasants sugar still smells but the official from below the most immortality
official from below the most immortality do the fixer okay so we will see this
do the fixer okay so we will see this sort of problem when we discuss
sort of problem when we discuss independence relationships and and
independence relationships and and evidence okay
[Music]
okay
and this would be the growth and the logo is this image on just the mission
logo is this image on just the mission we have sent up over all the she's
we have sent up over all the she's invaluable success okay so then this
invaluable success okay so then this have the visceral volume is the Sabbath
have the visceral volume is the Sabbath even vartanus and this is sort of the
even vartanus and this is sort of the main cost that allows you develop native
main cost that allows you develop native environments now the only thing I was
environments now the only thing I was gonna say is a little socially desirable
gonna say is a little socially desirable but Sir I was seven gardeners
but Sir I was seven gardeners there was the number of mobile growth so
there was the number of mobile growth so we can think of a gradual and that way
we can think of a gradual and that way the death of our decisions coming so the
the death of our decisions coming so the killer virus can be maybe indicator
killer virus can be maybe indicator punch values that tells you what it's
punch values that tells you what it's beautiful collect - what
beautiful collect - what Gaussian envelopes are they too late or
Gaussian envelopes are they too late or what you know okay so life is the
what you know okay so life is the composition is right that this hidden
composition is right that this hidden garden was the morning with a number of
garden was the morning with a number of the additional volume which in the graph
the additional volume which in the graph you can keep the prosperous
service parameters theta are independent but independent of the data you collect
but independent of the data you collect in the problem okay sure
in the problem okay sure and in real problems here in the
and in real problems here in the formation of the rebels will go to be
formation of the rebels will go to be able to achieve is a testament to this
able to achieve is a testament to this data parameters theta but this bottom of
missions to carefully account for the factors and somehow instance you have to
factors and somehow instance you have to do predictions by information of the
do predictions by information of the students to know is nobody here in a few
students to know is nobody here in a few weeks from now but because not wait a
weeks from now but because not wait a minute and the very natural self
minute and the very natural self directly linked to my website at least
directly linked to my website at least the previous one and this nice already
the previous one and this nice already aware and I will see here on next
aware and I will see here on next Tuesday suppose