all right so tomorrow we're gonna have a recitation related homework three and I
recitation related homework three and I suppose we'll achieve our homework two
suppose we'll achieve our homework two already when it was due today one last
already when it was due today one last time okay all right let's post it all
time okay all right let's post it all right because I offer an extension and
right because I offer an extension and all would be no more extension so that
all would be no more extension so that now when I saw their Bailey station
now when I saw their Bailey station regarding homework three and one of the
regarding homework three and one of the things we haven't discussed this about
things we haven't discussed this about projects for the class okay because you
projects for the class okay because you stopped working so you don't go the last
stopped working so you don't go the last week and you say to me my project is
week and you say to me my project is literally three days before the
literally three days before the presentations okay
presentations okay because then I'd really get mad and not
because then I'd really get mad and not think if in some sense you don't feel
think if in some sense you don't feel the need to have a broader it's good
the need to have a broader it's good thing to know so I can give more
thing to know so I can give more homework right that means one or the
homework right that means one or the other so projects are good for you
other so projects are good for you because it gives you an opportunity to
because it gives you an opportunity to integrate things with your research and
integrate things with your research and learn something new and I want simple
learn something new and I want simple projects for that way you know in other
projects for that way you know in other ways if you take a paper from the
ways if you take a paper from the literature in this area and you
literature in this area and you implement what it says the application
implement what it says the application examples of fantastic that's a project
examples of fantastic that's a project something we haven't discussed about so
something we haven't discussed about so that way when you give a presentation to
that way when you give a presentation to the class the class learn something new
the class the class learn something new and we have the whole idea so it's not a
and we have the whole idea so it's not a way to do nothing and then pretend
way to do nothing and then pretend here's my project okay that's not very
here's my project okay that's not very good for yourself for me and for the
good for yourself for me and for the university all right
university all right still may I suggest that we thin like to
still may I suggest that we thin like to the next week we'll talk you come up
the next week we'll talk you come up with an applet for your project okay and
with an applet for your project okay and this time you won't be able to change it
this time you won't be able to change it so make your abstract artwork with at
so make your abstract artwork with at least one reference so I know that
least one reference so I know that you're bounded by something okay you
you're bounded by something okay you miss the most important or the clause
and you know there were a few more slides left on the last lecture but is
slides left on the last lecture but is now posted because I realized we forgot
now posted because I realized we forgot to post it the same way we forgot to
to post it the same way we forgot to post the videos all right take note so
post the videos all right take note so we need to read this posted so today I'm
we need to read this posted so today I'm going to do is I'm going to move past
going to do is I'm going to move past the sum-product algorithm and discussed
the sum-product algorithm and discussed first the Maxum algorithm and we
first the Maxum algorithm and we discussed what that is in sort of very
discussed what that is in sort of very general terms then we'll actually take a
general terms then we'll actually take a step backwards if nothing else for
step backwards if nothing else for historical reasons and give you a few
historical reasons and give you a few slides on something that the sample of a
slides on something that the sample of a subtype of the sum-product I will be
subtype of the sum-product I will be photographed
photographed that is called belief propagation and at
that is called belief propagation and at least you need to know when you see a
least you need to know when you see a need because people talk about belief
need because people talk about belief propagation it's basically a subset of
propagation it's basically a subset of what we already have done but I want to
what we already have done but I want to just cover it a few slides so you see
just cover it a few slides so you see the notation coming from people that are
the notation coming from people that are grounded in information science is sort
grounded in information science is sort of a different perspective of what we
of a different perspective of what we have done up to now
have done up to now and assuming we have Pauline I'm gonna
and assuming we have Pauline I'm gonna start to discuss another exact inference
start to discuss another exact inference algorithm for general graphs which is
algorithm for general graphs which is called the junction tree algorithm I am
called the junction tree algorithm I am NOT going to give you all the details
NOT going to give you all the details some sort of simple examples and then
some sort of simple examples and then when we come back on Tuesday I will
when we come back on Tuesday I will provide some of the details from the
provide some of the details from the different versions of this algorithms
different versions of this algorithms and hopefully you can do one of these
and hopefully you can do one of these implementations in your homework once we
implementations in your homework once we cover these things or maybe the next
cover these things or maybe the next several lectures we're going to go
several lectures we're going to go backwards and do examples for example
backwards and do examples for example for hidden Markov models for state-space
for hidden Markov models for state-space models so we are going to try to revisit
models so we are going to try to revisit this knowledge in specific contexts so
this knowledge in specific contexts so in some sense you have another mark for
in some sense you have another mark for short the good luck to these notes and
short the good luck to these notes and read them again
read them again okay because we will release them on
okay because we will release them on specific examples so let me introduce
specific examples so let me introduce this magical algorithm when what the
this magical algorithm when what the problem is about so obviously in
problem is about so obviously in probabilistic graphical models we can
probabilistic graphical models we can model the joint probability distribution
model the joint probability distribution of many of the variables and we figure
of many of the variables and we figure out how given some evidence we compute
out how given some evidence we compute conditionals to marginal stuffing size
conditionals to marginal stuffing size up so right now let's say we have a
up so right now let's say we have a graph to represent a probability P of X
graph to represent a probability P of X and we want to find the value the
and we want to find the value the maximum effects that maximizes this P of
maximum effects that maximizes this P of X and also that maximum value of P of X
X and also that maximum value of P of X so if you think that P of X being the
so if you think that P of X being the prosperity Oracle may be asking what's
prosperity Oracle may be asking what's the value of x of Knox why is the
the value of x of Knox why is the posterior and what is not maximum value
posterior and what is not maximum value okay so the difficulty with this problem
okay so the difficulty with this problem right is that if you maximize marginals
right is that if you maximize marginals what you will get if you put all the XS
what you will get if you put all the XS together is not the same axis as we must
together is not the same axis as we must mies the
mies the the Joint Distribution and carry sort of
the Joint Distribution and carry sort of a trivial example we have binary
a trivial example we have binary particle section Y lists are the
particle section Y lists are the corresponding probabilities for these
corresponding probabilities for these items to take the value stone you can
items to take the value stone you can see the value of the probability of X
see the value of the probability of X equal to 0.6 the probability of X equal
equal to 0.6 the probability of X equal ones points y equal to 0.7 and why port
ones points y equal to 0.7 and why port 1 is 43 so X the argument affects that
1 is 43 so X the argument affects that takes gives you the maximum probability
takes gives you the maximum probability for the marginal is X equal to 0 right
for the marginal is X equal to 0 right we're doing and the maximum the kind of
we're doing and the maximum the kind of Y that much mice the marginal of Y is y
Y that much mice the marginal of Y is y equal to 0 but if you look at this table
equal to 0 but if you look at this table the this is basically the joint
the this is basically the joint probability distribution affection y the
probability distribution affection y the maximum happens when x equals 1 and y
maximum happens when x equals 1 and y equal to 0 not the same bar right so I
equal to 0 not the same bar right so I mean this is one example but you can
mean this is one example but you can generalize this and you can see that you
generalize this and you can see that you know you have to be very lucky where the
know you have to be very lucky where the axis of maximize the margin of the chain
axis of maximize the margin of the chain as the axis of maximize the the joint so
as the axis of maximize the the joint so what we need to do is we need to find an
what we need to do is we need to find an algorithm that we can do this with the
algorithm that we can do this with the same efficiency of doing influencing
same efficiency of doing influencing graphs or you can have algorithm and in
graphs or you can have algorithm and in principle looks identical to doing
principle looks identical to doing inference in graphs all right - some
inference in graphs all right - some small perturbations
you know I have mentioned that the lots of 12s algorithms really they they're
of 12s algorithms really they they're very common in you know in dynamic
very common in you know in dynamic programming source of all things you
programming source of all things you today they will also look like dynamic
today they will also look like dynamic programming so let's say this whole of
programming so let's say this whole of this tower evidence node this is a bunch
this tower evidence node this is a bunch of nodes we don't really care and this
of nodes we don't really care and this list the query nodes all right so we're
list the query nodes all right so we're interested to compute when we did
interested to compute when we did increase to compute the probability of X
increase to compute the probability of X F given XT and the whole idea of the
F given XT and the whole idea of the sum-product algorithm is to do sort of
sum-product algorithm is to do sort of estimations in an efficient way on the
estimations in an efficient way on the glass so now we want to find react but
glass so now we want to find react but maximize is this the probability except
maximize is this the probability except given the evidence which is basically
given the evidence which is basically the same as the probability maximizing
the same as the probability maximizing the joint because you know if you write
the joint because you know if you write is the joint divided by the evidence the
is the joint divided by the evidence the evidence doesn't accept so this is the
evidence doesn't accept so this is the same so effectively this light stays in
same so effectively this light stays in evidence or not doesn't matter you can
evidence or not doesn't matter you can treat the problem of finding the extras
treat the problem of finding the extras maximizes the joint all this probability
maximizes the joint all this probability for evidence account is basically the
for evidence account is basically the same way all right so in this case I
same way all right so in this case I mean you can put the extreme to the
mean you can put the extreme to the given value stand still you have the
given value stand still you have the joint distribution and maximize it with
joint distribution and maximize it with respect to itself right
respect to itself right now the religion that we will be able to
now the religion that we will be able to expand the inference algorithms to do
expand the inference algorithms to do this marks algorithm has the part of the
this marks algorithm has the part of the operator marks distribute over
operator marks distribute over multiplication the same way we show you
multiplication the same way we show you know with the summation when we did
know with the summation when we did inference algorithms so for example this
inference algorithms so for example this is what we took advantage to push
is what we took advantage to push summations in worlds you know when we
summations in worlds you know when we did elimination algorithms and you can
did elimination algorithms and you can see the same thing is applicable when we
see the same thing is applicable when we have maximization so the maximum a V and
have maximization so the maximum a V and H 3 is the same as a times the maximum
H 3 is the same as a times the maximum BC and and this distribution of the
BC and and this distribution of the match operator of a multiplication will
match operator of a multiplication will allow us to discipline the same sort of
allow us to discipline the same sort of idea that we did with elimination when
idea that we did with elimination when we were pushing salacious treatments so
we were pushing salacious treatments so we can be met let's algebra I'm doing
we can be met let's algebra I'm doing all of them simultaneously so if you
all of them simultaneously so if you have let's say stopped realization that
have let's say stopped realization that involves X 1 X 2 X 3 functions of the
involves X 1 X 2 X 3 functions of the three and you want to find the X 1 X 2 X
three and you want to find the X 1 X 2 X 3 that maximize this product obviously
3 that maximize this product obviously you can start pushing some of the much
you can start pushing some of the much of the latest in works I mean in this
of the latest in works I mean in this case of course it is trivial because 8 I
case of course it is trivial because 8 I do not put any x1 or x2 here then it
do not put any x1 or x2 here then it with anything else here so but obviously
with anything else here so but obviously you've got the spirit that somehow we
you've got the spirit that somehow we will be able to push this portal ok so
will be able to push this portal ok so here is the simple chain problem that we
here is the simple chain problem that we have seen everywhere undirected graph
have seen everywhere undirected graph let's say we define this these are the
let's say we define this these are the maximal cliques so we define this with a
maximal cliques so we define this with a potential so I want to try to 3 psi n
potential so I want to try to 3 psi n minus 1 n so if you want find the X of
minus 1 n so if you want find the X of maximizes first so effectively what you
maximizes first so effectively what you need to do is arrive this maximization
need to do is arrive this maximization of
of Racing on the way that you see on the
Racing on the way that you see on the bottom okay this is gonna be sort of the
bottom okay this is gonna be sort of the little complexity but we need to be able
little complexity but we need to be able to account for so here we are going x10
to account for so here we are going x10 appears on your list tab so you can
appears on your list tab so you can actually do this maximization then you
actually do this maximization then you will get something that depends only on
will get something that depends only on n minus 1 so this combined with the
n minus 1 so this combined with the previous potential you can do the
previous potential you can do the maximization or n minus 1 etc etc until
maximization or n minus 1 etc etc until basically you can do a maximization here
basically you can do a maximization here with respect to x1 actually if you
with respect to x1 actually if you understand this this example you
understand this this example you understand everything in the picture for
understand everything in the picture for this maximum algorithm and this
this maximum algorithm and this elimination algorithm and actually I
elimination algorithm and actually I copied the plot from one of our earlier
copied the plot from one of our earlier lectures where we were eliminating first
lectures where we were eliminating first X 6 and X 5 X 4 X 3 X 2 and X 1 so in
X 6 and X 5 X 4 X 3 X 2 and X 1 so in this case we want to find the maximum
this case we want to find the maximum that the joint probability of X 1 to 6
that the joint probability of X 1 to 6 but I take here vertex tricks is evident
but I take here vertex tricks is evident and as we said before it doesn't really
and as we said before it doesn't really make any difference
make any difference ok so this is the exact authorization
ok so this is the exact authorization nothing special again be FX 1 X 2 given
nothing special again be FX 1 X 2 given X 1 X 3 X 1 X 5 X 3 X 6 given X 2 and X
X 1 X 3 X 1 X 5 X 3 X 6 given X 2 and X 5 X 4 given X X 4 given X 2 X 4 X 4
5 X 4 given X X 4 given X 2 X 4 X 4 given a key to okay
given a key to okay and then I put Delta and evidence
and then I put Delta and evidence potential there to fix the value of x 6
potential there to fix the value of x 6 of X 6 bar
so we is compressing the maximization same words
same words so we suppress what parents involve sex
so we suppress what parents involve sex sticks and there is list times this
sticks and there is list times this potential but the only things that
potential but the only things that involve six six so we can actually find
involve six six so we can actually find the max2 of this with respect to its
the max2 of this with respect to its sixth when we say we're going to find an
sixth when we say we're going to find an option of this with respect to the sixth
option of this with respect to the sixth vistors for possible values of x 2 x 5
vistors for possible values of x 2 x 5 because in office in a function x 10 x 5
because in office in a function x 10 x 5 arguments then that given right so i
arguments then that given right so i mean this time a function of the three
mean this time a function of the three arguments okay
arguments okay so X 3 X 5 arbitrary here so when we
so X 3 X 5 arbitrary here so when we must merge with respect to X 6 we have
must merge with respect to X 6 we have to do for the possible values of X 3 X 5
to do for the possible values of X 3 X 5 this is very important move on okay you
this is very important move on okay you do this maximization and the same way we
do this maximization and the same way we did with elimination we're going to call
did with elimination we're going to call this 8 6 because 6 is the now to
this 8 6 because 6 is the now to eliminate and the arguments are so
eliminate and the arguments are so you're going to have to compute this
you're going to have to compute this expected shakes anyway call it the
expected shakes anyway call it the function HX X to connect start we did
function HX X to connect start we did the same thing with elimination but in
the same thing with elimination but in elimination what did we go to add 6
so to sum it all right if we must analyze it here we don't stop we must
analyze it here we don't stop we must okay the terms that involve x5 obviously
okay the terms that involve x5 obviously there was this term from the original
there was this term from the original distribution times this new potentially
distribution times this new potentially six so again the three arguments here
six so again the three arguments here are three and few so that we will get a
are three and few so that we will get a new function that is called H five
new function that is called H five because five is eliminated affects to
because five is eliminated affects to combine three then we need to eliminate
combine three then we need to eliminate on with much margin export this function
on with much margin export this function would be let's see we need what we said
would be let's see we need what we said to do it on Expo right so this function
to do it on Expo right so this function well playing it all attorney this blue
well playing it all attorney this blue thing that you see here all right so
thing that you see here all right so this would be a function of X to only
this would be a function of X to only which is H porn effective then we need
which is H porn effective then we need to much my selects three which will
to much my selects three which will involve this argument last this function
involve this argument last this function H five this is what you see here this is
H five this is what you see here this is a three of x1 and x2 then we need to
a three of x1 and x2 then we need to maximize on x2 everything that has X Q
maximize on x2 everything that has X Q which is this x dot time to the stage
which is this x dot time to the stage three we call this function a to x one
three we call this function a to x one and then we're vision because we only
and then we're vision because we only have a function of x1 we can maximize it
have a function of x1 we can maximize it and that will give me you know will give
and that will give me you know will give you something a value and that's the
you something a value and that's the maximum of this probability okay so for
maximum of this probability okay so for many ways
there is nothing very different from the elimination algorithm okay
there is something this process here doesn't say anything about so we
doesn't say anything about so we computed the maximum of this probability
distribution of X 1 X 2 X 3 X 4 X 5 that maximize that joint probability what are
maximize that joint probability what are you going to tell you so this calculated
you going to tell you so this calculated the maxim of the joint and now I am
the maxim of the joint and now I am asking you what is what are the values
asking you what is what are the values of X 1 X 2 X 3 X 4 X 5 but together they
of X 1 X 2 X 3 X 4 X 5 but together they maximize this distribution so I want you
maximize this distribution so I want you to look in the big areas there and try
to look in the big areas there and try to think what everything is going to be
to think what everything is going to be that you will see 10 slides from now and
that you will see 10 slides from now and you will look more confusing in verse 10
you will look more confusing in verse 10 slides down the road unless you actually
slides down the road unless you actually understand here how you're going to do
understand here how you're going to do it here
in this case right we let me make it safe from the leaves on the way to the
safe from the leaves on the way to the root so let's call this thing okay can
root so let's call this thing okay can do anything you want but the way we have
do anything you want but the way we have done it in this elimination sequence X 1
done it in this elimination sequence X 1 is the root so that's one that maximizes
is the root so that's one that maximizes this distribution the giant do we know
this distribution the giant do we know the prefix rock that much much
the prefix rock that much much distribution notice what in the last
distribution notice what in the last pair this problem right has only one
pair this problem right has only one argument here which sexual so do we know
argument here which sexual so do we know x1 can we compute X 1 yes this how are
x1 can we compute X 1 yes this how are you going to compute X 2 in this
you going to compute X 2 in this calculation to allow you to compute now
calculation to allow you to compute now the value of x do you remember when we
the value of x do you remember when we computed this when we perform this
computed this when we perform this maximization so what values of x1 we did
maximization so what values of x1 we did it for what value of x 1 did we do this
it for what value of x 1 did we do this maximization with spectryx - it's in the
maximization with spectryx - it's in the definition you can see
no but this is a culture and then what we do is revealed electron that you
we do is revealed electron that you completed here and that function will
completed here and that function will give you the optimal x2
yes are equal to I this is the optimum value of its to first try thinking three
value of its to first try thinking three vistas thereafter on volume
vistas thereafter on volume now we computed with my electron is when
now we computed with my electron is when we live payload so we can go back to the
we live payload so we can go back to the function the palace for each one if x1
function the palace for each one if x1 what's the corresponding X to the
what's the corresponding X to the maximizes this and piggy x1 + 2 x2 equal
maximizes this and piggy x1 + 2 x2 equal to that so degree when we beat
to that so degree when we beat elimination I'm going to write from the
elimination I'm going to write from the list of every we marginalize now it's
list of every we marginalize now it's okay to find the maximum of this joint
okay to find the maximum of this joint distribution yes it's a terrible
distribution yes it's a terrible calculation from the lives to the world
calculation from the lives to the world but to find the extra store do the job
but to find the extra store do the job we have to go backwards right so we now
we have to go backwards right so we now have to go and say you know what
have to go and say you know what we know that the X 2's would maximize
we know that the X 2's would maximize this for each X 1 but we know X 1 so
this for each X 1 but we know X 1 so this will give you the proper X 2 and
this will give you the proper X 2 and then he worked here in second awhat to
then he worked here in second awhat to do this maximization I need to know X 1
do this maximization I need to know X 1 and so in between X 1 and you connect
and so in between X 1 and you connect them together what is not going to make
them together what is not going to make an optimal path for the joint is the
an optimal path for the joint is the beauty
beauty all right so there are infinite paths
all right so there are infinite paths now you need to select the optimal path
now you need to select the optimal path by going back to the help you receive
by going back to the help you receive that so what we describe is actually
that so what we describe is actually very general but the implementation of
very general but the implementation of this the little language does distort it
this the little language does distort it a lot of models is called a return be
a lot of models is called a return be away from that system moves from the end
away from that system moves from the end of the most famous ability computer
of the most famous ability computer science okay
science okay it's used everywhere okay so so this is
it's used everywhere okay so so this is a very useful problem okay and and you
a very useful problem okay and and you can appreciate basically that now yes we
can appreciate basically that now yes we go forward
go forward we go from the links to the route
we go from the links to the route basically to find the maximum but to
basically to find the maximum but to find the x that leads to a maximum we
find the x that leads to a maximum we have to go backwards so there is a
have to go backwards so there is a forward calculation is a powerful
forward calculation is a powerful calculation similarly what we did with
calculation similarly what we did with the sample based on away with sending
the sample based on away with sending messages forward and backward basically
messages forward and backward basically to be able to compute marginals turn and
to be able to compute marginals turn and things like operation is basically you
things like operation is basically you just discuss it right so it looks the
just discuss it right so it looks the the initialization and the evidence is
the initialization and the evidence is exactly the same algorithm that you use
exactly the same algorithm that you use in the in actually this is the algorithm
in the in actually this is the algorithm that we used for the elimination you
that we used for the elimination you know but here I call this I suppose is
know but here I call this I suppose is hope is not a typo
hope is not a typo all right I mean I suppose not much from
all right I mean I suppose not much from you know SQL for Staters but here I
you know SQL for Staters but here I maybe this for the general distribution
maybe this for the general distribution with the map so anyways we initialize
with the map so anyways we initialize the same we have a directed graph we
the same we have a directed graph we initialize all the potentials we put
initialize all the potentials we put them on active list we introduced
them on active list we introduced evidence potentials the way we did
evidence potentials the way we did before and now we have to do the update
before and now we have to do the update all right and the updates are basically
all right and the updates are basically what I described with a particular
what I described with a particular example if you pick up
example if you pick up elimination over their 90th node I you
elimination over their 90th node I you find all the potentials that are
find all the potentials that are interesting node I and then you do
interesting node I and then you do stream optimize with respect to X I all
stream optimize with respect to X I all right
right and once you maximize with respective
and once you maximize with respective time you call this new potential you
time you call this new potential you will put this in potential of the octave
will put this in potential of the octave list okay this time the remaining
list okay this time the remaining knowledge from the elimination click and
knowledge from the elimination click and then the key proceeding until basically
then the key proceeding until basically you whatever number you gave up when you
you whatever number you gave up when you maximized with respect to the root node
maximized with respect to the root node will be the max want to join
will be the max want to join distribution optimization jointly no
distribution optimization jointly no it's right that you complete for
it's right that you complete for different you know there are there's no
different you know there are there's no you shall not eliminate it but you see
you shall not eliminate it but you see okay so for the possible values of this
okay so for the possible values of this you need need to keep track what is the
you need need to keep track what is the maximize your value X I okay and then
maximize your value X I okay and then when units eventually the root and you
when units eventually the root and you calculate the actual note the maximizes
calculate the actual note the maximizes the final potential that you get when
the final potential that you get when you go backwards and you can calculate
you go backwards and you can calculate the remaining of the
the remaining of the so this is not solely the sound good but
so this is not solely the sound good but basically what I described
so actually we the the calculations and the mysticism if you think of this as a
the mysticism if you think of this as a message passing algorithm it looks
message passing algorithm it looks identical to what we have done for the
identical to what we have done for the you know the the only difference except
you know the the only difference except of summations we now have maximization
of summations we now have maximization arguments all right so what the shown
arguments all right so what the shown here is basically when you are done and
here is basically when you are done and you have rates of the route all right so
you have rates of the route all right so then here it's the rate directly we have
then here it's the rate directly we have an evidence potential and the message is
an evidence potential and the message is coming from the children of the root to
coming from the children of the root to the root all right and then what you
the root all right and then what you need to do the only argument here is to
need to do the only argument here is to accept and they need most maximize with
accept and they need most maximize with accept all right so that we give you the
accept all right so that we give you the argument you know the know what's the
argument you know the know what's the value of the root note that the
value of the root note that the maximization and then what we have to do
maximization and then what we have to do is you have to build rapport we
is you have to build rapport we distribute command that you see here -
distribute command that you see here - actually that jointly we must join
actually that jointly we must join distribution at the message an arbitrary
distribution at the message an arbitrary no J's and try it's exactly what we have
no J's and try it's exactly what we have looked with with elimination algorithm
looked with with elimination algorithm before this is the evidence potential
before this is the evidence potential this is the parent potential phi xj and
this is the parent potential phi xj and this xi message is the go to node J
this xi message is the go to node J except I so basically the J sense try
except I so basically the J sense try it's not evidence this join potential
it's not evidence this join potential and all the masses are having to J
and all the masses are having to J except from now the I
except from now the I the basement of standing of three
the basement of standing of three neutralizing it said okay I need to get
neutralizing it said okay I need to get back the XJ right so we find the match
back the XJ right so we find the match to move here so we compute the XJ that
to move here so we compute the XJ that maximizes this alright but we need to
maximizes this alright but we need to find this as a function of X I notice
find this as a function of X I notice from children effects and then who is
from children effects and then who is this the bound and one step further down
this the bound and one step further down and we were to compute basically both
and we were to compute basically both the exits up to at least the point is
the exits up to at least the point is right if you calculate the X J's don't
right if you calculate the X J's don't maximize this whole bunch of exercise
maximize this whole bunch of exercise all right and unique need to keep track
all right and unique need to keep track nothing about maps my batteries because
nothing about maps my batteries because you will need to do this message passing
you will need to do this message passing on this much for that algorithm but also
on this much for that algorithm but also you need to keep values of the optimal
you need to keep values of the optimal taste for its participant bonds of X I
taste for its participant bonds of X I you need this until you get to root this
you need this until you get to root this is where this bullet changed because of
is where this bullet changed because of the work you will know what X is and
the work you will know what X is and then you can mark and compute all the
then you can mark and compute all the other exit
all right again you have to do this because the if
again you have to do this because the if you start selecting among them the sum
you start selecting among them the sum of the X J's that maximize this for
of the X J's that maximize this for whatever xre you're not going to get a
whatever xre you're not going to get a consistent solution basically so you get
consistent solution basically so you get the wrong solution and if I can show you
the wrong solution and if I can show you this actually please to grab some core
this actually please to grab some core I'm going to come back to this right so
you know if you have a Markov chain and you know extra let's say can take three
you know extra let's say can take three five or six you can take three values
five or six you can take three values etcetera xn xn plus 1 so this is one
etcetera xn xn plus 1 so this is one possible this is another possible part
possible this is another possible part right this is the optimal value and then
right this is the optimal value and then basically from there you find what is
basically from there you find what is the corresponding previous value for
the corresponding previous value for that value there is no and from there
that value there is no and from there with the corresponding value of xn and
with the corresponding value of xn and then xn minus 1 so basically you will
then xn minus 1 so basically you will find which is the consisting the
find which is the consisting the consistent part that gives you
consistent part that gives you maximization of the joint
again this is one of this little things right that you need to have to program
right that you need to have to program the state in action alright and what is
the state in action alright and what is interesting here is again the algorithm
interesting here is again the algorithm gives you the impression to start with
gives you the impression to start with but you can only you can maximize it by
but you can only you can maximize it by a forward calculation but to figure out
a forward calculation but to figure out the the argument the extras but maximize
the the argument the extras but maximize jointly the join you have to do the
jointly the join you have to do the Marquart algorithm as well and that's
Marquart algorithm as well and that's what this is all about let me see and
what this is all about let me see and I'm going to pick it up from where we
I'm going to pick it up from where we left it
left it so basically you notice that from the
so basically you notice that from the previous comics let's say and I'm not
previous comics let's say and I'm not sure you know maybe this will come in
sure you know maybe this will come in the next clock work but the clever
the next clock work but the clever program that we you know the multi
program that we you know the multi rejection inspector you can okay working
rejection inspector you can okay working with messages the way we have seen
with messages the way we have seen before
shows notifications then become additions and the algorithm becomes much
additions and the algorithm becomes much time and relation that this is working
time and relation that this is working is basically if you try to maximize the
is basically if you try to maximize the joint of the effect with respect to X
joint of the effect with respect to X and you take the long this is the same
and you take the long this is the same as much rising with respect X the log of
as much rising with respect X the log of P of X
P of X which most defining eggs to be able to
which most defining eggs to be able to the masses it's alright if I define H to
the masses it's alright if I define H to be the lots of the messages this is how
be the lots of the messages this is how the algorithm looks like okay so the
the algorithm looks like okay so the name of the message from JP y por el
name of the message from JP y por el festival values over time is the target
festival values over time is the target remember we have in the progress of the
remember we have in the progress of the incoming messages okay okay because with
incoming messages okay okay because with messages okay every a lot of these
messages okay every a lot of these messages will be extremely small and
messages will be extremely small and basically this message will be an
basically this message will be an informative and getting lots of zeros 10
informative and getting lots of zeros 10 to the minus 50 10 to the minus 30 etc
to the minus 50 10 to the minus 30 etc get in trouble so this is another flow
get in trouble so this is another flow problem that in fact using logs right
problem that in fact using logs right and doing these two missions aware is
and doing these two missions aware is the scope and even then there is the
the scope and even then there is the peak that you can find Pataca lee if you
peak that you can find Pataca lee if you start even in math you have you known
start even in math you have you known the toolbox everywhere on
the toolbox everywhere on Jevon method muslim to ducks or any
Jevon method muslim to ducks or any penny some problems you find whether
penny some problems you find whether they here's this message passing on what
they here's this message passing on what if the sort of positive use thanks for
if the sort of positive use thanks for the message this right but that
the message this right but that shouldn't be an addition i think well i
shouldn't be an addition i think well i wanted to show you because if you
wanted to show you because if you program without this trick and i what i
program without this trick and i what i want to go you're not going to be able
want to go you're not going to be able to actually do large-scale profits so
to actually do large-scale profits so here's where the three kids so the
here's where the three kids so the message is this is what we have before
message is this is what we have before I'm writing this in the context of the
I'm writing this in the context of the eliminating expected a so you can have
eliminating expected a so you can have the marks operator that's exactly the
the marks operator that's exactly the same thing so we use no messages all
same thing so we use no messages all right and so summation Alexei of this x
right and so summation Alexei of this x naught and because this are love
naught and because this are love messages I can write this then you see
messages I can write this then you see this would become estimation all right
this would become estimation all right and if I put outside because this term
and if I put outside because this term of masters and when I have an
of masters and when I have an exponential inside okay we need this
exponential inside okay we need this looks extremely complex right because we
looks extremely complex right because we have to find the local summation and by
have to find the local summation and by the way all estimation is very typical
the way all estimation is very typical in many other words in machine learning
in many other words in machine learning okay you cannot take this long and put
okay you cannot take this long and put it inside so novel destination in exit
it inside so novel destination in exit any survivors two terms as exponential
any survivors two terms as exponential of the law website this is what they
of the law website this is what they have and because I put the exponential
have and because I put the exponential of try so here I have a summation
of try so here I have a summation alright so you take all of this and you
alright so you take all of this and you call it ln j alright this is where they
call it ln j alright this is where they have exponential of halides a and then
have exponential of halides a and then you find out the maximum the prime
you find out the maximum the prime business that maximizes that is the
business that maximizes that is the maximum basically from all the holidays
maximum basically from all the holidays so you pull this out
so you pull this out and then with the leftist exponential of
and then with the leftist exponential of mij - mi z okay and this is how
mij - mi z okay and this is how basically you have to implement the log
basically you have to implement the log messages when you write your computer
messages when you write your computer program you can play with this and
program you can play with this and convince yourself actually that this
convince yourself actually that this avoids other flow issues the way it did
avoids other flow issues the way it did here okay so study members of this
here okay so study members of this little algorithm Stephan actually if you
little algorithm Stephan actually if you see it in computer programs you know
see it in computer programs you know know that these nothing strange
know that these nothing strange basically comes by the algebra okay can
basically comes by the algebra okay can you do too much time algorithm graphs
you do too much time algorithm graphs there are stories of course you can do
there are stories of course you can do anything you want to and if we use again
anything you want to and if we use again some messages the message the normal
some messages the message the normal condition is basically the track system
condition is basically the track system that saved in the list node the message
that saved in the list node the message that we send to the clique the first
that we send to the clique the first factor is zero unity when we did last
factor is zero unity when we did last lecture this message will come after
lecture this message will come after equal to AB natural pesticides is zero
equal to AB natural pesticides is zero and if the first value is a path then
and if the first value is a path then the message is the lung of the potential
the message is the lung of the potential of the factor and this is so this is the
of the factor and this is so this is the message is basically that we were
message is basically that we were working on the last lecture if you want
working on the last lecture if you want to send a message from a factor to a
to send a message from a factor to a node potential if you take all the
node potential if you take all the messages to derive from all the
messages to derive from all the neighbors of the factor except at that
neighbors of the factor except at that arrived to the factor you multiply them
arrived to the factor you multiply them and then you have you basically
and then you have you basically eliminate you integrate our x12 except
eliminate you integrate our x12 except all the nodes are involved in the fact
all the nodes are involved in the fact will accept nowadays okay so instantly
will accept nowadays okay so instantly if you wanted to find the message and
if you wanted to find the message and now since the factor
now since the factor is the message that central that no that
is the message that central that no that step of course the factor of pest so you
step of course the factor of pest so you might have been of incoming messages and
might have been of incoming messages and you fought with them the factor of s so
you fought with them the factor of s so if you take those and exchange the
if you take those and exchange the summations for the match operator and
summations for the match operator and you want to do a march time I will
you want to do a march time I will contact the graphs very trivial the
contact the graphs very trivial the message from dr. Novak's is the match
message from dr. Novak's is the match list all right notice we're going to
list all right notice we're going to have a love of this and estimation here
have a love of this and estimation here so obviously when I make this equation
so obviously when I make this equation the implication is that now this mere
the implication is that now this mere solutions of the actual messages right
solutions of the actual messages right there loves that's why you see here the
there loves that's why you see here the problem became estimation and and again
problem became estimation and and again from a note the fact that you notice the
from a note the fact that you notice the product becomes oscillation and the rest
product becomes oscillation and the rest is basic and the history when you reach
is basic and the history when you reach the root node you'll be able to find the
the root node you'll be able to find the value of x that does the maximization of
value of x that does the maximization of the fold where the summation of all the
the fold where the summation of all the messages coming from below and and then
messages coming from below and and then you need to do backtracking
you need to do backtracking from the root back all the way to the
from the root back all the way to the list to figure out what of the x's that
maximize the Joint Distribution so then if you have an implementation of the
if you have an implementation of the sample of the target for photographs you
sample of the target for photographs you can transform it to a nautical algorithm
can transform it to a nautical algorithm by changing the definitions of the
by changing the definitions of the salmon exchanging terms with the match
salmon exchanging terms with the match operator and if you're not already doing
operator and if you're not already doing this and you have to do this in your
this and you have to do this in your homework trying basically not to use
homework trying basically not to use messages will now use log message to see
messages will now use log message to see how things will look like
this mystery is the same thing we just discussed from the on a simple train as
discussed from the on a simple train as an example all right so that have a
an example all right so that have a message that you see on this block I
message that you see on this block I think this is the negation of a graph we
think this is the negation of a graph we had on an earlier lecture but now the
had on an earlier lecture but now the way I have it all the messages are
way I have it all the messages are basically for the for calculating the
basically for the for calculating the maximum distribution and they are lost
maximum distribution and they are lost so from that they are the same so the
so from that they are the same so the message to this right is the same as the
message to this right is the same as the message from this particle to this node
message from this particle to this node so whatever because this is same
so whatever because this is same whatever message this not receive from
whatever message this not receive from this factor sense it called with an X
this factor sense it called with an X Factor and if you want to find the
Factor and if you want to find the message let's see this is the message
message let's see this is the message from the factor n minus 1 n who is not
from the factor n minus 1 n who is not so this is we want to compute this
so this is we want to compute this message here right this is what we want
message here right this is what we want to compute so this message you know what
to compute so this message you know what the basis is this times incoming message
the basis is this times incoming message so what we're gonna do is we're gonna
so what we're gonna do is we're gonna take the arc match with respect to X n
take the arc match with respect to X n minus 1 Indianness HN minus 1 I'm
minus 1 Indianness HN minus 1 I'm carrying the potential we now have the
carrying the potential we now have the real potential last incoming message
real potential last incoming message which is here okay that's basically the
which is here okay that's basically the two relations that you need to be able
two relations that you need to be able to propagate messages for this
surrounding can you tell me what functional you wanna need to keep
what functional you wanna need to keep flaps here so here you compute the
flaps here so here you compute the maximum of this and you send it to this
maximum of this and you send it to this message but we also need to keep tariffs
message but we also need to keep tariffs of xn minus 1 for what for every value
of xn minus 1 for what for every value of x and you should have figure out we
of x and you should have figure out we need to do this maximization for our
need to do this maximization for our past reviews of Excel so you are gonna
past reviews of Excel so you are gonna need to find the optimal xn minus 1 as a
need to find the optimal xn minus 1 as a function of xn and this to the sponsors
function of xn and this to the sponsors who wrote this and then we can use all
who wrote this and then we can use all of this simple functions to go backwards
of this simple functions to go backwards to get all the previous section so when
to get all the previous section so when I find it say here the maximum this
I find it say here the maximum this expression that you see here at the same
expression that you see here at the same time it gives me the optimal there the -
okay we will not accept all right showing the next back we also need to
showing the next back we also need to keep collection as a function of xn plus
keep collection as a function of xn plus 1 and xn plus 1 is a function of xn plus
1 and xn plus 1 is a function of xn plus 2 until we say root note where we will
2 until we say root note where we will be able to figure out what they would
be able to figure out what they would value is and then go backwards
so before and if I have time to tell you about the jobs action tree algorithm
about the jobs action tree algorithm wanted to just put very few slides this
wanted to just put very few slides this sort of historical algorithm of belief
sort of historical algorithm of belief propagation on you know directed graphs
propagation on you know directed graphs without loops these most of its work is
without loops these most of its work is in a little very important book VIPRE on
in a little very important book VIPRE on probabilistic reasoning intelligent
probabilistic reasoning intelligent systems you may even be able to find
systems you may even be able to find this book online and so the dimension is
this book online and so the dimension is actually it somebody knows this is based
actually it somebody knows this is based on elimination this some product so this
on elimination this some product so this comes out to be a sub J's
comes out to be a sub J's so in some sense I'm going to be
so in some sense I'm going to be evidently be different for directed
evidently be different for directed graphs but you can say that the
graphs but you can say that the algorithm actually looks the same okay
algorithm actually looks the same okay so so this is this out directed graph
so so this is this out directed graph okay so we are looking at no text use of
okay so we are looking at no text use of the forints effects wise of the children
the forints effects wise of the children affection etc and physically okay so
affection etc and physically okay so this would be three note the the
this would be three note the the directionality of the edges basically
directionality of the edges basically you get an undirected today with single
you get an undirected today with single path basically from one node to any
path basically from one node to any other node the especially to be able to
other node the especially to be able to understand this idea of belief
understand this idea of belief propagation but the game is the same
propagation but the game is the same algorithm so we are looking at X and so
algorithm so we are looking at X and so the idea is that the probability of X
the idea is that the probability of X this is sort of the marginal effects
this is sort of the marginal effects this way we have done up now reminds
this way we have done up now reminds information from upstream and doused
information from upstream and doused so basically combines evidence
so basically combines evidence propagating from upstairs to and
propagating from upstairs to and evidence propagating from downstairs
evidence propagating from downstairs okay and the idea that I can submit the
okay and the idea that I can submit the evidence when upstream and downstream
evidence when upstream and downstream has to do with the park the next
has to do with the park the next disappearance the evidence from upstate
disappearance the evidence from upstate from up and down you can see this right
from up and down you can see this right to go if we have evidence there and
to go if we have evidence there and evidence out there and you have to pass
evidence out there and you have to pass through xxxx basically block start so
through xxxx basically block start so it's it does it separates the evidence
it's it does it separates the evidence from upstream and downstream so if you
from upstream and downstream so if you want to compute the probability of x
want to compute the probability of x given the evidence let's say this is our
given the evidence let's say this is our problem this is basically their belief
problem this is basically their belief all right that we want to compute about
all right that we want to compute about X so I can write this as the joint
X so I can write this as the joint affection 8 divided by the area the
affection 8 divided by the area the probability of the evidence I because
probability of the evidence I because the X dissipates the evidence plus and
the X dissipates the evidence plus and minus plus is the evidence of their -
minus plus is the evidence of their - the evidence down from it I can write
the evidence down from it I can write this yet + and against - and this is not
this yet + and against - and this is not important for it so we don't care so I
important for it so we don't care so I can write this as the probability of P X
can write this as the probability of P X minus given X and the X plus and the
minus given X and the X plus and the probability of x given Y X plus alright
probability of x given Y X plus alright and because X dissipates all right
and because X dissipates all right I can I don't need to keep the X plus
I can I don't need to keep the X plus here so this belief can be written as
here so this belief can be written as the community coming from upstream
the community coming from upstream evidence and this time that is the
evidence and this time that is the probability coming from downstream
probability coming from downstream evidence ok so this is basically using
evidence ok so this is basically using Bayes rule and the fact that we have a
Bayes rule and the fact that we have a dissipation here that I used in this
dissipation here that I used in this equation it allows me to write the
equation it allows me to write the the belief of the you know they in this
the belief of the you know they in this case is conditional on the evidence
case is conditional on the evidence right but you can think of the
right but you can think of the calculations we were doing area for
calculations we were doing area for marginals that they were sort of the
marginals that they were sort of the Train so think of this as the Masters
Train so think of this as the Masters coming from upstream five semesters come
coming from upstream five semesters come from downstream isn't it what we did
from downstream isn't it what we did when we computed the marginal right is
when we computed the marginal right is the product of the two messages but now
the product of the two messages but now you notice this things basically will
you notice this things basically will derive from Vegas rule
derive from Vegas rule I'm not going to level a depending by
I'm not going to level a depending by the simplistic we can philosophize on
the simplistic we can philosophize on this but you can call this you can put a
this but you can call this you can put a prior or next right and apply of naming
prior or next right and apply of naming and this is the likelihood a discount
and this is the likelihood a discount from downstream but right now you know
from downstream but right now you know we have to compute these ten that is
we have to compute these ten that is information coming from upstream and
information coming from upstream and disturb that comes from from downstream
which in combined ups limit downstream information to find the probability of x
information to find the probability of x idea to that this message does we know
idea to that this message does we know can be computed by local message passing
can be computed by local message passing algorithm which we have seen okay and
algorithm which we have seen okay and the last idea which also we have
the last idea which also we have discussed it they never sent to annul
discussed it they never sent to annul and investors the note sent to you
and investors the note sent to you that's it so I am going to move you the
that's it so I am going to move you the equations and I want you to actually
equations and I want you to actually study them because they have a
study them because they have a historical significance to be the
historical significance to be the conditional probability of x given the
conditional probability of x given the evidence and we just take this as the
evidence and we just take this as the information coming now let me see what
information coming now let me see what the definition here coming from
the definition here coming from downstream so this comes this term
downstream so this comes this term lambda comes from the children this is
lambda comes from the children this is what we derived various room and this is
what we derived various room and this is the information coming from the parents
the information coming from the parents okay certainly
okay certainly I'm gonna give you the message passing
I'm gonna give you the message passing algorithm but that's you what lambda is
algorithm but that's you what lambda is and what PI is based on what we have
and what PI is based on what we have done alright so we need the information
done alright so we need the information coming from the children but extract
coming from the children but extract looking at this graph can return me with
looking at this graph can return me with message passing algorithms what is the
message passing algorithms what is the information that comes from the children
information that comes from the children to X
and again timbers you know there on this slide but tell me which words basically
slide but tell me which words basically I want to find all the information comes
I want to find all the information comes from mastering 2x and I want to be this
from mastering 2x and I want to be this through messages of the children of X +
through messages of the children of X + 2 X so that is round effect is the
2 X so that is round effect is the product at what
is the protocol for the messages the chinder of X send text isn't it the way
chinder of X send text isn't it the way we have done it before - with masters
we have done it before - with masters passing all right so there's nothing
passing all right so there's nothing better one to fix is the program to
better one to fix is the program to folder messages which raised the
folder messages which raised the children of text right sent correct okay
children of text right sent correct okay let's now calculate the information of
[Applause]
the effects by taking the product of far upstream and downstream children sent to
upstream and downstream children sent to X to be able to do waste then I have to
X to be able to do waste then I have to complete the information of the VEX
complete the information of the VEX turns to children and also you are going
turns to children and also you are going to have to compute the information
to have to compute the information access to its parents right you're not
access to its parents right you're not gonna be able to calculate these
gonna be able to calculate these messages too long so you have to
messages too long so you have to calculate those master as well
this is what particular logically this is the method the XS it's part of your
is the method the XS it's part of your high so we have the question can it just
high so we have the question can it just you know anomic look at the questions
you know anomic look at the questions look at this picture can you tell me
look at this picture can you tell me what in what master deck sense to the
what in what master deck sense to the trade to you i what will it's time to
trade to you i what will it's time to act - you are what information actual
act - you are what information actual center yard
and examples right with message-passing story if I am asking whether extents to
story if I am asking whether extents to you I so which is this message what
you I so which is this message what wouldn't do
yes percent is received from the from your children because the amount of
your children because the amount of facts here was the person after former
facts here was the person after former messages from the kids okay because you
messages from the kids okay because you actually see from you are and you do etc
actually see from you are and you do etc so if you need to do this again the
so if you need to do this again the potential this is like the clip
potential this is like the clip potentially relax live in its past times
potentially relax live in its past times the messages we received from all of the
the messages we received from all of the other parents you notice k not equal to
other parents you notice k not equal to I and then of course that you need to do
I and then of course that you need to do is to integrate that child and of course
is to integrate that child and of course in this time we are going to have to
in this time we are going to have to integrate all the other parents out
integrate all the other parents out right and what you got here semesters
right and what you got here semesters with this defense on a UI it's exactly
with this defense on a UI it's exactly the same as before shown with messages
the same as before shown with messages the wave have dominated with message
the wave have dominated with message passing it looks very plain but this is
passing it looks very plain but this is an anomaly because she was developed in
an anomaly because she was developed in nineteen eighty fifty people talking
nineteen eighty fifty people talking about must in learning in any serious
about must in learning in any serious extent right and so this has been
extent right and so this has been experienced in text so you say them to
experienced in text so you say them to children say so you're not a skiing not
children say so you're not a skiing not equal to say but also you send all the
equal to say but also you send all the messages the parent effects and text
messages the parent effects and text which is what we have here with all the
which is what we have here with all the use integrate our
use integrate our she says the product before the mess is
she says the product before the mess is coming from all the kids but they shall
coming from all the kids but they shall actually to multiply with the message
actually to multiply with the message coming from that syndrome jail as well
coming from that syndrome jail as well and divide you can arrive the message
and divide you can arrive the message that you sent to a children's I as the
that you sent to a children's I as the Bourbon Arabic divided by the misses
Bourbon Arabic divided by the misses that the children James tends to you
that the children James tends to you the message that they sent you do you
the message that they sent you do you remember when you like this right invoke
remember when you like this right invoke this times the message that children
this times the message that children Jason's Plex which we're gonna listen to
Jason's Plex which we're gonna listen to what I'm gonna serve to tell you whether
what I'm gonna serve to tell you whether it's sent to us so we / it and you have
it's sent to us so we / it and you have this belief of X divided by this message
this belief of X divided by this message you know she has some electric
you know she has some electric advantages fear there and in some of the
advantages fear there and in some of the implementations of this message passing
implementations of this message passing algorithm you may see this type of
algorithm you may see this type of division so rather than saying do this
division so rather than saying do this multiplication for K different today
multiplication for K different today which another way of writing it right so
which another way of writing it right so the military / the message that wage and
the military / the message that wage and Jerry sent to X am I giving you a
Jerry sent to X am I giving you a headache already a little bit yes you
headache already a little bit yes you said yes yes all right
the slides are up on the web actually which I put them to get today alright so
which I put them to get today alright so there they trade their pipe so you don't
there they trade their pipe so you don't have to I'm just writing a questions and
have to I'm just writing a questions and tastes different than Jame and all of
tastes different than Jame and all of this can't duplicate this but yet it
this can't duplicate this but yet it takes so much of platform okay this is
takes so much of platform okay this is for professors who have nothing to do at
for professors who have nothing to do at night to just do lots of typing of our
night to just do lots of typing of our slides
slides okay ensue exception obviously this
okay ensue exception obviously this semester with his slides and but in some
semester with his slides and but in some sense when I ask you to type the
sense when I ask you to type the homework that is the reason right when
homework that is the reason right when you type things you look at them and you
you type things you look at them and you take a look again and again you say you
take a look again and again you say you know what doesn't look right and if it
know what doesn't look right and if it doesn't look like it is not right
doesn't look like it is not right and you can only say that when you type
and you can only say that when you type them when you do like that everything
them when you do like that everything but right good or bad you know I mean
but right good or bad you know I mean but when you type it it visually doesn't
but when you type it it visually doesn't look right it's most probably not right
look right it's most probably not right okay any questions all right
okay any questions all right so I am saying no because 132 so let me
so I am saying no because 132 so let me do it correctly I am going to discuss
do it correctly I am going to discuss the junction tree algorithm and I'm
the junction tree algorithm and I'm gonna give you it's sufficient time
gonna give you it's sufficient time actually to go through this today is an
actually to go through this today is an introduction and I'm gonna give you
introduction and I'm gonna give you formally the structure of the algorithm
formally the structure of the algorithm when we go back to it on Tuesday friends
when we go back to it on Tuesday friends by the way of the lecture today and also
by the way of the lecture today and also the lecture for Tuesday
the lecture for Tuesday one of the chapters of Michael Jordan's
one of the chapters of Michael Jordan's book or Junction 3 is basically the best
book or Junction 3 is basically the best read for the subject okay
read for the subject okay very elementary but sort of addresses
very elementary but sort of addresses everything very nice
so it's course again I'm going to do this through an example to motivate with
this through an example to motivate with the algorithm is so let's assume that we
the algorithm is so let's assume that we have a directed graph that looks like
have a directed graph that looks like this
all right obviously this is not a tree right you can see it
right you can see it I mean if it's they are was not there
I mean if it's they are was not there you can claim this two three but this is
you can claim this two three but this is not a tree so you know we have to see
not a tree so you know we have to see how the this new algorithm is action 300
how the this new algorithm is action 300 will help us to calculate ryx all right
will help us to calculate ryx all right so what we're gonna need is I'm gonna
so what we're gonna need is I'm gonna take you through the process okay so I
take you through the process okay so I notice here so I'm going to convert this
notice here so I'm going to convert this to an undirected graph and as we have
to an undirected graph and as we have seen before the the first step is to
seen before the the first step is to moralize basically and x5 is to balance
moralize basically and x5 is to balance so we wanna lies that we get an
so we wanna lies that we get an undirected graph that looks like that
we are going to say we're going to select an elimination order of this
select an elimination order of this graph and we're going to keep that
graph and we're going to keep that basically of the elimination plate and
basically of the elimination plate and we're going to pry interpretation we
we're going to pry interpretation we commute elimination clicks so this
commute elimination clicks so this elimination cliques or the junction
elimination cliques or the junction three that are going basically to
three that are going basically to contain the function the factors
contain the function the factors affiliated with our elimination clips we
affiliated with our elimination clips we will see this on this particular example
so this is that what we got right
that somehow Muhammad is on the previous slide and I'm going to connect nodes X 2
slide and I'm going to connect nodes X 2 and X 3 this is what I am saying I'm
and X 3 this is what I am saying I'm calling it I'm going to triangulate the
calling it I'm going to triangulate the glass and can you just potentially why
glass and can you just potentially why basically I need to premonition clicks
basically I need to premonition clicks so somebody why do you need why do I
so somebody why do you need why do I need to triangulate the graph what
need to triangulate the graph what potentially benefit may exist there you
potentially benefit may exist there you know if I call notes together what is
know if I call notes together what is the you know this is a big potential
the you know this is a big potential because in those for naught right so we
because in those for naught right so we need sort of to reduce that to 3 nodes
need sort of to reduce that to 3 nodes but blowing that there is a fundamental
but blowing that there is a fundamental property that I will show you one we
property that I will show you one we complete this that without any lighting
complete this that without any lighting in you're not going to be able to make
in you're not going to be able to make the junction tree algorithm or so so we
the junction tree algorithm or so so we may need to tell you when we reach the
may need to tell you when we reach the end of this example all right so the
end of this example all right so the first reason is we want to reduce the
first reason is we want to reduce the size of this clique but there is another
size of this clique but there is another important aspect that we will see when
important aspect that we will see when the algorithm produces ok is 1 2 3 1 1 2
the algorithm produces ok is 1 2 3 1 1 2 3 ok now we're going to eliminate the
3 ok now we're going to eliminate the chain let's see what is the next node we
chain let's see what is the next node we want to eliminate now - ok that's our
want to eliminate now - ok that's our order so the next elimination clique is
order so the next elimination clique is 2 3 &amp; 4 2 3 or 4 this is what we left
2 3 &amp; 4 2 3 or 4 this is what we left the next elimination clique is 3 4 &amp; 5
the next elimination clique is 3 4 &amp; 5 so we will eliminate
so we will eliminate three so three four five the next
three so three four five the next elimination will be for North Shore
elimination will be for North Shore so the next week would be falling five
so the next week would be falling five and then I have time so the next week is
and then I have time so the next week is now side and one in addition we kept
now side and one in addition we kept track of all these plygs and I'm going
track of all these plygs and I'm going to get rid of the clicks that there are
to get rid of the clicks that there are subsets of other maximal cliques all
subsets of other maximal cliques all right so what are you going to keep
right so what are you going to keep parked at this much more clicks one two
parked at this much more clicks one two three two three four and three four five
I am going to consider this as notes is in one God right so this is trick
in one God right so this is trick this is click one two three so the notes
this is click one two three so the notes the variables that are contained in
the variables that are contained in notes you all are X 1 X 2 3 bottom of 63
notes you all are X 1 X 2 3 bottom of 63 export excretes 4 X 5 so now I'm going
export excretes 4 X 5 so now I'm going to do is I am going to pay attention to
to do is I am going to pay attention to you notice I am connecting all of this
you notice I am connecting all of this together but this is not really to me
together but this is not really to me and so we come up with three that
and so we come up with three that involves this right and that click will
involves this right and that click will come with it as follows look at this
come with it as follows look at this connection here how many nodes as the
connection here how many nodes as the clip steps you can ask how many common
clip steps you can ask how many common notes they have to come out this two
notes they have to come out this two clicks who is one yes so we are going to
clicks who is one yes so we are going to design a three that has eight something
design a three that has eight something to resist and weight is accounted by how
to resist and weight is accounted by how many common notes served between these
many common notes served between these maximal cliques and honestly doctor you
maximal cliques and honestly doctor you will believe it may will be C 1 C 2 C 3
will believe it may will be C 1 C 2 C 3 and
because this is what we okay you know
all right
okay so in this case obviously this is
it's common to see one instance consistency between the clinics and in
consistency between the clinics and in the way we're going to be computing
the way we're going to be computing marginals if X belongs to C 1 and C 3 it
marginals if X belongs to C 1 and C 3 it also has to belong to any other click
also has to belong to any other click from c1 to c3 via this tree so basically
from c1 to c3 via this tree so basically we will not be able to propagate
we will not be able to propagate messages from c1 to c2 to c3 because how
messages from c1 to c2 to c3 because how are you going to propagate messages
are you going to propagate messages about the x3 when this is not a function
about the x3 when this is not a function of X 3 so this property is called the
of X 3 so this property is called the running intersection property okay so if
running intersection property okay so if viable is common to
viable is common to tip breaks but you see for example c1
tip breaks but you see for example c1 and c3 has to be also a fun intermediate
and c3 has to be also a fun intermediate click from c1 to c3 okay now again I
click from c1 to c3 okay now again I mentioned that this is essential for
mentioned that this is essential for maintaining consistency when you
maintaining consistency when you calculate multi notes on this graph I'm
calculate multi notes on this graph I'm going to actually discuss this in
going to actually discuss this in determined history right but right now
determined history right but right now this is basically how long's action 3
this is basically how long's action 3 looks like it's not that you need it but
looks like it's not that you need it but out of the way that people look at this
out of the way that people look at this algorithms in addition to these great
algorithms in addition to these great potentials the separators which are
potentials the separators which are basically the notes of their common
basically the notes of their common between these marks
between these marks all right so the message passing from
say if c1 is going to send the messages - - that will be information that
- - that will be information that will update with variable only the
will update with variable only the person who is not involving mr. Pareto I
person who is not involving mr. Pareto I mean you know more and more in Steinmetz
mean you know more and more in Steinmetz about that Schwann when this doesn't
about that Schwann when this doesn't depend on X was trying to try one side
depend on X was trying to try one side to side 3 is basically like if you have
to side 3 is basically like if you have this graph right you can make your own
this graph right you can make your own assignment of potentials having evolved
assignment of potentials having evolved such 1x to explain if you have
such 1x to explain if you have protesters of involve X 2 X 3 and
protesters of involve X 2 X 3 and similarly here it's great sports 5 you
similarly here it's great sports 5 you have choices if you start from a
have choices if you start from a directed graph of how you do this
directed graph of how you do this assignment but actively whatever
assignment but actively whatever optimization you have
optimization you have here you can transform this to Taiwan
here you can transform this to Taiwan Cyclops I predefined cupboard over this
Cyclops I predefined cupboard over this mask on trips and history you can use
mask on trips and history you can use these misses passing away that we have
these misses passing away that we have seen for priests and now you can do this
seen for priests and now you can do this injunction treats even though the
injunction treats even though the original problem had nothing to do with
original problem had nothing to do with please so how do you do this you can
please so how do you do this you can compute the Masters this clixsense
compute the Masters this clixsense 2 from 1 to 2 and how do you compute is
2 from 1 to 2 and how do you compute is the potential of two extreme 1 and then
the potential of two extreme 1 and then what do you do you integrate X 1 out
what do you do you integrate X 1 out there is no incoming message from any
there is no incoming message from any part right so this is like the root node
part right so this is like the root node there is no incoming message so this is
there is no incoming message so this is n - 1 2 - let me see if there is another
n - 1 2 - let me see if there is another picture if we look at the message from
picture if we look at the message from day 2 1 obviously I'm going to take this
day 2 1 obviously I'm going to take this potential all right but also there is an
potential all right but also there is an incoming message from city - -
incoming message from city - - which is that and then you have to
which is that and then you have to integrate variables that don't belong in
integrate variables that don't belong in the separator that's valuable export so
the separator that's valuable export so you integrate Explorer ok
you integrate Explorer ok and how do you compute so I can finish
and how do you compute so I can finish when you finish if you're interested to
when you finish if you're interested to compute the marginals corresponding of
compute the marginals corresponding of the Barnabus X 1 X 2 X 3 corresponding
the Barnabus X 1 X 2 X 3 corresponding to this trick but it is this is the
to this trick but it is this is the local potential sorry 1 times the
local potential sorry 1 times the message that arrives to see one from
message that arrives to see one from City the numbers and if you compute the
City the numbers and if you compute the marginal of X 2 X the export takes the
marginal of X 2 X the export takes the local potential times the message one
local potential times the message one sense the to take the message the priest
sense the to take the message the priest of the two and you're done actually it
of the two and you're done actually it comes out to be exact
comes out to be exact if you are using it even when you have
if you are using it even when you have graphs with loops and already we
graphs with loops and already we discussed the algorithm is called the
discussed the algorithm is called the loopy belief propagation algorithm here
loopy belief propagation algorithm here looks you basically have two there is no
looks you basically have two there is no such a thing as to the message from the
such a thing as to the message from the neighbors and then propagate them right
neighbors and then propagate them right because you have loop so what you need
because you have loop so what you need this initialize all this messages to
this initialize all this messages to maybe or something if any values so who
maybe or something if any values so who cares for sending messages to all the
cares for sending messages to all the other nodes and then you can apply your
other nodes and then you can apply your classical Esther passing so if you have
classical Esther passing so if you have the loops the junction tree I would make
the loops the junction tree I would make work and then lots of time works that if
work and then lots of time works that if you set the literature there some very
you set the literature there some very standard pain problems when it it pays
standard pain problems when it it pays drastically and it doesn't work a lot
drastically and it doesn't work a lot okay but there's no proofs why it works
okay but there's no proofs why it works when it works but it actually works and
when it works but it actually works and it works for arbitrary graphs and you
it works for arbitrary graphs and you know and you can make it actually work
know and you can make it actually work exactly okay so 146 the slides will have
exactly okay so 146 the slides will have a thing that is another example we did
a thing that is another example we did in maybe giant Satyam the junction tree
in maybe giant Satyam the junction tree algorithm so when we come back on
algorithm so when we come back on Tuesday we can finish this general
Tuesday we can finish this general inference algorithm is from online
inference algorithm is from online lecture so to make sure you have this
lecture so to make sure you have this transform you okay just reserve two
transform you okay just reserve two problems by tomorrow so you know what
cetera you can stop by when I'm there usually eat up tonight's the best time
usually eat up tonight's the best time okay so