I bet the dory will open as soon as I stop talking okay let's try it
stop talking okay let's try it so 1231 okay you can you count the
so 1231 okay you can you count the seconds when the door will open so the
seconds when the door will open so the main topic today is what is called the
main topic today is what is called the elimination algorithm that sort of we
elimination algorithm that sort of we have sort of seen it with examples up to
have sort of seen it with examples up to now but we're going to try to do it in a
now but we're going to try to do it in a sort of graph theoretic manner but
sort of graph theoretic manner but before that I need to cover maybe if you
before that I need to cover maybe if you slice from the previous lecture if you
slice from the previous lecture if you remember we're talking about you see I
remember we're talking about you see I was right
was right okay so we are going to talk it was not
okay so we are going to talk it was not about you okay so we're going to talk
about you okay so we're going to talk about examples of actually some of them
about examples of actually some of them we will see in very fine detail so it
we will see in very fine detail so it later on said things look weird in the
later on said things look weird in the context of Bayesian inference for gosh
context of Bayesian inference for gosh we have not seen these things we will
we have not seen these things we will come back to those things later on so
come back to those things later on so the example that we already did was one
the example that we already did was one of polynomial regression so this
of polynomial regression so this actually just Bayesian linear regression
actually just Bayesian linear regression so we treat the response of the system
so we treat the response of the system which is scalar and we call it P to some
which is scalar and we call it P to some polynomial with this coefficients WI
polynomial with this coefficients WI being random variables and we wrote the
being random variables and we wrote the joint probability distribution like that
joint probability distribution like that so this is the prior of W and this is
so this is the prior of W and this is the likelihood so if when you W with the
the likelihood so if when you W with the probability of here okay and this is in
probability of here okay and this is in its most general form all right where W
its most general form all right where W has the prior on Davi has some height of
has the prior on Davi has some height of our meters alpha and this likelihood
our meters alpha and this likelihood model for its input for its W depends on
model for its input for its W depends on some noise variance Sigma square which
some noise variance Sigma square which is not known so this is sort of again in
is not known so this is sort of again in more detail the joint probability of T
more detail the joint probability of T these the response and W of the unknown
these the response and W of the unknown regression coefficients so what we did
regression coefficients so what we did this we introduced this plate notation
this we introduced this plate notation and the everything is inside the box
and the everything is inside the box means it is repeating n times so when
means it is repeating n times so when you say you see here you know when you
you say you see here you know when you try to write the joint probability
try to write the joint probability distribution of all the variables on
distribution of all the variables on this model you're going to have the
this model you're going to have the probability of TN given X 10 but now you
probability of TN given X 10 but now you have n of those and that's how you get
have n of those and that's how you get this product and of course you have the
this product and of course you have the probability of W given alpha and alpha
probability of W given alpha and alpha and Sigma square is taken as fixed
and Sigma square is taken as fixed parameters right now so there's no
parameters right now so there's no probability affiliated to them so this
probability affiliated to them so this is the plate notation and when you get
is the plate notation and when you get expert in this type of things sometimes
expert in this type of things sometimes you will be drawing this book this pixel
you will be drawing this book this pixel sphere and immediately implying this a
sphere and immediately implying this a lot of other writing this and that
lot of other writing this and that saying here is the picture showing the
saying here is the picture showing the distribution okay but it will take some
distribution okay but it will take some time basically to get rain on doing that
time basically to get rain on doing that but in a lots of papers people don't
but in a lots of papers people don't want to do to solve the answer bus or
want to do to solve the answer bus or what they saw is this and that implies
what they saw is this and that implies everything you need to know okay and I
everything you need to know okay and I think we want to extend it first you
think we want to extend it first you know in the last few seconds of the
know in the last few seconds of the presentation last Thursday to include
presentation last Thursday to include also predictions so this is the joint
also predictions so this is the joint probability distribution of W of the
probability distribution of W of the training data the build is the training
training data the build is the training data corresponding to X ball and also we
data corresponding to X ball and also we have the prediction stick heart
have the prediction stick heart corresponding to X 1/2 so if you try to
corresponding to X 1/2 so if you try to form this joint distribution basically
form this joint distribution basically what you have is this is the posterior
what you have is this is the posterior of W this is what we had before but also
of W this is what we had before but also now you see the light liquid
now you see the light liquid corresponding to X hot okay so this is
corresponding to X hot okay so this is the probability of big heart given X hat
the probability of big heart given X hat and given the parameters W Sigma square
and given the parameters W Sigma square and again pictorially we have the same
and again pictorially we have the same thing as before but not what we have
thing as before but not what we have done is we have included a note that
done is we have included a note that will allow us for any text heart to
will allow us for any text heart to figure out what the prediction big heart
figure out what the prediction big heart is and you notice this prediction the
is and you notice this prediction the heart depends for next heart it depends
heart depends for next heart it depends from w and it depends on Sigma square so
from w and it depends on Sigma square so the arrows basically is to all the
the arrows basically is to all the dependencies that you need to know so
dependencies that you need to know so too extreme is complicated right but on
too extreme is complicated right but on the other hand someone would say this is
the other hand someone would say this is complicated already well this
complicated already well this incorporates the full model again if you
incorporates the full model again if you have not seen this problems in the
have not seen this problems in the context of regression it will take you
context of regression it will take you less than 20 minutes to read my
less than 20 minutes to read my regression lecture from not semester or
regression lecture from not semester or looking at the book like bishops or
looking at the book like bishops or leftist view to get some idea on this
leftist view to get some idea on this type of thing
that's another progression problem that goes with the name relevance vector
goes with the name relevance vector machines we actually don't believe we
machines we actually don't believe we cover this even in the course last
cover this even in the course last semester but basically a simple idea you
semester but basically a simple idea you it's similar in many ways to the
it's similar in many ways to the previous model but you notice now there
previous model but you notice now there is another plate around the boundary use
is another plate around the boundary use and this hyper parameters alpha they're
and this hyper parameters alpha they're inside this plate which means there must
inside this plate which means there must be some you that looks like that all
be some you that looks like that all right so this repetition so we have M
right so this repetition so we have M doubly use all right so when you look at
doubly use all right so when you look at this picture
this picture obviously it implies for each of this W
obviously it implies for each of this W eyes I am putting its own prior and
eyes I am putting its own prior and effectively they have the same type of
effectively they have the same type of distributions it's a gaussians but the
distributions it's a gaussians but the variance is different and the idea of
variance is different and the idea of these relevant wrestler machines that is
these relevant wrestler machines that is not coming this picture is that somehow
not coming this picture is that somehow when some of the supplies go to
when some of the supplies go to Trinity this distribution picks on zero
Trinity this distribution picks on zero and basically this W to become
and basically this W to become irrelevant in the whole picture so this
irrelevant in the whole picture so this is what this called relevance vector
is what this called relevance vector must change to tells you from all the
must change to tells you from all the input variables which ones are needed to
input variables which ones are needed to do predictions so similar to what we had
do predictions so similar to what we had before
before all right again this is the noise
all right again this is the noise variance in the model this is your Sigma
variance in the model this is your Sigma squared
squared but now the W is another plate that
but now the W is another plate that comes outside to introduce this sparsity
comes outside to introduce this sparsity inducing prior model of W so this mobile
inducing prior model of W so this mobile is sort of very simple but very powerful
is sort of very simple but very powerful and allows you to program it actually
and allows you to program it actually literally in the five lines so it's a a
literally in the five lines so it's a a very favorite model if you want to test
very favorite model if you want to test sparsity and do regression this is the
sparsity and do regression this is the type of things you want to do
on the mean well so basically we just the you know we say let's take this
the you know we say let's take this cigars and write this Gaussian it's
cigars and write this Gaussian it's going to be centered around zero zero
going to be centered around zero zero means the battery is not important okay
means the battery is not important okay and and with some with some confidence
and and with some with some confidence basically defined by this precision of
basically defined by this precision of high okay so nothing you know okay
and again this plate notation does not show the type of distributions are so
show the type of distributions are so you know if you want from Gaussian to go
you know if you want from Gaussian to go to other no student T distribution
to other no student T distribution something like that at this point you
something like that at this point you can do that as well so this is still a
can do that as well so this is still a bit more generic okay so that's the
bit more generic okay so that's the plate rotate we are going to discuss
plate rotate we are going to discuss we're going to spend maybe a whole week
we're going to spend maybe a whole week on hidden Markov models and state-space
on hidden Markov models and state-space models so you're going to see these
models so you're going to see these things multiple times okay and let me
things multiple times okay and let me I'm gonna play pass this unsupervised
I'm gonna play pass this unsupervised learning problem under the name of
learning problem under the name of Pittsburgh component analysis maybe we
Pittsburgh component analysis maybe we will cover this in a lecture of later on
will cover this in a lecture of later on using you know block of representation
using you know block of representation but then we concentrate on a very hidden
but then we concentrate on a very hidden Markov model called basically all the
Markov model called basically all the variables are discrete or in state-space
variables are discrete or in state-space models which basically they're similar
models which basically they're similar to hidden Markov models but this axis
to hidden Markov models but this axis are continuous variables and the
are continuous variables and the observations Y are also continuous
observations Y are also continuous variables and what I have done here just
variables and what I have done here just so I can sort of make things to look a
so I can sort of make things to look a little complicated are not simply
little complicated are not simply extending this hidden Markov model to a
extending this hidden Markov model to a state space model but I'm explaining it
state space model but I'm explaining it to what is called as reaching safe space
to what is called as reaching safe space water
water and again I'm talking where I said you
and again I'm talking where I said you know of the course but you know I want
know of the course but you know I want you to see this thing and Beyond so
you to see this thing and Beyond so actively this axis is the human state
actively this axis is the human state similar to what you have there why are
similar to what you have there why are the observations and that's the sort of
the observations and that's the sort of a descriptive variable that tells you if
a descriptive variable that tells you if you think of this representing let's say
you think of this representing let's say you know some mixture of models and the
you know some mixture of models and the state let's say s 1 can be 1 2 or 3 in
state let's say s 1 can be 1 2 or 3 in so you can be into the different
so you can be into the different components on the mixture
components on the mixture so this discrete variable S 1 defines
so this discrete variable S 1 defines basically import the evolution of the
basically import the evolution of the dynamical system how you go from x1 to
dynamical system how you go from x1 to x2 but also defines the observation how
x2 but also defines the observation how you get y1 from X to R ok and here this
you get y1 from X to R ok and here this discrete particle s also evolves the
discrete particle s also evolves the same way as we do in a hidden Markov
same way as we do in a hidden Markov model and the human-machine the tempest
model and the human-machine the tempest law sort of forcing the first arrow so
law sort of forcing the first arrow so for example if this is in the robotics
for example if this is in the robotics you know maybe would be some power input
you know maybe would be some power input or some force input torque or something
or some force input torque or something like that that you put in the model so
like that that you put in the model so this is the generic thing and this is
this is the generic thing and this is one of the extensions there are infinite
one of the extensions there are infinite books for extensions like that and the
books for extensions like that and the good news are for the bad news for those
good news are for the bad news for those doing a PhD is that all of the smallest
doing a PhD is that all of the smallest basically have been addressed 20 years
basically have been addressed 20 years ago ok so they may look complicated but
ago ok so they may look complicated but they are all done deals and actually
they are all done deals and actually they have revolutionized areas from
they have revolutionized areas from robotics to animation to just mention it
robotics to animation to just mention it navigation satellite tracking and all of
navigation satellite tracking and all of these things
these things right from but I'm giving you this is an
right from but I'm giving you this is an example again now what you see here
example again now what you see here we're going to spend more than a week or
we're going to spend more than a week or two later on in the course so what I
two later on in the course so what I wanted to do is say I just wanted to
wanted to do is say I just wanted to show you how meters come in this models
show you how meters come in this models again as a background so what i'm doing
again as a background so what i'm doing here is i'm writing the joint
here is i'm writing the joint probability of x and y in the state
probability of x and y in the state space model explicitly so this is node X
space model explicitly so this is node X 1 so you started with P of X 1 and then
1 so you started with P of X 1 and then P of y 1 given X 1 then P of X 2 given
P of y 1 given X 1 then P of X 2 given x1 and then give right to given X 2 etc
x1 and then give right to given X 2 etc etc all right so these are the hidden
etc all right so these are the hidden States you want to compute these are the
States you want to compute these are the observations you can think of them as
observations you can think of them as noisy or you know there are basically
noisy or you know there are basically noisy values of x if you like in some
noisy values of x if you like in some sense if the dynamics and the
sense if the dynamics and the observation models are now seeing this
observation models are now seeing this problem has a very nice analytical
problem has a very nice analytical solution that's what the Kalman filter
solution that's what the Kalman filter is all right but you can it can be a
is all right but you can it can be a mixture of gaussians can be anything and
mixture of gaussians can be anything and actually we know how to deal with all of
actually we know how to deal with all of these problems and we will problem these
these problems and we will problem these things later on but this is what I
things later on but this is what I wanted to show you there's more those so
wanted to show you there's more those so when you say dynamics you go from X hat
when you say dynamics you go from X hat minus 1 to X I obviously give that I
minus 1 to X I obviously give that I have to define this distribution and
have to define this distribution and usually the way you will define it it's
usually the way you will define it it's a Gaussian you can have some unknown
a Gaussian you can have some unknown parameters like mean and variance to
parameters like mean and variance to things like that and similarly for the
things like that and similarly for the observation model you're going to have
observation model you're going to have some unknown parameters okay and you
some unknown parameters okay and you know this fear the way that I define the
know this fear the way that I define the state space model is that this parameter
state space model is that this parameter state time this parameters sigh they are
state time this parameters sigh they are stared from other conditional
stared from other conditional distributions across the time so
distributions across the time so basically the parameters that define
basically the parameters that define that say the dynamical model or I go
that say the dynamical model or I go from X 1 to X 2 and X 3 to X 2 X 3
from X 1 to X 2 and X 3 to X 2 X 3 etcetera the parameters PI are the same
etcetera the parameters PI are the same okay so this is sort of where the school
okay so this is sort of where the school vomited rain you know so you use the
vomited rain you know so you use the same parameters to describe the dynamics
same parameters to describe the dynamics and the same parameters to define the
and the same parameters to define the observations obviously not very
observations obviously not very realistic right you can think you know
realistic right you can think you know it's not alive but gross normal emotions
it's not alive but gross normal emotions but something is not accelerating or
but something is not accelerating or something happens it's not spoiling so
something happens it's not spoiling so you don't expect the same dynamics at
you don't expect the same dynamics at all the time so this profit is obviously
all the time so this profit is obviously have to change with time but if you
have to change with time but if you really want a trivial case this is how
really want a trivial case this is how the graphical model would look like ok
the graphical model would look like ok and when I wanted to point on this
and when I wanted to point on this diagram and this is going to attempt to
diagram and this is going to attempt to be a problem later on in the course is
be a problem later on in the course is when you look at this directed graphical
when you look at this directed graphical model it just loops so on one hand you
model it just loops so on one hand you use the same parameters so obviously you
use the same parameters so obviously you save with lots of computation seems like
save with lots of computation seems like you know we will see this one we discuss
you know we will see this one we discuss inference but on the other hand you can
inference but on the other hand you can see there are loops and loops are not
see there are loops and loops are not good for you ok loops are not good for
good for you ok loops are not good for you I mean at least the loops if you
you I mean at least the loops if you remove the arrows right you can see
remove the arrows right you can see there are loops ok and this will create
there are loops ok and this will create it will make inference to leave it more
it will make inference to leave it more expensive than that one ok on the
expensive than that one ok on the state-space models you can have multiple
state-space models you can have multiple chains and you can see an example here
chains and you can see an example here of a factorial state space model so if
of a factorial state space model so if you think that each of these hidden
you think that each of these hidden states on the first chain can take em
states on the first chain can take em values and this can take em values of
values and this can take em values of this prime so you basically have n cube
this prime so you basically have n cube configurations at its time and it comes
configurations at its time and it comes out this is the only message I wanted to
out this is the only message I wanted to show you here is that if you have a
show you here is that if you have a model that looks complicated like that
model that looks complicated like that it actually must cheaper to do inference
it actually must cheaper to do inference than having one chain that has m2 the
than having one chain that has m2 the cube configurations
cube configurations all right so here I have my views have
all right so here I have my views have widest possible land values so I have F
widest possible land values so I have F to the Q possible States if I talk to
to the Q possible States if I talk to this with one chain only can take em to
this with one chain only can take em to the Q values right
the Q values right that's way much more complicated problem
that's way much more complicated problem because he's empty the cube like thing
because he's empty the cube like thing and so we will discuss about this
and so we will discuss about this factorial state space model so maybe
factorial state space model so maybe we'll give you a call mode to work on
we'll give you a call mode to work on later on in the course again we will do
later on in the course again we will do all the details and inference of them on
all the details and inference of them on this type of things maybe in three
this type of things maybe in three lectures or four lectures we'll come
lectures or four lectures we'll come back to his problem alright so I'm going
back to his problem alright so I'm going to take the lecture from last week with
to take the lecture from last week with one very specific example of inference
one very specific example of inference when everything in the graph is
when everything in the graph is described so what is not described I
described so what is not described I have the conditional probability
have the conditional probability distributions but the actual values of
distributions but the actual values of the you know we provide basically
the you know we provide basically information data for the actual
information data for the actual realizations of random variables in the
realizations of random variables in the nodes of the graph okay and I'm going to
nodes of the graph okay and I'm going to address this problem
address this problem not in this slide but the next slide I'm
not in this slide but the next slide I'm going to do an example where all the
going to do an example where all the variables are discrete and I will give
variables are discrete and I will give you very specific sort of calculation in
you very specific sort of calculation in in two slides on how things look like so
in two slides on how things look like so we have a graph where I have given you
we have a graph where I have given you any realization of the nodes of the
any realization of the nodes of the values of the random variables of the
values of the random variables of the nodes so it's realization is over to you
nodes so it's realization is over to you or it's no and I give you everybody know
or it's no and I give you everybody know so there is no missing data here all
so there is no missing data here all right I describe completely you know for
right I describe completely you know for its higher give you all the baggage of
its higher give you all the baggage of excise so the logical of the model so
excise so the logical of the model so the means data here we're going to use
the means data here we're going to use this as a notation in the core
this as a notation in the core people would be the unknown parameters
people would be the unknown parameters that became the conditional
that became the conditional distributions in the graph which we
distributions in the graph which we don't know what they are so the
don't know what they are so the likelihood is assuming iid data right is
likelihood is assuming iid data right is the probability of X i given theta x i
the probability of X i given theta x i again is the app data cased and evolves
again is the app data cased and evolves all the notes in the graph and then what
all the notes in the graph and then what I do is I use the factorization of the
I do is I use the factorization of the graph to write the probability of X i
graph to write the probability of X i given theta as the power over all nodes
given theta as the power over all nodes of the probability of for the I case of
of the probability of for the I case of no T given its parents and the
no T given its parents and the parameters theta
parameters theta nothing can see right in directive jobs
nothing can see right in directive jobs right so again the I means that's the
right so again the I means that's the beta case I so you can remove I when you
beta case I so you can remove I when you think of the second term the way we
think of the second term the way we factorized is the property is the
factorized is the property is the product of the probabilities of the
product of the probabilities of the facts that is not given the its parents
facts that is not given the its parents and you have comma the parameters
and you have comma the parameters because we don't know where the
because we don't know where the kilometers are so what I'm gonna do now
kilometers are so what I'm gonna do now is I am going to reverse to reverse the
is I am going to reverse to reverse the product over the node and the product
product over the node and the product over the dataset so I'm going to put the
over the dataset so I'm going to put the product over the data sets inside and
product over the data sets inside and some we have this point of outside and
some we have this point of outside and then the product over the data set even
then the product over the data set even be operating on the probability of XIT
be operating on the probability of XIT given the parents for the IPS of T and
given the parents for the IPS of T and the parameters theta and I call this the
the parameters theta and I call this the best associated with the family of node
best associated with the family of node P isn't in fact the likelihood of the
P isn't in fact the likelihood of the family
family the likelihood of the data over the
the likelihood of the data over the family of no T so if you move this
family of no T so if you move this outside right then you put it here
outside right then you put it here product over all the nodes and it here
product over all the nodes and it here this refers to T an exponent so isn't it
this refers to T an exponent so isn't it really the likelihood of the comedy of
really the likelihood of the comedy of know T it only involves the data that
know T it only involves the data that have to do with thinnest forest
who can sit up right so basically when you look at this equation like what does
you look at this equation like what does it do what can we say for the level of
it do what can we say for the level of likelihood in this formula that is over
over the notes so even though you have a very complicated diagram right the
very complicated diagram right the likelihood okay of the data it arises
likelihood okay of the data it arises over the likelihood you know when I
over the likelihood you know when I stayed with the knowledge were in it's
stayed with the knowledge were in it's not include the community of that node
not include the community of that node because V is the likelihood of the
because V is the likelihood of the family of that know and why is this
family of that know and why is this important because it tells you that this
important because it tells you that this problem is theta P for each node P can
problem is theta P for each node P can be computed separately for the parameter
be computed separately for the parameter which a pickle people Swan or fitness P
which a pickle people Swan or fitness P plus 2 so you can actually compute the
plus 2 so you can actually compute the parameters locally for its note because
parameters locally for its note because they decouple the way this to be the
they decouple the way this to be the case when you have incomplete data but
case when you have incomplete data but now I do notice if from this equation if
now I do notice if from this equation if you have complete data you get a product
you have complete data you get a product of terms solids
of terms solids no okay so the recipe would decompose
no okay so the recipe would decompose the quality the graphs left okay and if
the quality the graphs left okay and if you want you know to go blind likelihood
you want you know to go blind likelihood then you want to introduce a prior for
then you want to introduce a prior for the parameters you can make a simple
the parameters you can make a simple assumption that the prior of the
assumption that the prior of the parameter sort support arrives over the
parameter sort support arrives over the nodes so basically this makes sense
nodes so basically this makes sense right because you the distribution for
right because you the distribution for the Rises and you have every conditional
the Rises and you have every conditional distribution of leading with a node
distribution of leading with a node having this theta T so you can put a
having this theta T so you can put a prior but loops like that and then the
prior but loops like that and then the posterior
posterior Fox arises over notes as well right so
Fox arises over notes as well right so if you can do Bayesian inference to
if you can do Bayesian inference to compute theta T RT to note separately
compute theta T RT to note separately I'm going to give you a very specific
I'm going to give you a very specific example soon okay but this to sort of
example soon okay but this to sort of equations are extremely important here
make any bit of tact this is only when you have complete data describe if there
you have complete data describe if there are missing data this is not the case
are missing data this is not the case all right so you know they said it's a
all right so you know they said it's a different story that we will see later
different story that we will see later on but this is sort of a very trivial
on but this is sort of a very trivial case if you have complete data you can
case if you have complete data you can infer what the parameters are
infer what the parameters are by using this decomposition of the
by using this decomposition of the posterior detective the over the graph
on the next slide you will see numbers so if you don't understand this example
so if you don't understand this example you will understand hopefully the slides
you will understand hopefully the slides of counseling because it has specific
of counseling because it has specific numbers so let me add some when I
numbers so let me add some when I consider the case where the conditional
consider the case where the conditional probabilities are given in terms of
probabilities are given in terms of tables all right so we're talking about
tables all right so we're talking about discrete variables practically valuable
discrete variables practically valuable to follow a multi newly distribution so
to follow a multi newly distribution so let me see what that word eternal final
let me see what that word eternal final distribution Here I am looking at no T
distribution Here I am looking at no T and I say the probability of the given
and I say the probability of the given exponent is a categorical of
exponent is a categorical of multi-annual distribution with
multi-annual distribution with parameters theta T C so the subscripts
parameters theta T C so the subscripts Elstree have a minute here please we
Elstree have a minute here please we know that the looking Syst the value the
know that the looking Syst the value the parents are
so basically you can thank each other responding to the values of their
responding to the values of their parents okay and then what you do is you
parents okay and then what you do is you fit a categorical distribution okay so
fit a categorical distribution okay so the probability of T given its balance
the probability of T given its balance being a state C is a categorical
being a state C is a categorical distribution and obviously in this
distribution and obviously in this categorical distribution you remember
categorical distribution you remember they're going to have an opportunity of
they're going to have an opportunity of State and if you sum over all the stage
State and if you sum over all the stage this Thetas there for some to R T
this Thetas there for some to R T participate as you basically the
participate as you basically the probability of being theta T C 1 is the
probability of being theta T C 1 is the probability of being in state 1
probability of being in state 1 disappears the probability of being in
disappears the probability of being in state T so if you sum all of this you
state T so if you sum all of this you get 1 but remember it appreciates the
get 1 but remember it appreciates the probability of being state K at node 3
probability of being state K at node 3 given that the parents are in state C
given that the parents are in state C right so basically you cannot say I mean
right so basically you cannot say I mean you can't do the modular calculation if
you can't do the modular calculation if you want to but here too
you want to but here too we're going to the table tell us the
we're going to the table tell us the probability of 3 given the state of the
probability of 3 given the state of the parents all right and we pick this with
parents all right and we pick this with a categorical distribution of this
a categorical distribution of this parameters with this normalization so
parameters with this normalization so let's write this explicitly theta D CK
let's write this explicitly theta D CK is the probability P means again 90 okay
is the probability P means again 90 okay we're working at 90
we're working at 90 so it's no it has its own conditional
so it's no it has its own conditional probability so p ck is the probability
probability so p ck is the probability that X days it takes the value K when
that X days it takes the value K when the plants can take the monastry the
the plants can take the monastry the sequence of the industries here it's
sequence of the industries here it's arbitrary right you could have reverse
arbitrary right you could have reverse it so this is the notation used here
it so this is the notation used here there is the node K is the value that
there is the node K is the value that the XT will take given that the parents
the XT will take given that the parents are in state 3
are in state 3 we're going to assume that they're Katy
we're going to assume that they're Katy States for
States for no T we're going to ask you that the
no T we're going to ask you that the parents can be at categories of holder
parents can be at categories of holder City Sacramento City and City is what is
City Sacramento City and City is what is the penny how many parents you have is
the penny how many parents you have is the product basically of the states of
the product basically of the states of the poverty so tonight has two parents
the poverty so tonight has two parents at this point just to polish this just
at this point just to polish this just three will be 2 times 3
okay again I will show you this in a specific example but basically this is
specific example but basically this is the the house is discrete distributions
the the house is discrete distributions this conditional probabilities are
this conditional probabilities are defined using a multi newly or
defined using a multi newly or categorical distribution so what we're
categorical distribution so what we're gonna do is and now you know I expect
gonna do is and now you know I expect that at least you have some elementary
that at least you have some elementary understanding of a d-flat distribution
understanding of a d-flat distribution if you not send me an e-mail you'll know
if you not send me an e-mail you'll know who sent you a few pages from maybe
who sent you a few pages from maybe Bishop's book or make this book to read
Bishop's book or make this book to read whether it's really the distribution is
whether it's really the distribution is the the conjugate prior to this multi
the the conjugate prior to this multi annually distribution so each of this
annually distribution so each of this parameters they collect the vector that
parameters they collect the vector that involves all these people district a
involves all these people district a we're going to put a very clear prior
we're going to put a very clear prior alright and then because they are
alright and then because they are conjugate the posterior given the data D
conjugate the posterior given the data D is going to come up to be a vehicular
is going to come up to be a vehicular distribution with parameters cannot
distribution with parameters cannot deceive defined from the prior plus MT
deceive defined from the prior plus MT see where this is a vector right mister
see where this is a vector right mister vector and this is a vector and here's
vector and this is a vector and here's the definition of the vector so I want
the definition of the vector so I want you to look at it and tell me what this
you to look at it and tell me what this is using common sense language basically
is using common sense language basically P is the 90 K is the probability that
P is the 90 K is the probability that declares the body a value of note II can
declares the body a value of note II can take assuming that the parents are in in
take assuming that the parents are in in state C so what is n p ck
state C so what is n p ck in my data set because carol have
in my data set because carol have banished I multiply the likelihood with
banished I multiply the likelihood with this prior so what do you think PC case
this prior so what do you think PC case and you can look at the patient here is
and you can look at the patient here is the number of times in my data set the
the number of times in my data set the negative is in what state instead of
negative is in what state instead of Terry given that the parents are in
Terry given that the parents are in state C okay so that's the empirical
state C okay so that's the empirical count I mean this is sort of if you
count I mean this is sort of if you watch this is brother actually there's
watch this is brother actually there's no algebraic just like you know you know
no algebraic just like you know you know so this is sort of the sufficient
so this is sort of the sufficient statistics for this problem so it's a
statistics for this problem so it's a nation of the data scientists indicator
nation of the data scientists indicator function and counts the time senior data
function and counts the time senior data set that no T is in state k given that
set that no T is in state k given that it's parents are in state C so the the
it's parents are in state C so the the mean of the distribution the daily
mean of the distribution the daily distribution basically there has if you
distribution basically there has if you check on Wikipedia will see what the
check on Wikipedia will see what the meanest is for example for this
meanest is for example for this distribution is 50 G K divided by the
distribution is 50 G K divided by the summation of alpha T C K prime for all
summation of alpha T C K prime for all tape lines so the mean of the
tape lines so the mean of the distribution of the posterior comes to
distribution of the posterior comes to be this critical count plus alpha D CK
be this critical count plus alpha D CK from the prior and then in the numerator
from the prior and then in the numerator denominator you have this actually
denominator you have this actually should be inside parentheses you know
should be inside parentheses you know even though it's obvious here so this
even though it's obvious here so this whole automation here count over K prime
whole automation here count over K prime so if let's say you use an unintended
so if let's say you use an unintended clip I or where all the surface are
clip I or where all the surface are equal to one so actively this is sort of
equal to one so actively this is sort of regularization so you just add one in
regularization so you just add one in all the empirical counts so if let's say
all the empirical counts so if let's say foreign state
foreign state you have no measurements universe say
you have no measurements universe say that they would never happen
that they would never happen Swan you make it possible and that's
Swan you make it possible and that's what this thing does it sort of the
what this thing does it sort of the histogram is this problem for this type
histogram is this problem for this type of prevents well let's see an example so
of prevents well let's see an example so this is so we have a direct block with
this is so we have a direct block with five nodes and let's say we get some
five nodes and let's say we get some data
all right and the database will contain the realizations of X 1 X 2 X 3 X 4 X 5
the realizations of X 1 X 2 X 3 X 4 X 5 and we have I am going to I think
and we have I am going to I think obviously the binary body motion in this
obviously the binary body motion in this problem of forgot to mention obviously
problem of forgot to mention obviously so the process is 0 0 1 0 0 1 1 1 and
so the process is 0 0 1 0 0 1 1 1 and Here I am
Here I am counts in my data set where no this is
counts in my data set where no this is what this here is from stage 1 or stage
what this here is from stage 1 or stage 0 given that the parts are in state C
0 given that the parts are in state C which is defined on the rolls on the
which is defined on the rolls on the left hand side you see that ok so let's
left hand side you see that ok so let's look at the case when the parents are at
look at the case when the parents are at 1 1 how many times look at the data set
1 1 how many times look at the data set when X 2 next year of at 1 how many
when X 2 next year of at 1 how many times K the know T the first node is at
times K the know T the first node is at 1 so I see one case here and I see two
1 so I see one case here and I see two we do
similarly let's see how many times the note
note is a k equal to 0 when this is 1 and 1
is a k equal to 0 when this is 1 and 1 the 2 1 1 0 1 okay
the 2 1 1 0 1 okay 21 and so we can either they say the
21 and so we can either they say the probability if you don't do this a
probability if you don't do this a priori and you use the MLE estimate the
priori and you use the MLE estimate the probability let's say or v pc k equal to
probability let's say or v pc k equal to 1 I mean I should actually I hope I
1 I mean I should actually I hope I don't confuse you care what I mean 350
don't confuse you care what I mean 350 see k equal to 1 I mean pick up this G 1
see k equal to 1 I mean pick up this G 1 that's what I mean okay so the
that's what I mean okay so the probability of P that is T 1 the mean
probability of P that is T 1 the mean value if you don't do if you don't put
value if you don't do if you don't put any prior will be let's say 2 divided by
any prior will be let's say 2 divided by 3 but remember we have to add on the
3 but remember we have to add on the previous diagram if we use the clave
previous diagram if we use the clave distributions prior with coefficient 1
distributions prior with coefficient 1 we have to add 1 to the counts so it
we have to add 1 to the counts so it will be 3 divided by 5 and here will be
will be 3 divided by 5 and here will be 1 plus 1 2 divided by 5
1 plus 1 2 divided by 5 alright
obviously the variables are discrete you know so such a complicated but in
know so such a complicated but in essence you know even if the
essence you know even if the distributions were Gaussian or there are
distributions were Gaussian or there are something else you can do stimuli to
something else you can do stimuli to ideas you know and and do full Bayesian
ideas you know and and do full Bayesian analysis to compute the the parameters
analysis to compute the the parameters in the conditional distribution now in
in the conditional distribution now in currency girls right you don't know
currency girls right you don't know usually other nodes you know you have
usually other nodes you know you have personal data so you know some things
personal data so you know some things you don't know all the things so this
you don't know all the things so this could be the real problem we have to
could be the real problem we have to deal in this class but if your complete
deal in this class but if your complete data it's an easy problem and actually
data it's an easy problem and actually you know if products for example who use
you know if products for example who use simulation to generate a lots of data
simulation to generate a lots of data and then they fit these two models you
and then they fit these two models you know you may have the case indeed what
know you may have the case indeed what you described in the graph
you described in the graph you know everything or item karakuri
you know everything or item karakuri resistance so you can use this type of
resistance so you can use this type of organization so let me drink some coffee
organization so let me drink some coffee and then we change subject
today I fitted up the Starbucks because they told me that coffee went up to
they told me that coffee went up to three or five and I said since when
three or five and I said since when because I was there yesterday then they
because I was there yesterday then they said to me are you kiddin and I said of
said to me are you kiddin and I said of course then to 95
so you know maybe tomorrow you guys give me go around your student card so I can
me go around your student card so I can hit it you know and get my discount what
hit it you know and get my discount what is that it's like discrimination is it
I'm going to see me again they asked you on the scooter basically three things we
on the scooter basically three things we already have seen and then try to
already have seen and then try to introduce some concepts but we make the
introduce some concepts but we make the elimination over basically easily to
elimination over basically easily to program I'm gonna do something sort of a
program I'm gonna do something sort of a little bit stupid but you know we're all
little bit stupid but you know we're all mature so you know I'm gonna bring maybe
mature so you know I'm gonna bring maybe if not today
if not today on on Thursday one shouldn't directed by
on on Thursday one shouldn't directed by really discussing some details because I
really discussing some details because I don't want to split this lecture on
don't want to split this lecture on directed graphs and then three weeks
directed graphs and then three weeks later tell you the same things from
later tell you the same things from directed ok so I'm gonna sit in some
directed ok so I'm gonna sit in some information that you need to know about
information that you need to know about undirected graphs and discuss this
undirected graphs and discuss this elimination algorithm you can he'll
elimination algorithm you can he'll think of some notes that would describe
think of some notes that would describe them so this is bolded Aryan these are
them so this is bolded Aryan these are the evidence no notes these are the
the evidence no notes these are the query nodes right this is what you want
query nodes right this is what you want to compute and there are some hidden
to compute and there are some hidden notes and you know if you want to
notes and you know if you want to complete them you can complete them but
complete them you can complete them but here what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna
here what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna quite hidden noise because you don't
quite hidden noise because you don't care about all right so actively this is
care about all right so actively this is your Q K X 1 given X ticks and you can
your Q K X 1 given X ticks and you can all of this knows that you don't know so
all of this knows that you don't know so what you need to do is integrate them
what you need to do is integrate them out and I think we already have
out and I think we already have discussed that the big picture basically
discussed that the big picture basically looks like the equation you see on the
looks like the equation you see on the on the bottle alright so we want to
on the bottle alright so we want to compute the probability of X hath given
compute the probability of X hath given the X the evidence and I write this as
the X the evidence and I write this as the joint probability of X F and X T and
the joint probability of X F and X T and that probability can be written as all
that probability can be written as all the probability of all the joint all the
the probability of all the joint all the body moves with the hidden variables
body moves with the hidden variables integrated valve and then here you have
integrated valve and then here you have the probability of ecstasy which means
the probability of ecstasy which means it will have to the joint with excel
it will have to the joint with excel four exits integrated out remember that
four exits integrated out remember that nothing fancy really may be the rotation
nothing fancy really may be the rotation is slightly different right so that we
is slightly different right so that we need to know this is what the
need to know this is what the elimination algorithm is how can we use
elimination algorithm is how can we use of the product theoretic ideas to do
of the product theoretic ideas to do this effectively and and I think in some
this effectively and and I think in some of the examples we have highlighted this
of the examples we have highlighted this but hopefully today if we managed to
but hopefully today if we managed to finish this we will see some ideas have
finish this we will see some ideas have some graphs don't need absolutist so me
some graphs don't need absolutist so me tell you what the idea is here is we're
tell you what the idea is here is we're going to use the distribution law when
going to use the distribution law when we do these summations and so you know I
we do these summations and so you know I give you here an example you have the
give you here an example you have the summation of some constant times X I
summation of some constant times X I obviously you can move that constant R
obviously you can move that constant R far out and say alpha times Sigma X I so
far out and say alpha times Sigma X I so that's one of the compilations were
that's one of the compilations were going to use and in a more general sense
going to use and in a more general sense if we have summation on you know think
if we have summation on you know think of these discrete variables on the x1 xn
of these discrete variables on the x1 xn and inside we have alpha 1 X 1 over 2 X
and inside we have alpha 1 X 1 over 2 X 2 etcetera
2 etcetera look what I have done I took this
look what I have done I took this product and I split them in pieces and
product and I split them in pieces and then I pushed on with the summations so
then I pushed on with the summations so each of them operates only on the right
each of them operates only on the right argument so if I want to start on extend
argument so if I want to start on extend which
which the point of having the whole number can
the point of having the whole number can save groans time on extender for product
save groans time on extender for product where an X n it only appears from the
where an X n it only appears from the federal time xn all right so I have what
federal time xn all right so I have what you do this if you push xn all the way
you do this if you push xn all the way in so you could use this then you
in so you could use this then you compute the summation xn minus 1 and
compute the summation xn minus 1 and then eventually you compute the
then eventually you compute the sturbation on xn so the idea is what you
sturbation on xn so the idea is what you see here for performing this summation
see here for performing this summation that effectively will allow us to
that effectively will allow us to effectively do this marginalization all
effectively do this marginalization all right this is what the objective is we
right this is what the objective is we you know say this are two of their
you know say this are two of their cumulative rings but basically together
cumulative rings but basically together with the operations plus and
with the operations plus and multiplication so this is the
multiplication so this is the associative commutative law effectively
associative commutative law effectively generalizing for this elements a b c and
generalizing for this elements a b c and this commutative ring this property that
this commutative ring this property that you see here this is sort of what we
you see here this is sort of what we take advantage okay so for any ABN stick
take advantage okay so for any ABN stick where we can do this
where we can do this so the this one have to be discreet
so the this one have to be discreet mahalo which can be continuous can be
mahalo which can be continuous can be you know other weird things okay this
you know other weird things okay this property if it is valid then we can
property if it is valid then we can apply this this idea for computing
apply this this idea for computing modulation processors okay
now obviously we want to find an effective way for doing the summations
effective way for doing the summations because let me see if there is account
because let me see if there is account here if you let's say that if you want
here if you let's say that if you want to some so in this case the same we want
to some so in this case the same we want to somehow this hidden variable solve
to somehow this hidden variable solve okay so let's call them the total number
okay so let's call them the total number of hidden variables is is Billis all
of hidden variables is is Billis all right so obviously the summation of the
right so obviously the summation of the hidden variables will result in the
hidden variables will result in the computation which will be after this
computation which will be after this power for either the number of possible
power for either the number of possible values that this monomers can take or
values that this monomers can take or actually ever have to some dissipation
actually ever have to some dissipation values there are personal values of this
values there are personal values of this and for each of this they have monster
and for each of this they have monster one serve out and they are possible of a
one serve out and they are possible of a list of that so we are to the power
list of that so we are to the power rates and I'm not the kind of thing that
rates and I'm not the kind of thing that you will need to do this marginalization
you will need to do this marginalization for each module itself the of the
for each module itself the of the grantee body works okay but this is for
grantee body works okay but this is for the big graph this is a big number and
the big graph this is a big number and we don't like it it will not be
we don't like it it will not be efficient to do marginalization right so
efficient to do marginalization right so let's discuss this in star algorithm
so we have a better to go and let's say if we want to we want to do much an
if we want to we want to do much an unsession or no deck 6
unsession or no deck 6 ok so what we want to do so if you can
ok so what we want to do so if you can do this in an aviary right so this
do this in an aviary right so this summation would be six operations well
summation would be six operations well I'm sorry
I'm sorry six operations if this takes on the
six operations if this takes on the values the summation onyx 6 will be our
values the summation onyx 6 will be our operations for each of the other values
operations for each of the other values of this and this and this and this will
of this and this and this and this will be a total basically for to the six
be a total basically for to the six operation ok so let's see a way that
operation ok so let's see a way that this way white zipper in performing this
this way white zipper in performing this what we don't do up to the six
what we don't do up to the six operations so what I have done here is I
operations so what I have done here is I wrote the factorization of the golf
wrote the factorization of the golf right the effects 1 x2 given x1 x3 given
right the effects 1 x2 given x1 x3 given X 2 X 5 given the power that 3x tix
X 2 X 5 given the power that 3x tix given its parents etc and then when I
given its parents etc and then when I have done is like this the summation on
have done is like this the summation on X takes all the way to the right because
X takes all the way to the right because that's the only place 4 X 6 counts and
that's the only place 4 X 6 counts and the summation of this distribution is
the summation of this distribution is actually equal to 1 because it's a body
actually equal to 1 because it's a body conditional distribution that is
conditional distribution that is normalized so how much handsome I have
normalized so how much handsome I have to do 0 nothing so if you actually do
to do 0 nothing so if you actually do this you will find yourselves doing
this you will find yourselves doing after the 6th when this actually
after the 6th when this actually requires ok it is shown right maybe this
requires ok it is shown right maybe this it is it is not one which is something
it is it is not one which is something else here and if he has 3 arguments the
else here and if he has 3 arguments the doing the summation will be out to a
doing the summation will be out to a power which is way better than out to
power which is way better than out to the sixth power
the sixth power ok so this is what we need to take
ok so this is what we need to take advantage
advantage like there's a lot of a sell-off and
like there's a lot of a sell-off and actually remind me I'm going to send you
actually remind me I'm going to send you a copy of absorbance chapter to read
a copy of absorbance chapter to read this book where I extracted this big
this book where I extracted this big sirs okay so if I forget to do that not
sirs okay so if I forget to do that not me because the before I go home today so
me because the before I go home today so so again the same problem we want to
so again the same problem we want to compute no we want to compute a
compute no we want to compute a summation with a spectrum of Pi it's
summation with a spectrum of Pi it's more interesting okay so what I do is I
more interesting okay so what I do is I take the joint but it's factorize like
take the joint but it's factorize like this and then I am pushing the summation
this and then I am pushing the summation or X 5 to the right to include only the
or X 5 to the right to include only the terms that depend on X 5 and you notice
terms that depend on X 5 and you notice I have included X Y given X 3 all right
I have included X Y given X 3 all right but x6 given also it's part of the
but x6 given also it's part of the experience part ok so I have to perform
experience part ok so I have to perform a summation of this term and we're going
a summation of this term and we're going to call this a new potential we're going
to call this a new potential we're going to give it some name and I'm going to
to give it some name and I'm going to call the potential P and I'm going to
call the potential P and I'm going to put a subscript X 5 so X 5 reminds me
put a subscript X 5 so X 5 reminds me with snow that destination the tree
with snow that destination the tree which male is going to be eliminated
which male is going to be eliminated okay expiry is to know that I'm doing
okay expiry is to know that I'm doing the summation and when you sell on X 5
the summation and when you sell on X 5 what your master is the potential is
what your master is the potential is going to be a function of X 2 or X 3 and
going to be a function of X 2 or X 3 and X 6 so if you live there the arguments
X 6 so if you live there the arguments that you haven't thought the rest of you
that you haven't thought the rest of you saw basically whatever your Psalm is
saw basically whatever your Psalm is going to come as a substrate from this
going to come as a substrate from this potential okay so let's I have say so
potential okay so let's I have say so business the original graph and it tells
business the original graph and it tells you all the conditional probabilities
you all the conditional probabilities that define the distributions in this
that define the distributions in this graph you notice this is X 3 given X 1 X
graph you notice this is X 3 given X 1 X 5 and X 3 but here you have to parent so
5 and X 3 but here you have to parent so this is a table exit given X 2 and X 5
this is a table exit given X 2 and X 5 the three dimensional table in here
the three dimensional table in here let's you know figure out where the hell
let's you know figure out where the hell this graph says why he has this color
this graph says why he has this color when writing the biggest summation X 5
when writing the biggest summation X 5 and the little X 5 but notice what
and the little X 5 but notice what happens now x3 and x6 are coming
happens now x3 and x6 are coming together in a culture which means that
together in a culture which means that they're correlated now so I have to do
they're correlated now so I have to do wipe to them I mean I see here X 3 and X
wipe to them I mean I see here X 3 and X 6 X 6 they're coming together
missus eliminated I'm gonna have to connect basically X 3 and X 2 X 6
discussing anything yet in the context of the population here given explain
of the population here given explain this you know when I do a summation this
this you know when I do a summation this table will not exist anymore
table will not exist anymore this is the table effect sticks given X
this is the table effect sticks given X 2 and X 5
2 and X 5 when I integrate X 5 this will be the
when I integrate X 5 this will be the summation of this X 5 component will
summation of this X 5 component will disappear and effectively this
disappear and effectively this three-dimensional tape will become
three-dimensional tape will become actually 2 dimension table okay you will
actually 2 dimension table okay you will be getting this potential here that is
be getting this potential here that is declining in terms of this prefix given
declining in terms of this prefix given extreme all right okay multiplied by P
extreme all right okay multiplied by P of X 6 given what is that X 5 and X 2
of X 6 given what is that X 5 and X 2 summation X 5 and then I get this
so generally the subscript I to put on these potentials is the note that you're
these potentials is the note that you're eliminated or you are signing over and
eliminated or you are signing over and excess hi are the dependent variables of
excess hi are the dependent variables of come together in the new potential okay
come together in the new potential okay the way that you thought was basically a
the way that you thought was basically a comment in our case because X 2 X 3 and
comment in our case because X 2 X 3 and X X's all right so let's have seen on
X X's all right so let's have seen on this area notice elimination of
this area notice elimination of variables
variables elimination are good so this types begin
elimination are good so this types begin out exactly what's going on here so
out exactly what's going on here so let's do the marginalization for what
let's do the marginalization for what interested in theta X 1 X 2 only so we
interested in theta X 1 X 2 only so we need to sum on X 3 X 4 X 5 at 6:00
need to sum on X 3 X 4 X 5 at 6:00 so I'm going to do the summations one
so I'm going to do the summations one term at the time
term at the time starting from the leaves all the way up
starting from the leaves all the way up to X 3 all right
to X 3 all right and then we will see what happens to the
and then we will see what happens to the down so I leave X 2 X 4 2 X 5 here and I
down so I leave X 2 X 4 2 X 5 here and I do a summation on X 6 so when I stand on
do a summation on X 6 so when I stand on its sixth
its sixth alright obviously the Novik sixth will
alright obviously the Novik sixth will disappear now this is equal to 1 right
disappear now this is equal to 1 right but let's forget that it is equal to 1
but let's forget that it is equal to 1 this will give me a potential that I do
this will give me a potential that I do not play would subscribe that 6 because
not play would subscribe that 6 because this is the north of the song and the
this is the north of the song and the available selects will expire so I am
available selects will expire so I am giving you so I am going to eliminate
giving you so I am going to eliminate now that X 6 all right and notice there
now that X 6 all right and notice there is a dotted line there what is the
is a dotted line there what is the dotted line implies here
so here have displayed the new potential leads by reverse two and five and that's
leads by reverse two and five and that's what I do in the belly I basically say
what I do in the belly I basically say 35 are now linked together all right
an additional step at the time so this is a dotted line but you would see now
is a dotted line but you would see now in the next step I am going to make this
in the next step I am going to make this just a back line as well so it doesn't
just a back line as well so it doesn't you know my first oh here it is this
you know my first oh here it is this picture and it's gonna be summation on
picture and it's gonna be summation on on the so become the destination xx6
on the so become the destination xx6 we got the potential that depends on X 2
we got the potential that depends on X 2 X 5 and I am going to try and X Prime
X 5 and I am going to try and X Prime and the summation X 5 is gonna operate
and the summation X 5 is gonna operate on this x naught so on this x naught and
on this x naught so on this x naught and the new potential will have a subscript
the new potential will have a subscript X 5 because that's what I saw and what
X 5 because that's what I saw and what is left X 2 and X 3 and what am i doing
is left X 2 and X 3 and what am i doing that
that I'm connecting X 2 and X 3 all right and
I'm connecting X 2 and X 3 all right and then I would get rid of note 5 leading
then I would get rid of note 5 leading to this ok all right so let's continue
to this ok all right so let's continue eliminate now if I eliminate there is no
eliminate now if I eliminate there is no dependencies that I have to worry
dependencies that I have to worry actually this summation comes here to be
actually this summation comes here to be equal to 1 so this potential is equal to
equal to 1 so this potential is equal to 1 so this is eliminated I get a graph
1 so this is eliminated I get a graph like that and then if I get rid of for
like that and then if I get rid of for node 3 all right so now 3 there were
node 3 all right so now 3 there were sort of offenses that have generated in
sort of offenses that have generated in in between rights or node 3 I have
in between rights or node 3 I have expletive an X 1 but they have a
expletive an X 1 but they have a potential to expand that is a function
potential to expand that is a function of X 2 and X 3
of X 2 and X 3 remember all right the function of X 2
remember all right the function of X 2 and X 3 and and also have this potential
and X 3 and and also have this potential here with the function of X 2 it's equal
here with the function of X 2 it's equal to 1 but here we just keep it for
to 1 but here we just keep it for decoration purposes why are we
decoration purposes why are we and and so we have basically given X Ron
and and so we have basically given X Ron no actually I don't keep it the x 1 x 2
no actually I don't keep it the x 1 x 2 x 5 of X 2 and X 3 by 7 X 3 and then
x 5 of X 2 and X 3 by 7 X 3 and then what this mask is something depends on
what this mask is something depends on your x1 and x2 okay and this is
your x1 and x2 okay and this is basically my marginal distribution that
basically my marginal distribution that I going to compute so the margin
I going to compute so the margin distribution is P of X 1 P of x2 given X
distribution is P of X 1 P of x2 given X 1 and 2 potentials one depends on Xtreme
1 and 2 potentials one depends on Xtreme Ian one depends on X 1 and X 2 and this
Ian one depends on X 1 and X 2 and this again the subscripts telling me the
again the subscripts telling me the notes that the software eliminated as
notes that the software eliminated as they was proceeding okay so this make
they was proceeding okay so this make any sense
any sense all right okay so right but when you
all right okay so right but when you know whether we started this this dance
know whether we started this this dance here obviously the first the highest
here obviously the first the highest cost in the calculation is the one that
cost in the calculation is the one that involves basically the highest number of
involves basically the highest number of variables in in in this summation so for
variables in in in this summation so for example you have two variables so the
example you have two variables so the first of this if each of them can take
first of this if each of them can take our values will be R square right for
our values will be R square right for each 9 FX 3 here 2 is only two variables
each 9 FX 3 here 2 is only two variables and here I have two variables and shall
and here I have two variables and shall have my so this calculation of this
have my so this calculation of this potential will be basically the most
potential will be basically the most expensive in the process and exactly the
expensive in the process and exactly the nature you can actually you know you
nature you can actually you know you will see later on when we talk about
will see later on when we talk about laughs basically without this knowledge
laughs basically without this knowledge determine the maximum click on the
determine the maximum click on the corresponding undirected graph as I do
corresponding undirected graph as I do this elimination process okay so I'm
this elimination process okay so I'm gonna start to get shortly okay but I
gonna start to get shortly okay but I just want you to appreciate that maybe
just want you to appreciate that maybe you hear sound you have three variables
you hear sound you have three variables and you want to sound 1 X 5 for each of
and you want to sound 1 X 5 for each of the values of this Revati much so this
the values of this Revati much so this is for the highest fastest alright so
is for the highest fastest alright so this will define the cost of the output
this will define the cost of the output this is nice
how important is the way you start when you start doing this elimination right
you start doing this elimination right you can stop how many know but if you do
you can stop how many know but if you do only you can take the trivial problem
only you can take the trivial problem and make it very painful so here is a
and make it very painful so here is a problem let's say if you have all of
problem let's say if you have all of these variables and somebody tells you
these variables and somebody tells you you want to compute let's see let's say
you want to compute let's see let's say you want to I don't know what you want
you want to I don't know what you want to compute of the earth right but let's
to compute of the earth right but let's say we want to eliminate X 1 ok first
say we want to eliminate X 1 ok first right maybe you have some evidence and
right maybe you have some evidence and you want to start doing elimination from
you want to start doing elimination from X 1 if you eliminate the trial what
X 1 if you eliminate the trial what happens I mean I think actually the
happens I mean I think actually the joint probability distribution for miles
joint probability distribution for miles on the graph right if you do militates
on the graph right if you do militates one first what's going on
show the dependencies now will be between party all while it was depend on
between party all while it was depend on everything else good luck you took
everything else good luck you took something that sort of was not looking
something that sort of was not looking bad and now we have a graph that it's
bad and now we have a graph that it's pretty connected all right number and
pretty connected all right number and obviously you have to program this ideas
obviously you have to program this ideas right so because you cannot read say
right so because you cannot read say what a nice do not move this and do that
what a nice do not move this and do that because you know it's just visually you
because you know it's just visually you won't be able to see what's going on so
won't be able to see what's going on so certainly this is really not but look
certainly this is really not but look what happens if I go eliminated sorry X
what happens if I go eliminated sorry X 3 X 3 basically introduces no additional
3 X 3 basically introduces no additional dependencies because the X 3 comes only
dependencies because the X 3 comes only in the probability of X 3 given X 1
in the probability of X 3 given X 1 which is equal to 1 so nothing right ok
which is equal to 1 so nothing right ok nice
all right so remember to web to this elimination algorithm to formally stated
elimination algorithm to formally stated so let me this is sort of actually for
so let me this is sort of actually for decoration reasons this evidence
decoration reasons this evidence potentials but because it's in the books
potentials but because it's in the books let's talk about it so you need to say
let's talk about it so you need to say at least mathematically how we write
at least mathematically how we write this summations when some of the nodes
this summations when some of the nodes are logged out some particular values
are logged out some particular values and we denote this as X bar so it's an
and we denote this as X bar so it's an old I as a specific value we you know
old I as a specific value we you know this as X bar I all right so that's
this as X bar I all right so that's evidence we have so that now basically
evidence we have so that now basically is can only take the value by the
is can only take the value by the evidence and cannot change so
so so let's see how are we this evidence is going to come on the in various ways
is going to come on the in various ways on these estimations so let's say with
on these estimations so let's say with what does it say that we want to compute
what does it say that we want to compute P of x1 given the evidence exists okay
P of x1 given the evidence exists okay so you know we observe that ticks and we
so you know we observe that ticks and we won't find what's the condition of x1
won't find what's the condition of x1 given x2 so obviously to do this
given x2 so obviously to do this calculation we have to find the joint of
calculation we have to find the joint of X 1 and X 6 and I write this as a joint
X 1 and X 6 and I write this as a joint event or X 6 you know this is prescribed
event or X 6 you know this is prescribed okay so when I guess the same plate by
okay so when I guess the same plate by pushing the summation of seen words in
pushing the summation of seen words in the in the variables 2 3 4 5 but notice
the in the variables 2 3 4 5 but notice on this conditional of X 6 given X 2 and
on this conditional of X 6 given X 2 and X 5 if you have this probability that
X 5 if you have this probability that corresponds basically to accessorize or
corresponds basically to accessorize or the third dimensional table the precept
the third dimensional table the precept the X 16 take various values that say 0
the X 16 take various values that say 0 and 1 clear right so if I give you the
and 1 clear right so if I give you the next year next 6 the bar is 1 you're
next year next 6 the bar is 1 you're going to take one of this slice of this
going to take one of this slice of this table all right so this is what this
table all right so this is what this will imply so when you say mean X 5
will imply so when you say mean X 5 you're going to define a potential 3 X 5
you're going to define a potential 3 X 5 and the valley was left will be X 2 and
and the valley was left will be X 2 and X 3 all right then you have to sum 1 X 4
X 3 all right then you have to sum 1 X 4 so these are the only variables that
so these are the only variables that involve X fourth I'm sorry queries
involve X fourth I'm sorry queries theater now actually so this potential
theater now actually so this potential is outside the summation right I left it
is outside the summation right I left it to the right because from the particular
to the right because from the particular reason so I saw an X for this equal to 1
reason so I saw an X for this equal to 1 then I have to summon extreme this
then I have to summon extreme this potential depends on X 3 okay so I have
potential depends on X 3 okay so I have the point of the worst two terms so it
the point of the worst two terms so it will be a new potential 3 X 3 of X 1 and
will be a new potential 3 X 3 of X 1 and X 2 and and then I have to sum 1 X 2 and
X 2 and and then I have to sum 1 X 2 and I have the product of two potentials and
I have the product of two potentials and this conditional and I get basically a
this conditional and I get basically a new potential which is V X 2 and the
new potential which is V X 2 and the only variable left is
only variable left is Swan and if you so this is the joint
Swan and if you so this is the joint alright and if you want the conditional
alright and if you want the conditional given the evidence x6 bar is basically
given the evidence x6 bar is basically this is the final result
this is the final result okay so so this is sort of a way one of
okay so so this is sort of a way one of the ways to calculate the evidence by
the ways to calculate the evidence by taking slices of this table okay
taking slices of this table okay you don't need this the only way that
you don't need this the only way that you can account for evidence is using
you can account for evidence is using circle Delta function okay so the adage
circle Delta function okay so the adage sort of power to reveal a good thing you
sort of power to reveal a good thing you ever program it this way but let's say
ever program it this way but let's say rather some node if you give it the
rather some node if you give it the value so what you do is you are trying
value so what you do is you are trying to that node a potential that you can
to that node a potential that you can evidence potential and that potential is
evidence potential and that potential is a function do the observable of a
a function do the observable of a selection of the slice from that
selection of the slice from that conditional distribution without doing
conditional distribution without doing it sort of explicit to show for example
it sort of explicit to show for example if you want to write the probability
if you want to write the probability let's say of let's say we have you know
let's say of let's say we have you know this probability of x given X 2 and X 5
this probability of x given X 2 and X 5 all right so using this evidence
all right so using this evidence potential for now the 6 because the node
potential for now the 6 because the node X 6 is clung to this value you use this
X 6 is clung to this value you use this potential and you say when someone at 6
potential and you say when someone at 6 and obviously this summation 4 X 6 will
and obviously this summation 4 X 6 will give you an exit bar right because
give you an exit bar right because that's the only value of 6 can take
that's the only value of 6 can take usually programming like this but you
usually programming like this but you know sort of want to write it in in
know sort of want to write it in in in in a generic way mathematical you can
in in a generic way mathematical you can say the providers have given have
say the providers have given have married assigning an evidence potential
married assigning an evidence potential in addition to the condition of
in addition to the condition of distributions so when you write the
distributions so when you write the distribution the focus of the graph you
distribution the focus of the graph you also multiplied with the saboteurs
also multiplied with the saboteurs potentials from the rest basically in
potentials from the rest basically in the elimination algorithm is exactly is
the elimination algorithm is exactly is before and they're basically I
before and they're basically I generalized this with disturb this
generalized this with disturb this protection
protection all right so change the algorithm the
all right so change the algorithm the elimination algorithm and directed
elimination algorithm and directed graphs so you have a graph G with
graphs so you have a graph G with evidence T actually exists let me see
so is the evidence yes the evidence nodes an effort of the planning node
nodes an effort of the planning node okay so using Jordans notation here so
okay so using Jordans notation here so so what you need to do is you need to
so what you need to do is you need to initialize the graph okay basically yeah
initialize the graph okay basically yeah the good is to understand the potentials
the good is to understand the potentials that you have if you need to introduce
that you have if you need to introduce the evidence what nodes have prescribed
the evidence what nodes have prescribed values and sort of you know the
values and sort of you know the functions that we discussed it then if
functions that we discussed it then if you need to update the graph given the
you need to update the graph given the evidence so basically I will assume that
evidence so basically I will assume that see the next slide this is where this
see the next slide this is where this elimination algorithm is going to to
elimination algorithm is going to to happen and then effectively you have to
happen and then effectively you have to normalize to this location let's see the
normalize to this location let's see the details of what they saw what it was do
details of what they saw what it was do and then we'll come back to it nothing
and then we'll come back to it nothing on the top so let's have initialization
on the top so let's have initialization if you choose and I think this is very
if you choose and I think this is very important in ordering charts for the
important in ordering charts for the query nodes are appearing the last
okay so you an elimination ordering basically Department we were doing store
basically Department we were doing store let's say probability of X 1 given the
let's say probability of X 1 given the evidence right so you want the 20 notes
evidence right so you want the 20 notes to appear the last basically in the in
to appear the last basically in the in the elimination order and in the
the elimination order and in the initialization for its note
initialization for its note Yuma please place the conditional
Yuma please place the conditional probability in the activation potentials
probability in the activation potentials so you're gonna keep significant list of
so you're gonna keep significant list of the kind all the positions in the
the kind all the positions in the problem and best potentials to start
problem and best potentials to start would be this elimination so this is
would be this elimination so this is what you start with and obviously you
what you start with and obviously you need to have an active list because
need to have an active list because later on in the active list you are
later on in the active list you are going to help them to reduce these
going to help them to reduce these potentials when we do elimination
potentials when we do elimination variables so this active list will keep
variables so this active list will keep track of one of the potentials that
track of one of the potentials that define the factorization of your joint
define the factorization of your joint in the ground okay so we initialize and
in the ground okay so we initialize and you plate this active list where you put
you plate this active list where you put all this conditional distributions you
all this conditional distributions you have to put the elements effectively for
have to put the elements effectively for every node in the evidence you have to
every node in the evidence you have to place this evidence potential all right
place this evidence potential all right okay and you notice it says purchase the
okay and you notice it says purchase the evidence potential on the active list so
evidence potential on the active list so you have got a great sort of these
you have got a great sort of these sample functions this type of the
sample functions this type of the population because when you're in the
population because when you're in the factorization you're also going to
factorization you're also going to multiply and say let's say well fact six
multiply and say let's say well fact six for mac six bar because x6 cannot take
for mac six bar because x6 cannot take any other value by the next six bar okay
any other value by the next six bar okay so this will be part of the alright so
so this will be part of the alright so this is what the evident passed this is
this is what the evident passed this is what the initialization does setting is
what the initialization does setting is potentials from the active list and
potentials from the active list and let's say be a beta so you both need the
let's say be a beta so you both need the knowledge in the elimination order you
knowledge in the elimination order you think the potentials in the active list
think the potentials in the active list that contains the knowledge
that contains the knowledge and then go remove us from the after
and then go remove us from the after this is going to be summation X I and
this is going to be summation X I and you are going to come up with a new
you are going to come up with a new potential P of X I and then you have got
potential P of X I and then you have got a place that we are assigned the octave
a place that we are assigned the octave later everything else will disappear
later everything else will disappear from the actively
this is not good information is really didn't need them anymore alright so if
didn't need them anymore alright so if you are going to sum over this service
you are going to sum over this service the potentials basically that involved
the potentials basically that involved three they have no big sigh all right so
three they have no big sigh all right so you summon X I and you get rid of those
you summon X I and you get rid of those products and you stop see those
products and you stop see those potentials with f3 oxide okay and so
potentials with f3 oxide okay and so that's the update and then of course
that's the update and then of course when you finish and you have reached
when you finish and you have reached your query notes what you need to do is
your query notes what you need to do is you need these are the the potentials
you need these are the the potentials that only refer to the query - except
that only refer to the query - except obviously have to normalize those all
obviously have to normalize those all right and then get one okay so you are
right and then get one okay so you are going that way you have going to compute
going that way you have going to compute the conditional distribution of x given
the conditional distribution of x given X we have right but let me try to
X we have right but let me try to rapidly see if we can introduce here
rapidly see if we can introduce here what's going on with graphically want to
what's going on with graphically want to do this process so we're going again at
do this process so we're going again at this estimation all right so to come up
this estimation all right so to come up with potential we have this product that
with potential we have this product that contains X I all right and contained in
contains X I all right and contained in this potentials would know that ty
this potentials would know that ty all right and this knowledge the notes
all right and this knowledge the notes that are actually related with what I
that are actually related with what I call the elimination clique in the graph
call the elimination clique in the graph so identification of a set of nodes
so identification of a set of nodes right to disconnect it alright so as the
right to disconnect it alright so as the elimination process happens I have
elimination process happens I have creative three notes I integrate over
creative three notes I integrate over one node and then I'm elected with let's
one node and then I'm elected with let's say two nodes all right but the trick
say two nodes all right but the trick that I'm eliminating one node has three
that I'm eliminating one node has three notes that's the elimination clique and
notes that's the elimination clique and the maximum of this cliques is going to
the maximum of this cliques is going to define the complexity of the algorithm
so
so can you look at this you know different people for graphs and think
different people for graphs and think elimination I would have been proceeding
elimination I would have been proceeding with a method by the time and tell me
with a method by the time and tell me which one do you think is going to be
which one do you think is going to be more complicated computationally
more complicated computationally speaking do you look at the definitions
speaking do you look at the definitions but look at this if you're studying I
but look at this if you're studying I mean anything
mean anything one node at a time and then you have to
one node at a time and then you have to do summation over the affiliated no to
do summation over the affiliated no to that no chocolate shake
that no chocolate shake it's really my neighbors know how many
it's really my neighbors know how many nodes in the potentials are related to
nodes in the potentials are related to this node how many
so from here if you are there the you know they're the joint right the pop
know they're the joint right the pop your eyes and you want to eliminate this
your eyes and you want to eliminate this and you saw over that note how many in
and you saw over that note how many in the potential that is that you're going
the potential that is that you're going to be doing the some how many or the
to be doing the some how many or the body will start involved
my name's pinky all right what are you gonna have you're gonna have the
gonna have you're gonna have the probability of this given that and the
probability of this given that and the probability of that given that so many
probability of that given that so many coming in knowledge involve this how
coming in knowledge involve this how many times we have how many how many
how many times this actually 25 let's say comes problem so so if you calculate
say comes problem so so if you calculate right here we define the period as the
right here we define the period as the minimum size of a hospital immolations
minimum size of a hospital immolations of the rats monthly created during golf
of the rats monthly created during golf elimination - 1 so the click here is all
elimination - 1 so the click here is all right because I reversed in Iran and we
right because I reversed in Iran and we put the minus 1 because this is a
put the minus 1 because this is a twisting action we want to have this
twisting action we want to have this variable that forest is equal to 1 all
variable that forest is equal to 1 all right
right in this case basically this is the only
in this case basically this is the only potential you know that you will work
potential you know that you will work with so this is the click the clickers
with so this is the click the clickers is of size Q minus 1 the thing which we
is of size Q minus 1 the thing which we defined to be equal to 1
so how do you want to eliminate this all right
right what is going on well actually let's
what is going on well actually let's take something more accomplished you
take something more accomplished you know take something more complicated
know take something more complicated take something here you know you know
take something here you know you know how many you know how many things we
how many you know how many things we need to eliminate so if you try to
need to eliminate so if you try to eliminate this while we have to do
eliminate this while we have to do something in sequence so let's see which
something in sequence so let's see which will eliminate
I mean consider that this thing goes up and downs right so it is a
and downs right so it is a two-dimensional graph looking like that
two-dimensional graph looking like that so it doesn't matter let's concentrate
so it doesn't matter let's concentrate on this on this node and let's say we
on this on this node and let's say we have eliminated this so how many how
have eliminated this so how many how many potentials how many vegetables
many potentials how many vegetables where eliminate what is the elimination
where eliminate what is the elimination click where the summation is going to
click where the summation is going to operate how many nodes will involve
operate how many nodes will involve let's say this now we assume this
let's say this now we assume this already we eliminate it to the right how
already we eliminate it to the right how many how many 3 so 3 minus 1 so the 3
many how many 3 so 3 minus 1 so the 3 width is 2 and the chatter a more
width is 2 and the chatter a more complicated case
complicated case so obviously the nation's if everybody
so obviously the nation's if everybody both can take K values the cost of every
both can take K values the cost of every notice k2 w plus 1 could not use the 3
notice k2 w plus 1 could not use the 3 wait and then times V this gives you the
wait and then times V this gives you the order of the calculation if you didn't
order of the calculation if you didn't give elimination I would basically the
give elimination I would basically the cost would be K to the power D all right
cost would be K to the power D all right D is the total number of nodes so
D is the total number of nodes so obviously this is linear in V so it's V
obviously this is linear in V so it's V times K 2w plus 1
times K 2w plus 1 and lots of kinds of things so many
and lots of kinds of things so many lectures we think with the plus 1
lectures we think with the plus 1 because you know 12 years big the 1
because you know 12 years big the 1 doesn't make much difference but this is
doesn't make much difference but this is the sort of the correct route list okay
so the best and in the context of undirected graphs okay I mentioned we
undirected graphs okay I mentioned we are gonna be here in the Big Show you
are gonna be here in the Big Show you can unify the directed and undirected
can unify the directed and undirected graphs with the addition of a little bit
graphs with the addition of a little bit ahead of ourselves because I haven't
ahead of ourselves because I haven't discussed the factorization of the Joint
discussed the factorization of the Joint Distribution over undirected graphs but
Distribution over undirected graphs but let me just state it alright so then
let me just state it alright so then we're gonna be difficult here and we
we're gonna be difficult here and we will come back to this in details in the
will come back to this in details in the graphs you know the remember we have the
graphs you know the remember we have the probability of fabric now attacks
probability of fabric now attacks developments in analyzed in terms of you
developments in analyzed in terms of you know is X 1 X 2 X 5 X 3 it lik know why
know is X 1 X 2 X 5 X 3 it lik know why because X 1 and X 5 are not connected
because X 1 and X 5 are not connected because X 2 X they are not connected so
because X 2 X they are not connected so easily here that you have a sufficient
easily here that you have a sufficient undirected graph you have this clique we
undirected graph you have this clique we have this clique you have this clique
have this clique you have this clique and then you have it later of 3 and then
and then you have it later of 3 and then you have a clique of 2 so each of these
you have a clique of 2 so each of these cliques comes with the potential note
cliques comes with the potential note the distribution just the potential of
the distribution just the potential of those functions that sort of explains
those functions that sort of explains well standing variables are correlated
well standing variables are correlated involved late right but they're you know
involved late right but they're you know distributions their potentials you know
distributions their potentials you know if you elimination on undirected graphs
if you elimination on undirected graphs they will be actually literally is a
they will be actually literally is a typical form of the algorithm for
typical form of the algorithm for directed graphs but it's ridiculous
directed graphs but it's ridiculous complicated because there is no errors
complicated because there is no errors or anything like that so when I have
or anything like that so when I have been in this Bluff I took the joint
been in this Bluff I took the joint distribution I loved it in terms of
distribution I loved it in terms of potential over rocks more clicks as I
potential over rocks more clicks as I just called here alright I panting the
just called here alright I panting the evidence as you see in here okay and
evidence as you see in here okay and then to find this joint I the summations
and exactly as we did with very few graphs the rotation is practically
graphs the rotation is practically identical
identical this is thing that you see that is
this is thing that you see that is different here from what we did with
different here from what we did with directed graphs when you write this
directed graphs when you write this joint probabilities in terms of these
joint probabilities in terms of these potentials this optimization does not
potentials this optimization does not give you normalize distribution so the
give you normalize distribution so the normalization factor basically there is
normalization factor basically there is not no but eventually when you give me
not no but eventually when you give me lots of blood alright then you can fill
lots of blood alright then you can fill this joint and you want this conditional
this joint and you want this conditional you don't really need Z because once you
you don't really need Z because once you get this potential this is what you
get this potential this is what you believe this
believe this this conditional distribution and it is
this conditional distribution and it is what we're gonna do is so the skids can
what we're gonna do is so the skids can invade the room where the stress in
invade the room where the stress in action and then we are going to merge
action and then we are going to merge the two algorithms and give you sort of
the two algorithms and give you sort of a graph theoretic approach with
a graph theoretic approach with elimination of cliques but we'll do the
elimination of cliques but we'll do the elimination of it so you don't really
elimination of it so you don't really have to say division of variables but
have to say division of variables but basically you've been at eliminating
basically you've been at eliminating nodes one at the same time deprived of
nodes one at the same time deprived of the clicks for this and also eliminated
the clicks for this and also eliminated there will be some marriage with some
there will be some marriage with some organization process happening in the
organization process happening in the process and some other weird things but
process and some other weird things but they will all be theoretical approaches
they will all be theoretical approaches so will be operations on the graph not
so will be operations on the graph not in the distribution anymore okay
in the distribution anymore okay so actually so you can do it you can be
so actually so you can do it you can be ahead of me and I will say remember you
ahead of me and I will say remember you sometime in the very near future
sometime in the very near future okay so for any conditions in the former
okay so for any conditions in the former Rubick