I sent an email with a very long attachments and the noise you guys
attachments and the noise you guys receiveth it were true
receiveth it were true okay that is the the best reading
okay that is the the best reading basically improbably free graphical
basically improbably free graphical models that I know Elementary in some
models that I know Elementary in some sense but standard if you see pixels
sense but standard if you see pixels missing
missing don't start sending me all you know that
don't start sending me all you know that page is missing well that page missing
page is missing well that page missing because it's missing right that's what
because it's missing right that's what happens when you download income China
happens when you download income China okay some pages are missing
okay some pages are missing I'm just kidding but you know some pages
I'm just kidding but you know some pages don't exist actually
don't exist actually okay the offer has not completed them
okay the offer has not completed them yet especially energy to things like
yet especially energy to things like that
that alright so what I think I realize we're
alright so what I think I realize we're going extremely slowly and maybe is
going extremely slowly and maybe is because I don't want the class to drop
because I don't want the class to drop it before even the first homework is due
it before even the first homework is due or something like that okay but for sure
or something like that okay but for sure we need to accelerate the homeworks
we need to accelerate the homeworks otherwise advanced years doing six for
otherwise advanced years doing six for multiservice year okay so next one work
multiservice year okay so next one work is view made basically you know
is view made basically you know okay like some logistics here on Friday
okay like some logistics here on Friday we're not gonna have recitation but
we're not gonna have recitation but Subic is going to be in this office in
Subic is going to be in this office in 311 Cushing 3 Devon I think it says
311 Cushing 3 Devon I think it says ethoxide 311 M ok during the election
ethoxide 311 M ok during the election time and the purpose of the homework is
time and the purpose of the homework is for everybody to do it even if we have
for everybody to do it even if we have to give you the solution ok so you
to give you the solution ok so you cannot leave basically the room on
cannot leave basically the room on Friday without having a solution down
Friday without having a solution down there is no sort of thing all it's a
there is no sort of thing all it's a difficult problem I will leave it for
difficult problem I will leave it for later we want you to do it even if that
later we want you to do it even if that means you asked him for the solution ok
means you asked him for the solution ok we want it done on Monday I'm away and
we want it done on Monday I'm away and Subic is going to give the recitation
Subic is going to give the recitation for homework to that we hope it would be
for homework to that we hope it would be posted this weekend okay so the very
posted this weekend okay so the very station for homework 2 on Monday and
station for homework 2 on Monday and then I will take the lecture on Friday
then I will take the lecture on Friday occasionally when I mean Thursday and
occasionally when I mean Thursday and Friday will give the lecture next week
Friday will give the lecture next week ok so what we do today is we need to
ok so what we do today is we need to discuss we need to go back to the
discuss we need to go back to the elimination algorithm poaches start off
elimination algorithm poaches start off very trivial but where we stopped was
very trivial but where we stopped was sort of to provide the graph theoretic
sort of to provide the graph theoretic approach to elimination I mean we said
approach to elimination I mean we said we eliminate now you know we saw mobile
we eliminate now you know we saw mobile the potential to depend on the variables
the potential to depend on the variables we eliminate but what is the right
we eliminate but what is the right ordering how we control the complexity
ordering how we control the complexity of the algorithm and how we do this
of the algorithm and how we do this purely using graph theoretic approaches
purely using graph theoretic approaches that has not been discussed so we me and
that has not been discussed so we me and we have summarized very briefly the
we have summarized very briefly the algorithms so we remember what we are
algorithms so we remember what we are talking okay so the elimination
talking okay so the elimination algorithm basically has the following
algorithm basically has the following steps the first step is realized
you have to choose some ordering where the query notes we want that you want
the query notes we want that you want basically to compute let's say the
basically to compute let's say the marginal of the last okay so the
marginal of the last okay so the ordering it starts out except F is the
ordering it starts out except F is the query notes appears the last and then
query notes appears the last and then you have to create a list of acting
potentials if you like and because this is a direct graph you go through each
is a direct graph you go through each node in the graph and you place all of
node in the graph and you place all of the conditional probabilities that
the conditional probabilities that define basically altogether the
define basically altogether the capitalization of the Joint Distribution
capitalization of the Joint Distribution you put them on what's called the
you put them on what's called the actively now in addition to those in the
actively now in addition to those in the second step when you call evidence you
second step when you call evidence you also put in the active list this
also put in the active list this evidence functions which were nothing
evidence functions which were nothing else present the functions of course
else present the functions of course this variable to take value five let's
this variable to take value five let's say right so so you don't really need to
say right so so you don't really need to have it explicitly but conceptualize
have it explicitly but conceptualize this this needs to come somewhere so if
this this needs to come somewhere so if you want it just a formal presentation
you want it just a formal presentation basically you need to put this evidence
basically you need to put this evidence function right in the active list in
function right in the active list in editions of this condition of potential
editions of this condition of potential okay and then following your elimination
okay and then following your elimination or the what you need to do is you have
or the what you need to do is you have to go to every node X I following hot or
to go to every node X I following hot or dry and you have to find all the
dry and you have to find all the potentials the depend on X high alright
potentials the depend on X high alright so basically this will be the evidence
so basically this will be the evidence functions would be X I depending on
functions would be X I depending on exponent the children depending on
exponent the children depending on excise the excise the parent etc okay
excise the excise the parent etc okay snow multiply all those together some
snow multiply all those together some elect I and then form a new potential
elect I and then form a new potential which we call it the X I and then place
which we call it the X I and then place this potential in the activity and all
this potential in the activity and all the other potentials basically that you
the other potentials basically that you introduced
introduced that involve its I will be removed from
that involve its I will be removed from the after this okay so you'll be sucked
the after this okay so you'll be sucked into this with the effect I and the last
into this with the effect I and the last step is basically if you want to
step is basically if you want to normalize you know you can do this by
normalize you know you can do this by summing over all possible values of the
summing over all possible values of the query variables now to be able to
query variables now to be able to introduce sort of a graph theoretic
introduce sort of a graph theoretic version of this algorithm unfortunately
version of this algorithm unfortunately we have to discuss a little bit on how
we have to discuss a little bit on how we do factorization in in undirected
we do factorization in in undirected graphs which is actually my next lecture
graphs which is actually my next lecture so I'm gonna be sort of the little
so I'm gonna be sort of the little header and go backwards right so you may
header and go backwards right so you may think education is a right thing to do
think education is a right thing to do but in life not everything is the right
but in life not everything is the right thing to do alright so doing some things
thing to do alright so doing some things how to fold the hem sometimes we need to
how to fold the hem sometimes we need to hear something flies in different order
hear something flies in different order that can be helpful as well okay so
that can be helpful as well okay so let's see where the situations so we're
let's see where the situations so we're going to discuss this elimination
going to discuss this elimination algorithm directed graphs and the only
algorithm directed graphs and the only thing that I want you to know which will
thing that I want you to know which will be actually on next lecture there is no
be actually on next lecture there is no conditional probabilities general
conditional probabilities general directed graphs the way we have them in
directed graphs the way we have them in directed graphs what you have is you
directed graphs what you have is you have potential over the status now you
have potential over the status now you have product of potentials over the sets
have product of potentials over the sets of interconnected nodes which we call
of interconnected nodes which we call them clicks okay and those potentials
them clicks okay and those potentials are not really probability distributions
are not really probability distributions all right which means they're not they
all right which means they're not they don't normalize or they don't have the
don't normalize or they don't have the physical meaning that the conditional
physical meaning that the conditional distributions have in in directed graphs
distributions have in in directed graphs so in this undirected graph here if you
so in this undirected graph here if you look for the number of cliques the
look for the number of cliques the maximal cliques that somebody can have
maximal cliques that somebody can have is you can see X 1 X 2 is a clique
is you can see X 1 X 2 is a clique they're connected X 1 X 3 is a clique X
they're connected X 1 X 3 is a clique X 3 X 5 is a trait X 2 X 5 and X 6 is a
3 X 5 is a trait X 2 X 5 and X 6 is a clique
clique and x2 x4 is actually okay X 1 X 2 X 5
and x2 x4 is actually okay X 1 X 2 X 5 it is not a clique because the X 1 and X
it is not a clique because the X 1 and X 5 are not connected okay so the maximal
5 are not connected okay so the maximal cliques are basically the ones that are
cliques are basically the ones that are listed here the only thing I want you to
listed here the only thing I want you to know in the context of undirected graphs
know in the context of undirected graphs basically the Joint Distribution for the
basically the Joint Distribution for the variables will be written as the product
variables will be written as the product of some potentials that are defined
of some potentials that are defined using the variables over its clique and
using the variables over its clique and we will not give you any specific
we will not give you any specific details but they are can be anything the
details but they are can be anything the only constraint actually is that they
only constraint actually is that they are positive so effectively when you
are positive so effectively when you multiply them you get a probability
multiply them you get a probability distribution which will not be
distribution which will not be normalized but that's the only thing I
normalized but that's the only thing I want you to understand so for example if
want you to understand so for example if this is the same example with it earlier
this is the same example with it earlier but I am showing this form directly
but I am showing this form directly graphs if you want to find the joint of
graphs if you want to find the joint of X 1 and X 6 4 X 6 is given so that's an
X 1 and X 6 4 X 6 is given so that's an evidence node what you need to do is you
evidence node what you need to do is you have to write the you know you have to
have to write the you know you have to popularize the joint probability of all
popularize the joint probability of all the variables and integrate everything
the variables and integrate everything out except X 1 and X 6 you have to
out except X 1 and X 6 you have to integrate X 2 X 3 X 4 X 5 6 X 6 to the
integrate X 2 X 3 X 4 X 5 6 X 6 to the with this evidence function to these X
with this evidence function to these X bar sticks and you notice we instead of
bar sticks and you notice we instead of probabilities here I have this potential
probabilities here I have this potential function this is the way we define
function this is the way we define undirected graphs ok and again as I said
undirected graphs ok and again as I said we will see this slowly in the following
we will see this slowly in the following lecture we start today but I want you to
lecture we start today but I want you to sleep now because I'm going to use some
sleep now because I'm going to use some ideas from undirected graphs and already
ideas from undirected graphs and already following the elimination algorithm so
following the elimination algorithm so the probability of conditional
the probability of conditional probabilities but the rest the
probabilities but the rest the operations of putting some of the
operations of putting some of the summations in words and in order of
summations in words and in order of elimination of the nodes is the same for
elimination of the nodes is the same for both sets of graphs so for example here
both sets of graphs so for example here you know let's see X 6 is fixed to this
you know let's see X 6 is fixed to this value
value okay but I believe you notice when I
okay but I believe you notice when I guess this Lent the function the idea is
guess this Lent the function the idea is going to use the render function you
going to use the render function you will have to sound 1x6 right so when you
will have to sound 1x6 right so when you sound for all possible values of X takes
sound for all possible values of X takes only when you hit this X bar six this
only when you hit this X bar six this would be nonzero so the rest is non zero
would be nonzero so the rest is non zero so this summation sort of gets you only
so this summation sort of gets you only one value corresponding to this bar
one value corresponding to this bar value there okay so so the summation X 6
value there okay so so the summation X 6 is not some of the second line I already
is not some of the second line I already put the evidence here and then I have to
put the evidence here and then I have to summon X 5 that our Explorer X 3 and X
summon X 5 that our Explorer X 3 and X few and you notice here I have
few and you notice here I have potentials that involve the nodes 3 5
potentials that involve the nodes 3 5 all right and two five and six two five
all right and two five and six two five and six okay and I'm going to sum in
and six okay and I'm going to sum in five and I call this exactly as we did
five and I call this exactly as we did with directed graphs real quick five
with directed graphs real quick five subscript and whatever notes are left
subscript and whatever notes are left let's hear what is left there are X 5 is
let's hear what is left there are X 5 is Delta X 6 X has some specific body
Delta X 6 X has some specific body choice of no interest is X 2 X 3 all
choice of no interest is X 2 X 3 all right so this doesn't involve any
right so this doesn't involve any expression when I do the summation and
expression when I do the summation and export is exactly this before I get
export is exactly this before I get another potential fear of explore the
another potential fear of explore the defense on your legs to then I have to
defense on your legs to then I have to solve this product in X 3 and then I
solve this product in X 3 and then I have to sum everything in X 2 this is
have to sum everything in X 2 this is the normalization factor right so when
the normalization factor right so when we write it like that the distribution
we write it like that the distribution is normalized so we have to put some
is normalized so we have to put some normalization factor and effectively if
normalization factor and effectively if you want to find the conditional write
you want to find the conditional write once you compute this in the condition
once you compute this in the condition will be proportional to that so you can
will be proportional to that so you can normalize by summing this potential
normalize by summing this potential period view over all possible values of
period view over all possible values of x1 okay so the rest even under extra
x1 okay so the rest even under extra class don't really have any difference
class don't really have any difference when it comes to the implementation of
when it comes to the implementation of our standard elimination algorithm but
our standard elimination algorithm but they will help us to do this sort of
they will help us to do this sort of graphically okay and and it would be
graphically okay and and it would be easier way not only to conserve to get
easier way not only to conserve to get the concept here right but also to
the concept here right but also to Graham this and implemented let me see
Graham this and implemented let me see if I have anything else to say here okay
if I have anything else to say here okay so again the only difference is not
so again the only difference is not conditional probabilities but potentials
conditional probabilities but potentials defined over maximal cliques and I told
defined over maximal cliques and I told you how many clicks you have here one
you how many clicks you have here one two three four and five clicks okay this
two three four and five clicks okay this is what undirected graphs it's okay so
is what undirected graphs it's okay so we need a graphical way that somehow
we need a graphical way that somehow helps us to control the complexity of
helps us to control the complexity of the eliminate algorithm so we need to
the eliminate algorithm so we need to see how we're gonna do this and I'm
see how we're gonna do this and I'm going to start with this I deal with a
going to start with this I deal with a point guard elimination which is not of
point guard elimination which is not of the graph analog of the elimination
the graph analog of the elimination algorithm we have seen but I am gonna
algorithm we have seen but I am gonna post this for undirected graphs for a
post this for undirected graphs for a reason and then I will generalize the
reason and then I will generalize the directed graphs
directed graphs okay so let's see if this is part
theoretical so we have an elimination or drive for graph G and the elimination
drive for graph G and the elimination the gutter elimination algorithm white
the gutter elimination algorithm white domination does the trick
domination does the trick it says probably no reasoning
it says probably no reasoning elimination rule is connect all if it's
elimination rule is connect all if it's very boots and then let me move excite
very boots and then let me move excite from the graph and I put this in blue
from the graph and I put this in blue for the purpose connect all the
for the purpose connect all the neighbors of X I and the neighbors of
neighbors of X I and the neighbors of the graph is the DEF neighbors so that's
the graph is the DEF neighbors so that's a grant concept it's not like you have
a grant concept it's not like you have ever seen you say the patterns from the
ever seen you say the patterns from the kids and you know just the graph damage
kids and you know just the graph damage okay
okay so you connect all the neighbors and
so you connect all the neighbors and then we move excite from the graph so
then we move excite from the graph so let's take how this thing works
let's take how this thing works graphically so let's say we want this is
graphically so let's say we want this is the elimination order we want to
the elimination order we want to eliminate first let's fix then X 5 X 4 X
eliminate first let's fix then X 5 X 4 X 3 X 2 X 1 so to eliminate X 6
3 X 2 X 1 so to eliminate X 6 what do we need to do
what do we need to do elimination algorithm look at the
elimination algorithm look at the neighbors the neighbors have two and
neighbors the neighbors have two and five in the water the neighborhood's
five in the water the neighborhood's collective then we eliminated six we get
collective then we eliminated six we get this then in our earth of the next node
this then in our earth of the next node is expired before we eliminate expired
is expired before we eliminate expired would look at the name versus X 2 and X
would look at the name versus X 2 and X 3 we connect them and then with what we
3 we connect them and then with what we do to X 5 eliminate then our next node
do to X 5 eliminate then our next node is explore the neighbor is X 2 there is
is explore the neighbor is X 2 there is nothing no need to put a link so we
nothing no need to put a link so we eliminate X 4 which is list then the
eliminate X 4 which is list then the next fixed X 3 like this and then X 1
next fixed X 3 like this and then X 1 the key thing here is the following step
the key thing here is the following step that somehow we connect with the
that somehow we connect with the neighbors all right and who else did we
neighbors all right and who else did we connect the neighbors so this was
connect the neighbors so this was eliminated and then this thing here but
eliminated and then this thing here but connected nodes 2 &amp; 3
connected nodes 2 &amp; 3 okay and again the concept of the
okay and again the concept of the neighbors right is is a good political
neighbors right is is a good political concept in the context of undirected
concept in the context of undirected graphs now you notice that each time a
graphs now you notice that each time a node is eliminated all of its neighbors
node is eliminated all of its neighbors are correct are connected forming a
are correct are connected forming a clique that's what we call the
clique that's what we call the elimination Creek so for example here
elimination Creek so for example here when I connect now student 5 2 5 &amp; 6 is
when I connect now student 5 2 5 &amp; 6 is a clique fully connected set of nodes
a clique fully connected set of nodes ok when I go in and connect to a 3 2 or
ok when I go in and connect to a 3 2 or 3 &amp; 5 is the click ok so that is the
3 &amp; 5 is the click ok so that is the elimination click and it is very
elimination click and it is very important you can connect this back with
important you can connect this back with the elimination algorithm we discussed
the elimination algorithm we discussed before but we will see this now in a in
before but we will see this now in a in a graphical reading fashion so for
a graphical reading fashion so for example in in
example in in you know there clicks but we generated
you know there clicks but we generated in the previous example is this click
in the previous example is this click two five and six and I could exist six
two five and six and I could exist six because it corresponds to node six right
because it corresponds to node six right this is the note that I'm going to
this is the note that I'm going to eliminate from this click but this is
eliminate from this click but this is the click two five and six right and
the click two five and six right and there is another click that I generated
there is another click that I generated which is two three and five and I call
which is two three and five and I call it 5c five because I'm going to
it 5c five because I'm going to eliminate no time okay so three powerful
eliminate no time okay so three powerful visiting program elimination algorithm
visiting program elimination algorithm is that it's time to remove a node if
is that it's time to remove a node if you record the collection of nodes that
you record the collection of nodes that are the neighbors of X I at that moment
are the neighbors of X I at that moment including excite self which are this
including excite self which are this maximal leaks that are formed during the
maximal leaks that are formed during the elimination algorithm okay
nothing because the operations you're going to do right when you are going to
going to do right when you are going to eliminate the note you are going to
eliminate the note you are going to multiply basically I'm gonna work with
multiply basically I'm gonna work with the potentials from districts so the
the potentials from districts so the biggest the size of the click the more
biggest the size of the click the more complex the algorithm will be and that's
complex the algorithm will be and that's why the largest clique but that you
why the largest clique but that you can't with defines the order of complex
can't with defines the order of complex fields the of the algorithm
fields the of the algorithm okay so nowadays basically the maximum
okay so nowadays basically the maximum size of the Greeks is 3 so that will
size of the Greeks is 3 so that will define the complexity of the output so
define the complexity of the output so let's say if it's not takes K values
let's say if it's not takes K values this could be gave the power 3 so case
this could be gave the power 3 so case what we saw in the earlier lecture is
what we saw in the earlier lecture is defined as the 3 width of the graph okay
defined as the 3 width of the graph okay okay so this is dependence masking even
okay so this is dependence masking even a maximum size the size of the maximum
a maximum size the size of the maximum clique that you get when you implement
clique that you get when you implement this graph lumination output okay
all right so so the I'm looking here on the front bullet right so it says the
the front bullet right so it says the elimination of the node has the effect
elimination of the node has the effect of creating new dependencies between all
of creating new dependencies between all pairs of neighbors thus introducing a
pairs of neighbors thus introducing a new clique in the graph so the idea here
new clique in the graph so the idea here is by saying connect the neighbors of X
is by saying connect the neighbors of X 6 somehow nodes 2 &amp; 5 become now
6 somehow nodes 2 &amp; 5 become now dependent and in some circumstances you
dependent and in some circumstances you won't be able to see it say ha there is
won't be able to see it say ha there is a relation of nodes 2 &amp; 5 right I'm
a relation of nodes 2 &amp; 5 right I'm sorry yeah
sorry yeah no it's two in five I mean they're on
no it's two in five I mean they're on the other side of this graph system but
the other side of this graph system but somehow if you're going to eliminate X
somehow if you're going to eliminate X this X 6 during to reduce these
this X 6 during to reduce these dependencies between nodes 5 and we will
dependencies between nodes 5 and we will say if you don't do this step when we
say if you don't do this step when we work with with directed graphs basically
work with with directed graphs basically you will not be able to model this
you will not be able to model this correctly ok
correctly ok so in this particular case you notice
so in this particular case you notice you for voluntary angular's right and
you for voluntary angular's right and that's why this process is contouring
that's why this process is contouring relation of the graph for an undirected
relation of the graph for an undirected graph where we connect you know the
graph where we connect you know the inventor of elimination we connect the
inventor of elimination we connect the neighbors of the node to be eliminated
neighbors of the node to be eliminated forming these cliques lexical list can
forming these cliques lexical list can be extended to but notice here before
be extended to but notice here before you say okay transformation of directed
you say okay transformation of directed graph and then apply the undirected
graph and then apply the undirected graph elimination algorithm there is an
graph elimination algorithm there is an intermediate step and in previous step
intermediate step and in previous step that's extremely important it says where
that's extremely important it says where is the doctor and then transform it to
is the doctor and then transform it to an undirected graph about sort of a very
an undirected graph about sort of a very tricky concept if you miss the step
tricky concept if you miss the step basically this Albert do not work so the
basically this Albert do not work so the idea here is not simply to transform it
idea here is not simply to transform it an undirected graph but you have to
an undirected graph but you have to moisturize it and remind me which
moisturize it and remind me which modernization here let's make the
modernization here let's make the parents basically okay so the idea here
parents basically okay so the idea here is for example we need to connect the
is for example we need to connect the parents let's say of 6 which is 2 &amp; 5
parents let's say of 6 which is 2 &amp; 5 and then transform this to an undirected
and then transform this to an undirected graph can you know the next krishna is
graph can you know the next krishna is basically the so pictorially why if you
basically the so pictorially why if you don't do this step you would be messing
don't do this step you would be messing things up but can anybody basically just
things up but can anybody basically just stop thinking why that step is attention
no but we remembered in the in the in the undirected graph we also connect the
the undirected graph we also connect the neighbors right so somebody will say
neighbors right so somebody will say when let's say I limit X 6 2 &amp; 5 will be
when let's say I limit X 6 2 &amp; 5 will be neighbors I'm going to connect them so
neighbors I'm going to connect them so there is the modernization so I took
there is the modernization so I took care of it
care of it so why do I need to moralize
we're saying is it seems like in first loop but because here we collect the
loop but because here we collect the neighbors that maybe this does already
neighbors that maybe this does already demonisation does it
I mean let's not go through that it to the net right that's not just imagining
the net right that's not just imagining things so then we can bypass many of
things so then we can bypass many of them of the following slides so let's
them of the following slides so let's say we make this an undirected graph
say we make this an undirected graph alright okay so we connect Rene but I'm
alright okay so we connect Rene but I'm sorry this is okay so in this case this
sorry this is okay so in this case this is this distant my lines okay I this
is this distant my lines okay I this will not work my god okay so let's see
will not work my god okay so let's see here's the example if any minute x6
here's the example if any minute x6 the way we did it before there's not
the way we did it before there's not gonna be any issue right so let me do
gonna be any issue right so let me do the following let me try one in
the following let me try one in terminating x6 because there will not be
terminating x6 because there will not be able to how we're different some
able to how we're different some organization does let's say we eliminate
organization does let's say we eliminate X Pfeiffer was it you go back to this
X Pfeiffer was it you go back to this slide and eliminate X 5 and let's say we
slide and eliminate X 5 and let's say we don't do any monetization so if you
don't do any monetization so if you don't deny realization and you transfer
don't deny realization and you transfer this to you know to an undirected graph
this to you know to an undirected graph what is the first thing you're going to
what is the first thing you're going to do on this guy so there's no
do on this guy so there's no modernization here right so if I
modernization here right so if I eliminate X 5 what needs to happen in
eliminate X 5 what needs to happen in the undirected graph algorithm
whether the neighbor survived
so we let me show you the calculation right this is the undirected graph so if
right this is the undirected graph so if I'm going to eliminate X 5 what we need
I'm going to eliminate X 5 what we need to do is we need to sum or X 5 the
to do is we need to sum or X 5 the following conditional distributions
following conditional distributions expired given X 3 all right and X 6
expired given X 3 all right and X 6 given X 2 X 5 we read this from the
given X 2 X 5 we read this from the directed graph so basically one way or
directed graph so basically one way or another this is the calculation that we
another this is the calculation that we need to do and when you look at this
need to do and when you look at this calculation with X 5 integrated out who
calculation with X 5 integrated out who now get dependencies between which node
now get dependencies between which node X 2 X 3 and X 6 so let me see this X 2 X
X 2 X 3 and X 6 so let me see this X 2 X 3 and X X 6 is that dependency going to
3 and X X 6 is that dependency going to be there when we use just the undirected
be there when we use just the undirected graph elimination algorithm without
graph elimination algorithm without realization so again we have a
realization so again we have a dependence between X 2 X 3 and X 6 X 2 X
dependence between X 2 X 3 and X 6 X 2 X 3 and X fixed
what is going to be missing when I apply they the undirected graph elimination
they the undirected graph elimination algorithm so I need the dependency
algorithm so I need the dependency between x2 x3 and x6 so if you do this
between x2 x3 and x6 so if you do this in the undirected graph without the
in the undirected graph without the modernization step and you get me the
modernization step and you get me the perspire first what are you going to do
perspire first what are you going to do in the graph what Nick is going to be
in the graph what Nick is going to be introduced you remember in the simulator
introduced you remember in the simulator if you need to connect the neighbors
if you need to connect the neighbors right and whether the neighbors are 5 3
right and whether the neighbors are 5 3 &amp; 6 so what is going to be missing from
&amp; 6 so what is going to be missing from the girls but somehow is not going to
the girls but somehow is not going to account for the dependence implied here
account for the dependence implied here x2 and x3 so the link between x2 x3 is
x2 and x3 so the link between x2 x3 is going to be missing is not going to be
going to be missing is not going to be there ok is the perfect 6 what do you do
there ok is the perfect 6 what do you do you link X 2 and X 5 you see its
you link X 2 and X 5 you see its neighbors become what knows in the
neighbors become what knows in the undirected God now it sure you may
undirected God now it sure you may realize you're going to put this link
realize you're going to put this link from 3 to 5
from 3 to 5 right now that you're going to eliminate
right now that you're going to eliminate right there that says you need to
right there that says you need to connect there the neighbors and the
connect there the neighbors and the neighbors of 5 now going to be which 1 2
neighbors of 5 now going to be which 1 2 &amp; 3
&amp; 3 and that's how you get the link of 23
and that's how you get the link of 23 in other ways the motorization comes
in other ways the motorization comes from x6 right and the thing is not going
from x6 right and the thing is not going to be around but there but now there is
to be around but there but now there is a dependency that you need to introduce
a dependency that you need to introduce between x2 x3 but to see here that
between x2 x3 but to see here that they're going to be missing because you
they're going to be missing because you demoralize the parents of x6 okay so the
demoralize the parents of x6 okay so the sorry but if you do this and you do a
sorry but if you do this and you do a perfect 6 look that's where I was asking
perfect 6 look that's where I was asking me surely obviously you're not going to
me surely obviously you're not going to have a problem with the algorithm but if
have a problem with the algorithm but if you want to eliminate expiring first
you want to eliminate expiring first that's when the problem appears so here
that's when the problem appears so here is the algorithm you are going to you
is the algorithm you are going to you need to moralize the graph and then
need to moralize the graph and then apply this on directed graph eliminate
apply this on directed graph eliminate algo so does paralyze it to us for
algo so does paralyze it to us for eternal directed graph and apply this
eternal directed graph and apply this algorithm that is truly best for graph
algorithm that is truly best for graph theory do anything you know this is how
theory do anything you know this is how the algorithm is working in action for
the algorithm is working in action for example if let's say the elimination is
example if let's say the elimination is eliminate so this was the dark lines of
eliminate so this was the dark lines of the original graph you marry this to
the original graph you marry this to this dotted line comes from organization
this dotted line comes from organization and this line has come where this is
and this line has come where this is because you know you married the parents
because you know you married the parents of X 6 and this line comes because what
of X 6 and this line comes because what when you are ready to eliminate X 5 we
when you are ready to eliminate X 5 we need to correct its labels of their two
need to correct its labels of their two and three so two different origin one is
and three so two different origin one is the modernization the other one is is
the modernization the other one is is coming by connecting so long comes
coming by connecting so long comes basically from this part of the
basically from this part of the algorithm the other one comes from the
algorithm the other one comes from the undirected graph three minutes
all right the next thing is really now people really have seen it okay so I'm
people really have seen it okay so I'm going to stop there and then I'm going
going to stop there and then I'm going to switch lecture and I'm going to go to
to switch lecture and I'm going to go to punish my computer do you see a mouse on
punish my computer do you see a mouse on the screen
so what do I supposed to do okay let me remove this thing out first
remove this thing out first now people lost uh some of the computer
now people lost uh some of the computer screen
all right okay so we're going to basically see how
okay so we're going to basically see how slowly this positive factorization that
slowly this positive factorization that distributions in undirected God
distributions in undirected God okay and actually I'm going to come back
okay and actually I'm going to come back to this topic sort of in a more rigorous
to this topic sort of in a more rigorous language maybe four or five lectures
language maybe four or five lectures okay so but right now we're going to do
okay so but right now we're going to do sort of an intermediate easygoing
sort of an intermediate easygoing presentation of undirected graphs and
presentation of undirected graphs and maybe next Thursday we'll discuss a
maybe next Thursday we'll discuss a little bit about what's called factor
little bit about what's called factor graphs alright so we have seen this in
graphs alright so we have seen this in more detail we just discussed about
more detail we just discussed about directed graphs another name from the
directed graphs another name from the raphe graphs is Markov random fields for
raphe graphs is Markov random fields for ghosts in in physics engineering etc you
ghosts in in physics engineering etc you know must read you be interested on this
know must read you be interested on this type of models people for example in
type of models people for example in social networks in in problems that
social networks in in problems that there is a causal relations they are
there is a causal relations they are interested in Bayesian networks but
interested in Bayesian networks but actually most algorithms but you know if
actually most algorithms but you know if you if you want to operate on this you
you if you want to operate on this you will transport with some other core most
will transport with some other core most probably you know an undirected graph
probably you know an undirected graph for the factor graph okay so it's not
for the factor graph okay so it's not like we're going to let them different
like we're going to let them different techniques for each graph but I'm just
techniques for each graph but I'm just saying this is the standard way of doing
saying this is the standard way of doing things to tell in in engineering you
things to tell in in engineering you know modeling random properties and
know modeling random properties and things like that this is more in when
things like that this is more in when you have causality relation okay we
you have causality relation okay we mentioned one example that would like to
mentioned one example that would like to come back now to it okay so basically
come back now to it okay so basically you know our model so we have nodes
you know our model so we have nodes exactly as before but there are random
exactly as before but there are random variables we have entities that describe
variables we have entities that describe basically independent relations and
basically independent relations and there is no
there is no symmetry but has to do with directional
symmetry but has to do with directional arrows so there's a sense of think that
arrows so there's a sense of think that you know I'm your parent here everyone
you know I'm your parent here everyone is the parent you know so the summation
is the parent you know so the summation between a and C is equivalent okay there
between a and C is equivalent okay there is no directionality here and it comes
is no directionality here and it comes up but the independence realizes this
up but the independence realizes this very important one of the electric
very important one of the electric valves
valves they're basically got separation you
they're basically got separation you know ideas so here is a one relation I
know ideas so here is a one relation I said that a and B are independent given
said that a and B are independent given two T and D okay so what happens is to
two T and D okay so what happens is to the conditioned on C and D and I claim
the conditioned on C and D and I claim that a is independent of B because every
that a is independent of B because every party from A to B has to pass through C
party from A to B has to pass through C and D so if I given C and D the path is
and D so if I given C and D the path is blocked in a completely graph theoretic
blocked in a completely graph theoretic waste in other words there is no path
waste in other words there is no path from A to B that doesn't pass through
from A to B that doesn't pass through see the union of C and D okay it's a
see the union of C and D okay it's a critical Hritik graph theoretic
critical Hritik graph theoretic algorithm right so we do have this
algorithm right so we do have this explain a wasting we had with the torque
explain a wasting we had with the torque independence that we show in directed
independence that we show in directed graphical models so here you know if you
graphical models so here you know if you apply the beta small algorithm and if
apply the beta small algorithm and if you have to pass through a path of knows
you have to pass through a path of knows that I've described basically that
that I've described basically that immediately defines the conditional
immediately defines the conditional independence relations for this craft a
independence relations for this craft a very simple calculation if you have n
very simple calculation if you have n random variables okay and let's see what
random variables okay and let's see what I'm doing is I'm completing all possible
I'm doing is I'm completing all possible ways of coming up with relationships
ways of coming up with relationships that shake here between three random
that shake here between three random variables okay so in this case the
variables okay so in this case the player on the variables are fully
player on the variables are fully independent all right here this one
independent all right here this one connection or the connection etc and
if I have n random variables and they're binary let's take this case
binary let's take this case naturally not binary this two shares
naturally not binary this two shares thanks for what this is the total number
thanks for what this is the total number of undirected graphs because here mmm
of undirected graphs because here mmm the bottom also my claim is 2 to the
the bottom also my claim is 2 to the power n n minus 1 over 2 the distance
power n n minus 1 over 2 the distance for what I mean if I have to knowledge
for what I mean if I have to knowledge there's no self connect to go they are
there's no self connect to go they are not connected
not connected that's what are the two cups ok so the
that's what are the two cups ok so the total number of graphs that you can get
total number of graphs that you can get undirected graphs or the set of them
undirected graphs or the set of them from the variables is 2 to the power M
from the variables is 2 to the power M times n minus 1 over 2m is because you
times n minus 1 over 2m is because you have evernotes
have evernotes and every node can be connected with the
and every node can be connected with the other n minus 1 known and 2 because
other n minus 1 known and 2 because there is no directionality through you
there is no directionality through you have to you know to double count
have to you know to double count basically the number of graphs
basically the number of graphs now which God basically represents your
now which God basically represents your problem based on a realization of random
problem based on a realization of random variables
variables what's the graph structure of the my
what's the graph structure of the my session problem and we will come back to
session problem and we will come back to it way later in the course from history
it way later in the course from history independence relations in undirected
independence relations in undirected graphs is what I described before
graphs is what I described before extremely simple there is no you don't
extremely simple there is no you don't need to remember the rules
need to remember the rules you know we have to share them heads and
you know we have to share them heads and tails or all of these things that we did
tails or all of these things that we did could directly graphs this is
could directly graphs this is independent of not given X B when every
independent of not given X B when every path from this set of notes the result
path from this set of notes the result of not just passed through the xB notes
of not just passed through the xB notes okay so basically the concept of
okay so basically the concept of conditional independence becomes a graph
conditional independence becomes a graph theoretic concept okay
theoretic concept okay it has nothing to do with any particular
it has nothing to do with any particular the Delta we have seen for directed
the Delta we have seen for directed graphs
is this a position where I wants to look at this equation and telling me you know
at this equation and telling me you know so basically what I say here we have two
so basically what I say here we have two nodes on the graph and I'm assuming that
nodes on the graph and I'm assuming that they're not connected via net so another
they're not connected via net so another going give a no J not connected is this
going give a no J not connected is this equation based on my graph support the
equation based on my graph support the got this condition independence
got this condition independence condition is this correct if I and J are
condition is this correct if I and J are not connected right every part from I to
not connected right every part from I to J has to go through what I steer J is
J has to go through what I steer J is there they're not connected the only way
there they're not connected the only way to go is through the other node right
to go is through the other node right you have to go through whatever the
you have to go through whatever the other nodes and immediately we know if
other nodes and immediately we know if the other nodes are given like you we
the other nodes are given like you we condition they're then given various
condition they're then given various xixj have to be independent you see
I mean the couple we said right but this is independent that if a given XP if
is independent that if a given XP if every part from here to there has to
every part from here to there has to pass through it to be because XP would
pass through it to be because XP would block it so he heard if I and J don't
block it so he heard if I and J don't hold an edge I can claim that their
hold an edge I can claim that their condition independent given the rest of
condition independent given the rest of the nodes because the only way I can
the nodes because the only way I can work for my DJ is through the rest of
work for my DJ is through the rest of the nodes which that pop okay so the
the nodes which that pop okay so the addition is I am writing this as a
addition is I am writing this as a certified generic
certified generic
if you like it's an eric conditional independence relation but I won't desk a
independence relation but I won't desk a to motivate the concept that the joint
to motivate the concept that the joint probability distribution can be written
probability distribution can be written as a product or potential but each of
as a product or potential but each of them is declined to better click OK and
them is declined to better click OK and so this relation or pretentious defined
so this relation or pretentious defined over the clique is sort of a way to
over the clique is sort of a way to implicitly enforce the independence
implicitly enforce the independence relation that you see up there okay so
relation that you see up there okay so let's see what I don't know when I go on
let's see what I don't know when I go on this thing because we already have chin
this thing because we already have chin it okay so an example with some notes
it okay so an example with some notes and see what clicks we have here so the
and see what clicks we have here so the this of the edges of the graph so the
this of the edges of the graph so the only connection of the head is between
only connection of the head is between x1 and x4 okay
x1 and x4 okay so there are this is a click alright one
so there are this is a click alright one click X 1 X 2 X 3 is another click
click X 1 X 2 X 3 is another click expiry export is another Greek right and
expiry export is another Greek right and so the maximal cliques place take care
so the maximal cliques place take care of size of size 3 so I will write the
of size of size 3 so I will write the Joint Distribution we write it as
Joint Distribution we write it as product of potentials defined over it's
product of potentials defined over it's much more click OK
much more click OK actually what you should do right as a
actually what you should do right as a result of the little exercise and maybe
result of the little exercise and maybe sure we can give you a little homework
sure we can give you a little homework problem is go through this all right
problem is go through this all right with some simple tune-up and then
with some simple tune-up and then basically show the independence the
basically show the independence the condition independence relation that I
condition independence relation that I mentioned before that victim how this
mentioned before that victim how this knows come over maximal to X right
knows come over maximal to X right obviously they don't overlap and nothing
obviously they don't overlap and nothing flushes the refuse conditional
flushes the refuse conditional independence relations that we mentioned
independence relations that we mentioned before
before okay so Z's the normalization factor
okay so Z's the normalization factor because this potentials are not
because this potentials are not probabilities right they're just you
probabilities right they're just you know functions but in some sense even
know functions but in some sense even other probabilities they sort of the
other probabilities they sort of the values that they take Express how
values that they take Express how related power pairs or triplets Luce
related power pairs or triplets Luce variables right depending how many
variables right depending how many variables you have on this earth so they
variables you have on this earth so they are not probabilities but the actually
are not probabilities but the actually captured the way the variables are
captured the way the variables are correlated in the ground he didn't
correlated in the ground he didn't increase his mana
increase his mana [Applause]
[Applause] okay all right
okay all right so what I have done it there is the
so what I have done it there is the knowledge don't form a clique because WC
knowledge don't form a clique because WC is not connected so if I have these four
is not connected so if I have these four variables I can write the joint
variables I can write the joint probability distribution as the
probability distribution as the probability of T maximal cliques but R 1
probability of T maximal cliques but R 1 x y and z XY and Z and another one wy in
x y and z XY and Z and another one wy in there okay Austin all right
there okay Austin all right this is the composition that we see
this is the composition that we see there is not unique all right so
there is not unique all right so sometimes you know you you know you can
sometimes you know you you know you can manipulate it differently and come up
manipulate it differently and come up with some all the ways to express this
with some all the ways to express this discrete potential so this decomposition
discrete potential so this decomposition doesn't have to be unique but right now
doesn't have to be unique but right now that's not an issue because at the end
that's not an issue because at the end of the day you're interested on
of the day you're interested on joint distribution so let's try and do
joint distribution so let's try and do one example of simple three nodes okay
one example of simple three nodes okay and stick this what we can represent
and stick this what we can represent this in terms of put themselves okay so
this in terms of put themselves okay so one where it is I
one where it is I I'm gonna guess there is only enough
I'm gonna guess there is only enough separation in conditional independence
separation in conditional independence relation here the trace that given Y X
relation here the trace that given Y X and z are independent
and z are independent okay so when I try to enforce this and
okay so when I try to enforce this and see that this expression actually leads
see that this expression actually leads to decomposition of with leaks of the
to decomposition of with leaks of the Joint Distribution so what you see here
Joint Distribution so what you see here is P of x and y and z is equal to that
is P of x and y and z is equal to that so this equation that you see in the
so this equation that you see in the middle you justify that food there's no
middle you justify that food there's no nothing assumption there but I simplify
nothing assumption there but I simplify and I say that P of Z given x and y is P
and I say that P of Z given x and y is P of Z given Y what can I use to do this I
of Z given Y what can I use to do this I use the independence relation okay all
use the independence relation okay all right effectively what I can do is I can
right effectively what I can do is I can combine those things together and this
combine those things together and this becomes the joint affection of Y and
becomes the joint affection of Y and this becomes is the condition of Z given
this becomes is the condition of Z given Y so I can call really this my XY
Y so I can call really this my XY potential because that's one click and I
potential because that's one click and I can call this my Y Z potential that
can call this my Y Z potential that comes from from this click interesting
comes from from this click interesting you know there is no way in general to
you know there is no way in general to write this initiative an example but you
write this initiative an example but you cannot write this you cannot fertilize
cannot write this you cannot fertilize this distribution in terms of power
this distribution in terms of power let's say conditional distributions to
let's say conditional distributions to learn or joint distribution so long it's
learn or joint distribution so long it's just not going to happen
just not going to happen all right so in this case you get one
all right so in this case you get one joint distribution as one potential
joint distribution as one potential another one a conditional as the other
another one a conditional as the other potential and you know I can I mention
potential and you know I can I mention that this decomposition is not unique
that this decomposition is not unique it's just combining the P of Y would be
it's just combining the P of Y would be of Z comma Y I can write this in another
of Z comma Y I can write this in another factorization where the Y Z potential
factorization where the Y Z potential becomes the join of y MZ and the XY
becomes the join of y MZ and the XY potential becomes the conditional
potential becomes the conditional effects given one so it's not unique
effects given one so it's not unique okay and as I said it doesn't really
okay and as I said it doesn't really matter it's not like this is better than
matter it's not like this is better than that you know they will do the same idea
that you know they will do the same idea and actually we will not even bother to
and actually we will not even bother to model visitors and say it is a joint or
model visitors and say it is a joint or it's a condition no it's not some
it's a condition no it's not some potential another potential define over
potential another potential define over the two kliks enough to do the job all
the two kliks enough to do the job all right so the this is the first part of
right so the this is the first part of theorem basically and has two three
theorem basically and has two three versions from the theorem coming from
versions from the theorem coming from statistical mechanics really the
statistical mechanics really the homogeneity for theorem any distribution
homogeneity for theorem any distribution is consistent with an undirected graph
is consistent with an undirected graph and consistent means it satisfies this
and consistent means it satisfies this condition independence relationship
condition independence relationship supplied by the drop has the Joint
supplied by the drop has the Joint Distribution the factorizes of the
Distribution the factorizes of the maximal cliques and looks like this okay
maximal cliques and looks like this okay the structures at this point are any
the structures at this point are any pass the body functions of the variables
pass the body functions of the variables in its clip okay is two eyes I mean
in its clip okay is two eyes I mean there's really nothing to put there but
there's really nothing to put there but the so fundamentally traced
the so fundamentally traced any distribution satisfies this
any distribution satisfies this condition in the Paris relation supplied
condition in the Paris relation supplied by completely graph theoretic arguments
by completely graph theoretic arguments has to be authorized in as the product
has to be authorized in as the product of potentials is potential the point
of potentials is potential the point over much public okay so that's the
over much public okay so that's the hammer strictly for theorem
all right and and I mean this is basically another version of the same
basically another version of the same theorem says if you learn is the common
theorem says if you learn is the common of distributions the populace is like
of distributions the populace is like this and if you tour is the family of
this and if you tour is the family of distributions or satisfies also
distributions or satisfies also conditional independence relations than
conditional independence relations than you are equal to get to okay so you sit
you are equal to get to okay so you sit down and you write other personal
down and you write other personal distributions that account for all of
distributions that account for all of independence relations applied by this
independence relations applied by this undirected graph and then you take all
undirected graph and then you take all distributions of the fertilizer in a gap
distributions of the fertilizer in a gap then the two things are of the strength
may be fabulous you do an example okay and tell you in which form these
and tell you in which form these potentials are coming is an
potentials are coming is an improvisation so consider that this have
improvisation so consider that this have arranged for example in in this building
arranged for example in in this building right and it's over no it's the variable
right and it's over no it's the variable that measures that say if the
that measures that say if the temperature if it is original colt all
temperature if it is original colt all right the heating system is on or off so
right the heating system is on or off so we felt that this valuable exercise here
we felt that this valuable exercise here is a binary plus one minus one just to
is a binary plus one minus one just to make life busy obviously this one is
make life busy obviously this one is called light you expect when you're
called light you expect when you're going to be called right because they
going to be called right because they communicate through the world so there
communicate through the world so there is a correlation and that correlation
is a correlation and that correlation sort of would try to capture it with the
sort of would try to capture it with the potential that is the kind of the click
potential that is the kind of the click at higher next child and I am sure if
at higher next child and I am sure if you know in your elementary cautious
you know in your elementary cautious when you play with this type of mobiles
when you play with this type of mobiles you will say I'm going to take nearest
you will say I'm going to take nearest neighbors for interactions you know so
neighbors for interactions you know so in this graph
in this graph obviously what's the size of the biggest
obviously what's the size of the biggest clinics from this graph the way that you
clinics from this graph the way that you state
state is it what is the size of historic store
and the reason again is not know this because remember a take is you know a
because remember a take is you know a maximal clique is every knowledge has to
maximal clique is every knowledge has to be interconnected it cannot be caught
be interconnected it cannot be caught because this node and that node are not
because this node and that node are not connected so what's the matter sighs is
connected so what's the matter sighs is it great it's - okay so it's do so well
it great it's - okay so it's do so well then I have to work here with potentials
then I have to work here with potentials but involve basically two tables that
but involve basically two tables that there are sort of neighbors okay the
there are sort of neighbors okay the joint probability distribution and I
joint probability distribution and I will introduce some parameters you know
will introduce some parameters you know is let's say whatever parameters
is let's say whatever parameters defining the potential are unknown in
defining the potential are unknown in general all right but I'm going to write
general all right but I'm going to write this as a product of potentials and
this as a product of potentials and remember the potentials need to be
remember the potentials need to be positive because when you put them
positive because when you put them together you need to give the
together you need to give the probability distribution and an easy way
probability distribution and an easy way to make them positive is to write them
to make them positive is to write them as e to some power okay this is sort of
as e to some power okay this is sort of a very typical of disposable type of
a very typical of disposable type of distribution so here I am writing its
distribution so here I am writing its potential as e to the PI J that connects
potential as e to the PI J that connects nodes X I and X J so my potential is
nodes X I and X J so my potential is really not the price today is to e to
really not the price today is to e to the theta equal to PI J some function
the theta equal to PI J some function because that way the function can be
because that way the function can be positive or negative but e to the T PI J
positive or negative but e to the T PI J will always be positive
will always be positive I'm just very formulating basically so I
I'm just very formulating basically so I don't have to worry about something
don't have to worry about something being negative okay another advantage is
being negative okay another advantage is if you write this as product of this
if you write this as product of this exponential function when you might have
exponential function when you might have to put them together you know based on
to put them together you know based on that here we discussed before if you're
that here we discussed before if you're going to get e to the sum of the theta J
going to get e to the sum of the theta J is defined over all the edges of the
is defined over all the edges of the graph
okay all right and this is a normalization factor which means this
normalization factor which means this into the summation of this you're going
into the summation of this you're going to have to sample all possible values of
to have to sample all possible values of x our next area all right and after this
x our next area all right and after this and hopefully you may have to do it by
and hopefully you may have to do it by market show because this step is where
market show because this step is where all the physics is coming so if you want
all the physics is coming so if you want to do statistical mechanics or compute
to do statistical mechanics or compute interesting properties you mean
interesting properties you mean everything has to go through this
everything has to go through this normalization factor but sort of
normalization factor but sort of responds well to free energy for the
responds well to free energy for the system okay and you notice it's
system okay and you notice it's complicated because estimation of the
complicated because estimation of the estimation alright so how exactly do
estimation alright so how exactly do this is to be seen all right so this is
this is to be seen all right so this is a bunch maleic distribution okay and
a bunch maleic distribution okay and there's nothing here
now sir the previous example we started with the dolphin will bounty the
with the dolphin will bounty the authorization of the distribution over
authorization of the distribution over the ground now suppose we go all the way
the ground now suppose we go all the way around and somebody gives you a
around and somebody gives you a factorization defining over the sets of
factorization defining over the sets of know how do you specify an undirected
know how do you specify an undirected graph basically that the based work
graph basically that the based work authorization the other problem is so
authorization the other problem is so they might but be effects is some
they might but be effects is some function of X 1 X 2 X 5 times the
function of X 1 X 2 X 5 times the function of X 4 X 3 and X 25 how do you
function of X 4 X 3 and X 25 how do you make it go well the idea is very simple
make it go well the idea is very simple right this they have to be now is
right this they have to be now is corresponding to maximal cliques so what
corresponding to maximal cliques so what you need to do is you need to take all
you need to do is you need to take all the nodes to find Cyrus pretentious and
the nodes to find Cyrus pretentious and collector and when you're finished
collector and when you're finished that's basically your undirected graph
that's basically your undirected graph ok there is no other way around because
ok there is no other way around because that's the only way that will allow you
that's the only way that will allow you to have a factorization that basically
to have a factorization that basically looks in this ball
all right
so the this comes to be because because just to do with the independent
just to do with the independent relations but I didn't have to tell you
relations but I didn't have to tell you much about the biggest well Algar it
much about the biggest well Algar it right because if you want to share that
right because if you want to share that X 1 and X is to depend of X 5 given X 2
X 1 and X is to depend of X 5 given X 2 and and explore the only thing you have
and and explore the only thing you have to do is take a path from 1 to 5 and it
to do is take a path from 1 to 5 and it has to go through 2 &amp; 4 then the path is
has to go through 2 &amp; 4 then the path is blocked
blocked alright so you can use purely basically
alright so you can use purely basically reachability conditions if you can use
reachability conditions if you can use its with a set of nodes the one set of
its with a set of nodes the one set of nodes and other set by bypassing the
nodes and other set by bypassing the evidence then basically the condition
evidence then basically the condition independence relation will not be born
independence relation will not be born okay
so what's the name of this prevention table plate so you know because we have
table plate so you know because we have their condition distributions now you
their condition distributions now you know if I write this is the same example
know if I write this is the same example that we had before if I write this in
that we had before if I write this in terms of potentials these potentials of
terms of potentials these potentials of two nodes two variables two variables
two nodes two variables two variables two then three this are not
two then three this are not probabilities okay and they express
probabilities okay and they express correlations between variables so
correlations between variables so example you see the anthem let's like
example you see the anthem let's like this are discrete variables can you see
this are discrete variables can you see an element there that is very small
an element there that is very small means the particular set of variables
means the particular set of variables are not correlated with each other but
are not correlated with each other but many P potentially it's something
many P potentially it's something computationally we need to worry because
computationally we need to worry because this factors are not normalized you may
this factors are not normalized you may have a problem when you do computation
have a problem when you do computation and influence that share parameters
and influence that share parameters because maybe this potential here is way
because maybe this potential here is way at much higher values than that
at much higher values than that potential there that doesn't imply that
potential there that doesn't imply that the value were sexual X still basically
the value were sexual X still basically dominate the distribution simply this
dominate the distribution simply this happens because you have a normalize it
happens because you have a normalize it so you need to be careful when you do
so you need to be careful when you do inference because this terms may be
inference because this terms may be completely honest in the calculation
completely honest in the calculation because they are not probabilities okay
because they are not probabilities okay in some sense this can be a problem you
in some sense this can be a problem you know depending what the task is from all
know depending what the task is from all locations you may want to take advantage
locations you may want to take advantage of that
all right so the the most famous problem that fits in this concept of undirected
that fits in this concept of undirected graphical models is the Ising model for
graphical models is the Ising model for those who have taking elementary courses
those who have taking elementary courses in physics this is University model
in physics this is University model where the matter was raised she got a
where the matter was raised she got a plus minus 1 so this your typical run
plus minus 1 so this your typical run with this problem but actually as
with this problem but actually as trivial as this problem looks like right
trivial as this problem looks like right is also one of the most difficult
is also one of the most difficult problems to do especially in two and
problems to do especially in two and three dimensions anybody that thinks
three dimensions anybody that thinks this chapter a problem you know the I
this chapter a problem you know the I textbooks basically written of hundreds
textbooks basically written of hundreds of pages that are discuss about this
of pages that are discuss about this problem and it is
problem and it is Shanta file a good test case for
Shanta file a good test case for checking relationship actually they wore
checking relationship actually they wore okay
okay and so let's discuss it because she has
and so let's discuss it because she has to do a lot with statistical mechanics
to do a lot with statistical mechanics this is in one big experiment can be
this is in one big experiment can be plus minus one and when you need to
plus minus one and when you need to capture of the Ising model is you need
capture of the Ising model is you need to capture sort of correlations between
to capture sort of correlations between neighbors so if this is plus one you
neighbors so if this is plus one you know in thesis you say spin up for
know in thesis you say spin up for example in quantum mechanics so if this
example in quantum mechanics so if this is plus one then the neighbors tend to
is plus one then the neighbors tend to be plus one so the corresponding body is
be plus one so the corresponding body is that of the potential forgetting at
that of the potential forgetting at least plus one the sky of chance of
least plus one the sky of chance of getting this plus one in higher transfer
getting this plus one in higher transfer yelling this plus one and this table
yelling this plus one and this table step also look to represent that not in
step also look to represent that not in the context of probabilities but
the context of probabilities but certainly in the context you know you
certainly in the context you know you know in the context of
you know the potential so you can see here for example if this is minus one
here for example if this is minus one the probability of xn minus 1 B minus 1
the probability of xn minus 1 B minus 1 I mean so the probability is no divide
I mean so the probability is no divide of the prevention is much higher than
of the prevention is much higher than the probability of done the value of
the probability of done the value of excitements ought to be point two okay
excitements ought to be point two okay again I have to correct myself there's a
again I have to correct myself there's a lot probabilities then you notice they
lot probabilities then you notice they don't sum up basically in any direction
don't sum up basically in any direction you see them if you want so if you write
you see them if you want so if you write this joint distribution as the product
this joint distribution as the product of potential functions of the form e to
of potential functions of the form e to the minus Tate ok this product will lead
the minus Tate ok this product will lead to estimation of the potential and this
to estimation of the potential and this is basically your Hamiltonian for the
is basically your Hamiltonian for the system this is the energy of the system
system this is the energy of the system which is the summation of the energy
which is the summation of the energy storage click so in lots of problems in
storage click so in lots of problems in in in undirected graphical models not
in in undirected graphical models not just in the Ising model but all of them
just in the Ising model but all of them actually starting with potentials you
actually starting with potentials you know what to start this with an energy
know what to start this with an energy function and then e to the minus knob
function and then e to the minus knob basically will give you the potential
basically will give you the potential all right so much times you will see
all right so much times you will see people pasta mating directly the energy
people pasta mating directly the energy over clicked all right and the
over clicked all right and the corresponding distribution would be a
corresponding distribution would be a Boltzmann distribution reduce
Boltzmann distribution reduce distribution e to the minus 8 okay and
distribution e to the minus 8 okay and if you want to make it party you can
if you want to make it party you can introduce temperature effects of things
introduce temperature effects of things like that but of no interest right now
okay so this discuss was the Boltzmann distribution all right
distribution all right what's the matter fluently remind me
what's the matter fluently remind me what a Markov blanket in general for a
what a Markov blanket in general for a dialectic lab for example what was the
dialectic lab for example what was the definition
so it was the parents and the comparison the idea was given the market basically
the idea was given the market basically the notes independent of anything else
the notes independent of anything else in the graph alright so in in undirected
in the graph alright so in in undirected graphs if you want to think what the
graphs if you want to think what the Markov blanket is it is extremely
Markov blanket is it is extremely trivial because the Markov blanket is
trivial because the Markov blanket is really the neighbors of the node because
really the neighbors of the node because if you given the neighbors there's no
if you given the neighbors there's no way to go anywhere else because all
way to go anywhere else because all paths will be blocked okay so the Markov
paths will be blocked okay so the Markov blanket for an undirected graph is the
blanket for an undirected graph is the the neighbors of the nodes
okay
so you know when we were discussing about the record graphs we post some
about the record graphs we post some sort of trivial inference problem so if
sort of trivial inference problem so if you want for example so you have a
you want for example so you have a matching notes here by the tray this is
matching notes here by the tray this is the problem with X being hot or cold you
the problem with X being hot or cold you know different rooms and of course and
know different rooms and of course and these are the temperatures in in its
these are the temperatures in in its room if you want to find given some
room if you want to find given some evidence you won't find this conditional
evidence you won't find this conditional distribution where the rest of the
distribution where the rest of the volume of sixes are eliminated basically
volume of sixes are eliminated basically what you need to do is this you can
what you need to do is this you can write the numerator like that and the
write the numerator like that and the denominator of this thing stuff over a
denominator of this thing stuff over a possible bunch of XJ but in this case
possible bunch of XJ but in this case take values minus 1 and 1 and the way
take values minus 1 and 1 and the way you handle evidence is sort of identical
you handle evidence is sort of identical with a way you handle evident in the
with a way you handle evident in the directed graph so you can you know so on
directed graph so you can you know so on the denominator here you have the joint
the denominator here you have the joint of XJ with the evidence of type J
of XJ with the evidence of type J successively if this expression is
successively if this expression is written correctly this is the summation
written correctly this is the summation of over X bar the most accept XK but now
of over X bar the most accept XK but now this usually multiplied by the Joint
this usually multiplied by the Joint Distribution with the evidence functions
Distribution with the evidence functions to cross the bottom of society next day
to cross the bottom of society next day to take this fat body
to take this fat body okay so there's nothing again different
okay so there's nothing again different from before the only difference is that
from before the only difference is that this wrist briefly in terms of this
this wrist briefly in terms of this potentials 11 conditional distribution
potentials 11 conditional distribution so the algebra is basically sort of
so the algebra is basically sort of identical
all right how do we cannot stop now you know we did lots of things about
you know we did lots of things about directed graphs if you don't want to
directed graphs if you don't want to work with directed graphs how do you
work with directed graphs how do you respond to undirected graphs so let's
respond to undirected graphs so let's look at the let's look at the joint
look at the let's look at the joint probability distribution so x1 x2 x3
probability distribution so x1 x2 x3 have no product next right history part
have no product next right history part so we get something I got alright so
so we get something I got alright so that is based on on this and thinking
that is based on on this and thinking what the undirected graph is going to
what the undirected graph is going to look like what is the maximum clique
look like what is the maximum clique that I need to have in the problem to
that I need to have in the problem to represent correctly that the
represent correctly that the characterization what should i what is
characterization what should i what is the maximum click on it you have to
the maximum click on it you have to represent it
but this has X 1 X 2 X 3 X 4
right because export depends on X products to explain so like a return
products to explain so like a return here that involves basically variables
here that involves basically variables so what is the maximum clique that I
so what is the maximum clique that I expect to send the equivalent undirected
expect to send the equivalent undirected graph for but how can you get four from
graph for but how can you get four from this graph the only you can way you can
this graph the only you can way you can get Cortez moralization all right so
get Cortez moralization all right so basically you have to marry this balance
basically you have to marry this balance you have to marry response they have to
you have to marry response they have to marry this product and this basically
marry this product and this basically will give you a clique that is the
will give you a clique that is the maximum clique that reporter for so
maximum clique that reporter for so actually in this particular case right I
actually in this particular case right I can write this is only one potential
can write this is only one potential because really there's only one maximum
because really there's only one maximum clique that involves four four notes I
clique that involves four four notes I can write business try one of X 1 X 2 X
can write business try one of X 1 X 2 X 3 X 4 okay
3 X 4 okay the including strength if you try to
the including strength if you try to write the total prob in with more of the
write the total prob in with more of the terms it's mention right so you will get
terms it's mention right so you will get some results but in reality you will
some results but in reality you will never be able to exactly model a
never be able to exactly model a distribution of a crisis this way the
distribution of a crisis this way the only way you can do this is by having a
only way you can do this is by having a maximal clique that has all four nodes
maximal clique that has all four nodes and this much motley can only be of they
and this much motley can only be of they if you moralized the dialectic block
if you moralized the dialectic block okay I think I'm going to go back to
okay I think I'm going to go back to show you some cases of directed graphs
show you some cases of directed graphs but there is no way you can come up with
but there is no way you can come up with an equivalent undirected graph but right
an equivalent undirected graph but right now for this problem you just paralyze
now for this problem you just paralyze the parent and Verity okay so so here's
the parent and Verity okay so so here's another example if you have this
another example if you have this directed graph
PF next one has the balance the effects the given x1 x 4p f x3 has no parent and
the given x1 x 4p f x3 has no parent and then explore given x2 and x3 okay so so
then explore given x2 and x3 okay so so you notice here you have my numbers 2 3
you notice here you have my numbers 2 3 &amp; 4
and obviously to get 2 3 &amp; 4 you have to moralize you have to marry the parents 2
moralize you have to marry the parents 2 &amp; 3 and this is the line here potential
&amp; 3 and this is the line here potential notice because if I say I'm going to
notice because if I say I'm going to have a potential 2 3 &amp; 4
have a potential 2 3 &amp; 4 in that potential I can take actually
in that potential I can take actually this probability of Experion make it
this probability of Experion make it popular prevent itself alright so if you
popular prevent itself alright so if you want to go from the left to the right I
want to go from the left to the right I can combine P of X 3 with the
can combine P of X 3 with the probability of X 4 X 2 8 3 and define
probability of X 4 X 2 8 3 and define this potential and again because X 1 and
this potential and again because X 1 and X 2 is a clique of two nodes I can put
X 2 is a clique of two nodes I can put these things together as another
these things together as another potential so I want to of X 1 and X 2 so
potential so I want to of X 1 and X 2 so again you have potential to note and
again you have potential to note and another potential with three nodes and
another potential with three nodes and this problem before now belongs to non
this problem before now belongs to non potential and another is that any issue
I mean obviously you expect I mean if you think if this clicks are coming from
you think if this clicks are coming from the wave behind were supported late and
the wave behind were supported late and we take a bunch of them here and the
we take a bunch of them here and the boss of them
boss of them neighbors obviously they're going to be
neighbors obviously they're going to be staring some know if they don't say
staring some know if they don't say basically there is no point of doing a
basically there is no point of doing a methodology because the problem becomes
methodology because the problem becomes trivial so the fact that there is no
trivial so the fact that there is no trick here is not an issue you know this
trick here is not an issue you know this is typical in this sort of problems so
is typical in this sort of problems so let's look actually again for converting
let's look actually again for converting a directly to an undirected graph so
a directly to an undirected graph so what I have seven nodes this is the
what I have seven nodes this is the factorization for the directed graph and
factorization for the directed graph and what I have done is this conditional
what I have done is this conditional distributions I have written down as a
distributions I have written down as a product of joint distributions divided
product of joint distributions divided by marginals and if you look carefully
by marginals and if you look carefully of this expressions you will see that on
of this expressions you will see that on the numerator I have products of all
the numerator I have products of all right divide each of the progress of
right divide each of the progress of click intersections you see here there
click intersections you see here there is x1 x3 all right
is x1 x3 all right extract 3 so this play is basically the
extract 3 so this play is basically the intersection of the two clicks of course
intersection of the two clicks of course tallest tree in quadrants another
tallest tree in quadrants another intersection there and similarly for the
intersection there and similarly for the clicks 4 5 4 6 4 7
clicks 4 5 4 6 4 7 right you have these intersections later
right you have these intersections later when we develop everybody's basically
when we develop everybody's basically for influence on general graphs we will
for influence on general graphs we will try to take advantage on how these
try to take advantage on how these cliques communicate with each other so
cliques communicate with each other so this is sort of this idea will be
this is sort of this idea will be extended all right so this the trivial
extended all right so this the trivial example I don't think it's a Markov
example I don't think it's a Markov chain basically so you know again I
chain basically so you know again I combine this to on potential and each of
combine this to on potential and each of the other conditional distributions two
the other conditional distributions two other potentials occasional nothing
other potentials occasional nothing fancy so here you can remove all the
fancy so here you can remove all the arrows and make basically this graph to
arrows and make basically this graph to have the same identical independence
have the same identical independence relations as to direct graph that you
relations as to direct graph that you see on the top so what I have here is I
see on the top so what I have here is I have another direct III and direct III
have another direct III and direct III and the pol III okay and so can you
and the pol III okay and so can you remind me what's the definition of an
remind me what's the definition of an undirected three obviously some directed
undirected three obviously some directed what makes an undirected graph a three
it says the average a single path between any pair of nodes the way from
between any pair of nodes the way from here to there this is the only path to
here to there this is the only path to go from here to there there's only one
go from here to there there's only one path okay which is two three
so in audacity there is a red node let's say this knob here and every other
say this knob here and every other noxious how many parts only Ron
noxious how many parts only Ron so what's the relation of a directed
so what's the relation of a directed three you think around the elected three
three you think around the elected three you remember that - because home right a
you remember that - because home right a directive 3 - on directory we have to do
directive 3 - on directory we have to do first what process ionization so
first what process ionization so intensified demonization in the
intensified demonization in the directory nothing happened
directory nothing happened ok so basically because there's no
ok so basically because there's no mobilization has happened but in 3 a
mobilization has happened but in 3 a purity is like a directory but nodes can
purity is like a directory but nodes can have more than one power so what will
have more than one power so what will happen when I transform a 23 to an
happen when I transform a 23 to an undirected 3
so for example to make this around I left it well if I can make it this
left it well if I can make it this another mr. Pony three rights if I
another mr. Pony three rights if I wanted to make it an undirected graph
wanted to make it an undirected graph what is gonna happen here you will
what is gonna happen here you will connect the parents and if you connect
connect the parents and if you connect the power is what is going to happen is
the power is what is going to happen is that becoming a is not a tree no sir you
that becoming a is not a tree no sir you know that to be public because
know that to be public because influences we will see in twist is very
influences we will see in twist is very easy all right
easy all right we spend on lecture two so if you if the
we spend on lecture two so if you if the problem is a directed three PC you can
problem is a directed three PC you can transform it to a non directed tree and
transform it to a non directed tree and do everything extremely particularly
do everything extremely particularly disappointed tree if you can because you
disappointed tree if you can because you wanna lies you get loops a lot is a
wanna lies you get loops a lot is a problem and there is a way to get a
problem and there is a way to get a harvest if you actually transform the
harvest if you actually transform the poetry not to an undirected graph but
poetry not to an undirected graph but this dr. graph which is another type of
this dr. graph which is another type of graph that you know if we have a few
graph that you know if we have a few minutes I'm going to show you how it
minutes I'm going to show you how it looks like okay
looks like okay [Applause]
the reason you want to make direct loft you don't have to say okay let me select
you don't have to say okay let me select this to be there with no and start
this to be there with no and start pointing arrows away from there you know
pointing arrows away from there you know so we go this way and this this way and
so we go this way and this this way and then that way in that way but you can
then that way in that way but you can start reading note so you can produce
start reading note so you can produce actually and directed graphs but they're
actually and directed graphs but they're not necessarily equivalent okay I do see
not necessarily equivalent okay I do see no reason why anybody will be interested
no reason why anybody will be interested to transform an undirected graph to a
to transform an undirected graph to a directed graph alright unless of course
directed graph alright unless of course you are trying to learn the causal
you are trying to learn the causal relationship model and given data there
relationship model and given data there I can see a region in that case the
I can see a region in that case the problem will become a golf selection
problem will become a golf selection problem because you'll be asking which
problem because you'll be asking which of these graphs better represents the
of these graphs better represents the data that I collected and that's an
data that I collected and that's an interesting problem all right
okay so let me three minutes let me do a very simple for the problem every
very simple for the problem every textbook in machine lambda graphical
textbook in machine lambda graphical varnish has this problem and this is a
varnish has this problem and this is a problem related to image the noising so
problem related to image the noising so you can think exile presenting pixel
you can think exile presenting pixel values so that can be black or white
values so that can be black or white let's say bye honey
let's say bye honey okay and of any mods and why I are what
okay and of any mods and why I are what you measured which are noisy versions of
you measured which are noisy versions of Exile right so you have an English but
Exile right so you have an English but you only have some noisy version of it
you only have some noisy version of it that is represented by Y okay obviously
that is represented by Y okay obviously you know if you have an image
you know if you have an image if exercise we expect the neighbors to
if exercise we expect the neighbors to be black right so the clicks of the
be black right so the clicks of the Express sort of this sort of
Express sort of this sort of correlations would be the click that you
correlations would be the click that you see here okay
see here okay and obviously X Y and y I are correlated
and obviously X Y and y I are correlated because I envision what I to be a noisy
because I envision what I to be a noisy version of X are so if you want to add
version of X are so if you want to add the Joint Distribution of X I X &amp; Y or
the Joint Distribution of X I X &amp; Y or form the X pictures and why pictures
form the X pictures and why pictures from this image basically you have a
from this image basically you have a product of potentials that account for
product of potentials that account for the correlations of X i NX j alright and
the correlations of X i NX j alright and for potential define over the clicks x i
for potential define over the clicks x i and y which are this potential solution
and y which are this potential solution here all right
again is to play the spoilers rather than or anything this potential
than or anything this potential exclusively is to find them because them
exclusively is to find them because them down in terms of the energy of the
down in terms of the energy of the system and you remember that and
system and you remember that and symptoms are eight to the minus the
symptoms are eight to the minus the energy so the energy here it will be
energy so the energy here it will be defined by this little correlation on
defined by this little correlation on that I indicated before between X I and
that I indicated before between X I and X a and X I and Y I so those are the two
X a and X I and Y I so those are the two terms defined over the two cliques but
terms defined over the two cliques but they shall not astronomy term that
they shall not astronomy term that involves summation for the extra light
involves summation for the extra light okay and usually in physics right the
okay and usually in physics right the term is used to you know pixels in the
term is used to you know pixels in the model like or the concentration or
model like or the concentration or something like that is you sort of
something like that is you sort of characterizing reason all right you can
characterizing reason all right you can think of those X sorry one is not the
think of those X sorry one is not the maximal clique right but you can think
maximal clique right but you can think it's known as a sub click so if you
it's known as a sub click so if you throw an extra tab down okay somebody
throw an extra tab down okay somebody can pose the problem using the data wire
can pose the problem using the data wire to run computers parameters but right
to run computers parameters but right now let's say you fix them and you don't
now let's say you fix them and you don't you don't worry about J its neighbor and
you don't worry about J its neighbor and X I and why they relate together so I am
X I and why they relate together so I am NOT saying that X I is related to that
NOT saying that X I is related to that but if you try to write the conditional
but if you try to write the conditional distribution and you say if I can
distribution and you say if I can observe the whole image the noisy
observe the whole image the noisy version why can i compute X what X is
version why can i compute X what X is notice that all the x's are coupled with
notice that all the x's are coupled with the XS a couple with otherwise in both
the XS a couple with otherwise in both potential terms
potential terms all right so when we fight like this
all right so when we fight like this conditional you know this potential for
conditional you know this potential for water-wise right and this makes the
water-wise right and this makes the problem a little bit tricky on the way
problem a little bit tricky on the way we are going to implement oho me so to
we are going to implement oho me so to the trivial on bereavement to do this in
the trivial on bereavement to do this in red light so let's say that can we make
red light so let's say that can we make this a homework absolutely
this a homework absolutely all right just make this a home more
all right just make this a home more because it's his red light I mean this I
because it's his red light I mean this I have to motivate Subic to write the
have to motivate Subic to write the right homework or so you keep now it's
right homework or so you keep now it's coming of those become hot ones
coming of those become hot ones ok so here we are this is the original
ok so here we are this is the original image and user notice is very clean and
image and user notice is very clean and let's say you take the original image
let's say you take the original image and you perturb you know from black to
and you perturb you know from black to white white black 10% of the pixel
white white black 10% of the pixel services image and so that's what you
services image and so that's what you know so when you do this right you're
know so when you do this right you're asking you know if you want to complete
asking you know if you want to complete with save this you say so you have X
with save this you say so you have X given Y you want to find the x that
given Y you want to find the x that maximize is that posterior of X given Y
maximize is that posterior of X given Y so what you do is much smaller so the
so what you do is much smaller so the probability is the same has been amazing
probability is the same has been amazing the energy of the system so when you
the energy of the system so when you take a picture you can just back you
take a picture you can just back you complete the energy you share K now let
complete the energy you share K now let me make it wide because the energy goes
me make it wide because the energy goes now if it goes down then you keep it
now if it goes down then you keep it wide and the reversal loops through the
wide and the reversal loops through the pixels right by the director bring them
pixels right by the director bring them up and down alright until you reach the
up and down alright until you reach the minimum energy you can do this
minimum energy you can do this no we