all right 12:31 I thought 50 and some risking but look thought I think we are
risking but look thought I think we are maybe 10 20 slides residuals from
maybe 10 20 slides residuals from lecture 3 because I'm going to try to
lecture 3 because I'm going to try to cover them sort of part just the
cover them sort of part just the concepts there's nothing really
concepts there's nothing really substantial there and and hopefully in
substantial there and and hopefully in the majority of the lecture today I want
the majority of the lecture today I want to go through some examples of
to go through some examples of parametrized conditional distributions
parametrized conditional distributions right we said the this directed graphs
right we said the this directed graphs are defined with local conditional
are defined with local conditional probability so we need to see how we
probability so we need to see how we parameterize host and then I'll give you
parameterize host and then I'll give you an example a little bit ahead of the
an example a little bit ahead of the schedule here an example of how you
schedule here an example of how you compute the parameters on those
compute the parameters on those conditional distributions given some
conditional distributions given some data the other part I don't think we're
data the other part I don't think we're going to be able to reach it today
going to be able to reach it today it's basically an example so I even will
it's basically an example so I even will cover it on the next use the oral wait
cover it on the next use the oral wait until maybe a month or two down the road
so reminder we have seen three independent relationships for directed
independent relationships for directed graphs basically the most powerful was
graphs basically the most powerful was this constant of this separation based
this constant of this separation based on this biggest ball algorithm or at
on this biggest ball algorithm or at least the biggest bone structure rules
in essence the Talgo a to operate for both directed and undirected graphs for
both directed and undirected graphs for direct blocks we said we have to pay
direct blocks we said we have to pay attention to these B structures the
attention to these B structures the explaining away we have seen this
explaining away we have seen this directed local Markov property and
directed local Markov property and edenal descendants this is the
edenal descendants this is the predecessors and without really any
predecessors and without really any rigorous proof we basically said these
rigorous proof we basically said these relationships are equivalent to each
relationships are equivalent to each other right if you start with one you
other right if you start with one you can solve the rest and all of them are
can solve the rest and all of them are actually equivalent to a factorization
actually equivalent to a factorization of the Joint Distribution in in over the
of the Joint Distribution in in over the graph that takes this point okay so in
graph that takes this point okay so in in if you remember with this some
in if you remember with this some examples what we started with the
examples what we started with the factorization like this and then we
factorization like this and then we proved this village you remember by
proved this village you remember by doing marginalization and all of these
doing marginalization and all of these things the lefty way the idea now is
things the lefty way the idea now is when I'm going to start with this and
when I'm going to start with this and try to prove this you know if this not
try to prove this you know if this not established from the graph then this
established from the graph then this follows and this is what we need okay
follows and this is what we need okay all right
all right so just if you think that sort of you
so just if you think that sort of you have to type of distribution or family
have to type of distribution or family of distributions one the family of
of distributions one the family of distributions that factorizes this way
distributions that factorizes this way over the graph and then another family
over the graph and then another family of distributions to satisfies all the
of distributions to satisfies all the independence relations defined by the
independence relations defined by the graph then basically theorem which is
graph then basically theorem which is more or less we highlighted says that
more or less we highlighted says that this two distribution formulas are the
this two distribution formulas are the same okay so the distributions the
same okay so the distributions the SUBSCRIBE independence relations the
SUBSCRIBE independence relations the conditional independence relations
conditional independence relations applied by the graph or the
applied by the graph or the distributions of a price of like this
distributions of a price of like this they are basically the two distributions
they are basically the two distributions all the same okay again I'm not gonna be
all the same okay again I'm not gonna be repeating things we have discussed so
repeating things we have discussed so let me bring some definition I don't
let me bring some definition I don't think we will make enormous use but it
think we will make enormous use but it is something you may come across in the
is something you may come across in the literature so this definition of what is
literature so this definition of what is called the re equivalent I standing from
called the re equivalent I standing from independence so I of Z for a given graph
independence so I of Z for a given graph G is the set of all the conditional
G is the set of all the conditional independence statements and called it by
independence statements and called it by the graph what's the definition so for
the graph what's the definition so for example in the previous case let's say
example in the previous case let's say if this were all the relations for this
if this were all the relations for this graph then you know I of G R of this
graph then you know I of G R of this relation okay so it's to set or for
relation okay so it's to set or for conditioning in the present statement
conditioning in the present statement and coded by the graph and two blocks we
and coded by the graph and two blocks we call them I equivalent if I of G 1 is
call them I equivalent if I of G 1 is equal to I of G 2 and you can show if G
equal to I of G 2 and you can show if G 1 and G 2 have the same undirected
1 and G 2 have the same undirected skeleton and the same set of be
skeleton and the same set of be structures there I equivalent okay so
structures there I equivalent okay so they have the same independence
they have the same independence relations I am only going to process
relations I am only going to process these things that I marked here with red
these things that I marked here with red wine and
very important for directed glass it says we can only identify graph
says we can only identify graph structures are equivalent so basically
structures are equivalent so basically if you try to identify I would say the
if you try to identify I would say the directions are closed is it to the left
directions are closed is it to the left or to the right you do not be able to do
or to the right you do not be able to do that okay
that okay and in many ways not to limitation
and in many ways not to limitation basically of the directed glass but then
basically of the directed glass but then there are properties of directly graphs
there are properties of directly graphs that undirected graphs don't have but
that undirected graphs don't have but remember this all right you cannot
remember this all right you cannot identify the structure of directed graph
identify the structure of directed graph join this I equivalent okay and here's
join this I equivalent okay and here's another important definition let's say
another important definition let's say we have a distribution P okay and let's
we have a distribution P okay and let's define IFP to be the set of independent
define IFP to be the set of independent of the condition independent statements
of the condition independent statements implied by the distribution P right
implied by the distribution P right nobody situation right not just the
nobody situation right not just the distribution P so the story Sultan
distribution P so the story Sultan conditional independent statements we
conditional independent statements we call those I of P now for a given graph
call those I of P now for a given graph G if the I of G is a subset of I of P
G if the I of G is a subset of I of P then we call I agree to be an I map of
then we call I agree to be an I map of the distribution P so in some sense this
the distribution P so in some sense this is the bass work here we can use the
is the bass work here we can use the graph G as a proxy for the distribution
graph G as a proxy for the distribution P now what you need to keep in mind here
P now what you need to keep in mind here is that the distribution P may satisfy
is that the distribution P may satisfy additional independent relationships not
additional independent relationships not implied by the ground but every
implied by the ground but every independent relation prime where the
independent relation prime where the graph is satisfied by the distribution P
graph is satisfied by the distribution P ok that's why the idea here is you can
ok that's why the idea here is you can use it as a safe proxy for pin actually
use it as a safe proxy for pin actually I'll show you somewhere I don't know
I'll show you somewhere I don't know what it is a little picture from
what it is a little picture from Bishop's book but effectively treat this
Bishop's book but effectively treat this G as a filter that allows through it
G as a filter that allows through it only the distributions be the satisfy
only the distributions be the satisfy the independence relations implied by
the independence relations implied by the graph okay so if you have a
the graph okay so if you have a distribution without
distribution without doesn't describe independence relations
doesn't describe independence relations of the graph so if this is not satisfied
of the graph so if this is not satisfied then it cannot go through the graph the
then it cannot go through the graph the faculty if you cannot use the graph tool
faculty if you cannot use the graph tool to represent fertilizer distribution so
to represent fertilizer distribution so take an example let's take the discrete
take an example let's take the discrete distribution defined selection of Y I
distribution defined selection of Y I take values 0 and 1 and let's give some
take values 0 and 1 and let's give some values of the joint probability of the
values of the joint probability of the effects and why I am NOT going to do the
effects and why I am NOT going to do the algebra you can it's right here assuming
algebra you can it's right here assuming the calculations are correct right but
the calculations are correct right but it comes up that you can show that V of
it comes up that you can show that V of X to the Y is equal to P of X P of Y so
X to the Y is equal to P of X P of Y so the x and y are marginally independent
the x and y are marginally independent all right so the chickens for this
all right so the chickens for this problem is the center don't involve sex
problem is the center don't involve sex independent of Y all right no graph here
independent of Y all right no graph here or anything like that right so we have
or anything like that right so we have this distribution and the only
this distribution and the only independence relation you can solve is
independence relation you can solve is is what you see here so high F P is the
is what you see here so high F P is the set that only includes X independent of
set that only includes X independent of Y now let's consider different graphs
Y now let's consider different graphs and let's see what is I of G for each of
and let's see what is I of G for each of these graphs how many independent
these graphs how many independent relations we have here on the left
this noise exists between x and y nothing so so what is the relation
nothing so so what is the relation between x and y independent y FG is
between x and y independent y FG is include this this type of include 20x
include this this type of include 20x independent Y in this case there is no
independent Y in this case there is no independence relation 0 and this list no
independence relation 0 and this list no offense relation is 0 so the agreement
offense relation is 0 so the agreement made that all paragraphs basically you
made that all paragraphs basically you know they are can be used the surrogates
know they are can be used the surrogates for the distribution P whenever a page
for the distribution P whenever a page has this property
all right now can I list some of these three graphs to represent the
three graphs to represent the distribution P this of course because it
distribution P this of course because it satisfies the time dependence relation
satisfies the time dependence relation this doesn't require any independence
this doesn't require any independence relation so any distribution will go
relation so any distribution will go through it the distribution people
through it the distribution people especially in additional independence
especially in additional independence relation but that's okay right
relation but that's okay right you will not violate anything in this
you will not violate anything in this graph because this graph gives zero
graph because this graph gives zero independence relations embedded okay the
independence relations embedded okay the same in this case so how can we open
same in this case so how can we open three graphs I 1 I 2 I 3 etc the I of G
three graphs I 1 I 2 I 3 etc the I of G is subset the Phi of P so there are I
is subset the Phi of P so there are I Maps basically of the distribution P
Maps basically of the distribution P alright and if you like a little
alright and if you like a little graphical justification of what I said
graphical justification of what I said before something that we put in red just
before something that we put in red just here but since you can only identify
here but since you can only identify graph tracks or apply equivalent alright
graph tracks or apply equivalent alright so here are our three starter gets
so here are our three starter gets basically three graphs all right
basically three graphs all right and there are you know I not of the
and there are you know I not of the distribution P ok because to blast them
distribution P ok because to blast them satisfy basically the underlying
satisfy basically the underlying independent relations with pikas
independent relations with pikas ok which is this one
this doesn't say anything so a parent basically says if this is really formal
basically says if this is really formal language because already we have paid
language because already we have paid leave is ten times if G is and I'm a
leave is ten times if G is and I'm a puppy then people priced according to G
puppy then people priced according to G okay and fertilized according to G
okay and fertilized according to G basically implies this authorization
basically implies this authorization that we have seen up to now and the
that we have seen up to now and the proof is sort of trivial because if you
proof is sort of trivial because if you take the distribution P and you arrange
take the distribution P and you arrange the nodes in topological order using
the nodes in topological order using sort of the product rules of probability
sort of the product rules of probability you can write it as you see on the first
you can write it as you see on the first line or always be sick here and then
line or always be sick here and then these previous notes will be basically
these previous notes will be basically the parent and the known descendants to
the parent and the known descendants to accept the pilot so Z is the non
accept the pilot so Z is the non descendants - the parent and I can write
descendants - the parent and I can write this probability equal to that Y because
this probability equal to that Y because G is an I'm up of P and there is the
G is an I'm up of P and there is the proof of the fear all right Z is an IMAP
proof of the fear all right Z is an IMAP of T ok
of T ok then P Papa Hodges according to C so
then P Papa Hodges according to C so basically the idea is if this satisfies
basically the idea is if this satisfies the independence relations implied by
the independence relations implied by the God then peak and fertilized on the
the God then peak and fertilized on the graph the way we have seen it which is
graph the way we have seen it which is this ok so again nothing extraordinary
this ok so again nothing extraordinary we have seen this ten times but the
we have seen this ten times but the first is total four it only requires
first is total four it only requires this property of conditional
this property of conditional independence implied by the graph Z and
independence implied by the graph Z and this is what I have used okay now if you
this is what I have used okay now if you weigh around and I think it may be
weigh around and I think it may be coming in a few slides I won't cover
coming in a few slides I won't cover that but if you want to start with
that but if you want to start with ition that but for a sizzler gratin you
ition that but for a sizzler gratin you want to prove independence relation such
want to prove independence relation such as based equal to that if you can
as based equal to that if you can actually do directly by similar to the
actually do directly by similar to the examples we developed three lectures
examples we developed three lectures okay so you can just talk about
okay so you can just talk about distribution compute this and then
distribution compute this and then Sullivan is equal to that all right this
Sullivan is equal to that all right this is just the example we discussed we have
is just the example we discussed we have seen this no need
seen this no need okay definition many definitions here
okay definition many definitions here nothing really amazing so with the
nothing really amazing so with the current ago being an IMAP for the
current ago being an IMAP for the distribution right so now I will define
distribution right so now I will define it to be a line and a graph is a minimal
it to be a line and a graph is a minimal IMAP well if the removal of even a
IMAP well if the removal of even a single edge from the graph when the
single edge from the graph when the street not a map of the distribution in
street not a map of the distribution in other ways there is not a step set of Z
other ways there is not a step set of Z such that Z prime is an IMAP of P okay
such that Z prime is an IMAP of P okay so that we call it the name a Lima
so that we call it the name a Lima alright and the last thing I want to
alright and the last thing I want to define is the Osher this is the graph of
define is the Osher this is the graph of was telling you with which is
was telling you with which is pictorially a nice way to think of this
pictorially a nice way to think of this I maps right so the discipline has a
I maps right so the discipline has a distribution to pass through all right
distribution to pass through all right when the distribution satisfies the
when the distribution satisfies the independence relations implied by the
independence relations implied by the graph but the distribution P can have
graph but the distribution P can have additional independence relations not
additional independence relations not implied by the graph right but whatever
implied by the graph right but whatever is implied by the graph has to be
is implied by the graph has to be satisfied by the distribution otherwise
satisfied by the distribution otherwise this doesn't pass through that's why you
this doesn't pass through that's why you know the concept here is you use this is
know the concept here is you use this is a distribution filter
a distribution filter well I tell me bring the last pair
well I tell me bring the last pair another complicated actually concept we
another complicated actually concept we will get with one very fundamental
will get with one very fundamental example so if somebody gives you a
example so if somebody gives you a distribution P of many variables can you
distribution P of many variables can you find the directed graph that has exactly
find the directed graph that has exactly the same independent relations condition
the same independent relations condition independent relations as the
independent relations as the distribution P the P is not possible you
distribution P the P is not possible you can write down some winner distribution
can write down some winner distribution with some conditional independence
with some conditional independence relation can you find a graph that is
relation can you find a graph that is basically a perfect map of the
basically a perfect map of the distribution this is what I call a
distribution this is what I call a perfect map
I mean you can can you appreciate that this type of is a little bit more
this type of is a little bit more difficult problem than before if one is
difficult problem than before if one is you make a graph and you say okay I know
you make a graph and you say okay I know what relations are satisfied
what relations are satisfied so I know which distributions which
so I know which distributions which let's find out now you were given a
let's find out now you were given a distribution P and you say can you find
distribution P and you say can you find me a graph that represents the
me a graph that represents the distribution precisely okay so the
distribution precisely okay so the answer is not every distribution has a
answer is not every distribution has a perfect map and a very fundamental
perfect map and a very fundamental example in the literature you will love
example in the literature you will love point many pages devoted actually to
point many pages devoted actually to this example is an example with four
this example is an example with four variables this is the an undirected
variables this is the an undirected version of the graph that satisfies the
version of the graph that satisfies the following relation using dependency
following relation using dependency given B and D and this independent of B
given B and D and this independent of B given a FC by the way that since the
given a FC by the way that since the biggest bottleneck in principle is
biggest bottleneck in principle is become interpolation algorithm in in
become interpolation algorithm in in undirected graphs you may want to
undirected graphs you may want to appreciate the path here but when they
appreciate the path here but when they are independent given a and T and a and
are independent given a and T and a and C are independent given D and B because
C are independent given D and B because in essence the let's say aliens here
in essence the let's say aliens here independent given T and B because the
independent given T and B because the path from A to C is blocked if you go
path from A to C is blocked if you go this way call it block if you move out
this way call it block if you move out way given D and B okay so the separation
way given D and B okay so the separation is really this separation the way we
is really this separation the way we have said in directed graphs but this
have said in directed graphs but this undirected graph satisfies this relation
undirected graph satisfies this relation okay this can you pass me that the
okay this can you pass me that the biggest one out which basically it
biggest one out which basically it doesn't care care about arrows or
doesn't care care about arrows or anything if the you know you give them B
anything if the you know you give them B then this path is blocked then this path
then this path is blocked then this path is blocked
is blocked okay if you're given a and T and you
okay if you're given a and T and you want to go to these the two paths are
want to go to these the two paths are also blocked so this have the relations
also blocked so this have the relations and so you're asking is can I find the
and so you're asking is can I find the directed graph that actually satisfies
directed graph that actually satisfies these two relations
these two relations and this and so here are two examples
and this and so here are two examples this examples have despite its two
this examples have despite its two relation what do you think
I mean you can you know and I would say this actually you spend maybe 10 minutes
this actually you spend maybe 10 minutes to prove if this to the lessons are
to prove if this to the lessons are satisfied by these graphs but just look
satisfied by these graphs but just look at it visually are this two graphs
at it visually are this two graphs basically having the same independent
basically having the same independent relation says this undirected graph so
relation says this undirected graph so it says here so let's say this graph
it says here so let's say this graph right which is being dependent on this
right which is being dependent on this graph what is the part of the biggest
graph what is the part of the biggest algorithm of Facebook based independent
algorithm of Facebook based independent of D with no conditioning nothing is
of D with no conditioning nothing is given right here right there's no
given right here right there's no evidence so that is no condition and the
evidence so that is no condition and the goal from B to D the only ways to go
goal from B to D the only ways to go through there and what is this is the
through there and what is this is the best marks right this is the explaining
best marks right this is the explaining away this time parents basically causes
away this time parents basically causes of the same the factory so basically
of the same the factory so basically since this is not even being their blog
since this is not even being their blog though they are independent okay
though they are independent okay so this relation has nothing to do with
so this relation has nothing to do with any of Austria's similarly BN one does
any of Austria's similarly BN one does not satisfy basically those two
not satisfy basically those two relations so bottom line
relations so bottom line not every distribution has a perfect
not every distribution has a perfect mark okay so don't expect to basically
mark okay so don't expect to basically have a distribution and then sprinkle
have a distribution and then sprinkle the graph that represents it usually you
the graph that represents it usually you start with a graph with some
start with a graph with some mathematical intuition and then you use
mathematical intuition and then you use the graph as a proxy for the
the graph as a proxy for the distributions you want to to work with
distributions you want to to work with it but the idea to do that is if you are
it but the idea to do that is if you are limiting yourself to the distributions
limiting yourself to the distributions of satisfies the properties of our graph
of satisfies the properties of our graph anything else basically
anything else basically working with it's not look like a
working with it's not look like a mathematical model and you are have to
mathematical model and you are have to obey the rules of that model and if the
obey the rules of that model and if the model is wrong you have problems all
model is wrong you have problems all right don't need was to basically
right don't need was to basically they're repeating project part so next
they're repeating project part so next time go to the limits for today
the lecture is not being posted didn't have time
they have time to have lots of drink my coffee so this is priority number six
coffee so this is priority number six okay so you'll be there by later today
so inferencing the office effectively means right but we are giving some
means right but we are giving some evidence and we have to estimate some
evidence and we have to estimate some unknown quantities which can be either
unknown quantities which can be either the student variables and and we do lots
the student variables and and we do lots of examples basically hidden variables
of examples basically hidden variables would be one for each data point but
would be one for each data point but also will be lots of static parameters
also will be lots of static parameters like the parameters in the conditional
like the parameters in the conditional distributions that we need just made so
distributions that we need just made so that's an interest problem okay for
that's an interest problem okay for example in hidden Markov models that we
example in hidden Markov models that we will spend maybe two lectures to to go
will spend maybe two lectures to to go through the details you just made the
through the details you just made the hidden states if you've given the
hidden states if you've given the technology observations okay in for
technology observations okay in for example in disease-causing I'm sorry in
example in disease-causing I'm sorry in in symmetrical applications for example
in symmetrical applications for example did you know the some symptoms that the
did you know the some symptoms that the patient has and you are asking what is
patient has and you are asking what is the disease that causes those symptoms
the disease that causes those symptoms okay so it's basically the same thing as
okay so it's basically the same thing as in hmm but the variables some of them
in hmm but the variables some of them can be continuous or discrete
can be continuous or discrete so some mixing with state-space models
so some mixing with state-space models may be the case and there's many other
may be the case and there's many other examples as well so the equation that we
examples as well so the equation that we discussed is basically this equation
discussed is basically this equation that you see here and I'm going to do a
that you see here and I'm going to do a very specific example today with
very specific example today with discrete variables hopefully before the
discrete variables hopefully before the end of the lecture so you can see this
end of the lecture so you can see this equation in action
equation in action so here the notation this is the
so here the notation this is the evidence V means visible variable states
evidence V means visible variable states that hidden feet are the static
that hidden feet are the static parameters like that the distributions
parameters like that the distributions defining the probability tables
you basically write the Joint Distribution like that and this is the
Distribution like that and this is the evidence and the evidence basically
evidence and the evidence basically requires marginalization over the hidden
requires marginalization over the hidden variables as you see on the bottom and
variables as you see on the bottom and and these are the three examples
and these are the three examples basically that you know or two of the
basically that you know or two of the examples of liberation so this is the
examples of liberation so this is the kind of operations we need to do and you
kind of operations we need to do and you notice here there is a big summation so
notice here there is a big summation so if these variables are hundreds of
if these variables are hundreds of thousands if you need to do this in raft
thousands if you need to do this in raft in a very effective way all right
in a very effective way all right otherwise this calculation would be
otherwise this calculation would be computationally sort of not easy thing
computationally sort of not easy thing to do
to do okay so don't get the impression or the
okay so don't get the impression or the summation and X a yes but let's say it's
summation and X a yes but let's say it's exhales its thousand variables and each
exhales its thousand variables and each of them takes ten values then you're in
of them takes ten values then you're in trouble
trouble okay sprinkler problem the web graph is
okay sprinkler problem the web graph is the visible variables right so W is the
the visible variables right so W is the variables the hidden variables is let's
variables the hidden variables is let's say in this particular case we're
say in this particular case we're interested to know it the sprinkler is
interested to know it the sprinkler is on or okay and they call them here
on or okay and they call them here nuisance variables in the sense but I
nuisance variables in the sense but I only want to estimate if the sprinkler
only want to estimate if the sprinkler is all wrong I don't really care about
is all wrong I don't really care about the Claudian array so there are hidden
the Claudian array so there are hidden bottom is listed as I have no interest
bottom is listed as I have no interest to the estimation and if you have no
to the estimation and if you have no interest in estimation you know what you
interest in estimation you know what you need to do with them you need to
need to do with them you need to integrate them out by that's the
integrate them out by that's the Bayesian way okay so again this T naught
Bayesian way okay so again this T naught and s they're really hidden variables
and s they're really hidden variables but in this case they only care involved
but in this case they only care involved the sprinkler so this is where there are
the sprinkler so this is where there are called my query or hidden variables this
called my query or hidden variables this again are hidden by was don't care so I
again are hidden by was don't care so I am going to
am going to - great them out and you can see the
- great them out and you can see the integration out on CNR so when I write
integration out on CNR so when I write this the joint probability of s and W
this the joint probability of s and W divided by the probability of W you
divided by the probability of W you notice in the denominator since I have
notice in the denominator since I have the joint of all the variables i
the joint of all the variables i marginalize this would be the
marginalize this would be the probability of love you shall have to
probability of love you shall have to multi relies on s C and R on the
multi relies on s C and R on the numerator this is the join of S&amp;W
numerator this is the join of S&amp;W S&amp;W shall have to marginalize with
S&amp;W shall have to marginalize with respects to these notions variables
respects to these notions variables cloudy and rain and this is what you see
cloudy and rain and this is what you see here okay
here okay these modernisations you can start off
these modernisations you can start off think you know visually at least in the
think you know visually at least in the context of discrete variables s as some
context of discrete variables s as some sort of collapsing big tables so you can
sort of collapsing big tables so you can take care if you have an XYZ table that
take care if you have an XYZ table that the speed of a pie with numbers all
the speed of a pie with numbers all right so each of this little love boxes
right so each of this little love boxes the cubes contains the probability of x
the cubes contains the probability of x y&amp;z having the particular values in this
y&amp;z having the particular values in this box right so if you want from this to
box right so if you want from this to get the marginal attractively you can be
get the marginal attractively you can be conception in the direction of Z to get
conception in the direction of Z to get the two-dimensional table right slope
the two-dimensional table right slope this which is easily processed in two
this which is easily processed in two dimensions if it is in fifty dimensions
dimensions if it is in fifty dimensions really performing all these summations
really performing all these summations it's a if they're expensive task okay so
it's a if they're expensive task okay so keep that in mind
so again for this particular probably might give you you know some of the
might give you you know some of the calculations I think they were contained
calculations I think they were contained also in the previous slide so
also in the previous slide so effectively what you do is you plug in
effectively what you do is you plug in the Joint Distribution of the variables
the Joint Distribution of the variables you plug in the values of s and W that
you plug in the values of s and W that your of interest and then you have to
your of interest and then you have to sum over all the possible values of
sum over all the possible values of these cloudy and rain
these cloudy and rain so this summations each of these
so this summations each of these variables which say takes two values all
variables which say takes two values all along so you're going to have terms that
along so you're going to have terms that are as big as this so four terms and
are as big as this so four terms and then I feel you're gonna have eight
then I feel you're gonna have eight terms so generally if the body of this
terms so generally if the body of this table if the favors are obviously the
table if the favors are obviously the present discrete variables that's a very
present discrete variables that's a very easy problem all right
easy problem all right there is a problem solved out the years
there is a problem solved out the years ago so there's really no interest to do
ago so there's really no interest to do any research right then you take this
any research right then you take this because the money curves except in our
because the money curves except in our plot right now at least distributions
plot right now at least distributions are sort of forgotten I want to believe
are sort of forgotten I want to believe that everything has been done also
that everything has been done also thirty forty years ago
thirty forty years ago okay so there's nothing no it's just to
okay so there's nothing no it's just to do if these conditional distributions
do if these conditional distributions are members of the exponential family I
are members of the exponential family I think the things you already have been
think the things you already have been done and they don't look very much
done and they don't look very much different from working with gaussians
different from working with gaussians for those who don't know what's an
for those who don't know what's an exponential family of distributions you
exponential family of distributions you may want to look on my slice from the
may want to look on my slice from the first in the previous semester and just
first in the previous semester and just the sample a nice table but tells you
the sample a nice table but tells you which distribution speak you know
which distribution speak you know category and why things are nice when we
category and why things are nice when we work with that but right now I mean a
work with that but right now I mean a Detroit's our most basic unit with
Detroit's our most basic unit with discrete values and Gaussian to convey
discrete values and Gaussian to convey the message basically on how to operate
the message basically on how to operate with this graph
with this graph so let's start with discrete animals if
so let's start with discrete animals if something doesn't make sense to stop me
something doesn't make sense to stop me because this sort of this examples were
because this sort of this examples were built on lots more complicated graphs as
built on lots more complicated graphs as we go along in the course so let's say I
we go along in the course so let's say I have two discrete variables X 1 and X 2
have two discrete variables X 1 and X 2 and they form a multi noni distribution
and they form a multi noni distribution so they can take each of them can take
so they can take each of them can take take different values each of these
take different values each of these values with probability mu I for the sum
values with probability mu I for the sum of holding is equal to R so you can
of holding is equal to R so you can think you know this is a generalization
think you know this is a generalization of a binary value me I can take values 0
of a binary value me I can take values 0 1 here I can take 10 values each of
1 here I can take 10 values each of those values with probability mu army to
those values with probability mu army to UK okay so there are two cases if the
UK okay so there are two cases if the most general will be to write the Joint
most general will be to write the Joint Distribution the way that you see here
Distribution the way that you see here okay for both not familiar notation here
okay for both not familiar notation here this axis right on 0 1 alright so we
this axis right on 0 1 alright so we send each of the botanist but this body
send each of the botanist but this body was to take with probabilities mu i all
was to take with probabilities mu i all right
right is the only one but you don't know which
is the only one but you don't know which of the K variables is active so what we
of the K variables is active so what we do here you notice is this is the joint
do here you notice is this is the joint distribution the probability of this
distribution the probability of this take the value I and still manage the
take the value I and still manage the exclude theta value J we call it V IJ
exclude theta value J we call it V IJ right so this is the joint probability
right so this is the joint probability that this just has the value R in this
that this just has the value R in this case the body J and I put in the
case the body J and I put in the exponent X 1 IX today and I take the
exponent X 1 IX today and I take the part of a forecast massage Sanjay
part of a forecast massage Sanjay because in this product only mission I
because in this product only mission I and one terry from X 1 and X 2 will take
and one terry from X 1 and X 2 will take the value 1 and everything else will be
the value 1 and everything else will be 0 right and something preserving did you
0 right and something preserving did you work
work you are alright because the various
you are alright because the various effects the star right so if we went to
effects the star right so if we went to a like this this is the only way we can
a like this this is the only way we can do it one of the night distance a each
do it one of the night distance a each vector r1 is equal to 1 this equal to
vector r1 is equal to 1 this equal to market x12 equal to that than equal to
market x12 equal to that than equal to that because we were run out of paper
that because we were run out of paper okay
okay this equation is compact it works you
this equation is compact it works you the joint probability distribution mu IJ
the joint probability distribution mu IJ and you isolate God
and you isolate God okay so this is you know it says the
okay so this is you know it says the number of counts that parameters in this
number of counts that parameters in this polish k square- walk will will be this
polish k square- walk will will be this number control
so we have K squared then the one comes from quad
so kmkj square and the one comes from
what's the password why one there's one there
nope
because when I some write all the possible probabilities the you know of
possible probabilities the you know of the different states the sum has to be
the different states the sum has to be equal to one is a normalization sir K
equal to one is a normalization sir K square minus one right now if I assume
square minus one right now if I assume that the distributions of X 1 and X 2
that the distributions of X 1 and X 2 are independent given the parameters
are independent given the parameters mean I can write instead of repeating
mean I can write instead of repeating this with this joint probabilities mean
this with this joint probabilities mean say I can write this as the progress of
say I can write this as the progress of UI's times the product of u j's
UI's times the product of u j's okay and here the way it is written I am
okay and here the way it is written I am assuming that mu is the same basically
assuming that mu is the same basically about x1 x2 okay I don't see anything
about x1 x2 okay I don't see anything that separates the two so right they are
that separates the two so right they are independent and particularly way the
independent and particularly way the circle I'm going to tell you in a circle
let's count to support is not released and then we will discuss what this is
and then we will discuss what this is about
about what is the 210 minus r oncoming flow to
what is the 210 minus r oncoming flow to describe each of this distribution sorry
describe each of this distribution sorry because this is the product of two
because this is the product of two independent solutions of x1 x2 how many
independent solutions of x1 x2 how many values from a parameter need for each of
values from a parameter need for each of this individual product terms and it
this individual product terms and it came minus one right here 10 years
came minus one right here 10 years normalization of each of the P of x1 pfx
normalization of each of the P of x1 pfx do so k minus 1 and then I have two
do so k minus 1 and then I have two blocks so the new essentially means that
blocks so the new essentially means that when I have it the notation is not clear
when I have it the notation is not clear of saying that chuan has it song lyrics
of saying that chuan has it song lyrics to has its own new you see that
yes No
so basically this works the same is this equation right so x1 can take a states
equation right so x1 can take a states each of this case 2 I is with four
each of this case 2 I is with four committed in the I so let's say for
committed in the I so let's say for example that this was a mining anything
example that this was a mining anything right so near land it would be the
right so near land it would be the probability of x1 is during minute 2
probability of x1 is during minute 2 which is 1 minus b1 that the probability
which is 1 minus b1 that the probability equal to 1 but Sarah have a of those
equal to 1 but Sarah have a of those stage so I like all of them like that
stage so I like all of them like that and because I have K State's and K news
and because I have K State's and K news they we have to someone so I really have
they we have to someone so I really have K minus 1 K minus 1 parameters okay so I
K minus 1 K minus 1 parameters okay so I have K minus twelve parameter the
have K minus twelve parameter the implication is that this term use are
implication is that this term use are different now this is a thing right so
different now this is a thing right so you know this year I you know for
you know this year I you know for example for this independent
example for this independent distribution have it like that if you
distribution have it like that if you have a general distribution of LM
have a general distribution of LM variables basically the total number of
variables basically the total number of parameters is K to the N minus 1 all
parameters is K to the N minus 1 all right this is similar to what we had
right this is similar to what we had here so we have two values k square-
here so we have two values k square- want for them to be K to the M minus 1
want for them to be K to the M minus 1 so this is gross too fast for actually
so this is gross too fast for actually being able to do anything
being able to do anything now if the values are independent the
now if the values are independent the novel problem should be K minus 1 for
novel problem should be K minus 1 for its distribution times M so very small
its distribution times M so very small number and if I have a Markov chain
number and if I have a Markov chain alright where everything is defined in
alright where everything is defined in terms of this conditional distributions
terms of this conditional distributions of X i given only the previous value so
of X i given only the previous value so this is a first-order Markov chain it
this is a first-order Markov chain it says that the total number of parameters
says that the total number of parameters is K minus 1 plus n minus 1 K K minus 1
is K minus 1 plus n minus 1 K K minus 1 and and tell me what it says there what
and and tell me what it says there what is this novel comic problem so if I have
is this novel comic problem so if I have a Markov chain a first-order wide the
a Markov chain a first-order wide the total number of parameters for you know
total number of parameters for you know my variables is K minus 1 plus M minus 1
my variables is K minus 1 plus M minus 1 K minus 1 J minus 1 is from you remember
K minus 1 J minus 1 is from you remember to describe the Joint Distribution you
to describe the Joint Distribution you need to start with P of x1 and then P of
need to start with P of x1 and then P of X will give the next 100 P or 53 given
X will give the next 100 P or 53 given x2 etc so P reflects one has K minus
x2 etc so P reflects one has K minus small variables where it is and then I
small variables where it is and then I have remaining n minus 1 particles and
have remaining n minus 1 particles and they are defined through this
they are defined through this conditional distribution and how much
conditional distribution and how much how many body must I need for this case
how many body must I need for this case here and K any K square minus K because
here and K any K square minus K because this distribution for its many effects I
this distribution for its many effects I minus one has to sum to one and I have
minus one has to sum to one and I have three values of X I minus 1 so the K
three values of X I minus 1 so the K squared minus K okay for a Markov chain
squared minus K okay for a Markov chain basically you can see the cost is linear
basically you can see the cost is linear in M you can see here K 2 parallel
in M you can see here K 2 parallel alright that's not very good
alright that's not very good so this is sort of the most trivial case
so this is sort of the most trivial case and and the graph basically for that
and and the graph basically for that looks like now I know some of you have I
looks like now I know some of you have I mean I'm assuming of taking other
mean I'm assuming of taking other statistics process some took the course
statistics process some took the course the semester and some have not
the semester and some have not so you know I know you got some homework
so you know I know you got some homework problems where the assumption was that
problems where the assumption was that you look at the graph and you know
you look at the graph and you know everything from the skies what it means
everything from the skies what it means with I suggest this if when you come
with I suggest this if when you come across these things and you don't know
across these things and you don't know or you want to see more references send
or you want to see more references send me an email I will send you very few
me an email I will send you very few pages of reading to see these things in
pages of reading to see these things in in detail just in case you haven't seen
in detail just in case you haven't seen them before
them before so this is
so this is the cases with discreet Barnabas and I
the cases with discreet Barnabas and I give you a few examples so let's look at
give you a few examples so let's look at the example of the top okay it says we
the example of the top okay it says we take everything to be discrete right now
take everything to be discrete right now okay so I have a Markov chain
okay so I have a Markov chain okay next one next to the exam but x1
okay next one next to the exam but x1 depends on I mean you can sit here some
depends on I mean you can sit here some parameters mean you are excused from you
parameters mean you are excused from you to examine some um and mainly depends
to examine some um and mainly depends means the general the composition or
means the general the composition or factorization of the distribution of
factorization of the distribution of we're looking at this graph the
we're looking at this graph the distribution is given you on its power
distribution is given you on its power alright the distributions of x2 given x1
alright the distributions of x2 given x1 and given you two extremes even
and given you two extremes even explained given in you three acceptance
explained given in you three acceptance of this product okay
of this product okay potential the product of P of me to feel
potential the product of P of me to feel from you three P of MU M so this is the
from you three P of MU M so this is the factorization over the gap okay so um
factorization over the gap okay so um are basically the parameters that are
are basically the parameters that are needed to define this dynamical model or
needed to define this dynamical model or the terms you have to go from X minus n
the terms you have to go from X minus n minus 1 to xn okay and in this case you
minus 1 to xn okay and in this case you know there's no levels because they are
know there's no levels because they are discrete and take K values
discrete and take K values this can take K values and I will need
this can take K values and I will need to put some priority good poverty put is
to put some priority good poverty put is a dealer distribution the red
a dealer distribution the red distributions are going to count very
distributions are going to count very often later in the question I only want
often later in the question I only want you to look on Wikipedia and get some
you to look on Wikipedia and get some sense of what
sense of what it's a conjugate prior basically to the
it's a conjugate prior basically to the Volta and Moody distribution so it's
Volta and Moody distribution so it's very important to to play and it's
very important to to play and it's social a very sort of interesting topic
social a very sort of interesting topic for research because here some I very
for research because here some I very recent ideas a colleague from dear
recent ideas a colleague from dear Claire processes not distributions okay
Claire processes not distributions okay and statistical computer science because
and statistical computer science because this is a very important topic does this
this is a very important topic does this looking at this graph does it make any
looking at this graph does it make any sense right the optimization this is all
sense right the optimization this is all my own on battabox my exes and my new is
my own on battabox my exes and my new is nothing I don't give anything right so
nothing I don't give anything right so the Joint Distribution I write it like
the Joint Distribution I write it like that
that is this equation like the first and
is this equation like the first and second line do we make tent no general
right so you you know you have to put these conditionals giving the parents
these conditionals giving the parents but then sometimes when her parents
but then sometimes when her parents meanwhile has no parent so he will come
meanwhile has no parent so he will come home Nia took has no plans we come alone
home Nia took has no plans we come alone um he's no father he come alone all
um he's no father he come alone all right and because we would be interested
right and because we would be interested to eventually sort of the Bayesian
to eventually sort of the Bayesian analysis on the parameters in the model
analysis on the parameters in the model is good to put the prior all right a lot
is good to put the prior all right a lot prior theories to declare prior that is
prior theories to declare prior that is going to have its own type of parameters
going to have its own type of parameters alpha alpha mutant yep
from n equal to 2 thank you yep okay so the product to be m equal to 2 I wish I
the product to be m equal to 2 I wish I can just say to my computer please
can just say to my computer please change doesn't I don't know why the
change doesn't I don't know why the technology is not as sophisticated so
technology is not as sophisticated so please remind me if I forget to change
please remind me if I forget to change this and the same I supposed to have to
this and the same I supposed to have to it right okay so this is the very
it right okay so this is the very general setting and I am taking the same
general setting and I am taking the same problem and I'm actually simplifying it
problem and I'm actually simplifying it enormously with a second Republic the
enormously with a second Republic the graphical model so what's the
graphical model so what's the simplification that you see on the
simplification that you see on the second graph that is enormous so what is
second graph that is enormous so what is the simplification you can stick on the
the simplification you can stick on the top so the parameters start I made some
top so the parameters start I made some using the same parameters to define all
using the same parameters to define all this conditional probability
this conditional probability distributions okay I mean that's of
distributions okay I mean that's of course a major assumption but you can
course a major assumption but you can appreciate the inference with one meal
appreciate the inference with one meal versus doing influence with thousands of
versus doing influence with thousands of gnu's
gnu's okay all right so time of the parameters
okay all right so time of the parameters makes things extremely late so I think
makes things extremely late so I think maybe in the processing we maybe
maybe in the processing we maybe advocated this problem and we said is
advocated this problem and we said is not going to be here so often in this
not going to be here so often in this course but let me use this as a sort of
course but let me use this as a sort of a counter example so let's say we have M
a counter example so let's say we have M variables again that they are discrete
variables again that they are discrete and each of them can take K different
and each of them can take K different states and I'm interested in some sort
states and I'm interested in some sort of a classification problem strike one
of a classification problem strike one for example to know if X 1 to X what's
for example to know if X 1 to X what's the probability of y equal to 1 right
the probability of y equal to 1 right given X 1 and X n so maybe why can't one
given X 1 and X n so maybe why can't one is 1000 from
is 1000 from later come y equal to zero some other
later come y equal to zero some other Gaussian okay but I'm interested to just
Gaussian okay but I'm interested to just compute only to do classification in
compute only to do classification in this probability
this probability okay so somebody can build this
okay so somebody can build this complicated graphs that we had before
complicated graphs that we had before and form the joint probability of Y and
and form the joint probability of Y and all the XS alright and do interested of
all the XS alright and do interested of graph but an approach that is actually
graph but an approach that is actually the best if the only thing you carry is
the best if the only thing you carry is this conditional probability is actually
this conditional probability is actually to try to flip it in some non-linearity
to try to flip it in some non-linearity and what non-linearity here is the
and what non-linearity here is the sigmoid function so basically what you
sigmoid function so basically what you say is you know what I'm going to model
say is you know what I'm going to model this as a sigmoid function where I'm
this as a sigmoid function where I'm gonna use some linear approach linear
gonna use some linear approach linear interpolation of the artists okay with
interpolation of the artists okay with some unknown parameters W so you know
some unknown parameters W so you know conditional distributions or anything
conditional distributions or anything like that and then of analysis or the
like that and then of analysis or the W's and I only have M plus small W all
W's and I only have M plus small W all right so this says things you can write
right so this says things you can write in the quantities of classification
in the quantities of classification these are the best ways to actually to
these are the best ways to actually to model this using a parameter is
model this using a parameter is basically model for this conditional
basically model for this conditional distribution around about claiming the
distribution around about claiming the whole Joint Distribution working sort of
whole Joint Distribution working sort of in in in of the narrative sense okay but
in in in of the narrative sense okay but this gives you only this probability you
this gives you only this probability you cannot do much except just using that
cannot do much except just using that probability that's good you stop there
probability that's good you stop there if it's not good then it has to look at
if it's not good then it has to look at a more general way
all right tell me the example that you guys should be given in the homework
guys should be given in the homework okay anybody has go to this problem so
okay anybody has go to this problem so let me work it for you because I haven't
let me work it for you because I haven't read the solution so I don't know what
read the solution so I don't know what it is asking maybe he's asking you to do
it is asking maybe he's asking you to do what's on the slide and flop is the case
what's on the slide and flop is the case you better correct my slide because I'm
you better correct my slide because I'm sure something must be wrong
sure something must be wrong all right not just typed wrong but you
all right not just typed wrong but you know so you guys find a mistake software
know so you guys find a mistake software linearization model you can think again
linearization model you can think again of you know where this conditional
of you know where this conditional distributions of X i given its parents
distributions of X i given its parents we're going to model it as a linear
we're going to model it as a linear thousand model what does that mean means
thousand model what does that mean means we're going to take the mean of this
we're going to take the mean of this condition the tribution to be a weighted
condition the tribution to be a weighted average of their parents this is what
average of their parents this is what this is plus some bias term and then
this is plus some bias term and then plus some noise this is very generic
plus some noise this is very generic actually this is what we call the linear
actually this is what we call the linear Gaussian model alright so in this case
Gaussian model alright so in this case what is very particular for this linear
what is very particular for this linear Gaussian model is that the axis that you
Gaussian model is that the axis that you use to define the mean defined from the
use to define the mean defined from the products right this one of the finest
products right this one of the finest this X J's are the parents of no diary
this X J's are the parents of no diary but this mean is linear in X J and then
but this mean is linear in X J and then I plug in some noise V so the announced
I plug in some noise V so the announced basically in the problem our world is
basically in the problem our world is double used all right the bias terms
double used all right the bias terms based and the variance is V okay so if
based and the variance is V okay so if you want to share this being a model
you want to share this being a model written sort of in an algebraic form you
written sort of in an algebraic form you can say the VEX hi
can say the VEX hi the main value plus square root of VI
the main value plus square root of VI times from normal Gaussian but they
times from normal Gaussian but they actually okay with this elementary
actually okay with this elementary properties so you can see this this way
properties so you can see this this way or you can see it this way it is the
or you can see it this way it is the same thing okay
same thing okay so linear motion because you know this
so linear motion because you know this the in the mean is a linear function of
the in the mean is a linear function of the exist the linearity comes everywhere
the exist the linearity comes everywhere it's Gaussian because not only this
it's Gaussian because not only this condition distribution of X i given the
condition distribution of X i given the parent is down shell for that so you can
parent is down shell for that so you can so if you take all of these gardens you
so if you take all of these gardens you multiply them with each other if you
multiply them with each other if you expand and then you close the square as
expand and then you close the square as they say you can solve that the joint
they say you can solve that the joint distribution is also Gaussian right it's
distribution is also Gaussian right it's a quadratic I mean and I again I am NOT
a quadratic I mean and I again I am NOT doing the algebra because it's not water
doing the algebra because it's not water but if you take the logs right and you
but if you take the logs right and you come up the product of all these
come up the product of all these distributions becomes summation of the
distributions becomes summation of the logs and then you get this squares and
logs and then you get this squares and if you expand them you can basically get
if you expand them you can basically get a square for to fit that they're
a square for to fit that they're multivariate gaussian so this leads to
multivariate gaussian so this leads to the multivariate Gaussian so the problem
the multivariate Gaussian so the problem here is we want for this graph but is
here is we want for this graph but is represented by this conditional
represented by this conditional distributions we want to compute the
distributions we want to compute the mean of all the nodes and we want to
mean of all the nodes and we want to compute the the covariance right and
this are the equations where he wants you to prove them for me they are my
you to prove them for me they are my sites but once you take some time to
sites but once you take some time to prove this equations because they are
prove this equations because they are not obvious okay nothing is obvious in
not obvious okay nothing is obvious in life and so if you take the mean let's
life and so if you take the mean let's here this is the main of the condition
here this is the main of the condition of the tradition of next events parlance
of the tradition of next events parlance okay
okay [Applause]
[Applause] take the main effect I is actually let
take the main effect I is actually let me give this equation the meaning of X I
me give this equation the meaning of X I is summation over the parents of Waj the
is summation over the parents of Waj the mean effect A plus bi and the mean of
mean effect A plus bi and the mean of this which is zero all right
using this little equation the this means if you put them together alright
means if you put them together alright if you calculate them recursively and
if you calculate them recursively and you put them in order you know it will
you put them in order you know it will give you the mean of the multivariate
give you the mean of the multivariate body will exit everybody says this the
body will exit everybody says this the question I'm just using this and I take
question I'm just using this and I take the mean of X I the summation there will
the mean of X I the summation there will be the mean of its J this is constant
be the mean of its J this is constant the mean of this is zero alright so
the mean of this is zero alright so basically they have very testy relation
basically they have very testy relation and those means of what I put them
and those means of what I put them together in a vector form will give me
together in a vector form will give me the mean of vector X
the mean of vector X okay now bit more complicated the name
okay now bit more complicated the name of the covariance is giving sort of a
of the covariance is giving sort of a similar expression this coefficient WJ k
similar expression this coefficient WJ k for k of the parent i have to use a cake
for k of the parent i have to use a cake here because there's an ion is a there
here because there's an ion is a there right so WJ k the covariance of excite
right so WJ k the covariance of excite with the XK minus of X I XJ so notice
with the XK minus of X I XJ so notice here there's a j from the urban decay
here there's a j from the urban decay that are the parlance of j and then
that are the parlance of j and then there is an extra pair that is another
there is an extra pair that is another function alright so a equal to RF i and
function alright so a equal to RF i and j is equal otherwise 0 square root of
j is equal otherwise 0 square root of the IV j mr. variance is right so i need
the IV j mr. variance is right so i need to have VI VJ and when i like the
to have VI VJ and when i like the situation I forgot to maybe to put this
situation I forgot to maybe to put this from the previous slide this is for I
from the previous slide this is for I less or equal to J so you may want to
less or equal to J so you may want to take and
take and so this in the weight of a habit is for
so this in the weight of a habit is for I less or equal to jelly okay if you
I less or equal to jelly okay if you know this right you can need something
know this right you can need something else you can use symmetry and you can
else you can use symmetry and you can get for I greater than say a similar
get for I greater than say a similar expression but this is choir less or
expression but this is choir less or equal to Z how do you prove this
equal to Z how do you prove this equation alright doesn't ask you this or
equation alright doesn't ask you this or I don't know if he does anything they
I don't know if he does anything they say prove it okay all right so if you
say prove it okay all right so if you want to prove it so if you want the
want to prove it so if you want the covariance of X I XJ by definition is
covariance of X I XJ by definition is this
this it's like if XY minus the mean of X
it's like if XY minus the mean of X sorry XJ minus the mean of XJ I'm using
sorry XJ minus the mean of XJ I'm using this you can leave this relation this
this you can leave this relation this linear starting point that I had the urn
linear starting point that I had the urn and I'm subtracting the means of X I and
and I'm subtracting the means of X I and XJ and basically I stopped invest and he
XJ and basically I stopped invest and he will take this fall will case amount of
will take this fall will case amount of jail ok so now I'm going to have a
jail ok so now I'm going to have a summation of the points of j WJ k and
summation of the points of j WJ k and then i'm going to have the expectation
then i'm going to have the expectation of this parentheses final thought is the
of this parentheses final thought is the covariance of X I X K so the first times
covariance of X I X K so the first times that is it there and then there is the
that is it there and then there is the expectation of this parentheses times
expectation of this parentheses times this term that involves if she'll say
this term that involves if she'll say all right and if the previous equation
all right and if the previous equation square but progress of expectation needs
square but progress of expectation needs to come to be equal to rest and the only
to come to be equal to rest and the only way that I have been able to actually
way that I have been able to actually prove this is sort of doing it
prove this is sort of doing it recursively okay so if you guys come up
recursively okay so if you guys come up with a cleaner way not only you send me
with a cleaner way not only you send me the right proof but you send me the
the right proof but you send me the correct
correct question to cut and paste on my style
question to cut and paste on my style it's today because I saw to play not
it's today because I saw to play not particularly happy with provost
particularly happy with provost derivation but so again we want to pull
derivation but so again we want to pull the expectation of this x naught is
the expectation of this x naught is equal to that and the way that I do it
equal to that and the way that I do it is I write rest from our original
is I write rest from our original equation right I stops you this in terms
equation right I stops you this in terms of its power and values right this is
of its power and values right this is the expectation okay and then whether
the expectation okay and then whether whether I started doing is remember I
whether I started doing is remember I have a no-life here
have a no-life here the files have default node I and the
the files have default node I and the parents of higher default that so what I
parents of higher default that so what I this I recursively introduce the
this I recursively introduce the parlance of Pi and then for its power in
parlance of Pi and then for its power in the PI M I introduce its own term and I
the PI M I introduce its own term and I keep doing this until it's norm so when
keep doing this until it's norm so when you do it sort of this way okay it comes
you do it sort of this way okay it comes up but when you take it
up but when you take it most times that and expectations the
most times that and expectations the contributions you will get from this
contributions you will get from this summation left to you know to zero and
summation left to you know to zero and then you're going to care basically this
then you're going to care basically this BJP I epsilon R epsilon J expectation
BJP I epsilon R epsilon J expectation which effectively at the end of the day
which effectively at the end of the day will give you this
will give you this I'm highlighting the proof is part of
I'm highlighting the proof is part of your homework if you want to look at it
your homework if you want to look at it okay it sounds about right
okay it sounds about right but this is going to compute
but this is going to compute expectations this is how you complete
expectations this is how you complete the covariance both equations are
the covariance both equations are requested because to compute the
requested because to compute the covariance of X IJ with high in less or
covariance of X IJ with high in less or equal to J you need the prevalence of
equal to J you need the prevalence of excited with a parent of J and to
excited with a parent of J and to compute this you need the parents of K
compute this you need the parents of K and etc etc from here it's the the
and etc etc from here it's the the let me give you an example if you have
let me give you an example if you have three minutes
the first impression the expectation can you tell me for first equation control
alright I remind you I remind you this nice equation the expectation of any
nice equation the expectation of any node is w IJ times the expectation of
node is w IJ times the expectation of the pilots of 12 J okay I'll tell the
the pilots of 12 J okay I'll tell the parents pi times D I so okay not great I
want them to be with zinnias memory to remember this equation right not three
remember this equation right not three what are the odds of not playing just
the expectation of x two times the expectation of Nordics few and what is
expectation of Nordics few and what is the expectation of no to the expectation
the expectation of no to the expectation of note a will be 1 times the
of note a will be 1 times the expectation of X 1 and what is the
expectation of X 1 and what is the expectation of X 1 is B 1 because there
expectation of X 1 is B 1 because there are no power
are no power all right so when you put all of this
all right so when you put all of this together you get this nice integration
together you get this nice integration of this and this and similarly good
of this and this and similarly good check for example let's say the
check for example let's say the covariance of X 1 and X 3 I have the
covariance of X 1 and X 3 I have the formula clear so we don't have to go
formula clear so we don't have to go back and forth this is the formula that
back and forth this is the formula that says they are the parents of of 3 the
says they are the parents of of 3 the parts of 3 still straight will be done 3
parts of 3 still straight will be done 3 2 times the covariance of X 1 and X 2
2 times the covariance of X 1 and X 2 the covariance of X 1 and X 2 unique the
the covariance of X 1 and X 2 unique the potential 2 which is 1 so it will be W 2
potential 2 which is 1 so it will be W 2 1 times the covariance of X 1 X 1 plus
1 times the covariance of X 1 X 1 plus these delta function 1 2 times B 2 this
these delta function 1 2 times B 2 this function is 0 so you get W 3 2 W 2 1 and
function is 0 so you get W 3 2 W 2 1 and the covariance of X 1 X 1 is V 1 ok so
the covariance of X 1 X 1 is V 1 ok so it's a complicated painful calculation
it's a complicated painful calculation we have on the other hand it's a closed
we have on the other hand it's a closed form solution you have the mean just by
form solution you have the mean just by playing together with this conditional
playing together with this conditional probability distributions you can
probability distributions you can compute the mean of the Joint
compute the mean of the Joint Distribution and the covariance and and
Distribution and the covariance and and and you know you have everything alright
how many parameters from this model so again the parameters in the model are
again the parameters in the model are these variances and there are diverse
these variances and there are diverse because you know I suppose my god just
because you know I suppose my god just denote in this case alright so I have
denote in this case alright so I have the variant it and then it says the
the variant it and then it says the parameters W IJ Rd square minus V over 2
parameters W IJ Rd square minus V over 2 what do I get out if you remember this
what do I get out if you remember this problem is defined the you know your
problem is defined the you know your dependence on the parents right so if
dependence on the parents right so if I'm interested to try on w12 how much is
I'm interested to try on w12 how much is w12 there's not that we want to 0 right
w12 there's not that we want to 0 right I mean the only thing I have here is
I mean the only thing I have here is let's if I look at no.3 I have W 3 2 and
let's if I look at no.3 I have W 3 2 and W you know W 3 2 is nonzero because the
W you know W 3 2 is nonzero because the parent of 2 is the parent of three all
parent of 2 is the parent of three all right so I am looking is this not B to
right so I am looking is this not B to be a lower triangular matrix and a lower
be a lower triangular matrix and a lower triangular matrix change the dimensions
triangular matrix change the dimensions is what totally the square minus B in
is what totally the square minus B in the Bellarmine I'll then take half you
the Bellarmine I'll then take half you get this square minus B over 2
it comes that this complicated linear Gaussian model if you solve this 2 is 3
Gaussian model if you solve this 2 is 3 times 3 plus 1 over 2 which is actually
times 3 plus 1 over 2 which is actually the same as the covariance matrix of you
the same as the covariance matrix of you know the division alright symmetric
know the division alright symmetric various metrics so that effectively the
various metrics so that effectively the Joint Distribution is a Gaussian alright
Joint Distribution is a Gaussian alright so obviously this probably needs to be
so obviously this probably needs to be sort of equivalent to to you know to
sort of equivalent to to you know to this order of parameters required for a
this order of parameters required for a multivariate Gaussian basically to
multivariate Gaussian basically to define the covariance matrix okay simple
define the covariance matrix okay simple 12 approach to this problem that is from
12 approach to this problem that is from Malthus book and it is Center for a very
Malthus book and it is Center for a very simple calculation without any recursive
simple calculation without any recursive relationships okay so you may appreciate
relationships okay so you may appreciate this derivation because only one slide
this derivation because only one slide or two
so I kept the notation from a meta so don't mixed up that's how many equations
don't mixed up that's how many equations but this kilonewtons acting on the same
but this kilonewtons acting on the same problem alright so in several V this
problem alright so in several V this conditional variance here he is using
conditional variance here he is using Sigma T Square this is my bias term was
Sigma T Square this is my bias term was because ultimately the same problem okay
because ultimately the same problem okay so what she does is the coloring have
so what she does is the coloring have bunnies I subtracted the mean from the
bunnies I subtracted the mean from the values of each node
values of each node okay so okay so from this node and the
okay so okay so from this node and the parents basically would have done is not
parents basically would have done is not subtracting the mean okay and so this is
subtracting the mean okay and so this is the similar equation with what I had
the similar equation with what I had before this is like my noise level
before this is like my noise level emtional I had before but by writing the
emtional I had before but by writing the equation like not where the mean of the
equation like not where the mean of the normal values come explicitly I can
normal values come explicitly I can write this whole equation as a vector
write this whole equation as a vector form as follows X minus mu is a vector
form as follows X minus mu is a vector equal lower diagonal matrix W similar to
equal lower diagonal matrix W similar to what we had before times X minus Mew
what we had before times X minus Mew okay and I can write this as the matrix
okay and I can write this as the matrix s in this case will be the banner that
s in this case will be the banner that contains the noise viruses okay I
contains the noise viruses okay I suppose yes this before we had the
suppose yes this before we had the square root of the variance so this is
square root of the variance so this is you know it's the standard deviation so
you know it's the standard deviation so this correct stress is the diagonal of
this correct stress is the diagonal of Sigma times the vector Z this is the
Sigma times the vector Z this is the same equation I had discovered the only
same equation I had discovered the only difference is now alright that I can
difference is now alright that I can write this as a matrix equation where
write this as a matrix equation where what is different from the expression we
what is different from the expression we used before is that instead of Texas
used before is that instead of Texas with X minus left the means of the
with X minus left the means of the northern body and there's a reason to do
northern body and there's a reason to do this because so this is an equation if
this because so this is an equation if you trying just to start with it will be
you trying just to start with it will be s times if RS is this diagonal of the
s times if RS is this diagonal of the standard deviations in the conditional
standard deviations in the conditional distribution so this is e x minus mu you
distribution so this is e x minus mu you can see from here times 9 minus 9 is
can see from here times 9 minus 9 is going to come to be e all right so
going to come to be e all right so finally this explicitly e equal I - down
finally this explicitly e equal I - down the year
the year alright a nice invertible matrix times X
alright a nice invertible matrix times X minus mu all right and I can solve for X
minus mu all right and I can solve for X minus mu by inverting this matrix I
minus mu by inverting this matrix I minus W times P all right and ok is f
minus W times P all right and ok is f prime Z when I try let me call this
prime Z when I try let me call this matrix you alright well this matrix is U
matrix you alright well this matrix is U times s times Z all right when we need
times s times Z all right when we need the complicated calculation the
the complicated calculation the constraints approach the same as the
constraints approach the same as the covariance of X minus mu X minus mu from
covariance of X minus mu X minus mu from this equation is again this is me way
this equation is again this is me way the investor fineliners now the use of
the investor fineliners now the use of the waist right so the terms of real
the waist right so the terms of real times test as you remember is the
times test as you remember is the diagonal of the conditional standard
diagonal of the conditional standard deviation s times G is minus vector and
deviation s times G is minus vector and the covariance of U times s times D from
the covariance of U times s times D from classical identity from your probability
classical identity from your probability cost is us times the covariance of J
cost is us times the covariance of J times the transpose of this as you
times the transpose of this as you Forest Service identity so you get us
Forest Service identity so you get us four different sports so define the
four different sports so define the covariance of the join vector X which we
covariance of the join vector X which we need this you need to complete you and
need this you need to complete you and use in terms of the weights and you need
use in terms of the weights and you need s a nest of the noise body world the
s a nest of the noise body world the noise standard deviations of the
noise standard deviations of the conditional distributions so now the
conditional distributions so now the pension calculation solo very cash
pension calculation solo very cash investors disappeared with one trick and
investors disappeared with one trick and the trick is to work not through the
the trick is to work not through the experiments but with the X minus mu
experiments but with the X minus mu value okay so say q1 we need to
value okay so say q1 we need to implement this linear Gaussian model
implement this linear Gaussian model this is photo to the busiest way you can
this is photo to the busiest way you can get basically the expectations the way
get basically the expectations the way we did in the earlier slide expectations
we did in the earlier slide expectations are very easy to do I was really compact
are very easy to do I was really compact so for example at this trivial case when
so for example at this trivial case when you collect data x1 to xn and they all
you collect data x1 to xn and they all come up from some distribution of some
come up from some distribution of some unknown parameter theta a good way to
unknown parameter theta a good way to represent this so here actually I should
represent this so here actually I should have notes right is X 2 here X 3
have notes right is X 2 here X 3 etcetera xn so a good way to represent
etcetera xn so a good way to represent compound in a compact fashion list is to
compound in a compact fashion list is to represent this with a presentation the
represent this with a presentation the vs. follows you from the backside at X I
vs. follows you from the backside at X I and you indicate that you have n
and you indicate that you have n instances of X all right
instances of X all right you have any generalizations of X I and
you have any generalizations of X I and all of these realizations have the same
all of these realizations have the same theta when they come from the same
theta when they come from the same distribution that there's a parameter
distribution that there's a parameter theta so theta has to be outside the box
theta so theta has to be outside the box because only thing things inside the
because only thing things inside the battery repeat things outside the next
battery repeat things outside the next are basically independent of hi okay so
are basically independent of hi okay so this is basically equivalent to the
this is basically equivalent to the notation that you see here for simple
notation that you see here for simple problems you can do this for more
problems you can do this for more complicated problems this may be candy
complicated problems this may be candy but you have to do it carefully because
but you have to do it carefully because some of these boxes and complicated
some of these boxes and complicated distributions may be nested and you can
distributions may be nested and you can sort of come up with wrong with you know
sort of come up with wrong with you know the wrong conclusions because your
the wrong conclusions because your distribution represented by this graph
distribution represented by this graph of this graph is not the same so in this
of this graph is not the same so in this case if you interested in the Joint
case if you interested in the Joint Distribution of all the variables the
Distribution of all the variables the next time and then you have n instances
next time and then you have n instances of the probability of X i given theta
of the probability of X i given theta which we see with this product here so
which we see with this product here so this is the joint distribution and it's
this is the joint distribution and it's really identical to the Joint
really identical to the Joint Distribution of Yashida okay so this
Distribution of Yashida okay so this again it's a more compact way and it's
again it's a more compact way and it's called the plate notation for
called the plate notation for representing graphical models
all right
so if this don't extend come from adoption that has some unknown the mean
adoption that has some unknown the mean and variance that same your standard
and variance that same your standard deviation Sigma this is the plate
deviation Sigma this is the plate notation for representing some good data
notation for representing some good data from this Gaussian with parameters mu
from this Gaussian with parameters mu and Sigma all right so the Joint
and Sigma all right so the Joint Distribution is for unity of Sigma and
Distribution is for unity of Sigma and then you have M installations of the
then you have M installations of the probability of x given mu and Sigma or
probability of x given mu and Sigma or additionally to parents so this is a
additionally to parents so this is a reduction the amount disruption where we
reduction the amount disruption where we have one of this you know everything
have one of this you know everything indicating that every node X depends
indicating that every node X depends from you know Sigma or you prefer this
from you know Sigma or you prefer this mister screen notation okay so let me
mister screen notation okay so let me finish
finish we have exactly five minutes again for
we have exactly five minutes again for those who have not seen regression
those who have not seen regression models I will suggest that you look on
models I will suggest that you look on on my lecture in you know in the poll
on my lecture in you know in the poll and the exact same problem basically
and the exact same problem basically limitation I don't think we're going to
limitation I don't think we're going to come back to the aggression problems in
come back to the aggression problems in this course but right now I just want to
this course but right now I just want to give you a modular presentation of for
give you a modular presentation of for regression for base and regression to
regression for base and regression to see how it works like so today we are
see how it works like so today we are given some data and T are the positive
given some data and T are the positive values and we try to the division
values and we try to the division fitting in the sense that for some unix
fitting in the sense that for some unix we want to be able to predict the value
we want to be able to predict the value of T and also the uncertainty in T so we
of T and also the uncertainty in T so we come up with integration function that
come up with integration function that this basically in this case a linear
this basically in this case a linear model okay so WI x 6i okay and least
model okay so WI x 6i okay and least this coefficients table review we take
this coefficients table review we take them as random bottom so they're gonna
them as random bottom so they're gonna put some flour on them all right and so
put some flour on them all right and so the giant probability of tmw is you can
the giant probability of tmw is you can think of being our measurements of some
think of being our measurements of some given points X but in this equation is
given points X but in this equation is not strong but the Joint Distribution of
not strong but the Joint Distribution of what they have observed which is T and
what they have observed which is T and of this on all kilometers lovely you is
of this on all kilometers lovely you is the prior in boundary times the
the prior in boundary times the likelihood of each data point TN with
likelihood of each data point TN with known parameters so this is how the
known parameters so this is how the aggression more than reaching the
aggression more than reaching the standard sense all right this are the
standard sense all right this are the observations T the parameters WL unknown
observations T the parameters WL unknown all right
all right so for every given X but the graph
so for every given X but the graph wasn't so much and I emphasize this I
wasn't so much and I emphasize this I need to know what values of T 1 depends
need to know what values of T 1 depends on WT to defense of W so this is the
on WT to defense of W so this is the graphical representation in a period
graphical representation in a period called it becomes trivial and to make it
called it becomes trivial and to make it interesting and this is the type of
interesting and this is the type of relationship problem we did last it has
relationship problem we did last it has high parameters to me and we almost have
high parameters to me and we almost have the parameters alpha and if you also
the parameters alpha and if you also want to make this values of P n to be
want to make this values of P n to be noisy with some unknown noise Sigma
noisy with some unknown noise Sigma square then this is the very general
square then this is the very general description of a Bayesian regression
description of a Bayesian regression model okay I know there is a lot there
model okay I know there is a lot there but you may need to study
but you may need to study all right but the equation is for every
all right but the equation is for every extent all right I measured the end and
extent all right I measured the end and my actual you know function very
my actual you know function very especially from the end by some noise
especially from the end by some noise Sigma square that I got of what it is ok
Sigma square that I got of what it is ok in my regression model I need these
in my regression model I need these coefficients w all right that define my
coefficients w all right that define my regression function and
regression function and the memory is the same regardless of n
the memory is the same regardless of n little n and because I put a prior LW
little n and because I put a prior LW that has some macabre parameter salsa I
that has some macabre parameter salsa I need to basically have an arrow from
need to basically have an arrow from alpha to W so this model represents the
alpha to W so this model represents the joint distribution that looks like this
joint distribution that looks like this okay
okay again there is rare right so this is the
again there is rare right so this is the joint distribution of things I observed
joint distribution of things I observed which is this noisy function evaluations
which is this noisy function evaluations and the parameters given the inputs X
and the parameters given the inputs X now the inputs come here this kind of
now the inputs come here this kind of economic the social time given the no
economic the social time given the no single square I don't know and the Joint
single square I don't know and the Joint Distribution you can read it from the
Distribution you can read it from the graph but for those who have never seen
graph but for those who have never seen this glass before and they know about
this glass before and they know about regression basically this is the power
regression basically this is the power the Joint Distribution is the player
the Joint Distribution is the player this is you can think of this portray
this is you can think of this portray the Joint Distribution as the UH
the Joint Distribution as the UH normalize for studio all right okay so
normalize for studio all right okay so it is the prior the depends on Alpha
it is the prior the depends on Alpha like that that part of it lock and then
like that that part of it lock and then you have the right we could model that
you have the right we could model that gives you the probability of TN give an
gives you the probability of TN give an extent but that probability depends of
extent but that probability depends of the noise Sigma square and the function
the noise Sigma square and the function W so effectively we don't have to write
W so effectively we don't have to write this lengthy equation if I look at this
this lengthy equation if I look at this graph I know what is going on and I know
graph I know what is going on and I know where the problem is and that's why when
where the problem is and that's why when you've got the homework problem Subic
you've got the homework problem Subic said they know everything so let me give
said they know everything so let me give the report then you figure out what it
the report then you figure out what it means says here is an equation here's a
means says here is an equation here's a plot going away the problem to do this
plot going away the problem to do this okay so what program basically we need
okay so what program basically we need to require that you understand that this
to require that you understand that this graph implies all of this ok now in
graph implies all of this ok now in is there is nothing for predictions
is there is nothing for predictions basically it has only the information
basically it has only the information the values for training the T values and
the values for training the T values and the X values the prior tsunami but
the X values the prior tsunami but there's nothing of prediction so if you
there's nothing of prediction so if you want to add things for prediction so
want to add things for prediction so don't let's say not going to train the
don't let's say not going to train the model but also today both for a new X to
model but also today both for a new X to predict what the value of the function
predict what the value of the function is the heart this is the whole diagram
is the heart this is the whole diagram that includes the joint probability
that includes the joint probability distribution of everything so the
distribution of everything so the distribution of W the take data that you
distribution of W the take data that you gave but also the prediction T that you
gave but also the prediction T that you want to do at that point X and you
want to do at that point X and you notice it contains the ANOVA lies
notice it contains the ANOVA lies posterior which is the prior times the
posterior which is the prior times the likelihood all right this comes again
likelihood all right this comes again from what we did before but also now it
from what we did before but also now it has so this is sort of where you know
has so this is sort of where you know the posterior value you literally times
the posterior value you literally times the likelihood okay and the likelihood
the likelihood okay and the likelihood from the prediction point is between UW
from the prediction point is between UW and she was square for my