all right so we're going to continue to finish up
so we're going to continue to finish up lecture 2 with a few basic definitions
lecture 2 with a few basic definitions and then discussed about this separation
and then discussed about this separation which is sort of the most rigorous and
which is sort of the most rigorous and easiest way to take independence
easiest way to take independence relations from on directed and
relations from on directed and undirected jobs so let's pick up a few
undirected jobs so let's pick up a few slides from lecture two so this is an
slides from lecture two so this is an example but I mean I hope you take ten
example but I mean I hope you take ten minutes for somebody to type this
minutes for somebody to type this equation right which means I expect me
equation right which means I expect me to at least spend ten minutes to
to at least spend ten minutes to actually a minute
actually a minute okay and it looks awful for everything
okay and it looks awful for everything trivial but there's a lot of substance
trivial but there's a lot of substance in terms of calculation so I'm going to
in terms of calculation so I'm going to carry on everywhere in the course so I
carry on everywhere in the course so I wanted to go through this example in a
wanted to go through this example in a few more details maybe you know spend a
few more details maybe you know spend a minute or two so this note is not about
minute or two so this note is not about sex - x3 indicate and this belong will
sex - x3 indicate and this belong will be the case today in the course indicate
be the case today in the course indicate evidence so the idea is we have observed
evidence so the idea is we have observed next to X 3 that's quite a mark okay and
next to X 3 that's quite a mark okay and what we want to prove this if we have
what we want to prove this if we have observed exponent 3 X 1 and X 6 are
observed exponent 3 X 1 and X 6 are independent okay so this but the
independent okay so this but the notation rates
notation rates so again explore extreme anthems by got
so again explore extreme anthems by got some evidence and I want to know now are
some evidence and I want to know now are given the prevalence of X 1 and X 6
given the prevalence of X 1 and X 6 independent okay so effectively what we
independent okay so effectively what we need to prove is so we need X 2 and X 3
need to prove is so we need X 2 and X 3 different so we need to prove now the
different so we need to prove now the probability of matchsticks given X 1 X 2
probability of matchsticks given X 1 X 2 X 3 it's equal to the probability of
X 3 it's equal to the probability of extreme given X 2 X 3 in other way is
extreme given X 2 X 3 in other way is knowing this evidence the information of
knowing this evidence the information of X 1 doesn't sell making you about X 6
X 1 doesn't sell making you about X 6 okay
okay and obviously this brute
and obviously this brute the long way but this is what we are at
the long way but this is what we are at the course at this point ok so where the
the course at this point ok so where the headband is I noticed as the joint in
headband is I noticed as the joint in the numerator is the joint probability
the numerator is the joint probability of X 1 X 2 X 3 and X 6 which means this
of X 1 X 2 X 3 and X 6 which means this is the total joint probability polarized
is the total joint probability polarized on the graph and then obviously have to
on the graph and then obviously have to integrate how's X 4 and X 5 all right
integrate how's X 4 and X 5 all right and then in the denominator have the
and then in the denominator have the joining of X 1 X 2 X 3 which means I
joining of X 1 X 2 X 3 which means I have to integrate out X 4 X 5 and X 6
have to integrate out X 4 X 5 and X 6 okay the important thing that algorithm
okay the important thing that algorithm that is going to save us when we work
that is going to save us when we work through this type of graphs is that we
through this type of graphs is that we can put some of these summations in
can put some of these summations in words so for example you have summation
words so for example you have summation X 5 and the only terms that depends
X 5 and the only terms that depends region X 5 or goes to last term so you
region X 5 or goes to last term so you can put X 5 the situation at this point
can put X 5 the situation at this point okay and then the destination in X for
okay and then the destination in X for this x don't depend on exposure you can
this x don't depend on exposure you can push destination in here but not you
push destination in here but not you know notice there is an X 2 there right
know notice there is an X 2 there right and and that will be part of destination
and and that will be part of destination that after forming expired all right so
that after forming expired all right so the summation is person X 5 then in
the summation is person X 5 then in export and similarly in the denominator
export and similarly in the denominator is the summation X 6 and X 5 then export
is the summation X 6 and X 5 then export it's important to this is sort of the
it's important to this is sort of the main trick use to allow
main trick use to allow rocking inconsistent overly structured
rocking inconsistent overly structured water a pentacle for modulation for the
water a pentacle for modulation for the same time good luck okay alright so a
same time good luck okay alright so a lot of the things cancel out so this may
lot of the things cancel out so this may because this is a condition distribution
because this is a condition distribution distillation
distillation becomes equal to 1 regardless what
becomes equal to 1 regardless what exteriors so this and this cancel out so
exteriors so this and this cancel out so basically I'm sorry business and cancel
basically I'm sorry business and cancel out this cut is equal to 1 this is equal
out this cut is equal to 1 this is equal to 1 so basically this illustris allow
to 1 so basically this illustris allow this
you know it's one anyways so I get this big donation on the numerator which is
big donation on the numerator which is this and then there's somebody pointed
this and then there's somebody pointed me just they would he came to see me he
me just they would he came to see me he says to me why is this equal to laughs
says to me why is this equal to laughs because you notice suddenly I plug in
because you notice suddenly I plug in Ian's in addition to extreme x2 and in
Ian's in addition to extreme x2 and in addition to extra x5 I plug in an
addition to extra x5 I plug in an extreme white house
so here I have X 5 given X 3 X 5 given X 3 and then I could but this is equal to
3 and then I could but this is equal to X 5 and X 3 and X 2 what property from
X 5 and X 3 and X 2 what property from the ones we say parent no I don't see a
the ones we say parent no I don't see a parent X 2 is not the power
yeah but one of the fundamental independent properties that we stated
independent properties that we stated and we will see three times today or
and we will see three times today or four is the given the parent the node is
four is the given the parent the node is independent of of the non-descendants
independent of of the non-descendants again the no descendants of the unjust
again the no descendants of the unjust was basically plus some extra notes okay
was basically plus some extra notes okay so in this case X 2 is not an ancestor
so in this case X 2 is not an ancestor is a lone dissenter because the only
is a lone dissenter because the only access third of X 5 is X 3 and X 1 all
access third of X 5 is X 3 and X 1 all right
right x2 is a non descendant so in other ways
x2 is a non descendant so in other ways you can see the arrows you can go from 5
you can see the arrows you can go from 5 to 6
to 6 you know what to do so XQ is a non
you know what to do so XQ is a non descender ok so again we will see this
descender ok so again we will see this property together but given the power
property together but given the power and X 3 this the probability of X 5 is
and X 3 this the probability of X 5 is independent X 5 is independent of the
independent X 5 is independent of the non depends on X and similarly on the
non depends on X and similarly on the second probability I plug in what I can
second probability I plug in what I can here 3 so given X 2 and X 5 2 and 5
here 3 so given X 2 and X 5 2 and 5 which are the parents of extinct I plug
which are the parents of extinct I plug in 3 and 3 is a what it's a you know
in 3 and 3 is a what it's a you know it's obviously not descendant but it you
it's obviously not descendant but it you know it's a grandparent basically 50
know it's a grandparent basically 50 okay it's an ancestor of lectures okay
okay it's an ancestor of lectures okay so in the reason I have to plug in this
so in the reason I have to plug in this time start is because these two
time start is because these two distributions together they give me the
distributions together they give me the probability of X 5 and X 6 condition X 2
probability of X 5 and X 6 condition X 2 X 3 and if I integrate X 5 altogether
X 3 and if I integrate X 5 altogether from Reliford 6 given X 2 X 3 and then
from Reliford 6 given X 2 X 3 and then this identity has been put okay
this identity has been put okay so this way when tisha here at work is a
so this way when tisha here at work is a lot of little things that are important
lot of little things that are important basically when you work with high
basically when you work with high dimensional distributions so obviously
dimensional distributions so obviously we use the factorization of this
we use the factorization of this distribution of the graph we managed to
distribution of the graph we managed to do some of the optimizations by
do some of the optimizations by appropriately removing the stations in
appropriately removing the stations in words okay starting basically from the
words okay starting basically from the Leafs base and then eventually going to
Leafs base and then eventually going to the to the root as needed and then we
the to the root as needed and then we use the independence relation here of
use the independence relation here of the parent overall being given the parts
the parent overall being given the parts being independent no descendants and
being independent no descendants and that's it okay so let me we discuss this
that's it okay so let me we discuss this example but I want to go back to it and
example but I want to go back to it and then we will do this with again with the
then we will do this with again with the distillation algorithm so we have a case
distillation algorithm so we have a case here over wet grass sprinkler being on
here over wet grass sprinkler being on or off rain overall so basically these
or off rain overall so basically these are binary variables okay and you can
are binary variables okay and you can see various problems one the goes from
see various problems one the goes from causes to effects such as cloudy this
causes to effects such as cloudy this will cause rain and this will cause to
will cause rain and this will cause to say the glass will be wet so far forward
say the glass will be wet so far forward inference problems in B is the glass
inference problems in B is the glass weren't given that's cloudy
weren't given that's cloudy right so information from a gates in the
right so information from a gates in the direction of the graph all right so this
direction of the graph all right so this is from positive x and that's the
is from positive x and that's the problem
all right so that's a very easy problem this is very similar sort of to what you
this is very similar sort of to what you do in Bayesian statistics will be likely
do in Bayesian statistics will be likely to write if you know the parameters what
to write if you know the parameters what is the output so here this causes the
is the output so here this causes the grass to be red so you're asking what is
grass to be red so you're asking what is will become equal 1 given to the sequel
will become equal 1 given to the sequel to the more important problem is the
to the more important problem is the English problem to go for the factory
English problem to go for the factory closes so if the grass is wet somebody
closes so if the grass is wet somebody can say is it raining in other words if
can say is it raining in other words if W is equal to R is R equal to R what's
W is equal to R is R equal to R what's the probability of L even more important
the probability of L even more important questions if the grass is wet is the
questions if the grass is wet is the probability that the drain higher than
probability that the drain higher than the probability that the sprinkler
the probability that the sprinkler result okay
well actually that's a little bit different from from the one I have here
different from from the one I have here but basically seen in the same spirit
but basically seen in the same spirit and something that we will see in more
and something that we will see in more detail in the lecture today is this in a
detail in the lecture today is this in a pond so let's look at it again carefully
pond so let's look at it again carefully because we went through it but you know
because we went through it but you know what should you start getting this event
what should you start getting this event if you sleep ten times in the slide so I
if you sleep ten times in the slide so I have to condition probabilities both of
have to condition probabilities both of them stray or conditional on the grass
them stray or conditional on the grass being wet double equal to one and what I
being wet double equal to one and what I try to infer is if the sprinkler is on
try to infer is if the sprinkler is on or off and the argument here if this
or off and the argument here if this equation is correct I say given the
equation is correct I say given the damage equals one I say that if I also
damage equals one I say that if I also know that it's rain this probability is
know that it's rain this probability is less involved all right so I want you to
less involved all right so I want you to look at this equation carefully because
look at this equation carefully because what the sprinkler and the rain they
what the sprinkler and the rain they cause the glass to be wet so if somehow
cause the glass to be wet so if somehow so with this is an evidence if you have
so with this is an evidence if you have some information that they play this
some information that they play this immediately reduces the probabilities of
immediately reduces the probabilities of the sprinkler result because this
the sprinkler result because this evidence
evidence the grass is wet right so you have two
the grass is wet right so you have two possible causes here that the grass is
possible causes here that the grass is wet and if this was not there at all
wet and if this was not there at all right so we didn't have any the lower
right so we didn't have any the lower part of the graph is the probability of
part of the graph is the probability of the sprinkler is the sprinkler drain
the sprinkler is the sprinkler drain independent of each other
independent of each other if there is no no connection spacing you
if there is no no connection spacing you just have the sprinkler and Lorraine are
just have the sprinkler and Lorraine are they independent
they independent all right if they're independent now
all right if they're independent now once you observe the gas all right
once you observe the gas all right that's on vacation they are not
that's on vacation they are not independent right because knowing that
independent right because knowing that something about if it rained or not
something about if it rained or not immediately tells you something about it
immediately tells you something about it the sprinkler is all about so this is a
the sprinkler is all about so this is a weird event that it only appears in
weird event that it only appears in directional graphs and it is going to
directional graphs and it is going to vary many names explaining away is the
vary many names explaining away is the most common sense name right so
most common sense name right so observing one of the causes that the
observing one of the causes that the grass is wet it explains the way in the
grass is wet it explains the way in the fact that the sprinkler result okay sort
fact that the sprinkler result okay sort of a concept that doesn't come in other
of a concept that doesn't come in other sorts of graphs like under X undirected
sorts of graphs like under X undirected jobs
okay I personally have some additional questions you can work them out okay and
questions you can work them out okay and the same way is the first example that I
the same way is the first example that I showed you today so using which
showed you today so using which marginalization and moving the
marginalization and moving the summations in words so I'm going to
summations in words so I'm going to repeat this example shortly the local
repeat this example shortly the local property micro property that we have
property micro property that we have used them and I will try to give you
used them and I will try to give you well shapes different resistance of this
well shapes different resistance of this is that given the parts of a node V xB
is that given the parts of a node V xB is independent of the non descendents of
is independent of the non descendents of the node V and I am generalizing here
the node V and I am generalizing here I'm not saying have to be of the parents
I'm not saying have to be of the parents of V I mean I'm not saying of the
of V I mean I'm not saying of the ancestors of the am saying the
ancestors of the am saying the non-descendants
non-descendants which that is bigger the unstressed
which that is bigger the unstressed orthogonal descendants
which type is bigger the ancestral stronger non-descendants the
stronger non-descendants the non-descendants is bigger right so I can
non-descendants is bigger right so I can write this also I can take a subset of
write this also I can take a subset of anyway which are the ancestors and text
anyway which are the ancestors and text me is independent of the ancestors given
me is independent of the ancestors given the part and I want you to think if you
the part and I want you to think if you have a topological ordering the
have a topological ordering the ancestors basically are the notes that
ancestors basically are the notes that are numbered before we in the authority
are numbered before we in the authority but the non-descendants they have
but the non-descendants they have numbers that they're higher than C all
numbers that they're higher than C all right it's important here the
right it's important here the non-descendants you have numbers that
non-descendants you have numbers that have higher than this okay
have higher than this okay [Applause]
it's obviously in this case the for mr. Chappel good let's say this contest for
Chappel good let's say this contest for the student that gets different grades
the student that gets different grades and some is also from via safekeeping so
and some is also from via safekeeping so the let's accept this graph like that so
the let's accept this graph like that so we don't have to discuss all the details
we don't have to discuss all the details but basically the parents of this are
but basically the parents of this are there's no difficulty in intelligence
there's no difficulty in intelligence but you know the socialist idea is a non
but you know the socialist idea is a non descender right so wouldn't be ni this
descender right so wouldn't be ni this no this is the friend of SAT okay the
no this is the friend of SAT okay the note is something that I am discussing
note is something that I am discussing on the bottle but if you look at the
on the bottle but if you look at the great differently in terms of difficulty
great differently in terms of difficulty alright it's not independent of the
alright it's not independent of the letter right because this is this is not
letter right because this is this is not in the list of the non-descendants okay
in the list of the non-descendants okay so G is not independent well given a and
so G is not independent well given a and B
a little bit about inference and again we discuss it very fast them and we were
we discuss it very fast them and we were spent at least two lectures to discuss
spent at least two lectures to discuss inference later also right now
inference later also right now accept this as an introduction to the
accept this as an introduction to the topic not that we cover anything so for
topic not that we cover anything so for those who know about hidden Markov
those who know about hidden Markov models and I think we saw in lecture 1
models and I think we saw in lecture 1 we have a hidden state and we have some
we have a hidden state and we have some noisy let's say observations maybe the
noisy let's say observations maybe the problem is to estimate the state given
problem is to estimate the state given the information because you know when we
the information because you know when we say inference not only you try to say
say inference not only you try to say something about known observe variables
something about known observe variables but maybe there are lots of parameters
but maybe there are lots of parameters started parameters in the module for
started parameters in the module for example we would say you know you
example we would say you know you decompose the joint probability
decompose the joint probability distribution in conditionals
distribution in conditionals did you notice conditional we know the
did you notice conditional we know the probability of x2 given x1 maybe have
probability of x2 given x1 maybe have some parametric definition right you say
some parametric definition right you say this is defined by this table everything
this is defined by this table everything is alone and everything is unknown means
is alone and everything is unknown means the toast probabilities in this table
the toast probabilities in this table are those parameters theta all right so
are those parameters theta all right so there is how are you there are two
there is how are you there are two things right one is to estimate the
things right one is to estimate the scottie parameters theta and those
scottie parameters theta and those priorities theta don't increase as your
priorities theta don't increase as your dataset increases so for example in the
dataset increases so for example in the hidden Markov model you can keep
hidden Markov model you can keep collecting data this theta will remain
collecting data this theta will remain the same
the same ok and we will do those things later on
ok and we will do those things later on but the number of shaded variables
but the number of shaded variables increases the number of observation data
increases the number of observation data type increases okay so in some sense the
type increases okay so in some sense the hidden exists and treated differently
hidden exists and treated differently from computing
from computing I'm gonna sleep in the morning okay so I
I'm gonna sleep in the morning okay so I I don't know I think I'm gonna show you
I don't know I think I'm gonna show you a slide or two an archery I'm surprised
a slide or two an archery I'm surprised but this is okay I don't know why this
but this is okay I don't know why this thinking here all right it doesn't
thinking here all right it doesn't matter I think actually talks about
matter I think actually talks about evidence we're gonna go to this light
evidence we're gonna go to this light bit so this takes the parameters people
bit so this takes the parameters people so let's say you know the conditional
so let's say you know the conditional distributions change your graph so
distributions change your graph so that's why you stay conditioning or
that's why you stay conditioning or theta so we're not people in the oil
theta so we're not people in the oil problems you do not know what we face
problems you do not know what we face you have to complete but you know theta
you have to complete but you know theta and you want given some evidence so
and you want given some evidence so these are the visible notes the
these are the visible notes the invisible notes actually means like in
invisible notes actually means like in this graph the budget notes alright and
this graph the budget notes alright and then you want to say start thinking
then you want to say start thinking about the kids in the valleys to the
about the kids in the valleys to the hidden rocks so you want to compute the
hidden rocks so you want to compute the probability of XT given X 3 with fixed
probability of XT given X 3 with fixed parameters so effectively what you do is
parameters so effectively what you do is a simple calculation that we say this
a simple calculation that we say this the question there is a resonance a show
the question there is a resonance a show that you have to do the denominator all
that you have to do the denominator all right this is a very important quantity
right this is a very important quantity this is the evidence this is basically
this is the evidence this is basically tells you how probable are the data that
tells you how probable are the data that you have observed
you have observed okay so this is how you calculate the
okay so this is how you calculate the evidence and in the numerator you need
evidence and in the numerator you need the Joint Commission of the kid another
the Joint Commission of the kid another vehicle body but the way I can tell you
vehicle body but the way I can tell you and it may be on a coming slide that if
and it may be on a coming slide that if you want to post a step or a problem in
you want to post a step or a problem in this area how do we compute this
this area how do we compute this parameters theta effectively
parameters theta effectively you compute the parameters by maximizing
you compute the parameters by maximizing the evidence which is the denominator T
the evidence which is the denominator T of XT given theta all right so
okay we don't need this life we'll need some partial details so this
we'll need some partial details so this is actually I mentioned that see that
is actually I mentioned that see that you want to compute it you maximize the
you want to compute it you maximize the evidence don't pay attention to this one
evidence don't pay attention to this one here to the second what have I done here
here to the second what have I done here before I had the probability of X being
before I had the probability of X being given theta so here I wrote this this is
given theta so here I wrote this this is sort of my new evidence the
sort of my new evidence the log-likelihood data logical but I have
log-likelihood data logical but I have done something else the fact I wrote the
done something else the fact I wrote the destination over N so what is this
destination over N so what is this summation you think why is Tommy what is
summation you think why is Tommy what is N what's capital N
the hidden letters not see the Lakers here say there's only one who do
here say there's only one who do calculate the likelihood right you
calculate the likelihood right you maximize the life of the data what is
maximize the life of the data what is the assumption implicitly implied by
the assumption implicitly implied by writing like this that my data by ad
writing like this that my data by ad okay all right so so basically we're
okay all right so so basically we're trying to filter that much minus the log
trying to filter that much minus the log likelihood and also just analyze the
likelihood and also just analyze the problem which is the preeminent to
problem which is the preeminent to computing a map estimate I have added
computing a map estimate I have added here the love of the pile of theta right
here the love of the pile of theta right so this likely Qin times the prior they
so this likely Qin times the prior they give you the posterior of theta okay see
give you the posterior of theta okay see the values are not there can be anything
the values are not there can be anything any ground okay so much smizing this and
any ground okay so much smizing this and performing this problem you get you
performing this problem you get you point parameters and again we will see
point parameters and again we will see this problem in detail with a lot of
this problem in detail with a lot of numerical and analytical results later
numerical and analytical results later on in the course cause it's a good idea
on in the course cause it's a good idea to know what it means
to know what it means completing the hidden variables
completing the hidden variables parameters sleep
right and another problem that maybe we will discuss in April very close to the
will discuss in April very close to the end of the semester would be this
end of the semester would be this problem it goes under the links not
problem it goes under the links not celerity so for example in our sprinkle
celerity so for example in our sprinkle with glass problem let's say got a
with glass problem let's say got a different day somebody does observations
different day somebody does observations when it's cloudy if the sprinkler is on
when it's cloudy if the sprinkler is on it drains with the grass is wet and you
it drains with the grass is wet and you collect amounts of data on I did data so
collect amounts of data on I did data so maybe somebody will ask if I have this
maybe somebody will ask if I have this observation can you figure it out for me
observation can you figure it out for me what is the graph that represents these
what is the graph that represents these observations the only ways you know can
observations the only ways you know can you tell me that particular differential
you tell me that particular differential being cloudy of not rain defense a lot
being cloudy of not rain defense a lot with grass defense of sprinkler rain etc
this problem effectively is false as a structure learning problem and see this
structure learning problem and see this as follows G you can get the log
as follows G you can get the log likelihood of the data all right so the
likelihood of the data all right so the problem here is find the graph G that
problem here is find the graph G that maximizes the log likelihood of the day
maximizes the log likelihood of the day all right so for each graph like this
all right so for each graph like this graph for example you can go and
graph for example you can go and calculate this okay
calculate this okay and if you calculate then for many
and if you calculate then for many graphs you can say finding the graph
graphs you can say finding the graph that maximizes that and this is sort of
that maximizes that and this is sort of a penalty terms to be sure that you
a penalty terms to be sure that you don't have an overly complex graph we
don't have an overly complex graph we discussed a bit about these things in
discussed a bit about these things in the fall of the balance of
the fall of the balance of between keeping the data and complexity
between keeping the data and complexity right so you don't want to overdo it
right so you don't want to overdo it again we will come up to this problem in
again we will come up to this problem in sometimes we need a tree okay and I want
sometimes we need a tree okay and I want to introduce one more from the mental
to introduce one more from the mental concept that you may have traditional
concept that you may have traditional programming and hopefully Tuvok takes
programming and hopefully Tuvok takes notes on this that has to do with
notes on this that has to do with ancestral subject okay because this is
ancestral subject okay because this is sort of a very essential for you know
sort of a very essential for you know clever and distribution of it a graph
clever and distribution of it a graph and you want to take samples full of
and you want to take samples full of distribution there is a very efficient
distribution there is a very efficient way of doing this so remember in in in
way of doing this so remember in in in directed graphs right the distribution
directed graphs right the distribution was let's say we have a chain okay so
was let's say we have a chain okay so the probability of X 1 X 2 X 3 X 3 is
the probability of X 1 X 2 X 3 X 3 is the probability of X 1 times the
the probability of X 1 times the probability of x2 given X 2 and 5 the
probability of x2 given X 2 and 5 the probability of X 3 given X 2 or in
probability of X 3 given X 2 or in general we have a product of the
general we have a product of the probability effect and even the parents
probability effect and even the parents of all right so I'm just on something
of all right so I'm just on something the sample we take a sample of this bar
the sample we take a sample of this bar and with such 1/2 let's say X K or
and with such 1/2 let's say X K or extreme we do is you start talking
extreme we do is you start talking interest from the probability P x1 we
interest from the probability P x1 we start with the root note then the sample
start with the root note then the sample the problem there if you sample from the
the problem there if you sample from the conditional effect still given the
conditional effect still given the participant still and the part of it
participant still and the part of it still basically is x1 which already
still basically is x1 which already focused on hope right and then the
focused on hope right and then the probability of X 3 given the powers of X
probability of X 3 given the powers of X 3 which I will assume are x1 and x2
3 which I will assume are x1 and x2 right so you basically proceed from the
right so you basically proceed from the root to the left
root to the left countering first from this marginal and
countering first from this marginal and then from this conditional and this is
then from this conditional and this is called ancestral soundly
called ancestral soundly and there's many algorithm this thing in
and there's many algorithm this thing in Montecarlo reference that sort of take
Montecarlo reference that sort of take advantage of that so in other ways if
advantage of that so in other ways if the distribution is 50 dimensional near
the distribution is 50 dimensional near South Point between dimensions the
South Point between dimensions the sample from very low dimensional
sample from very low dimensional distributions by taking a particular in
distributions by taking a particular in effect they we realizations of the
effect they we realizations of the directions on the box makes a bit of
directions on the box makes a bit of sense okay so many things from election
sense okay so many things from election to with another little concept and those
to with another little concept and those within a Markov blanket okay blanket is
within a Markov blanket okay blanket is the set of nodes that render Sanofi
the set of nodes that render Sanofi conditionally independent of folder all
conditionally independent of folder all the nodes in the dock in other ways what
the nodes in the dock in other ways what is the minimal number of nodes which I
is the minimal number of nodes which I need to know so that no information from
need to know so that no information from any other nodes we make any difference
any other nodes we make any difference in my about saying something about the T
in my about saying something about the T no no T so it's the set of nodes but
no no T so it's the set of nodes but make the node conditional independence
make the node conditional independence all the other nodes in a graph okay
all the other nodes in a graph okay and so let me just tell you that what it
and so let me just tell you that what it consists of
it consists of the violence of the node the hindrance of the node and the
the hindrance of the node and the copilot of the node right because some
copilot of the node right because some node step too far and so the components
node step too far and so the components of the road so can you tell me what is
of the road so can you tell me what is the mark of blanket
the mark of blanket no talk huh I'm here 23 no there are 23
no talk huh I'm here 23 no there are 23 under father so you let me wander
under father so you let me wander without the children five six and seven
without the children five six and seven and what are the components what are the
and what are the components what are the components of five you notice Frank is a
components of five you notice Frank is a a kid seven and if you can't another
a kid seven and if you can't another father or mother for of poor is a
father or mother for of poor is a co-parent of long time okay
co-parent of long time okay now you may ask me
now you may ask me you know is there any proof of this
you know is there any proof of this place is coming and I'm going to at
place is coming and I'm going to at least highlight its being in one slide
least highlight its being in one slide to see this but then the Marfa Blanca
to see this but then the Marfa Blanca the five of the forest two and three
the five of the forest two and three right the children six and seven and
right the children six and seven and then the cool parents in this case is
then the cool parents in this case is for so basically knowing two three four
for so basically knowing two three four six and seven
six and seven no fives in the friend of node 1 okay so
no fives in the friend of node 1 okay so in essence think with this notes isolate
in essence think with this notes isolate note 5 all right
note 5 all right the separation of five from the rest of
the separation of five from the rest of the launch integral ok and and actually
the launch integral ok and and actually this thing did what this graph shows
this thing did what this graph shows let's say this is this other parent
let's say this is this other parent all right these are the children which
all right these are the children which are the copilot from knowing all this
are the copilot from knowing all this information separate this is what's a
information separate this is what's a blanket which sort of to isolate X from
blanket which sort of to isolate X from the rest of the graph an extremely sort
the rest of the graph an extremely sort of important idea here all right the
of important idea here all right the drawing parents and again everybody
drawing parents and again everybody forgets not the components come in the
forgets not the components come in the picture okay like you know the fourth
picture okay like you know the fourth year list extremely important so we do
year list extremely important so we do this example
this example so any highlight the point okay it's you
so any highlight the point okay it's you know a lot of these things terms of
know a lot of these things terms of their authors but I want you to sort of
their authors but I want you to sort of realize that they don't come from north
realize that they don't come from north where there is some common sense
where there is some common sense derivation there so let's say
we know the probability we won't me all the relevant notes but no die what's the
the relevant notes but no die what's the problem being to fix all right remember
problem being to fix all right remember we said the market market is the
we said the market market is the strength of the notes the thighs the
strength of the notes the thighs the lays know the eye from the rest of the
lays know the eye from the rest of the notes so you need to know from what is
notes so you need to know from what is this perform infinity depends on carry
this perform infinity depends on carry put it basically excited given all the
put it basically excited given all the other notes and what I'm asking is do I
other notes and what I'm asking is do I really need all the other notes or some
really need all the other notes or some of us you know it's basically we come to
of us you know it's basically we come to they are important so when I could not
they are important so when I could not is I wrote this as the joint probability
is I wrote this as the joint probability of for the notes in the mouth in the
of for the notes in the mouth in the track event and here he kept - I have
track event and here he kept - I have the probability of list of quarter notes
the probability of list of quarter notes Mathari so I have to materialize my out
Mathari so I have to materialize my out so I use the factorization on the top is
so I use the factorization on the top is an authorization on the bottom okay
an authorization on the bottom okay and now though I don't want you to need
and now though I don't want you to need anything here right so don't get
anything here right so don't get polluted by reading look this ratio and
polluted by reading look this ratio and figure out what terms you know sometimes
figure out what terms you know sometimes are going to cancel from the numerator
are going to cancel from the numerator and denominator what is going to be left
and denominator what is going to be left there so here I have the whole
there so here I have the whole distribution and they're like have X
distribution and they're like have X trying to graveyard so what is left what
trying to graveyard so what is left what is what are the common terms doesn't
is what are the common terms doesn't disappear so that this X I who made a
disappear so that this X I who made a time dependent
time dependent given this Markov Blanca dimension so
given this Markov Blanca dimension so what you know term some disappearing
what you know term some disappearing from this ratio
look for you know even better what notes are they going to stay in that
are they going to stay in that calculation
with my mind that's not very good
okay so there is an integration care of its high right so let's see in in this
its high right so let's see in in this product there is a distribution of X my
product there is a distribution of X my given the parent right ladies
given the parent right ladies distributions that involves the children
distributions that involves the children given the politics i right
given the politics i right and those distributions involve also the
and those distributions involve also the copilot you see that I mean somehow here
copilot you see that I mean somehow here because an integrative annex I write in
because an integrative annex I write in the denominator anything that relates
the denominator anything that relates book starring of the top has to stay
book starring of the top has to stay there and what this relations contain at
there and what this relations contain at tie is the distribution of X i given its
tie is the distribution of X i given its parents right
parents right nice ghostie nodes and then the
nice ghostie nodes and then the distribution of the children of X I in
distribution of the children of X I in that differential from the co-pilot
that differential from the co-pilot so this children depends on the trolley
so this children depends on the trolley and the copilot you see those are the
and the copilot you see those are the only distributions of any display yep so
only distributions of any display yep so basically this type of nodes that you
basically this type of nodes that you see there are the mark of Naga
now the so the market wanted basically gives a very efficient way for computing
gives a very efficient way for computing the probability of a now given all the
the probability of a now given all the other nodes all right because we said
other nodes all right because we said this probably the only depends on the
this probably the only depends on the parents for parents and children okay
parents for parents and children okay and I did it here one example of the
and I did it here one example of the probability of X 5 given all the other
probability of X 5 given all the other I'm sorry given all the nodes with type
I'm sorry given all the nodes with type right you can write this reverse the
right you can write this reverse the factorization of the Joint Distribution
factorization of the Joint Distribution the only terms of pay is expired given
the only terms of pay is expired given experience three right five depends on
experience three right five depends on the parents children depending on five
the parents children depending on five and three right and then notice what
and three right and then notice what else we never have several depending on
else we never have several depending on five and six the parlance and the
five and six the parlance and the copilot for a case why I indicated here
copilot for a case why I indicated here for five states in this calculation can
for five states in this calculation can here well it's written here again those
here well it's written here again those who have taken courses for should the
who have taken courses for should the computational statistics course in which
computational statistics course in which means in the fall we recognize basically
means in the fall we recognize basically business the distribution we need to do
business the distribution we need to do get something right so this is the
get something right so this is the cognition we need to give to give
cognition we need to give to give something and you see a nice
something and you see a nice fertilization to keep in mind the sort
fertilization to keep in mind the sort of idea so far instead of something and
of idea so far instead of something and the concept of Markov blanket welcome to
the concept of Markov blanket welcome to camp with a very nice implementation of
camp with a very nice implementation of get started
get started so we will assure give you homework from
so we will assure give you homework from this soon okay
this soon okay so let me summarize and then we're done
so let me summarize and then we're done with lecture to every know given the you
with lecture to every know given the you know descendants okay now try moving the
know descendants okay now try moving the parent is independent of the
parent is independent of the non-disabled and I assume for the
non-disabled and I assume for the parents and the predecessors are a
parents and the predecessors are a subset of the you know descendants so T
subset of the you know descendants so T is independent of the three defendants
is independent of the three defendants given the powers and so this is called
given the powers and so this is called the directive local Markov property this
the directive local Markov property this is called the order Markov property we
is called the order Markov property we can appreciate why it's for London
can appreciate why it's for London because in essence this knowledge of
because in essence this knowledge of numbering that is before the number of T
so this local property L immediately gives to you the order Markov property
gives to you the order Markov property because this is a subset of the known
because this is a subset of the known dependents what is interesting is if
dependents what is interesting is if this property is true then also the
this property is true then also the other properties to all right and that
other properties to all right and that makes a bit of calculation if you are
makes a bit of calculation if you are interested you can read this move for
interested you can read this move for the derivation so effectively this still
the derivation so effectively this still Markov properties are equivalent and
Markov properties are equivalent and both of them can be shown that they are
both of them can be shown that they are equivalent with a polarization that we
equivalent with a polarization that we have seen you know talking in lecture
have seen you know talking in lecture one
one electric drums so again a local property
electric drums so again a local property an order Markov property and this
an order Markov property and this factorization you can feel from one of
factorization you can feel from one of them you can prove what the other ones
them you can prove what the other ones and the other way around
and the other way around remember in some of the little examples
remember in some of the little examples we did without the information we were
we did without the information we were proving you know sort of identities but
proving you know sort of identities but also you can prove that starting with
also you can prove that starting with any of this you can solve a district
any of this you can solve a district relationship one can
I have to drink some coffee at lunchtime because from my system it's gotten at
because from my system it's gotten at this time and without it we may still
this time and without it we may still equally in this little here okay but one
equally in this little here okay but one day I'm sure that you see all the coffee
day I'm sure that you see all the coffee coming on the top of me not paying
coming on the top of me not paying attention because talking and drinking
attention because talking and drinking coffees not the jungle can be continued
coffees not the jungle can be continued so drinking wine isn't talking
so drinking wine isn't talking alright and this is going to be a little
alright and this is going to be a little bit weird it's not very public is
bit weird it's not very public is basically the graphical way to figure
basically the graphical way to figure out what independence relations you have
out what independence relations you have in a graph okay so we want to dis have a
in a graph okay so we want to dis have a calculation so I'll go under the name
calculation so I'll go under the name this separation is what is going to
this separation is what is going to allow us to figure out independence in
allow us to figure out independence in the graph so I have to admit when you
the graph so I have to admit when you first see them this may sound a little
first see them this may sound a little bit weird the only thing I'm going to
bit weird the only thing I'm going to say just our homes because Rose has to
say just our homes because Rose has to decide and you can secular satisfied
decide and you can secular satisfied then you can test independence
then you can test independence relationships
relationships so this'll look like something will
so this'll look like something will drive we cannot for this reason you can
drive we cannot for this reason you can solve that they're equivalent to this
solve that they're equivalent to this local mark of properties that we
local mark of properties that we discussed before and this will go on the
discussed before and this will go on the name the separation so definitions there
name the separation so definitions there is way too much information that's right
is way too much information that's right so let's go line by line and undirected
so let's go line by line and undirected path is this separated by a set of nodes
path is this separated by a set of nodes II so he clearly implies the notes that
II so he clearly implies the notes that I know about the evidence so an
I know about the evidence so an undirected graph is the separated if at
undirected graph is the separated if at least one of the Tony Hawk so in the
least one of the Tony Hawk so in the various graphs that you see this is my
various graphs that you see this is my evidence right this is my evidence
evidence right this is my evidence so here the path from X to Z right the
so here the path from X to Z right the arrows point in this way but
arrows point in this way but can also find the opposite way so it can
can also find the opposite way so it can be this or that so in this case we say
be this or that so in this case we say that x and z are be separated from Y if
that x and z are be separated from Y if Y is observed okay so a lot of times
Y is observed okay so a lot of times what you say basically is whenever this
what you say basically is whenever this node and you see the arrow converging
node and you see the arrow converging this chance and tail so if you have
this chance and tail so if you have heads entailed already obtained and
heads entailed already obtained and shares the other way around and this is
shares the other way around and this is an observed node the next year this
an observed node the next year this operator is given Y okay mr. Paretti so
operator is given Y okay mr. Paretti so you can you can start getting the
you can you can start getting the concept right means the Texans they're
concept right means the Texans they're independent really given Y reinstitute
independent really given Y reinstitute not really rich Z from X by going
not really rich Z from X by going through the evidence known why okay and
through the evidence known why okay and this sort of little blocks that you see
this sort of little blocks that you see on the bottom that's what they indicate
on the bottom that's what they indicate but somehow the path from X to Z is
but somehow the path from X to Z is broke if you observe why okay I'm
broke if you observe why okay I'm throwing a lots of terminology there but
throwing a lots of terminology there but so this is one part of the definition if
so this is one part of the definition if you have this situation and wise observe
you have this situation and wise observe okay excellent zero disparate from Y
okay excellent zero disparate from Y another case is when if you have a stock
another case is when if you have a stock situation right so this is the parent
situation right so this is the parent pointing into two children so again we
pointing into two children so again we contain support and wise and evidence
contain support and wise and evidence excellency then and be separated by Y so
excellency then and be separated by Y so again you notice the path is indicated
again you notice the path is indicated here products the Z is blocked because Y
here products the Z is blocked because Y doesn't allow this to go through
doesn't allow this to go through and try to go from X to Z or from seed
and try to go from X to Z or from seed to X the pocketbook have instead what's
to X the pocketbook have instead what's the relation with independence for
the relation with independence for anything I'm defining I'm just giving
anything I'm defining I'm just giving some definitions right but we can
some definitions right but we can motivate what these definitions are
motivate what these definitions are going to be about okay so again we will
going to be about okay so again we will show that in this case given Y and
show that in this case given Y and sharing this fork structure with Y given
sharing this fork structure with Y given being in the evidence actions here
being in the evidence actions here conditionally independent given Y and
conditionally independent given Y and then of course we have this explaining
then of course we have this explaining away situation where we have X and G be
away situation where we have X and G be the causes of the same Y right so the
the causes of the same Y right so the arrows bullet at this is a restructure
arrows bullet at this is a restructure and notice that the patient suddenly
and notice that the patient suddenly changed
changed it says they contain service trucks like
it says they contain service trucks like that and we say the text in Z are
that and we say the text in Z are dissipated if the destruction like math
dissipated if the destruction like math and y is not in the evidence why is not
and y is not in the evidence why is not observed so in other ways the path from
observed so in other ways the path from X to Z is block if y is not a safe
perfect why is nothing set okay
so basically if wise not observed we will see in the comics life that
will see in the comics life that excellency you know are they will give
excellency you know are they will give this example what did we say for X and Z
this example what did we say for X and Z alone what did we say there were
alone what did we say there were handsome undefended all right so
handsome undefended all right so obviously this wise and himself I know
obviously this wise and himself I know not the excellency of artillery
not the excellency of artillery independent once I observed why they
independent once I observed why they become dependent okay
so before we had done you you know XY &amp; z notes but you can tell relies this to
z notes but you can tell relies this to a set of notes or fear percentage we
a set of notes or fear percentage we don't say we say that in a given graph
don't say we say that in a given graph is dissipated from a set of notes be
is dissipated from a set of notes be given some evidence on the step of no 60
given some evidence on the step of no 60 if basically this is be separated from
if basically this is be separated from the given e so to try to mystical for
the given e so to try to mystical for any note way to an old in me to be
any note way to an old in me to be evidence knows that part is block okay
evidence knows that part is block okay using the rules that we have seen so so
using the rules that we have seen so so this may involve a small angle it right
this may involve a small angle it right I mean the thing is you know when you
I mean the thing is you know when you start putting this topics in place right
start putting this topics in place right 350 years ago when people doing that you
350 years ago when people doing that you can call anything anything you know so
can call anything anything you know so the idea is I don't know the history I
the idea is I don't know the history I think is very possible mr. Vaile
think is very possible mr. Vaile reference 98 introduced responsible very
reference 98 introduced responsible very small so the idea is to to graphically
small so the idea is to to graphically business operation the probable and you
business operation the probable and you try to shape a ball that you throw text
try to shape a ball that you throw text can reach Z all right and you have some
can reach Z all right and you have some rules the best date tells you when the
rules the best date tells you when the ball can pass through and evidence we
ball can pass through and evidence we all don't know
all don't know okay and so if you can read Z then
okay and so if you can read Z then basically the path is not block if you
basically the path is not block if you cannot reach the path is blocked and the
cannot reach the path is blocked and the notes are independent given the evidence
notes are independent given the evidence so basically this is the same picture
so basically this is the same picture that we had before but again think
that we had before but again think you're throwing it home and it's
you're throwing it home and it's important on the northeast a song called
important on the northeast a song called the most in travel offers it to be as
the most in travel offers it to be as directions right
directions right and this has to do with the fact that
and this has to do with the fact that you know like in this case the arrows
you know like in this case the arrows can look the other direction as well you
can look the other direction as well you get the same result so the most can have
get the same result so the most can have an opposite to the s directions so
an opposite to the s directions so here's the case given why if you throw a
here's the case given why if you throw a ball is blocked here so actions here be
ball is blocked here so actions here be separated
separated if Y is not given the ball can go
if Y is not given the ball can go through you can go from X to Z here if Y
through you can go from X to Z here if Y is given to the spot from X Y Z is
is given to the spot from X Y Z is blocked so if you you know the monster
blocked so if you you know the monster me back so actions here independent
me back so actions here independent basically given Y I'm just giving you
basically given Y I'm just giving you this you know because this is what we're
this you know because this is what we're gonna use again if Y is not given then
gonna use again if Y is not given then the ball can go from X to Z no problem
the ball can go from X to Z no problem and then this is the is explaining a way
and then this is the is explaining a way situation excellency the path is blocked
situation excellency the path is blocked to Y if Y is not observed was very
to Y if Y is not observed was very important it's observe then you can go
important it's observe then you can go from X to Z so if you remember those
from X to Z so if you remember those rules basically you can test
rules basically you can test independence in any directed drop
independence in any directed drop without doing any calculations budget
without doing any calculations budget okay now when I say you can do any
okay now when I say you can do any calculations obviously books given with
calculations obviously books given with 135 but actually they give you the right
135 but actually they give you the right answers right so maybe I will do a
answers right so maybe I will do a trivial example you guys can do a more
trivial example you guys can do a more complicated example but before you do an
complicated example but before you do an example I also need to tell you oh this
example I also need to tell you oh this is the same slide but you have to
is the same slide but you have to confirm under conditions so what happens
confirm under conditions so what happens is the bone which is the root node of
is the bone which is the root node of the list and so there are pusher to
the list and so there are pusher to boundary conditions if you reach
boundary conditions if you reach Nick node and the myth note is observed
Nick node and the myth note is observed the note comes back all right if this is
the note comes back all right if this is observed basically the more the us the
observed basically the more the us the ball okay now if the error goes in the
ball okay now if the error goes in the other direction okay so in this case if
other direction okay so in this case if Y is different the path is blocked all
Y is different the path is blocked all right so the ball doesn't return back
right so the ball doesn't return back the opposite would interfere
the opposite would interfere and if Y's are observed the mall
and if Y's are observed the mall compartment this way we need something
compartment this way we need something to have to stop the algorithm dot
to have to stop the algorithm dot something it is listed among the
something it is listed among the relationship when we do some examples
relationship when we do some examples remind me to come back on the slide 29
remind me to come back on the slide 29 so you can see that through these
so you can see that through these boundary conditions actually do make
boundary conditions actually do make Church okay so this is what we were
Church okay so this is what we were talking on the previous slide right this
talking on the previous slide right this is exactly this situation here so if Y
is exactly this situation here so if Y is observable x mark if Y will observe
is observable x mark if Y will observe the model block so let's consider the
the model block so let's consider the following situation we have this V
following situation we have this V structure-wise are observed all right
structure-wise are observed all right don't pay attention to this
don't pay attention to this the walls are observed so if I found
the walls are observed so if I found from it what is going to happen here
you can tell em f of X in this case we're more definitely the answer is no
we're more definitely the answer is no all right this is what okay so the
all right this is what okay so the poppies blow however let's consider how
poppies blow however let's consider how many K Y is not observed but let's say
many K Y is not observed but let's say it's children of Y or some noise in the
it's children of Y or some noise in the presentation of eyes observe then with
presentation of eyes observe then with if accomplice so religion is why the
if accomplice so religion is why the Magnaflow but now what you seen desired
Magnaflow but now what you seen desired then what happens in an in a and a heavy
then what happens in an in a and a heavy disclosed sentiment analysis for y prime
disclosed sentiment analysis for y prime is a noisy version of Y effectively y
is a noisy version of Y effectively y prime is a noisy version of Y observing
prime is a noisy version of Y observing y Prime's the stainless observing Y and
y Prime's the stainless observing Y and when you observed Y what confidence to
when you observed Y what confidence to remote
you remember
so when you observe live right if it's not vote for X you can reach you can
not vote for X you can reach you can reach Z okay so this is a tricky
reach Z okay so this is a tricky situation
situation all right to you when you have this
all right to you when you have this restructure this explaining away and you
restructure this explaining away and you have something here an observation we
have something here an observation we have evidence from the children of Y
have evidence from the children of Y pretty effectively the same as having
pretty effectively the same as having observations on Y itself because
observations on Y itself because basically this unlocks the path from X
basically this unlocks the path from X to Z all right so let's write this and
to Z all right so let's write this and see that this is not just released but
see that this is not just released but somehow they do make sense so let's
somehow they do make sense so let's start with the most trivial case so
start with the most trivial case so we're going to take this alright song
we're going to take this alright song writing my dissolution Direction Y and
writing my dissolution Direction Y and VST effects py given X P of Z given Y
VST effects py given X P of Z given Y all right so all right so we condition
all right so all right so we condition on Y so next if I am evidence of Y what
on Y so next if I am evidence of Y what happens between X and Z and I'm just
happens between X and Z and I'm just using you know from the numerator little
using you know from the numerator little bit of XY and Z and denominator
bit of XY and Z and denominator convinced of Y this is P of x and y so
convinced of Y this is P of x and y so this is no P of x given Y so you notice
this is no P of x given Y so you notice that excellency become independent of
that excellency become independent of given Y right okay so when we have this
given Y right okay so when we have this you know observed and it can contain
you know observed and it can contain here had some pain and observe then the
here had some pain and observe then the path is blocked and that's we you know
path is blocked and that's we you know we call this graph separation right and
we call this graph separation right and it's equivalent to
it's equivalent to this independent simulation would be
this independent simulation would be seamless a question so the idea here is
seamless a question so the idea here is rather than having to prove an equation
rather than having to prove an equation like that if you can prove that the note
like that if you can prove that the note section Z are not separated all right
section Z are not separated all right and the rien tation of the arrow scale
and the rien tation of the arrow scale don't even make a big difference okay
don't even make a big difference okay stretch he'll use the biggest mole
stretch he'll use the biggest mole algorithm for something from extra
algorithm for something from extra between zero and that part is blocked
between zero and that part is blocked then excellency are independent even why
then excellency are independent even why okay Felicia Rizal would it improve to
okay Felicia Rizal would it improve to check this permission independent spirit
okay you know this is the Michael che all right first folder and it says given
all right first folder and it says given X I X I plus 1 is independent of for the
X I X I plus 1 is independent of for the previous exercise right this the
previous exercise right this the first-order Markov chain can give me an
first-order Markov chain can give me an argument of this being through using the
argument of this being through using the separation however going to stop this
separation however going to stop this that this is you know so let's say in
that this is you know so let's say in this case x-rays the evidence for my
this case x-rays the evidence for my eyes 3 then I say that basically what we
eyes 3 then I say that basically what we need to prove is to let's say that X for
need to prove is to let's say that X for all right exploits in the final text 1
you actually you know so okay so this is the evidence right so we improve our
the evidence right so we improve our exports in defender of x2 and x1 Topshop
exports in defender of x2 and x1 Topshop are you going to drink this how you
are you going to drink this how you gonna prove that given explain that
gonna prove that given explain that exports independent effects to without
exports independent effects to without doing any calculations
but remove the algorithm that makes war angry
so what situation do we have killed with the arrows in this evidence no this is
the arrows in this evidence no this is what Henson tell you all right so if you
what Henson tell you all right so if you throw a ball look and no trees observe
throw a ball look and no trees observe what happens when you throw the ball
what happens when you throw the ball from x264 the pocket no all right so
from x264 the pocket no all right so it's sports independent XP sing with me
it's sports independent XP sing with me if I put a little extra on when it rates
if I put a little extra on when it rates extreme I want to probe in the pencil
extreme I want to probe in the pencil for X 4 for X 1 so if I throw and we're
for X 4 for X 1 so if I throw and we're from extraordinaire its X 3
from extraordinaire its X 3 yes because this node is not observe but
yes because this node is not observe but popular tax free
ok so now this tutorial example I think you take it for granted but you know if
you take it for granted but you know if I start making fancy connections between
I start making fancy connections between the norms mister very easy algorithm to
the norms mister very easy algorithm to prove independence without having to do
prove independence without having to do any calculations by hand and mayors
any calculations by hand and mayors against assuming to give you a platform
against assuming to give you a platform work to work on this thing okay so all
work to work on this thing okay so all right an issue because it's sort of an
right an issue because it's sort of an important way of doing this ok again
important way of doing this ok again showing in this case with a dispatcher
showing in this case with a dispatcher right with a tail and tail and observe
okay what no I'm sorry it's okay it's not at this time sir
not at this time sir this is this is the four o'clock sir
this is this is the four o'clock sir rights and fail and fail and observe the
rights and fail and fail and observe the path is blocked for I didn't observe the
path is blocked for I didn't observe the part is unblocked okay so in this case
part is unblocked okay so in this case of the fourth given why actions they're
of the fourth given why actions they're independent
independent if why some observe that you know if in
if why some observe that you know if in this case you can see that the
this case you can see that the probability affection see margarine
probability affection see margarine basically you know this is not equal to
basically you know this is not equal to P of X x gives independence
and again vistas this is the most difficult case certificate I have two
difficult case certificate I have two causes of why if the part is blocked
causes of why if the part is blocked when y is nothing self that's the
when y is nothing self that's the opposite from all the previous cases if
opposite from all the previous cases if Y is observed in the both can walk
Y is observed in the both can walk through all right
okay so again goes to its opposite from the other case x and z are marginally
the other case x and z are marginally independent but you can try to establish
independent but you can try to establish basically initial independence given the
basically initial independence given the evidence Y X is not independent you okay
evidence Y X is not independent you okay and we talked about this let's
and we talked about this let's concentrate on this on this example
concentrate on this on this example right they need anything because you
right they need anything because you know I have no idea with the space here
know I have no idea with the space here okay because we need to think together
okay because we need to think together here so you can help me as you aspiring
here so you can help me as you aspiring speaking here so in this case I have
speaking here so in this case I have nothing observed and I thought well for
nothing observed and I thought well for next can you tell me what happens step
next can you tell me what happens step by step and maybe if you don't remember
by step and maybe if you don't remember we go back to all the previous slides
from from X and I want to see where this not hasn't involved
not hasn't involved so what is my extraction phase of the
so what is my extraction phase of the structure all right so this is
structure all right so this is unobserved alright so what happens to
unobserved alright so what happens to the both look nervous to the to the path
the both look nervous to the to the path here when I look at the two arrows being
here when I look at the two arrows being down like that
can I go from X to Y no because those are observed can I move over from X to W
can I go from X to W yeah because mrs. Stetson tale based on observed life is
Stetson tale based on observed life is Pakistan block okay then I mixed loudly
Pakistan block okay then I mixed loudly and what happens to the volume down to
and what happens to the volume down to you when that me is not observed goes up
you when that me is not observed goes up so the ball is lost they never come back
so the ball is lost they never come back okay tell me now what happens when I
okay tell me now what happens when I observed that me you
observed that me you so obviously the volume there all right
so obviously the volume there all right you know we don't say anything
you know we don't say anything stimulus situation so the ball comes
stimulus situation so the ball comes here okay what happens this from zero
here okay what happens this from zero from our bounding conditions the mall
from our bounding conditions the mall comes back and then this one observed
comes back and then this one observed the wall was too wide to here
the wall was too wide to here what can we say about x and y given W
so we have this RR is the x and y in the separated and both the list can reach Y
separated and both the list can reach Y so what can you tell me when that B is
so what can you tell me when that B is observed so in order for next year it's
observed so in order for next year it's Y all right so this is the Ritz ability
Y all right so this is the Ritz ability condition so annoying W is more or less
condition so annoying W is more or less the same as knowing easy and you can
the same as knowing easy and you can remember from the destructor
remember from the destructor knowing this the evidence makes notes x
knowing this the evidence makes notes x and y what makes them dependent right
and y what makes them dependent right because anything we say about X or Y
because anything we say about X or Y imply something about yoga okay
imply something about yoga okay all right so here the take apart is any
all right so here the take apart is any information that you get down from
information that you get down from chamber is basically four five eighths
chamber is basically four five eighths half points and this is the tricky part
half points and this is the tricky part for this graphs
I know but the idea is right we're trying to see you know when interesting
trying to see you know when interesting to go back from X to X right there is
to go back from X to X right there is you know we want to stick its the
you know we want to stick its the volcano rich wife Theresa part ever
volcano rich wife Theresa part ever no Peppa okay
this is an example that you read if your target stays the same things and this is
target stays the same things and this is a very nice example from Bishop's book
a very nice example from Bishop's book actually about buzzes compilations for
actually about buzzes compilations for this explaining away paste okay so I
this explaining away paste okay so I remember I go through all the answer bra
remember I go through all the answer bra and I believe I'm not sure but I think
and I believe I'm not sure but I think one of their former chrome works has
one of their former chrome works has this something like this okay so there
this something like this okay so there is a former problem but so certainly do
is a former problem but so certainly do this homework and when we see the
this homework and when we see the algebra algebra they say here in wrote
algebra algebra they say here in wrote you've got zero point 1 1 1 then 0 1 1 1
you've got zero point 1 1 1 then 0 1 1 1 because you will appreciate
because you will appreciate but this numbers is not magic right
but this numbers is not magic right there's not become basically by this
there's not become basically by this condition of of abilities that we assume
condition of of abilities that we assume them known and this prior okay so when
them known and this prior okay so when you do this algebra so in this case it's
you do this algebra so in this case it's basically to the same example that we
basically to the same example that we will discuss in with the rain case
will discuss in with the rain case alright so knowing that this is 0
alright so knowing that this is 0 somehow saying something about B
somehow saying something about B produces the probability that this left
produces the probability that this left is 0 all right since we explained the
is 0 all right since we explained the observation that I receive from Z this
observation that I receive from Z this is a very nice example please
is a very nice example please winded and do that calculation okay
can you show me with the biggest Milan written that they even have right as my
written that they even have right as my evidence is independent of B given a
evidence is independent of B given a tell me what you will do with the
tell me what you will do with the biggest ball algorithm
so terrible I fell beyond the rules can I reach and if this is true right mr.
I reach and if this is true right mr. Sanford the ball is blocked right so no
Sanford the ball is blocked right so no no wait because we believe we cannot
no wait because we believe we cannot think it's like eating and blind being
think it's like eating and blind being right Oh checking your phone when you
right Oh checking your phone when you walk and then you expect me to pay
walk and then you expect me to pay attention to you right the same thing
attention to you right the same thing so a independent big given up you know
so a independent big given up you know tell me about the ball so I like the
tell me about the ball so I like the ball I say if I bought from a what
ball I say if I bought from a what happens to it when it comes here then
happens to it when it comes here then the whole roll up left alright so the
the whole roll up left alright so the motor is blocked right right because
motor is blocked right right because this is unobserved okay so this part is
this is unobserved okay so this part is blocked but anyways we verify was not
blocked but anyways we verify was not the case and then one goes up there
the case and then one goes up there because this to observe this part will
because this to observe this part will also be blocked right so you know but
also be blocked right so you know but not there
okay this is sort of the same language or different waters exactly the same
or different waters exactly the same thing okay these are all the rules
now you may ask me why are the slides not liquid because you know sometimes I
not liquid because you know sometimes I in here let's say 2005 I ride the slide
in here let's say 2005 I ride the slide and that I forgot and then you have 2015
and that I forgot and then you have 2015 I prefer something else and and then you
I prefer something else and and then you get it's nothing it's nice but you know
get it's nothing it's nice but you know what I like to keep that because when
what I like to keep that because when you read them yes you put an extra page
you read them yes you put an extra page but you may get something from the
but you may get something from the different slide that seems to be the
different slide that seems to be the same but may have something different
same but may have something different there okay
don't be pissed so some simple example just before we
so some simple example just before we finish the election today right we
finish the election today right we really have to take this
really have to take this so this is the proportion if you collect
so this is the proportion if you collect data from iid data with little
data from iid data with little innovation and something new what can be
innovation and something new what can be something else actually this can be an
something else actually this can be an indicator variables no tells you what
indicator variables no tells you what Gaussian in a mixture here's but the
Gaussian in a mixture here's but the idea here is would you look at the
idea here is would you look at the probability of the data so these all the
probability of the data so these all the collections of data x1 to xn each of
collections of data x1 to xn each of these the excise given you is
these the excise given you is independent alright so this is the iid
independent alright so this is the iid assumption that you guys use in every
assumption that you guys use in every statistics course you pay and the idea
statistics course you pay and the idea here is representation a graphical
here is representation a graphical representation of the I I need property
representation of the I I need property is the simple graph with the city so can
is the simple graph with the city so can somebody tell me just you know why this
somebody tell me just you know why this graph basically invent this independence
graph basically invent this independence relation otherwise my x1 is independent
relation otherwise my x1 is independent of X 2
what is the only way to go from x1 to x2 in this case the broken arrow right
so wait when do I get this
so don't get coaster scared okay because my exes are my date obviously have to
my exes are my date obviously have to mark them because that's my evidence
mark them because that's my evidence right but when I write this relation and
right but when I write this relation and I'm looking at this Malaysian my
I'm looking at this Malaysian my evidence from public speakings what
evidence from public speakings what right you know what variable when I say
right you know what variable when I say three of the given moon right so if I
three of the given moon right so if I want to welcome x1 to x2 I have to go
want to welcome x1 to x2 I have to go through the evidence new alright so I've
through the evidence new alright so I've got another 2x2 the path from here is
got another 2x2 the path from here is blocked all right
blocked all right because I already know the values of me
because I already know the values of me okay so you need to start get years to
okay so you need to start get years to do this little drops basically that
do this little drops basically that they're not just a sort of dummy doctor
they're not just a sort of dummy doctor relations but they embed from holistic
relations but they embed from holistic relationship so in essence when you have
relationship so in essence when you have this graph immediately this is their
this graph immediately this is their right so it's not one of the other once
right so it's not one of the other once you plot it this is what immediately you
you plot it this is what immediately you are implying that you have the iid
are implying that you have the iid assumption
assumption okay and you can obviously you know hear
okay and you can obviously you know hear that if you might analyze me out all
that if you might analyze me out all right
right that marginally basically you can P of
that marginally basically you can P of me
me it doesn't factor is P of X 1 P of X 2
it doesn't factor is P of X 1 P of X 2 etc okay and so there's no really
etc okay and so there's no really all right the basically you cannot you
all right the basically you cannot you cannot approve any independence so let's
cannot approve any independence so let's do
so again please maybe one of those trivial example so let's prove this all
trivial example so let's prove this all right so we have evidence x2 and we want
right so we have evidence x2 and we want to prove that X for two different
to prove that X for two different effects on an extinct
effects on an extinct okay so excuse my red Nestor we want to
okay so excuse my red Nestor we want to say exports in the final factoid exit so
say exports in the final factoid exit so with the biggest mall algorithm rather
with the biggest mall algorithm rather than going to do
than going to do all right so given X still we need to
all right so given X still we need to prove those exports in the panel of X 1
prove those exports in the panel of X 1 and X 6 so let's not miss X 1 the proof
and X 6 so let's not miss X 1 the proof independence of export X 1 where your
independence of export X 1 where your own role in the boy can go this way or
own role in the boy can go this way or can go all the way like that so if the
can go all the way like that so if the ball goes this way what happens here
ball goes this way what happens here you know if the world goes this way then
you know if the world goes this way then you know yes yes yes
well you tell me what happens there
so can I go from X chicks can I go to x2
so we can know okay
but remember next text is the way that I say is a mismatch sir
say is a mismatch sir all right so it's not observed it's not
all right so it's not observed it's not observable missed
if x6 is no observe what happens it's no okay and then from X to X is right this
okay and then from X to X is right this is given and and then I'm working on
is given and and then I'm working on this way and then it's you know
this way and then it's you know protected too so this is true so you
protected too so this is true so you know if you write to this sort of this
know if you write to this sort of this calculation with the factorization of
calculation with the factorization of the probability distribution it will
the probability distribution it will take you basically half an hour or
take you basically half an hour or something
something if you dress this relationship you do
if you dress this relationship you do they may be lost by it you don't have to
they may be lost by it you don't have to bother again so let's finish so X 1
bother again so let's finish so X 1 given X clinics the exponents in the
given X clinics the exponents in the benefit sticks okay so it's no exponents
benefit sticks okay so it's no exponents in the time no fixed is there two parts
in the time no fixed is there two parts one part is this way is this parking lot
one part is this way is this parking lot yes right now is this part yes not here
yes right now is this part yes not here it states that given X for Linux state
it states that given X for Linux state x2 is not independent extreme so given X
x2 is not independent extreme so given X 1 X 6 roll it a little more like this
1 X 6 roll it a little more like this the more can walk from this distraction
the more can walk from this distraction why because this is observed then the
why because this is observed then the more can go there can go to explain
more can go there can go to explain there is a path so this going the
there is a path so this going the backwards
backwards okay
all right so this is the biggest model thing in action for a must know
thing in action for a must know computation problems okay
computation problems okay let me just finish what's 144 so I don't
let me just finish what's 144 so I don't know what's my last slide because I had
know what's my last slide because I had and we're going to come back from on
and we're going to come back from on this would do the slides on Thursday but
this would do the slides on Thursday but I went basically to summarize the same
I went basically to summarize the same slide that had before for now in
slide that had before for now in addition to this local the northern and
addition to this local the northern and lack of property I also put this
lack of property I also put this deceleration property okay you know
deceleration property okay you know which is you know sort of a graph
which is you know sort of a graph theoretic way of separating a set of
theoretic way of separating a set of notes a from beginner so main evidence
notes a from beginner so main evidence shall any the say if I throw this
shall any the say if I throw this property this global map of property
property this global map of property ecology this is an ahkam directed by the
ecology this is an ahkam directed by the profit division is the order Markov
profit division is the order Markov property and if you can solve the G next
property and if you can solve the G next 12 leads to old and then you can
12 leads to old and then you can actually show the opposite which is not
actually show the opposite which is not trivial but only 12 Nick stingy all of
trivial but only 12 Nick stingy all of them relatively well if you could put
them relatively well if you could put one you can write the other two okay and
one you can write the other two okay and also you can solve the poultry basically
also you can solve the poultry basically lead to the same factorization of the
lead to the same factorization of the Joint Distribution the graph which is
Joint Distribution the graph which is the relation that you share the body
the relation that you share the body okay so this sort of is you know
okay so this sort of is you know something easy to remember this is way
something easy to remember this is way more powerful basically because in
more powerful basically because in essence doesn't really even care what
essence doesn't really even care what are the non descendants invert the
are the non descendants invert the direction of the arrow says although the
direction of the arrow says although the numbering of the
numbering of the right so this made separation actually
right so this made separation actually can be applied to both directed and
can be applied to both directed and undirected graphs and it is the way to
undirected graphs and it is the way to prove condition independence to this
prove condition independence to this again if you want the top of each of
again if you want the top of each of these we're learning this this you have
these we're learning this this you have shown them at least with examples the
shown them at least with examples the truth is very few lines and again you
truth is very few lines and again you can consult one of the Bible's in in
can consult one of the Bible's in in community graphical models for people
community graphical models for people okay 1:46 we will come back and and
okay 1:46 we will come back and and three some slides and then discuss about
three some slides and then discuss about the elimination algorithm when we return
the elimination algorithm when we return on Thursday