throughout this part we supposed to start
start obviously you realize the lectures are
obviously you realize the lectures are videotaped that's why I have to start
videotaped that's why I have to start exactly 1213 I suppose I have your
exactly 1213 I suppose I have your permission with the tape here we are not
permission with the tape here we are not actually in the video but if you say
actually in the video but if you say anything
anything also you don't have to worry because
also you don't have to worry because it's not going to pick you up very micro
it's not going to pick you up very micro points which made but the lectures are
points which made but the lectures are going to be videotaped and posted on the
going to be videotaped and posted on the website of the course and also on what's
website of the course and also on what's the system
but you know we put the lectures from YouTube so you can download them
YouTube so you can download them directly from the next notes the course
directly from the next notes the course website it's an under construction which
website it's an under construction which means it's only the link is there the
means it's only the link is there the rest is going to be up when I managed to
rest is going to be up when I managed to get some sleep of 12 hours
get some sleep of 12 hours deadlock okay so maybe tomorrow or
deadlock okay so maybe tomorrow or something you know certainly before the
something you know certainly before the next lecture I hope to have this thing
next lecture I hope to have this thing up with today's lecture and video as
up with today's lecture and video as well let's see
well let's see the glass is Tuesdays and Thursdays
the glass is Tuesdays and Thursdays 12:32 unqualified I know there has been
12:32 unqualified I know there has been lots of changes from the timing it's
lots of changes from the timing it's really not something I control when you
really not something I control when you use the lecture room like 126 the
use the lecture room like 126 the Bartolo that has videotaping you know
Bartolo that has videotaping you know everybody wants this room so it's very
everybody wants this room so it's very difficult to watch that
difficult to watch that yes everything is on yeah thank you
yes everything is on yeah thank you thanks for stopping by
thanks for stopping by so this room is on high demand so we
so this room is on high demand so we were in then we were out in and out so
were in then we were out in and out so we are in as of today the Baku next
we are in as of today the Baku next rescue station first place and maybe not
rescue station first place and maybe not every Friday but once a while we're
every Friday but once a while we're going to have recitations to get we've
going to have recitations to get we've helped with a homework and in addition
helped with a homework and in addition when there are missing lecture I'm going
when there are missing lecture I'm going to use cry this to cover up for that so
to use cry this to cover up for that so let's see what else that's my email
let's see what else that's my email address whatever information you need I
address whatever information you need I want to try to provide it on the course
want to try to provide it on the course website okay there's a lots of there you
website okay there's a lots of there you know regarding the course objectives
know regarding the course objectives this is not an application course right
this is not an application course right that don't usually teach application of
that don't usually teach application of courses so Vista course on the
courses so Vista course on the fundamentals of community graphical
fundamentals of community graphical modules and I remember someone's had
modules and I remember someone's had asked me in the past you know what's
asked me in the past you know what's probabilistic graphical models thinking
probabilistic graphical models thinking must be something graphical you know
must be something graphical you know probably the graphical models is a
probably the graphical models is a constant yet is a way to work with many
constant yet is a way to work with many random variables and if you think this
random variables and if you think this many of the valuable some somehow
many of the valuable some somehow interconnected because they are
interconnected because they are correlated there is a graph and then
correlated there is a graph and then maybe we can do some graph theoretic
maybe we can do some graph theoretic approaches to doing transpose but don't
approaches to doing transpose but don't expect to have a problem where there is
expect to have a problem where there is a graph and then you say oh do something
a graph and then you say oh do something with this graph the graph is there all
with this graph the graph is there all right so you have to think of something
right so you have to think of something being represented as a graph and I think
being represented as a graph and I think it comes tense that's the most difficult
it comes tense that's the most difficult part of
part of of the of the cost being able to
of the of the cost being able to actually visualize on how what is a good
actually visualize on how what is a good model to represent the relations between
model to represent the relations between many other body okay so I'm going to try
many other body okay so I'm going to try to give you all the fundamentals to do
to give you all the fundamentals to do inference in graphs and when I talk
inference in graphs and when I talk about the interest rate refer to
about the interest rate refer to Bayesian inference I'm going to discuss
Bayesian inference I'm going to discuss both directed and undirected graphs
both directed and undirected graphs maybe people in social science do
maybe people in social science do psychology they like directed graph
psychology they like directed graph people in science and engineering the
people in science and engineering the like undirected graphs but we've
like undirected graphs but we've received some how we can connect the
received some how we can connect the different types of graphs we learned one
different types of graphs we learned one all the types quite easily obviously you
all the types quite easily obviously you know I'm going to give you examples here
know I'm going to give you examples here and there represent the potential of
and there represent the potential of using graphical models from standard
using graphical models from standard machine learning problems the computer
machine learning problems the computer vision to doing scientific computing two
vision to doing scientific computing two certifications of natural language
certifications of natural language processing computational biology I don't
processing computational biology I don't believe we have anybody from biology the
believe we have anybody from biology the audience do we
audience do we okay
obviously nobody does anything related to the type of things so we don't have
to the type of things so we don't have anything any contributions from students
anything any contributions from students this year right well the course is
this year right well the course is appropriate basically for students in
appropriate basically for students in math statistics and computer science for
math statistics and computer science for students in engineering that have good
students in engineering that have good mathematical skills but very relevant
mathematical skills but very relevant and students in all areas of time this
and students in all areas of time this including cognitive sciences biology if
including cognitive sciences biology if it's called chemical etc some of this
it's called chemical etc some of this course is to not universally so popular
course is to not universally so popular I'd noticed for example you go to
I'd noticed for example you go to Stanford
Stanford the cost is more than click on the
the cost is more than click on the students attending again because there
students attending again because there is interest from every direction ok here
is interest from every direction ok here you have the selective ones are not the
you have the selective ones are not the same we have the carrots to come and
same we have the carrots to come and attend these lectures to Delhi and I
attend these lectures to Delhi and I hope to see you on with the next lecture
hope to see you on with the next lecture on Thursday as well okay and I hope to
on Thursday as well okay and I hope to see you the day after I give the first
see you the day after I give the first homework because usually that's when the
homework because usually that's when the class population goes down by 50%
class population goes down by 50% okay now B this is not that caused us to
okay now B this is not that caused us to get four credits I am assuming you only
get four credits I am assuming you only reason you're here is because you want
reason you're here is because you want to learn the topic and integrated with
to learn the topic and integrated with your research and I'm going to help you
your research and I'm going to help you in doing that but if you just need four
in doing that but if you just need four credits this is on the right course for
credits this is on the right course for you okay I want to you know this is a
you okay I want to you know this is a very hot important area in many ways and
very hot important area in many ways and I'm going to educate you but to be able
I'm going to educate you but to be able to learn this you need to have and
to learn this you need to have and interest from the top
interest from the top if you don't this is not the place to be
if you don't this is not the place to be now the cost you know it's going to be
now the cost you know it's going to be one of the core courses from the new
one of the core courses from the new center for informatics and computational
center for informatics and computational science is basically the second in
science is basically the second in sequence from a course to PI I taught on
sequence from a course to PI I taught on Bayesian statistics in the fall if you
Bayesian statistics in the fall if you don't really need the previous course
don't really need the previous course and if you need something well I mean
and if you need something well I mean when I say you don't need it you need
when I say you don't need it you need everything right the more you know the
everything right the more you know the better but I cannot expect you that you
better but I cannot expect you that you know what was covered to the previous
know what was covered to the previous course so when there are some
course so when there are some fundamental concepts that we need to
fundamental concepts that we need to bring in I will either cover them in
bring in I will either cover them in this course where I will give you know
this course where I will give you know it's basically to read about them I
it's basically to read about them I think and it is possible that I'm gonna
think and it is possible that I'm gonna go back to you some of the topics
go back to you some of the topics covered in the poll anyways but try to
covered in the poll anyways but try to address them in a graph theoretic wonder
address them in a graph theoretic wonder okay so new algorithmic problems we
okay so new algorithmic problems we cover for example related to data
cover for example related to data stimulation so you need to know
stimulation so you need to know probability theory you don't know
probability theory you don't know anything about probabilities period will
anything about probabilities period will disappoint you you need to know the
disappoint you you need to know the fundamentals at least Vegas rules and
fundamentals at least Vegas rules and the lights about Bayesian inference and
the lights about Bayesian inference and if we have taken even an introductory
if we have taken even an introductory cost to must in learning may be useful
cost to must in learning may be useful okay
okay machine learning for me means
machine learning for me means computational statistics
computational statistics so whatever we need I will bring it back
so whatever we need I will bring it back for your convenience but it is going to
for your convenience but it is going to be helpful if you have a book in your
be helpful if you have a book in your desk but you can look for information
desk but you can look for information okay and I'm going to give you lots of
okay and I'm going to give you lots of readings that you can go through this
readings that you can go through this semester and also after the course is
semester and also after the course is over you need to know programming
over you need to know programming because we will make an effort every
because we will make an effort every homework didn't have a computational
homework didn't have a computational problem and we're going to try to do
problem and we're going to try to do this even on the first homework these
this even on the first homework these are the first home mortgage deduction
are the first home mortgage deduction calculations but what going sort of to
calculations but what going sort of to try to give you a computer assignment
try to give you a computer assignment simply because we you know we want to
simply because we you know we want to precise this because that these
precise this because that these computers is not to do ten calculations
computers is not to do ten calculations there's too much you know computation
there's too much you know computation and ten calculations were not tempted to
and ten calculations were not tempted to do any serious problems okay all right
like in the fall semester of relying on the help from others around the court
the help from others around the court so dr. Rubik Chakraborty this neck you
so dr. Rubik Chakraborty this neck you know the over there with his mark is
know the over there with his mark is going is volunteering to help with some
going is volunteering to help with some of the vegetation preparing some of the
of the vegetation preparing some of the homework solutions and also doing some
homework solutions and also doing some of the grading and so he's gone around
of the grading and so he's gone around the resistance and maybe once if I give
the resistance and maybe once if I give a lecture or two when I'm out of town so
a lecture or two when I'm out of town so the homework is going to be submitted
the homework is going to be submitted electronically to this email address I'm
electronically to this email address I'm going to provide more information on the
going to provide more information on the website in the cover that you need to
website in the cover that you need to submit the homework this address may
submit the homework this address may change actually by tomorrow that's why I
change actually by tomorrow that's why I said this email address this is a Google
said this email address this is a Google email account but you may have made
email account but you may have made design one just for this class okay
I notice some of you look worn oh yes you know we like typed homework because
you know we like typed homework because it is for me especially computational
it is for me especially computational silence and writing by 10:00 there's no
silence and writing by 10:00 there's no way we can figure out what you're
way we can figure out what you're writing there if you write if you type
writing there if you write if you type something nice to me it is very easy to
something nice to me it is very easy to know what is going on okay
know what is going on okay so indeed with preferred type homework
so indeed with preferred type homework but some of your lazy and I'm referring
but some of your lazy and I'm referring to my students my own students so for
to my students my own students so for those who are lazy you can stop the you
those who are lazy you can stop the you can stick on your homework and stormy if
can stick on your homework and stormy if there's a PDF attachment okay if you do
there's a PDF attachment okay if you do this thing's might can't ask me you will
this thing's might can't ask me you will identify 90% of the mistakes in your
identify 90% of the mistakes in your homework just by typing it slowly and
homework just by typing it slowly and looking at it say oh it doesn't look
looking at it say oh it doesn't look good and it doesn't look good mint is
good and it doesn't look good mint is wrong okay but if you tied by hand it
wrong okay but if you tied by hand it never looks good so you never have lost
never looks good so you never have lost is it right because most of the time is
is it right because most of the time is wrong okay so we learnt that convert not
wrong okay so we learnt that convert not to mention you know what if you type
to mention you know what if you type this nice 3 tomorrow you go for a job
this nice 3 tomorrow you go for a job interview and you say yeah I took this
interview and you say yeah I took this course and here is what I did and that
course and here is what I did and that counts a lot ok because this is not
counts a lot ok because this is not intro to happy hour type of port let's
intro to happy hour type of port let's see the information on how you have to
see the information on how you have to touch your homeworks and how to name
touch your homeworks and how to name your submission again sir I will give
your submission again sir I will give that information of the website MOOCs
that information of the website MOOCs I'm gonna start actually in different
I'm gonna start actually in different orders from what is given here the this
orders from what is given here the this book by Michael Jordan and introductions
book by Michael Jordan and introductions published graphical models is actually
published graphical models is actually what is used in
what is used in most universities for breeding and it's
most universities for breeding and it's actually turtlecom
actually turtlecom you know everybody's taste in
you know everybody's taste in preparation reprint this book has been
preparation reprint this book has been in preparation for 25 years which means
in preparation for 25 years which means professor jonathan has given up
professor jonathan has given up basically because things are changing so
basically because things are changing so rapidly it's like what's the point of
rapidly it's like what's the point of finishing this book now okay and so
finishing this book now okay and so versus actually the easiest and the most
versus actually the easiest and the most insightful reading that you can have and
insightful reading that you can have and for those who register in the course I
for those who register in the course I am going to send you a PDF so I
am going to send you a PDF so I shouldn't be saying this on faith
shouldn't be saying this on faith somehow you've been going to library
somehow you've been going to library find it okay all right the let's see if
find it okay all right the let's see if you really want to do research in this
you really want to do research in this area a heavy book that you need to have
area a heavy book that you need to have in your desk is the textbook by Colin is
in your desk is the textbook by Colin is written is more than a thousand pages
written is more than a thousand pages maybe 1,200 pages has a lot of
maybe 1,200 pages has a lot of information some we will cover it in
information some we will cover it in this course in detail some all the
this course in detail some all the details you don't need them but toughen
details you don't need them but toughen the vistas the state of the art both in
the vistas the state of the art both in theory and algorithms so business you
theory and algorithms so business you know recommended book basically or you
know recommended book basically or you know
know to have the the textbook that we usually
to have the the textbook that we usually fit last fall by Kevin Rushdie has you
fit last fall by Kevin Rushdie has you know it's like an encyclopedia of
know it's like an encyclopedia of machine learning it's not really a
machine learning it's not really a readable text book but it has lots of
readable text book but it has lots of new algorithm still much more modern
new algorithm still much more modern Abroad's and it has a structural also
Abroad's and it has a structural also that goes with all the examples in the
that goes with all the examples in the book which I recommend it right and it
book which I recommend it right and it is actually less probabilistic than for
is actually less probabilistic than for example Jordan's reprint okay
example Jordan's reprint okay it used likes to use point estimates for
it used likes to use point estimates for fast inference for most of the
fast inference for most of the algorithms but you know there are I
algorithms but you know there are I don't know six seven chapters are
don't know six seven chapters are thinking for published graphical models
thinking for published graphical models and we will cover at least the essential
and we will cover at least the essential parts of those this of just one chapter
parts of those this of just one chapter on probabilistic graphical models that
on probabilistic graphical models that is actually an ideal read if you want to
is actually an ideal read if you want to know everything about this court before
know everything about this court before we even start to get a good stance let's
we even start to get a good stance let's say this week is to read what's after is
say this week is to read what's after is it a a so if you're in separate even
it a a so if you're in separate even just without the details alright just
just without the details alright just going through it it would serve you
going through it it would serve you extremely well because it has everything
extremely well because it has everything not loops or anything like that but has
not loops or anything like that but has the lots of insights as to what
the lots of insights as to what probabilistic graphical models are and
probabilistic graphical models are and how to go about okay
how to go about okay so certainly this would be a good start
so certainly this would be a good start point and also if he has the cube has
point and also if he has the cube has many other things that utilized the
many other things that utilized the machinery of probabilistic graphical
machinery of probabilistic graphical models that we will also use in this
models that we will also use in this course 16 readable most probably
course 16 readable most probably the most readable book on machine
the most readable book on machine learning in the market and even watched
learning in the market and even watched about 20 years tall you will find it I
about 20 years tall you will find it I pressed when I read it every other day I
pressed when I read it every other day I find something new there okay and so I
find something new there okay and so I obviously I recommend all of this book
obviously I recommend all of this book okay grading so we're going to have six
okay grading so we're going to have six homework the homework will be 60% of the
homework the homework will be 60% of the grades and it be a project 40% for some
grades and it be a project 40% for some maybe that's too much you know but if
maybe that's too much you know but if you think about it no exams no meters no
you think about it no exams no meters no finals
finals nothing okay so this is a gradual course
nothing okay so this is a gradual course we don't operate the classical way but
we don't operate the classical way but the expectations are higher than giving
the expectations are higher than giving an example you write something wrong
an example you write something wrong page that say congratulations we pass
page that say congratulations we pass the course right so the project it the
the course right so the project it the program we have to change the leave it
program we have to change the leave it from those who took the course in in the
from those who took the course in in the poll because I was very disappointed
poll because I was very disappointed with the attitude of many students here
with the attitude of many students here when it comes to the course to the
when it comes to the course to the project
project I get freedom to everybody to define
I get freedom to everybody to define their own project relevant to the course
their own project relevant to the course and I can tell you there were at least
and I can tell you there were at least seven students who came up with a new
seven students who came up with a new definition of the project about three
definition of the project about three days before the presentation
days before the presentation I mean asked not normal just ridiculous
I mean asked not normal just ridiculous okay so so I don't know exactly how
okay so so I don't know exactly how we're going to do it but I'm gonna think
we're going to do it but I'm gonna think in the next two or three weeks but the
in the next two or three weeks but the possibility would be to actually
possibility would be to actually literally five you ten twenty projects
literally five you ten twenty projects and save it to Z and here are the
and save it to Z and here are the references become whatever you like and
references become whatever you like and do one of those and you cannot say
do one of those and you cannot say right well we may do it as last fall but
right well we may do it as last fall but with strict guidelines that you changed
with strict guidelines that you changed project means you get zero breaking your
project means you get zero breaking your project
project we cannot allow basically a week before
we cannot allow basically a week before the representation solidifying what the
the representation solidifying what the project is and I'm not talking about the
project is and I'm not talking about the trying a little bit I'm talking about
trying a little bit I'm talking about going from A to Z okay not to mention
going from A to Z okay not to mention going from A to Z and SIF having no
going from A to Z and SIF having no relation to the course at all right so
relation to the course at all right so that's number I take so certainly I want
that's number I take so certainly I want with the project to give you an
with the project to give you an opportunity to do something that is
opportunity to do something that is relevant to your research right so that
relevant to your research right so that not only you benefit because you learn
not only you benefit because you learn the material of the course for those
the material of the course for those strong you benefit because the course in
strong you benefit because the course in fact you're already served and that's
fact you're already served and that's very important okay so now because of so
very important okay so now because of so the the project is going to require a
the the project is going to require a report which is not limited to six pages
report which is not limited to six pages a written presentation like PowerPoint
a written presentation like PowerPoint of Beamer and another presentation and
of Beamer and another presentation and because we have two dates in the fall
because we have two dates in the fall with scheduling with our presentations
with scheduling with our presentations and videotaping them have not seen any
and videotaping them have not seen any of the videos yet by the way of artists
of the videos yet by the way of artists presentations yet because they have not
presentations yet because they have not been provided to me but have what we're
been provided to me but have what we're going to do to avoid all that the next
going to do to avoid all that the next weekend we're going to take maybe the
weekend we're going to take maybe the last three or four lectures of the
last three or four lectures of the course and we're going to have the
course and we're going to have the presentations in class so you're going
presentations in class so you're going to be on this real video and not
to be on this real video and not issue because the videos are automatic
issue because the videos are automatic okay so we don't have to worry about
okay so we don't have to worry about story there's nothing available in May
story there's nothing available in May sorry
sorry in June this building is closed in July
in June this building is closed in July is open for something else and that
is open for something else and that we're gonna do it in class even if that
we're gonna do it in class even if that takes lecture so be prepared the that
takes lecture so be prepared the that the project would be you wave before the
the project would be you wave before the end of the semester the wave means you
end of the semester the wave means you know three lectures of this before the
know three lectures of this before the end of the semester so we're gonna have
end of the semester so we're gonna have to move on the projects quite strong
to move on the projects quite strong okay the services are very preliminary
okay the services are very preliminary so some of these topics we may cover
so some of these topics we may cover them in lots of details but some not
them in lots of details but some not we're going to discuss as I mentioned
we're going to discuss as I mentioned directive of the undirected graph this
directive of the undirected graph this should be of interest to everybody but
should be of interest to everybody but mainly you know in social and in social
mainly you know in social and in social sciences natural language modeling
sciences natural language modeling things I thought market models are
things I thought market models are basically essential for people to work
basically essential for people to work in scientific applications we're going
in scientific applications we're going to do it lots of 12 hours for data
to do it lots of 12 hours for data simulation problems starting with
simulation problems starting with basically a little relating everything
basically a little relating everything that you may already know from other
that you may already know from other courses or not some of these topics we
courses or not some of these topics we cover them and in the fall so ideas for
cover them and in the fall so ideas for example of doing dynamical systems with
example of doing dynamical systems with particle methods now we will see how to
particle methods now we will see how to develop the same identical algorithms
develop the same identical algorithms but with a graph theoretic approach so
but with a graph theoretic approach so for example you can think of doing
for example you can think of doing Kalman filtering and generalization
Kalman filtering and generalization always with no effort using algorithms
always with no effort using algorithms on graphs
on graphs nothing new but the risk of slipping
nothing new but the risk of slipping would grass you babel action to develop
would grass you babel action to develop your own Oliver effect you want to that
your own Oliver effect you want to that this extension of standard methodologies
this extension of standard methodologies that have been around for thirty years
we're gonna spend maybe more than two lectures may be anything from five to
lectures may be anything from five to ten lectures to discuss inference in
ten lectures to discuss inference in graphs and this concept of exacting
graphs and this concept of exacting first of course is you know it's not
first of course is you know it's not always possible so we are gonna start
always possible so we are gonna start with this and then we will so we will
with this and then we will so we will cover as part of exactly current idea so
cover as part of exactly current idea so far the new propagation destruction pre
far the new propagation destruction pre algorithm elimination and the light will
algorithm elimination and the light will discuss about approximate inference
discuss about approximate inference using generalizations of means you know
using generalizations of means you know means till the type of algorithms so
means till the type of algorithms so this is an important area and it
this is an important area and it actually an earlier that literally goes
actually an earlier that literally goes coefficient with graph theoretic
coefficient with graph theoretic algorithms so this will be an essential
algorithms so this will be an essential part of the cost and if we have time I
part of the cost and if we have time I think maybe we spend two three lectures
think maybe we spend two three lectures to discussed on how do you learn the
to discussed on how do you learn the structure of a graph so if somebody for
structure of a graph so if somebody for hours view realizations for a few
hours view realizations for a few hundred of variables and you want to
hundred of variables and you want to figure out how they are correlated how
figure out how they are correlated how do we do this how do you come up with
do we do this how do you come up with learning destruction of a graph and of
learning destruction of a graph and of course we've realized the this is a very
course we've realized the this is a very difficult open problem right so this is
difficult open problem right so this is actually the fantastic area to do a PhD
actually the fantastic area to do a PhD not one piece P you can work for 100
not one piece P you can work for 100 feet this because I don't believe this
feet this because I don't believe this problem can be scaled
problem can be scaled many of the variables alright but it's
many of the variables alright but it's an important topic that is to be
an important topic that is to be discussed so the lectures will give in
discussed so the lectures will give in the tape I think we think an hour two of
the tape I think we think an hour two of the lectures are available on Sakai when
the lectures are available on Sakai when the website is up if not today tomorrow
the website is up if not today tomorrow we will post these videotapes the on
we will post these videotapes the on YouTube so will be that youtube link
YouTube so will be that youtube link where the lecture PDFs will be posted
where the lecture PDFs will be posted I hesitate actually have to think about
I hesitate actually have to think about this if I want to post the lectures like
this if I want to post the lectures like we did in the fall so that you have them
we did in the fall so that you have them in front of you during the lectures
in front of you during the lectures because I was observing certain
because I was observing certain individuals in this room but they are
individuals in this room but they are still clear okay
still clear okay during my lectures basically doing
during my lectures basically doing nothing else but just looking on that
nothing else but just looking on that computer that's not the way to go I mean
computer that's not the way to go I mean why have you you know I mean they are
why have you you know I mean they are looking at bookkeeping you can look at
looking at bookkeeping you can look at form right since the business will be
form right since the business will be available this you need to come to them
available this you need to come to them I mean make me spill good of course if
I mean make me spill good of course if you come and I appreciate but I think
you come and I appreciate but I think the idea is to be able to benefit even
the idea is to be able to benefit even partially by listening in person to
partially by listening in person to these lectures okay but for sure the
these lectures okay but for sure the lectures will be positive if not before
lectures will be positive if not before immediately after you know you know in
immediately after you know you know in the afternoon of the same day there will
the afternoon of the same day there will be a lots of references of papers and
be a lots of references of papers and books and things I got that I will link
books and things I got that I will link to the lectures so consider those as
to the lectures so consider those as very useful readings and also there will
very useful readings and also there will be a lot of chalkboard links that you
be a lot of chalkboard links that you can use this well why would I forgot
can use this well why would I forgot this because we're video tape I want to
this because we're video tape I want to encourage questions but I'm gonna have
encourage questions but I'm gonna have to repeat your questions
to repeat your questions otherwise nobody Houston anything okay
otherwise nobody Houston anything okay so let me stop there any questions about
so let me stop there any questions about the structure of it all really there's
the structure of it all really there's no structure I mean we do anything we
no structure I mean we do anything we want to we can change our mind tomorrow
want to we can change our mind tomorrow all right
all right we are interest money to learn and not
we are interest money to learn and not to go from A to B to C because I there's
to go from A to B to C because I there's no such a thing okay so and feel free to
no such a thing okay so and feel free to take advantage drop any questions
of course the question I have to ask is how many of you will love stick with us
how many of you will love stick with us on Thursday
on Thursday alright and I hope everybody alright
alright and I hope everybody alright bring the cousins - okay we need all the
bring the cousins - okay we need all the support we can get
I mean one of my students is teaching now at Purdue similar course as the one
now at Purdue similar course as the one without clearing in the fall more or
without clearing in the fall more or less things are a little more basic but
less things are a little more basic but she told me she has more than 60 they
she told me she has more than 60 they had to limit the cluster talents was
had to limit the cluster talents was fixed it because they were students from
fixed it because they were students from every quarter interested but you know
every quarter interested but you know here we're a small population so we
here we're a small population so we don't have the Nutri of 60 20 is
don't have the Nutri of 60 20 is actually a great number for example for
actually a great number for example for okay but you guys need to not to give up
okay but you guys need to not to give up when I give homework okay if you do give
when I give homework okay if you do give up I'm sorry for you all right so no
up I'm sorry for you all right so no questions
any questions just to entertain the thing no but the way whichever I know
thing no but the way whichever I know who have at least and students that will
who have at least and students that will be listening to be stopped from various
be listening to be stopped from various places overseas okay I have been
places overseas okay I have been surprised the receiving names of
surprised the receiving names of students from certain universities in
students from certain universities in China but they even do the homework and
China but they even do the homework and they submit me corrections to the
they submit me corrections to the homework okay so and corrections to the
homework okay so and corrections to the software of the homework the case though
software of the homework the case though and I have seen the impact some of this
and I have seen the impact some of this lectures have had on various health so
lectures have had on various health so it served quite rewarding
it served quite rewarding okay so we're going to start with sort
okay so we're going to start with sort of some elementary introduction to
of some elementary introduction to control in a geographical borders
control in a geographical borders discussing some terminology maybe one or
discussing some terminology maybe one or two basic examples I am NOT gonna do any
two basic examples I am NOT gonna do any mathematics linear questions or anything
mathematics linear questions or anything like that but
like that but so if you see saying things that really
so if you see saying things that really require a lot of explanations keep in
require a lot of explanations keep in mind and when I come back to those
mind and when I come back to those topics and discuss them in detail as we
topics and discuss them in detail as we go along right so this is just to give
go along right so this is just to give you a flavor of what a probabilistic
you a flavor of what a probabilistic graphical model is and what the type of
graphical model is and what the type of promise were interested by the way in
promise were interested by the way in addition to the video lectures if from
addition to the video lectures if from our course if you served with the
our course if you served with the constant form you say probabilistic
constant form you say probabilistic graphical models you will find notes
graphical models you will find notes from many short court system here have
from many short court system here have heroes living divani and Christmas of
heroes living divani and Christmas of have a series of lectures on
have a series of lectures on probabilistic graphical
probabilistic graphical with videos and PDFs but you know you
with videos and PDFs but you know you can find online
can find online the Stanford courses and many other
the Stanford courses and many other universities the courses from Cornell
universities the courses from Cornell etc so you can sort of if you have
etc so you can sort of if you have questions with a certain topic
questions with a certain topic if you turn you'll be able to find a lot
if you turn you'll be able to find a lot of resources I think the good thing is
of resources I think the good thing is this area of machine learning it's an
this area of machine learning it's an area of a very open society that likes
area of a very open society that likes things out there to be open okay we
things out there to be open okay we don't hide anything everybody can
don't hide anything everybody can actually benefit and we like it that way
so we're really probabilistic graphical models just to model the relations
models just to model the relations between many random variables okay so
between many random variables okay so now effectively would be a way to
now effectively would be a way to produce the joint probability of this
produce the joint probability of this body most so X here is a vector so the
body most so X here is a vector so the probabilistic graphical models will give
probabilistic graphical models will give us sort of file an efficient way to
us sort of file an efficient way to model this distribution fire fact and
model this distribution fire fact and something that we would need to be able
something that we would need to be able to take advantage when we work with
to take advantage when we work with grouches we're going to be able to
grouches we're going to be able to account for the independent relations
account for the independent relations between these variables by somehow
dropping some links from the graph as we wish it softly all right so I have these
wish it softly all right so I have these two variables and they're not connected
two variables and they're not connected darkus an implication probabilistically
darkus an implication probabilistically speaking so the idea here would be that
speaking so the idea here would be that the joint probability distribution when
the joint probability distribution when it is factorized according to a graph or
it is factorized according to a graph or a graph is not right the model in the
a graph is not right the model in the police relations
police relations you know inside this probability
you know inside this probability distribution if we do that we will be
distribution if we do that we will be able to take advantage of inference
able to take advantage of inference algorithms but still very nicely in
algorithms but still very nicely in graphs all right and in some of the
graphs all right and in some of the solvent you used completely graph
solvent you used completely graph theoretic sort of argument and so they
theoretic sort of argument and so they are very convenient now if somebody if
are very convenient now if somebody if you if I give you let's say 50 variables
you if I give you let's say 50 variables and you learn the joint probability
and you learn the joint probability distribution and somehow you can
distribution and somehow you can factorize in some nice way the main
factorize in some nice way the main interest will be to do inference which
interest will be to do inference which means if I knowledge say this stand
means if I knowledge say this stand variables what's the probability of very
variables what's the probability of very many variables all right and so we're
many variables all right and so we're going to have to do somehow develop some
going to have to do somehow develop some algorithms that will allow us to compute
algorithms that will allow us to compute marginal and conditional distributions
marginal and conditional distributions out of this joint distribution the Adisa
out of this joint distribution the Adisa Teno the joint we should be able to do
Teno the joint we should be able to do lots of things cheaply and in particular
lots of things cheaply and in particular that will be the case for graphs now
that will be the case for graphs now when you have a joint distribution like
when you have a joint distribution like that you will always have lots of
that you will always have lots of unknown parameters to define the joint
unknown parameters to define the joint distribution so one of the tasks in
distribution so one of the tasks in probabilistic graphical model is to
probabilistic graphical model is to figure out what those parameters are
figure out what those parameters are given realizations of some random
given realizations of some random variables okay so we would see examples
variables okay so we would see examples of that
let's go so probably a feminist is basically for military plus graph theory
basically for military plus graph theory okay
okay we obviously we won't drop it because
we obviously we won't drop it because we're graph speak we can visualize the
we're graph speak we can visualize the independence relation between the many
independence relation between the many of the variables and once we do that we
of the variables and once we do that we can motivate the lots of new algorithms
can motivate the lots of new algorithms I mean the posture can tell you when I
I mean the posture can tell you when I was interested in solving some weird
was interested in solving some weird multi scale problems I've as long as
multi scale problems I've as long as visualizing of how this may look like
visualizing of how this may look like and everybody thought that was an idiot
and everybody thought that was an idiot because somehow they couldn't see how
because somehow they couldn't see how probabilistic graphical model can be
probabilistic graphical model can be relevant but if it is here then you
relevant but if it is here then you should be able to put it in a computer
should be able to put it in a computer program okay
program okay so visualizing the structure of a
so visualizing the structure of a probability model of thing is essential
probability model of thing is essential to get nice algorithms all right so
to get nice algorithms all right so we're going to develop algorithms that
we're going to develop algorithms that they take advantage of this graph
they take advantage of this graph structure so we're going to be able to
structure so we're going to be able to do inference learning and all of these
do inference learning and all of these things affected in the graphs and the
things affected in the graphs and the ideas for example of these masters
ideas for example of these masters passing algorithms will be something
passing algorithms will be something that you cannot do without a graph
that you cannot do without a graph theoretic approach
so the benefit you get in sizing for the model you look actually graphically and
model you look actually graphically and you can say lots of things as to how the
you can say lots of things as to how the around the variables correlate to each
around the variables correlate to each other you can develop many new
other you can develop many new algorithms by playing with the structure
algorithms by playing with the structure of the graph and most of the inference
of the graph and most of the inference we will do in this course can scale
we will do in this course can scale nicely simply because of this
nicely simply because of this independence relations but implied by by
independence relations but implied by by the gun action and actually I can tell
the gun action and actually I can tell you that's quite all you don't need to
you that's quite all you don't need to know anything as a background all the
know anything as a background all the calculations always in machine learning
calculations always in machine learning there are nothing else but applications
there are nothing else but applications of the solid product rules of
of the solid product rules of probability and we will see this
probability and we will see this something on Thursday when we develop
something on Thursday when we develop simple things on graphs so realist you
simple things on graphs so realist you know the definitions of probabilities
know the definitions of probabilities and what the stomach for the fruits are
and what the stomach for the fruits are then you are ready best bid to do lots
then you are ready best bid to do lots of nice things
but I told you that don't be scared I power lots of concepts because we will
power lots of concepts because we will develop all of this in separate lectures
develop all of this in separate lectures so I'm just throwing this as an
so I'm just throwing this as an introduction so the dart is going to
introduction so the dart is going to encode the whatever independence
encode the whatever independence assumptions exist for my many random
assumptions exist for my many random variables all right and basically we'll
variables all right and basically we'll be able to factorize the probability
be able to factorize the probability distribution on the graph or given a
distribution on the graph or given a graph we will know what type of
graph we will know what type of factorization the graph complies for the
factorization the graph complies for the probability distributions that we define
probability distributions that we define the idea is that somehow this
the idea is that somehow this factorization of the joint probability
factorization of the joint probability distribution of the graph would be with
distribution of the graph would be with local functions that are defined on the
local functions that are defined on the notes of the graph so these local
notes of the graph so these local functions will be different things for
functions will be different things for directed graph which we also called the
directed graph which we also called the Bayesian networks and will be different
Bayesian networks and will be different for undirected graphs that also we call
for undirected graphs that also we call them a mark of network okay but the idea
them a mark of network okay but the idea is somehow a joint distribution between
is somehow a joint distribution between many of our variables can be written as
many of our variables can be written as a product of local functions and this is
a product of local functions and this is great right but it's not so physically
great right but it's not so physically what you very did because if for example
what you very did because if for example you think spatially many of the
you think spatially many of the variables the variables here don't
variables the variables here don't depend on the volume is their right
depend on the volume is their right correlation sort of local extent so
correlation sort of local extent so somehow if you can arrange these things
somehow if you can arrange these things to the graph you have a similar nature
to the graph you have a similar nature you will be able to do lots of work that
you will be able to do lots of work that is local and from these local functions
is local and from these local functions you'll be able to say
you'll be able to say build this this joint distribution of
build this this joint distribution of the menu of the volumes by the way when
the menu of the volumes by the way when I said some wearables of here and there
I said some wearables of here and there this is in the special context or in the
this is in the special context or in the time context but the goth can be a very
time context but the goth can be a very abstract entity they have nothing to do
abstract entity they have nothing to do with space of time okay so don't you
with space of time okay so don't you know again depending on the type of
know again depending on the type of things you're interested you can
things you're interested you can envision different scenarios so Bayesian
envision different scenarios so Bayesian networks are probabilistic graphical
networks are probabilistic graphical models that are defined on directed
models that are defined on directed graphs and I'm gonna show you an example
graphs and I'm gonna show you an example shortly and this Markov random pills
shortly and this Markov random pills this Markov networks are basically
this Markov networks are basically probabilistic graphical models for
probabilistic graphical models for undirected graphs three so these are the
undirected graphs three so these are the main two types right and you can have
main two types right and you can have some graphs that have some directed
some graphs that have some directed component some undirected components and
component some undirected components and also you can pose this in sort of some
also you can pose this in sort of some unified way using what's called
unified way using what's called photographs and we will discuss verse as
photographs and we will discuss verse as well
well so actually you know three lectures
so actually you know three lectures there's no point of discussion one type
there's no point of discussion one type or another we will unify development for
or another we will unify development for all of this at the same time okay
all of this at the same time okay the nodes in the graph we represent are
the nodes in the graph we represent are the variables and this is very important
the variables and this is very important the lack of transition the graph will
the lack of transition the graph will imply conditional independence
imply conditional independence assumptions in other ways if I have
assumptions in other ways if I have nodes representing random variables and
nodes representing random variables and I have to take ten variables and I
I have to take ten variables and I connected smart evil with every other
connected smart evil with every other body world then there's no point of
body world then there's no point of doing graphs because that problem
doing graphs because that problem complexity will never allow you to go
complexity will never allow you to go anyway
anyway it's somehow some edges are missing that
it's somehow some edges are missing that implies to military somebody who don't
implies to military somebody who don't depend on all the volume which the lots
depend on all the volume which the lots what we need to think about so the idea
what we need to think about so the idea is we are interested in graphs that they
is we are interested in graphs that they are not fully connected right they are
are not fully connected right they are fully connected one of gaining anything
fully connected one of gaining anything by learning this course right the idea
by learning this course right the idea is not everything depends on everything
is not everything depends on everything and we need to learn about part of the
and we need to learn about part of the structure problem that we discussed the
structure problem that we discussed the second part of the course but again the
second part of the course but again the lack of threads is what represents
lack of threads is what represents conditional independence assumptions and
conditional independence assumptions and we spend two or three lectures to
we spend two or three lectures to discuss that and I will give you a
discuss that and I will give you a number of formal projects to work on all
number of formal projects to work on all right so something just let's go from
right so something just let's go from right in there this is a directed graph
right in there this is a directed graph I'm gonna give you the terminology in of
I'm gonna give you the terminology in of the you know in follow up slide but just
the you know in follow up slide but just to get things going basically here you
to get things going basically here you can use common sense interpretation for
can use common sense interpretation for now you know so all of this are other
now you know so all of this are other variables we have a b c d e are on two
variables we have a b c d e are on two variables can be continuous or discrete
variables can be continuous or discrete doesn't really matter and the idea here
doesn't really matter and the idea here of the service means that C depends
of the service means that C depends today and B it depends on C and D right
today and B it depends on C and D right and so this implies this direction of
and so this implies this direction of the arrow the causal relationship
the arrow the causal relationship alright so big doesn't depend on me it
alright so big doesn't depend on me it depends from D that's what I know from
depends from D that's what I know from here okay
here okay the rest you will need to derive from
the rest you will need to derive from the factorization employed by this
the factorization employed by this directive model now this one direction
directive model now this one direction graph there is no error okay so
graph there is no error okay so obviously if there's no arrows and you
obviously if there's no arrows and you see this connections
see this connections obviously C is related to a a and B
obviously C is related to a a and B obviously she's related to you
obviously she's related to you and to be envied so you serious tricks
and to be envied so you serious tricks there was this interconnected sets of
there was this interconnected sets of notes so both imply really correlations
notes so both imply really correlations but there is no directional component so
but there is no directional component so in essence the effect of EMV and BMC has
in essence the effect of EMV and BMC has no direction okay so this is very
no direction okay so this is very different from what this chain is drawn
different from what this chain is drawn okay
okay now I'm not going to discuss what this
now I'm not going to discuss what this is in detail right but this is sort of
is in detail right but this is sort of another type of graph that will allow us
another type of graph that will allow us to sort of unify those two graphs okay
to sort of unify those two graphs okay and somehow to do that we need to
and somehow to do that we need to introduce the sectional squared note but
introduce the sectional squared note but effectively explicitly spell out these
effectively explicitly spell out these local functions these local potentials
local functions these local potentials but you have either in this undirected
but you have either in this undirected graphs or in the directed graphs so
graphs or in the directed graphs so these are functional and that's why this
these are functional and that's why this is called a photograph okay so this are
is called a photograph okay so this are the random variables and it's a constant
the random variables and it's a constant okay and so we would be able to how to
okay and so we would be able to how to eventually do inference in factor graphs
eventually do inference in factor graphs and not way accounting for inference
and not way accounting for inference both directed and undirected model again
both directed and undirected model again you don't need to know anything any of
you don't need to know anything any of this because we will spent many lectures
this because we will spent many lectures discussing each of this but I thought
discussing each of this but I thought you should see this on lecture one so
you should see this on lecture one so now is representative of variables edges
now is representative of variables edges dependencies and really what we're
dependencies and really what we're interested is in the lack of the edges
interested is in the lack of the edges so the path but there is no edge between
so the path but there is no edge between a and B that's very important if you try
a and B that's very important if you try to connect a to B to D to Eve than
to connect a to B to D to Eve than don't expect to gain anything by doing
don't expect to gain anything by doing graph theoretic approach okay
graph theoretic approach okay so in if you have many nodes so this is
so in if you have many nodes so this is the trek high-dimensional this village h
the trek high-dimensional this village h 100 the first objective when you work
100 the first objective when you work with graphs is to come up with the joint
with graphs is to come up with the joint probability distribution and in
probability distribution and in particularly with the factorized form of
particularly with the factorized form of the joint probability distribution okay
the joint probability distribution okay the fact is form that somehow can easily
the fact is form that somehow can easily be visualized in a graph accounting for
be visualized in a graph accounting for whatever independence relations exist
whatever independence relations exist between these values now you can
between these values now you can appreciate that if the variables
appreciate that if the variables dependent there is no independence
dependent there is no independence relations right and each of these
relations right and each of these variables can take K values and let's
variables can take K values and let's say each of these columns is also
say each of these columns is also discrete and can take K values how many
discrete and can take K values how many values how much information you need to
values how much information you need to describe this probability distribution
describe this probability distribution so you need K values for each of them
so you need K values for each of them and you have via block how many
and you have via block how many variables Divinity's try to describe
variables Divinity's try to describe this joint distribution
this joint distribution with no independence relations at all
take away the power
the power B right so it least 10 forget about you won't be able to do anything
about you won't be able to do anything okay so we will see on what we can
okay so we will see on what we can benefit take and run up to this
benefit take and run up to this condition in the ventilation and drop
condition in the ventilation and drop now once somehow you can come up with
now once somehow you can come up with the proper authorization of this then
the proper authorization of this then you can stop talking about the inference
you can stop talking about the inference so for example if you let's say measure
so for example if you let's say measure the value of variable X 1 you have you
the value of variable X 1 you have you know what the value is then you can stay
know what the value is then you can stay with the value of x 2 given X 1 where
with the value of x 2 given X 1 where the rest of the variables maybe you want
the rest of the variables maybe you want analyze them ok to get rid of them
analyze them ok to get rid of them so obviously you appreciate that the sum
so obviously you appreciate that the sum and product rule will come candy to
and product rule will come candy to actually manipulate this but also Bayes
actually manipulate this but also Bayes rule would be essential when you have
rule would be essential when you have evidence to be able to do inference
applications really you know you just mentioned any anything right
mentioned any anything right so in diaphragmatic this standard
so in diaphragmatic this standard methods in in medical diagnosis actually
methods in in medical diagnosis actually almost every you know diagnosis now
almost every you know diagnosis now actually every time I am reading
actually every time I am reading articles but visual to make the systems
articles but visual to make the systems for diagnosing diseases would take from
for diagnosing diseases would take from images etc they operate with much less
images etc they operate with much less chance for false alarms than the best
chance for false alarms than the best doctor in the world right they're
doctor in the world right they're extremely accurate so now it's not like
extremely accurate so now it's not like this is for mathematicians or computer
this is for mathematicians or computer scientists people in practice are
scientists people in practice are actually using probably splatter model
actually using probably splatter model for prognosis all the
for prognosis all the loss of diseases computer vision speech
loss of diseases computer vision speech recognition Google Translate I mean I
recognition Google Translate I mean I use it you know when I go to China I
use it you know when I go to China I always say something and it translates
always say something and it translates and I always see what it translates to
and I always see what it translates to be sure it was laced correctly because
be sure it was laced correctly because sometimes I say something and I read
sometimes I say something and I read this like wow I'm gonna get in trouble
this like wow I'm gonna get in trouble and so it really works very well okay I
and so it really works very well okay I mean I have seen it even working when
mean I have seen it even working when there are several people speaking
there are several people speaking simultaneously with action and it does
simultaneously with action and it does miracles so it's really a director
miracles so it's really a director filtration of republished graphical
filtration of republished graphical models practically every topic of the
models practically every topic of the algorithm machine learning can be posed
algorithm machine learning can be posed on probabilistic graphical models for
on probabilistic graphical models for okay so we may I don't know if we have
okay so we may I don't know if we have time I covered it with ideas of blatant
time I covered it with ideas of blatant holy Moses model reduction in the fall
holy Moses model reduction in the fall so misspent electrocuted go back and
so misspent electrocuted go back and address the ocean generalize them using
address the ocean generalize them using graphical model so if you don't know
graphical model so if you don't know anything about what solvent is fine
anything about what solvent is fine because when we post them in graphic we
because when we post them in graphic we will post them as new problems and so
will post them as new problems and so you will see sort of a modern aspect of
you will see sort of a modern aspect of this algorithm and and I think you know
this algorithm and and I think you know you like of more than a questions that
you like of more than a questions that without the means to visualizer the you
without the means to visualizer the you know error control codes and the way you
know error control codes and the way you know your computer you know restart and
know your computer you know restart and figure out what goes wrong right and and
figure out what goes wrong right and and became properly it's really based in in
became properly it's really based in in probabilistic graphical models if you
probabilistic graphical models if you take for most in engineering to take
take for most in engineering to take sort of
sort of you know we talked about little to
you know we talked about little to undividable scanner there but actually
undividable scanner there but actually the source of this adapter ones can be
the source of this adapter ones can be extremely effective for this knowledge
extremely effective for this knowledge they're not simply random variables but
they're not simply random variables but the interconnected complicated systems
the interconnected complicated systems of differing ology and mechanical model
of differing ology and mechanical model the thermal model etc and each of them
the thermal model etc and each of them has its own random by the Wilson within
has its own random by the Wilson within right but you have interconnected
right but you have interconnected systems that speak to each other and
systems that speak to each other and this is really sort of an important area
this is really sort of an important area for development because it points a lot
for development because it points a lot of tolerances because a lot of these
of tolerances because a lot of these systems are governed by models that are
systems are governed by models that are very compassionate very expensive so so
very compassionate very expensive so so a lot of the methodologies for doing
a lot of the methodologies for doing inference would not be able to sort of
inference would not be able to sort of what directly you would have to do
what directly you would have to do something there to simplify the
something there to simplify the representation of these systems okay so
representation of these systems okay so let's you know go fast through the
let's you know go fast through the patient knowledge of the variables exist
patient knowledge of the variables exist already said for publicity Lester the
already said for publicity Lester the lock opens it basically will provide
lock opens it basically will provide information on independence relations so
information on independence relations so graft has a number of nodes as a number
graft has a number of nodes as a number of edges the number of nodes from want
of edges the number of nodes from want to be the number of edges if we have a
to be the number of edges if we have a directed graph basically would be this
directed graph basically would be this pair s comma T where the else goes from
pair s comma T where the else goes from the you know the arrow goes convexity
the you know the arrow goes convexity okay now to really you know extend this
okay now to really you know extend this the bottom directed and directed graphs
the bottom directed and directed graphs you have to use what's called an
you have to use what's called an adjacency matrix so if you define the
adjacency matrix so if you define the adjacency matrix
GF S&amp;P little notes equals one if the ads s comma T is in this set all right
ads s comma T is in this set all right and this allows you to extend this to
and this allows you to extend this to undirected graphs because if you have G
undirected graphs because if you have G of s comma T equal 12 and simultaneous
of s comma T equal 12 and simultaneous in G of T comma X equal to 1 right then
in G of T comma X equal to 1 right then this is an undirected graph there is no
this is an undirected graph there is no going from s to T and T 2 s is the same
going from s to T and T 2 s is the same okay so two examples and I threw a lot
okay so two examples and I threw a lot so far terminology here that's going to
so far terminology here that's going to come in the following slides but it
come in the following slides but it helps to see them several times so you
helps to see them several times so you have note one two three four five I am
have note one two three four five I am going to call note one the road all
going to call note one the road all right can you give me without rocks or
right can you give me without rocks or even reading the pull up slides just
even reading the pull up slides just look on the graph what do you think the
look on the graph what do you think the route will be I mean wouldn't be a good
route will be I mean wouldn't be a good this mixture
this mixture I mean you notice okay there is from you
I mean you notice okay there is from you know so so in other ways why you know
know so so in other ways why you know the route is of five and it's one what
the route is of five and it's one what will be a good definition
right so so so I am repeating the answer here in this case one has not lost
here in this case one has not lost coming to it okay and as we will see
coming to it okay and as we will see this implies following in definitions
this implies following in definitions when I come up with one has no father
when I come up with one has no father okay
okay and with a definition five them that is
and with a definition five them that is the nature of the graph five has no
the nature of the graph five has no children
children okay so five has not simply sent one is
okay so five has not simply sent one is the ornament of - all right and three
the ornament of - all right and three you know here you know 40s - power is
you know here you know 40s - power is two and three
two and three okay etc and to achieve what else to
okay etc and to achieve what else to come together is important and it phase
come together is important and it phase again this is coming up later but I want
again this is coming up later but I want you to see hundreds of times so we can
you to see hundreds of times so we can communicate it says this directed a
communicate it says this directed a means it has no cycles of a cyclic graph
means it has no cycles of a cyclic graph all right
all right you noticed has no better it has no
you noticed has no better it has no cycles someone would say this is a cycle
cycles someone would say this is a cycle but actually because this is the
but actually because this is the electric graph you notice when I go the
electric graph you notice when I go the direction of the arrows here I cannot go
direction of the arrows here I cannot go from four to three
from four to three so there are no cycles them okay
so there are no cycles them okay alright so we discussed this and then it
alright so we discussed this and then it says the notes are number in topological
says the notes are number in topological order so what does not mean looks very
order so what does not mean looks very sensual for the left graph what do we
sensual for the left graph what do we mean - political order just looking at
mean - political order just looking at this graph basically what will be sort
this graph basically what will be sort of your imagination share with us so the
of your imagination share with us so the numbering change in topological order so
I mean complain I have always one two three four five
all right the tradition hearing bit right which since we define the route to
right which since we define the route to be the note that has no parents all
be the note that has no parents all right so basically we have to start
right so basically we have to start numbering from the root to the leaves
numbering from the root to the leaves basically okay and that's a topological
basically okay and that's a topological order not to more complicated God you
order not to more complicated God you know this may not be a unique
know this may not be a unique topological order all right but you
topological order all right but you start majestically you are not going to
start majestically you are not going to assign to the chain to the children
assign to the chain to the children notice that they're in the order of
notice that they're in the order of numbering on the part right number the
numbering on the part right number the parents and the children that's the idea
parents and the children that's the idea here
here okay so 2 &amp; 3 are the children so 1 will
okay so 2 &amp; 3 are the children so 1 will be there to enter it will be there
be there to enter it will be there similarly these are the parents of
similarly these are the parents of course draw the numbering of topological
course draw the numbering of topological order makes sense ok the same graph now
order makes sense ok the same graph now if it was an undirected graph okay
if it was an undirected graph okay these I'm pouring and lots of things
these I'm pouring and lots of things because you know I want you to see those
because you know I want you to see those things
things hundreds of times and I'm details that
hundreds of times and I'm details that are going to be discussed with lots of
are going to be discussed with lots of simple examples in coop lectures right
simple examples in coop lectures right but I want you to see these things now
but I want you to see these things now so in some sense I'm claiming that the
so in some sense I'm claiming that the gallop you see here it is very much the
gallop you see here it is very much the same as that job but they see there is
same as that job but they see there is something going on that's a little bit
something going on that's a little bit different what's the difference between
different what's the difference between the two block when you look at them okay
the two block when you look at them okay there are no arrows but there is
there are no arrows but there is something else that is different so what
something else that is different so what is definitely when you visually look at
is definitely when you visually look at this two and three are connected
this two and three are connected and that's an essential step when you go
and that's an essential step when you go from directly drafts from directed so
from directly drafts from directed so what are the two and three note what is
what are the two and three note what is common between two and three their
common between two and three their parent just know the
their points of what of power so when you went from a directed graph to UM
you went from a directed graph to UM directive what you need to do is you
directive what you need to do is you need to be sure the parents are married
need to be sure the parents are married because this is not today we don't allow
because this is not today we don't allow Mary power okay so we marry them all
Mary power okay so we marry them all right and this process methodical is
right and this process methodical is called a modernization process okay
called a modernization process okay people who think that I'm you know my
people who think that I'm you know my let you guess religious connotations but
let you guess religious connotations but that's the terminology moralization
that's the terminology moralization okay so you basically have to marry the
okay so you basically have to marry the parents okay
parents okay and actually immediately you can see
and actually immediately you can see when you marry the parents you get moved
when you marry the parents you get moved in this graph
in this graph okay so suddenly you went from no loops
okay so suddenly you went from no loops to two loops right and and obvious
to two loops right and and obvious implications in the way we're going to
implications in the way we're going to treat this process now in the graphs
treat this process now in the graphs once you moralize you marry the parts
once you moralize you marry the parts two and three we define what this whole
two and three we define what this whole page and if particularly of interest
page and if particularly of interest here is what is called maximal cliques
here is what is called maximal cliques okay so click is a set of interconnected
okay so click is a set of interconnected no okay so for example if you this is
no okay so for example if you this is one two or three is a clique right
one two or three is a clique right because one is connected to one squared
because one is connected to one squared - 3 + 2 is correct - 3 all the nodes are
- 3 + 2 is correct - 3 all the nodes are connected now you say is 1 2 3 and
connected now you say is 1 2 3 and privately why not
privately why not one employee without connected right 2 +
one employee without connected right 2 + 5 3 &amp; 5 are not correct ok so 1 2 &amp; 3 2
5 3 &amp; 5 are not correct ok so 1 2 &amp; 3 2 3 &amp; 4 &amp; 3 &amp; 5 of what they call we
3 &amp; 4 &amp; 3 &amp; 5 of what they call we called maxima please
called maxima please and I can tell you and this will come in
and I can tell you and this will come in four five lectures I don't know the idea
four five lectures I don't know the idea of identifying this parchment which will
of identifying this parchment which will be but when we take a joint probability
be but when we take a joint probability distribution of this paragraph around
distribution of this paragraph around the variables we're going to be able to
the variables we're going to be able to write the joint distribution as the
write the joint distribution as the product of potentials is with this
product of potentials is with this potential behind on our table please
potential behind on our table please so the local potentials what its
so the local potentials what its potential would be on automatically and
potential would be on automatically and that would be actually an amazing
that would be actually an amazing theorem which we are going to prove
theorem which we are going to prove right but somehow if you have a graph
right but somehow if you have a graph like that and a probability distribution
like that and a probability distribution defined on this graph then that you can
defined on this graph then that you can decompose it on potentials defined over
decompose it on potentials defined over this box conflicts okay
this box conflicts okay again think of this as start from the
again think of this as start from the air ideas because we will discuss those
air ideas because we will discuss those as we go in underneath a course okay so
as we go in underneath a course okay so let's see the parents of a node all
let's see the parents of a node all right you remember the conduit defining
right you remember the conduit defining what was the name of G this is the
what was the name of G this is the adjacency matrix so the parent of a node
adjacency matrix so the parent of a node s are all the node equal G of T comma s
s are all the node equal G of T comma s is equal to R so for example the parent
is equal to R so for example the parent of non-stick are two and five okay and
of non-stick are two and five okay and you can denote this as five six equal to
you can denote this as five six equal to point 5 or X 5 6 you know different
point 5 or X 5 6 you know different notations I think this is participating
notations I think this is participating both notations are the ones used by
the Michael Jordan stuff the two dates of no vest are basically the notes leaf
of no vest are basically the notes leaf touch of Geo Testament equal to one the
touch of Geo Testament equal to one the climbing of an old alright is best and
climbing of an old alright is best and the pairing suppressed and so I actually
the pairing suppressed and so I actually what I was looking is like you know why
what I was looking is like you know why they don't like the children all right
they don't like the children all right but somehow that's why maybe I never use
but somehow that's why maybe I never use the terminology commonly but until we
the terminology commonly but until we find that this is not right in
find that this is not right in definition this is what it is there so
definition this is what it is there so the family is asked and the parts of us
the family is asked and the parts of us we already discussed route least the
we already discussed route least the knows no parents to leave the know dot
knows no parents to leave the know dot children the ancestors of an LP are all
children the ancestors of an LP are all the notes s where there is a path from s
the notes s where there is a path from s to T and equal to directed graph this
to T and equal to directed graph this path has to be a directed path if some
path has to be a directed path if some directed basically any path from s to T
directed basically any path from s to T will do it and the descendants of an
will do it and the descendants of an arrest are all the nodes right but you
arrest are all the nodes right but you can find the trail from s to T and again
can find the trail from s to T and again in the ref graphs this trail we have to
in the ref graphs this trail we have to follow the arrow so these are the
follow the arrow so these are the ancestors and goes to the central the
ancestors and goes to the central the [Applause]
[Applause] neighborhoods and it doesn't matter what
neighborhoods and it doesn't matter what I will graph we have the immediately
I will graph we have the immediately corrected note so the neighbors of s all
corrected note so the neighbors of s all the taste provided 0% equal to one of G
the taste provided 0% equal to one of G of T of s equal to one
of T of s equal to one okay so in defining the neighbors given
okay so in defining the neighbors given even if it's a directed graph the
even if it's a directed graph the orientation
orientation it's not important so the degree of a
it's not important so the degree of a node is the number of neighbors and in
node is the number of neighbors and in particular you would see this and lots
particular you would see this and lots of Muslim leavening books the in-and-out
of Muslim leavening books the in-and-out degrees basically count the number of
degrees basically count the number of parents and the number of children so
parents and the number of children so when they say the in degrees the number
when they say the in degrees the number of parents they are degrees the number
of parents they are degrees the number of children and this is sort of an
of children and this is sort of an important concept because when we write
important concept because when we write the joint probability distribution we
the joint probability distribution we would see the factorization will still
would see the factorization will still basically with this in degrees with a
basically with this in degrees with a number of parents retaining I may
number of parents retaining I may actually show you in the slide shortly
actually show you in the slide shortly we already discuss the concept of a
we already discuss the concept of a directed cycle alright so in this
directed cycle alright so in this diagram here there is no directed cycle
diagram here there is no directed cycle but you notice from this this one okay
but you notice from this this one okay on this there is no directed cycle all
on this there is no directed cycle all right so a directed Pacific Loft is a
right so a directed Pacific Loft is a directed graph with non directed cycles
directed graph with non directed cycles okay
okay and most of the graphs we are going to
and most of the graphs we are going to use will be direct the strictly graphs
use will be direct the strictly graphs but you know when we generalized we will
but you know when we generalized we will be able to go away without okay this
be able to go away without okay this principle the three and the direct entry
principle the three and the direct entry is very essential because algorithms on
is very essential because algorithms on three are they just implement all right
three are they just implement all right and you know we wish that every graph
and you know we wish that every graph was a three because if it's a three we
was a three because if it's a three we can do inference in second so this total
can do inference in second so this total would be an ideal situation so an
would be an ideal situation so an undirected three is an undirected graph
undirected three is an undirected graph with no cycles all right and for an
with no cycles all right and for an undirected tree there is a single path
undirected tree there is a single path between any pair of nodes okay
between any pair of nodes okay and I'm starting with this right because
and I'm starting with this right because I would be to be able to define this
I would be to be able to define this concept of 23 for directed graphs and
concept of 23 for directed graphs and with an internal directory strain on
with an internal directory strain on directory is an undirected graph with no
directory is an undirected graph with no cycles okay so for example did we have
cycles okay so for example did we have an undirected three stomach work without
an undirected three stomach work without cycles here so this is not good then we
cycles here so this is not good then we have reading picture anyway specimen and
have reading picture anyway specimen and don't see it and maybe we'll want to
don't see it and maybe we'll want to come alright for our way so you know
come alright for our way so you know directory has no cycles so there is a
directory has no cycles so there is a single path from any pair of nodes now a
single path from any pair of nodes now a directed three is a directed three is a
directed three is a directed three is a directed a strictly graph in which every
directed a strictly graph in which every node has at most one Parliament can we
node has at most one Parliament can we tell me why do we want one parent and
tell me why do we want one parent and how is that going to be connected with
how is that going to be connected with the modernization process that I
the modernization process that I mentioned
mentioned for it says the director 3 is a dog in
for it says the director 3 is a dog in which every notice at most one part you
which every notice at most one part you never are certified for there this
never are certified for there this equivalency of a directive three-wheeler
equivalency of a directive three-wheeler on directly after we did some operations
on directly after we did some operations which we called moralization success a
which we called moralization success a directory is a dog in which every notice
directory is a dog in which every notice of Western palate so why the authorities
of Western palate so why the authorities think has one polished because it has
think has one polished because it has two polished then what is going to
two polished then what is going to happen when we transform it to know
happen when we transform it to know directly graph we will marry those
directly graph we will marry those parents and as a result we will get the
parents and as a result we will get the site right so in directed three needs to
site right so in directed three needs to care everyone has at most one part okay
care everyone has at most one part okay now so this will be ideal situations
now so this will be ideal situations right to have enough directly or the
right to have enough directly or the direction three now if we have directed
direction three now if we have directed a strictly graphical just one on one
a strictly graphical just one on one parent right and we mobilize it
parent right and we mobilize it effectively we will get you know we get
effectively we will get you know we get cycles but if the undirected glass that
cycles but if the undirected glass that we get is a tree all right then we can
we get is a tree all right then we can call this the recognizer for the pony
call this the recognizer for the pony tree okay so let's see some examples
tree okay so let's see some examples here
can you tell me which one this graphs is a train which to one is a poly-tree or
a train which to one is a poly-tree or you know what is this car is this Satori
you know what is this car is this Satori they're coming to our definition right
they're coming to our definition right over there ft3 is very very noxious of
over there ft3 is very very noxious of most one pilot does this loop to be like
most one pilot does this loop to be like a tree right so this actually transform
a tree right so this actually transform in eastern undirected graph right there
in eastern undirected graph right there will be no novelization of step so the
will be no novelization of step so the interconnect is not in that because you
interconnect is not in that because you know this just this is the part that has
know this just this is the part that has happened father
happened father so you have every not just one part so
so you have every not just one part so there would be a single platform
there would be a single platform everybody know to any other node so this
everybody know to any other node so this 2 3 now why is this a 33 it looks like
2 3 now why is this a 33 it looks like in a simple tree but actually it's a 43
in a simple tree but actually it's a 43 the reason is what this night has how
the reason is what this night has how many product is 2 so when you merge them
many product is 2 so when you merge them all right
all right and you make this an undirected graph
and you make this an undirected graph yes there is a single path from every
yes there is a single path from every node to any other node but there is a
node to any other node but there is a cycle there ok
cycle there ok now obviously you know the algorithms
now obviously you know the algorithms will get a bit more complicated when you
will get a bit more complicated when you have a poly-tree
have a poly-tree but actually when you transform this to
but actually when you transform this to the third form of graph that I call it
the third form of graph that I call it the pasta graph but you will see that
the pasta graph but you will see that you can treat the 23 basically a penny
you can treat the 23 basically a penny tree will become actually there at 3
tree will become actually there at 3 okay and then you can apply the standard
okay and then you can apply the standard algorithm so we've seen this cost okay
algorithm so we've seen this cost okay but you need to change the grade the the
but you need to change the grade the the graph is the quad so now think this
graph is the quad so now think this would be a fantastic for graphs look
would be a fantastic for graphs look like that this will also be fantastic so
like that this will also be fantastic so it is more complicated but somehow we
it is more complicated but somehow we will be able to do you know develop
will be able to do you know develop algorithms that they have the same
algorithms that they have the same complex this it will work
complex this it will work okay so this is basically the same thing
okay so this is basically the same thing we just discussed and the same thing
we just discussed and the same thing here so we talked about cliques and
here so we talked about cliques and maximal cliques so there is this
maximal cliques so there is this constant of a clique is only defined for
constant of a clique is only defined for undirected graphs and again a much more
undirected graphs and again a much more clique is the the highest number of
clique is the the highest number of interconnected nodes and highest number
interconnected nodes and highest number means you cannot go and consider adding
means you cannot go and consider adding another no to the clique without
another no to the clique without violating the property okay so this
violating the property okay so this would be an essential development sir
would be an essential development sir charies a directed graph when you
charies a directed graph when you mobilize this to make it an undirected
mobilize this to make it an undirected graph that looks like up okay so what
graph that looks like up okay so what what parents if I married here 2 &amp; 3
what parents if I married here 2 &amp; 3 right 5 this pillow and that C 7 has how
right 5 this pillow and that C 7 has how many parents has 3 votes right how's the
many parents has 3 votes right how's the post will have three parts well there's
post will have three parts well there's some religion is allowed okay so we
some religion is allowed okay so we marry for a 5 pollen sticks okay so
marry for a 5 pollen sticks okay so alright and again you know I'm trying
alright and again you know I'm trying this just to treat from now but yeah
this just to treat from now but yeah we're going to discuss this in details
we're going to discuss this in details right so you know just remember what
right so you know just remember what this process of organization means and
this process of organization means and somehow we haven't proved the district
somehow we haven't proved the district we will into this and whatever you know
we will into this and whatever you know how many I said well equivalent means
how many I said well equivalent means right so we will see when we discussed
right so we will see when we discussed about optimization of the joint
about optimization of the joint probability distribution
probability distribution - gross alright so highways the goal
- gross alright so highways the goal right so let me give you without any
right so let me give you without any prints or anything like that okay
prints or anything like that okay because we will come back to this I
because we will come back to this I would join probably distribution of this
would join probably distribution of this seven variables is they compose based on
seven variables is they compose based on the graph that you see okay so the
the graph that you see okay so the notation next one to seven means this is
notation next one to seven means this is the joint probability electronic Stewart
the joint probability electronic Stewart seven and now if we have a graph right
seven and now if we have a graph right and somebody gives you the the you know
and somebody gives you the the you know P effects want to at seven the theory
P effects want to at seven the theory tells you what's the what is going to be
tells you what's the what is going to be the right hand side
the right hand side I mean without looking at this right so
I mean without looking at this right so you don't look at this what is to
you don't look at this what is to improve ability relates to join of
improve ability relates to join of variables of the two effects one touch
variables of the two effects one touch seven varieties will be north x one
seven varieties will be north x one times what the effect is even worth
times what the effect is even worth after and and p53 given x1 x2 etc now if
after and and p53 given x1 x2 etc now if you notice general claiming well it's
you notice general claiming well it's actually much simpler that states P of
actually much simpler that states P of x1 times P of x2 given X 1 P of X 3
x1 times P of x2 given X 1 P of X 3 given X 1 P notice that in the worst
given X 1 P notice that in the worst case there are like three arguments in
case there are like three arguments in the condition can look at the graph to
the condition can look at the graph to look at this equation and tells me again
look at this equation and tells me again I'm feeling nothing like I'm spying is
I'm feeling nothing like I'm spying is there and can you look at this and
there and can you look at this and somehow imagine what the God tells you
somehow imagine what the God tells you but somehow it's not first this equation
but somehow it's not first this equation without integration
well it's so basically if service Bathurst is so every which is a copter
Bathurst is so every which is a copter and in this case this parcel is a
and in this case this parcel is a probability is a conditional probability
probability is a conditional probability distribution of the the variable in that
distribution of the the variable in that note conditioned on its parent so here I
note conditioned on its parent so here I have the probability of X 1 conditioned
have the probability of X 1 conditioned on the parents of X 1 what parents each
on the parents of X 1 what parents each one has no extradition apparent which is
one has no extradition apparent which is one extreme condition the parents which
one extreme condition the parents which is one except 12 condition the parents
is one except 12 condition the parents which is 2 X tribe on 2 &amp; 3 that's fixed
which is 2 X tribe on 2 &amp; 3 that's fixed on 5 &amp; 3 &amp; at 7 on 4 5 &amp; 6
on 5 &amp; 3 &amp; at 7 on 4 5 &amp; 6 now the reason that this looks way
now the reason that this looks way simpler run the what the product will
simpler run the what the product will repel you write the people first time we
repel you write the people first time we have actually said one condition of x1
have actually said one condition of x1 x2 x3 x4 x5 x6 the fact that you don't
x2 x3 x4 x5 x6 the fact that you don't have X 1 X 2 X 3 X 2 X 3 means that X 7
have X 1 X 2 X 3 X 2 X 3 means that X 7 is independent of the variables X 1 X 2
is independent of the variables X 1 X 2 X 3
X 3 given the variables X 4 X 5 vs. now I
given the variables X 4 X 5 vs. now I have no proof anything I'm just telling
have no proof anything I'm just telling what the answers would be when we do the
what the answers would be when we do the proof okay so somehow look at the graph
proof okay so somehow look at the graph you should be able to immediately just
you should be able to immediately just from the graph presented the composition
from the graph presented the composition that you know is the correct
that you know is the correct decomposition so here I have to do
decomposition so here I have to do calculations by chant and try for 10
calculations by chant and try for 10 hours and addition so that you know
hours and addition so that you know immediately with that perform this and
this you know you know if we had seven variables and each variable takes K
variables and each variable takes K values the with no independence
values the with no independence relations right I'm gonna need five to
relations right I'm gonna need five to the seventh to describe the joint
the seventh to describe the joint probability distribution on the left
probability distribution on the left hand side but you noticed
hand side but you noticed requiring sort of probability tables
requiring sort of probability tables Hotel smaller size so let's say P X 1
Hotel smaller size so let's say P X 1 you need K values be affected to give an
you need K values be affected to give an extra on K square I'm not a counting
extra on K square I'm not a counting here for the harmonization of this
here for the harmonization of this probabilities make like is e this is K 3
probabilities make like is e this is K 3 and this is K 4 so basically if we have
and this is K 4 so basically if we have independence relations that you see in
independence relations that you see in the graph we haven't really proved
the graph we haven't really proved anything again I emphasized this is
anything again I emphasized this is lecture wrong to just scare you so you
lecture wrong to just scare you so you can not come on closely but this it's K
can not come on closely but this it's K to the fourth versus if you have no
to the fourth versus if you have no independence at all which would be K to
independence at all which would be K to the sub okay so independence relations
the sub okay so independence relations and independence relations in the graph
and independence relations in the graph G no imply from the talk but let's say
G no imply from the talk but let's say no two and three are not linked right
no two and three are not linked right two and seven are not linked politics on
two and seven are not linked politics on of being one is definitely so this lot
of being one is definitely so this lot of edges between knowledge is what leads
of edges between knowledge is what leads to this factorization and that's very
to this factorization and that's very nice because you can read it on the
nice because you can read it on the clock because each of these
clock because each of these distributions is a factor of the
distributions is a factor of the probability of hits note from this
probability of hits note from this knowledge part
145 that's when we supposed to finish all right so I'm going to continue on
all right so I'm going to continue on this lecture with a few more examples
this lecture with a few more examples and then we will take things slowly and
and then we will take things slowly and discuss all the details on directed
discuss all the details on directed graphs and we will move from there
graphs and we will move from there so the website I will try to put the
so the website I will try to put the neck strap at the latest way tomorrow
neck strap at the latest way tomorrow we've had the latest by tomorrow okay
we've had the latest by tomorrow okay and and actually I'm going to tend to
and and actually I'm going to tend to those register and when I sent a copy of
those register and when I sent a copy of at least paper Bakula chapter from
at least paper Bakula chapter from Jordans butcher you can start reading
Jordans butcher you can start reading them all right so I'll see you on
them all right so I'll see you on Thursday