all right let's see as you know the second homework has less time for you to
second homework has less time for you to work simply because I want to be sure
work simply because I want to be sure that we at least cover 6 homework 9 I
that we at least cover 6 homework 9 I noticed some of you don't bother about
noticed some of you don't bother about homework because you're auditing the
homework because you're auditing the class disappointed to hear that okay
a recommendation when we post home most keep revisiting them because when I get
keep revisiting them because when I get comments from students from when I look
comments from students from when I look back I go directly and who changes their
back I go directly and who changes their and I don't want to keep sending
and I don't want to keep sending messages saying we change this and that
messages saying we change this and that so please you know look on the website
so please you know look on the website for changes okay so we talked about the
for changes okay so we talked about the elimination algorithm last week both for
elimination algorithm last week both for directed or undirected graphs and today
directed or undirected graphs and today we want sort of to revisit the
we want sort of to revisit the elimination algorithm but put it on a
elimination algorithm but put it on a form that is related to what's called
form that is related to what's called message passing and the Beyonder that
message passing and the Beyonder that goes through this name is called the
goes through this name is called the Stamper of the algorithm in essence is
Stamper of the algorithm in essence is the same sort of a state elimination
the same sort of a state elimination algorithm but read people way more
algorithm but read people way more efficient depending on what type of so
efficient depending on what type of so we're going to apply this first to twist
we're going to apply this first to twist and then next week we will extend it to
and then next week we will extend it to general graph so actually when we apply
general graph so actually when we apply it brings me we see that this algorithms
it brings me we see that this algorithms are really exact incredible items so
are really exact incredible items so there are no proximation to be done
there are no proximation to be done right so let me bring out some of the
right so let me bring out some of the basic ideas we have seen with the
basic ideas we have seen with the elimination algorithm so here is the
elimination algorithm so here is the directed graph 5 note this is the
directed graph 5 note this is the decomposition of the joint the total
decomposition of the joint the total ization of the joint applied by the
ization of the joint applied by the graph and let's say that the inference
graph and let's say that the inference asked that were interested is to compute
asked that were interested is to compute the probability of pay given the Capital
the probability of pay given the Capital steez needle stick okay so you know so
steez needle stick okay so you know so this is the problem actually we have
this is the problem actually we have discussed up to now for several lectures
discussed up to now for several lectures so obviously you know you know you can
so obviously you know you know you can start completing this conditional using
start completing this conditional using this factorization and this is going to
this factorization and this is going to be elective process so let's check how
be elective process so let's check how you're going to do this with 20 of
you're going to do this with 20 of resistance so to complete this you will
resistance so to complete this you will need to compute the jointer plane three
need to compute the jointer plane three divided by the probability of capital C
divided by the probability of capital C being the trustee to compute the joint
being the trustee to compute the joint of a entity series and evidence killed
of a entity series and evidence killed equal to little T obviously you're going
equal to little T obviously you're going to have to take this join distribution
to have to take this join distribution of ABCDE and marginalize out BD any so
of ABCDE and marginalize out BD any so you have to perform this operation of
you have to perform this operation of this here and if we assume that these
this here and if we assume that these variables are all binary you will need
variables are all binary you will need two terms from B two terms for these two
two terms from B two terms for these two terms for e so eight terms and you need
terms for e so eight terms and you need to compute the same terms for each of
to compute the same terms for each of the values of a which are two so this
the values of a which are two so this calculation is 16 operation okay so this
calculation is 16 operation okay so this is what you seal the you know the
is what you seal the you know the numerator here to compute this you will
numerator here to compute this you will have to do marginalization a okay so
have to do marginalization a okay so that's two operations and to compute
that's two operations and to compute this ratio you have to compute this for
this ratio you have to compute this for every value of pay in order to operation
every value of pay in order to operation so if the calculation count is correct
so if the calculation count is correct you need 20 operations basically to do
you need 20 operations basically to do this right so the more efficient method
this right so the more efficient method based on the elimination when we discuss
based on the elimination when we discuss is to actually compute this by pushing
is to actually compute this by pushing forward some of the summation so now if
forward some of the summation so now if you notice I put the semester only on
you notice I put the semester only on this peril reservation on the investor
this peril reservation on the investor all the terms come from the factories
all the terms come from the factories ation of the joint and by magic because
ation of the joint and by magic because these are conditional distributions this
these are conditional distributions this term is equal to 1 this term is equal to
term is equal to 1 this term is equal to 1 and the only thing you have to compute
1 and the only thing you have to compute is literation right so two values of B
is literation right so two values of B and you have to compute them for two
and you have to compute them for two values to pay this is only for
values to pay this is only for operations and if you look back this was
operations and if you look back this was 16 operations right so basically the
16 operations right so basically the elimination algorithm now allows us to
elimination algorithm now allows us to compute this marginals things like this
compute this marginals things like this in a way more efficient way than just
in a way more efficient way than just doing you know multi-generation using
doing you know multi-generation using this factorization implied by the graph
this factorization implied by the graph alright so 20 operations if you don't do
alright so 20 operations if you don't do anything special if you use the
anything special if you use the elimination algorithm for this directed
elimination algorithm for this directed graph you only get this in eight
graph you only get this in eight operations eight operations because this
operations eight operations because this is for than the other two steps are
is for than the other two steps are basically identical less so there is a
basically identical less so there is a problem with this algorithms with
problem with this algorithms with elimination algorithm and the problem is
elimination algorithm and the problem is that we focus on calculating one
that we focus on calculating one marginal or unconditional distribution
marginal or unconditional distribution of the time all right so in this problem
of the time all right so in this problem if let's say your objective is to
if let's say your objective is to calculate I don't know the probability
calculate I don't know the probability of being given streak one little tree
of being given streak one little tree you will have to repeat this from
you will have to repeat this from scratch
scratch that's waste of time so the algorithms
that's waste of time so the algorithms we will discuss today is how do we
we will discuss today is how do we complete not just let's say one
complete not just let's say one condition
or one marginal but other conditionals are all marginal in the graph all
are all marginal in the graph all applaud so given the evidence
applaud so given the evidence what's the conditional distribution of
what's the conditional distribution of 40 other notes okay one at the time can
40 other notes okay one at the time can we do this more efficiently without
we do this more efficiently without having to repeat this for every case in
having to repeat this for every case in principle can we do some calculations
principle can we do some calculations that can be recycled as we compute one
that can be recycled as we compute one marginal or one conditional at the time
marginal or one conditional at the time can we recycle some calculations and the
can we recycle some calculations and the operation that we discuss today it's
operation that we discuss today it's basically sub chaser for the score
basically sub chaser for the score belief propagation methods okay but
belief propagation methods okay but today what we will see is exactly the
today what we will see is exactly the wave propagation in tricks okay so you
wave propagation in tricks okay so you will see mathematically there is really
will see mathematically there is really no new techniques on what we will
no new techniques on what we will discuss but the algorithm is way more
discuss but the algorithm is way more Christians and elimination of so any
Christians and elimination of so any questions with what we have seen up to
questions with what we have seen up to now with the elimination algorithm for
now with the elimination algorithm for directed or undirected graphs okay so
directed or undirected graphs okay so some kind of thing I have a repeat of
some kind of thing I have a repeat of the algorithm again but we still Isis
the algorithm again but we still Isis will go so the idea is to you know
will go so the idea is to you know remember when we did the elimination
remember when we did the elimination algorithm we calculated a lots of
algorithm we calculated a lots of intermediate factors so the adage can we
intermediate factors so the adage can we really use those intravenous factors to
really use those intravenous factors to compute multiple Martinez at the same
compute multiple Martinez at the same time and we will do this today but only
time and we will do this today but only we will do this for priests and three
we will do this for priests and three like graphs
like graphs okay if you try to do this for general
okay if you try to do this for general graphs basically the algorithm needs to
graphs basically the algorithm needs to lots of modifications and the algorithm
lots of modifications and the algorithm we go the general average wanted the
we go the general average wanted the name Junction tree algorithm okay and we
name Junction tree algorithm okay and we will discuss this next next week so
will discuss this next next week so right now we will concentrate on three
right now we will concentrate on three stand three like graphs
stand three like graphs and we received wiser so let's turn
and we received wiser so let's turn motivate what's going on with a little
motivate what's going on with a little chain so let's say we have the joint
chain so let's say we have the joint distribution of x1 to xn and we want to
distribution of x1 to xn and we want to compute the marginal distribution of
compute the marginal distribution of literary note the extent but we wanted
literary note the extent but we wanted to compute in a way that will allow us
to compute in a way that will allow us almost no additional costs to compute
almost no additional costs to compute the marginal support of the other notes
the marginal support of the other notes as well so we're going to do this
as well so we're going to do this calculation in a little bit more
calculation in a little bit more efficient way than we have done before
efficient way than we have done before so perfect I am taking the maximal
so perfect I am taking the maximal cliques here - or for this bill so I
cliques here - or for this bill so I write the effectors this undirected
write the effectors this undirected graph is the potential of the nodes 1 &amp;
graph is the potential of the nodes 1 &amp; 2 2 &amp; 3 and minus 1 and then and and
2 2 &amp; 3 and minus 1 and then and and because these are not probabilities
because these are not probabilities argue the factorization I use the an
argue the factorization I use the an organization factor T there to take care
organization factor T there to take care but this product basically one of us he
but this product basically one of us he gives me a value all right so this guy
gives me a value all right so this guy in the question below
in the question below it's sort of an elimination algorithm
it's sort of an elimination algorithm but very much different from what we
but very much different from what we have seen up to now with the elimination
have seen up to now with the elimination both of the resident of directed graphs
both of the resident of directed graphs so I want you to look at this equation
so I want you to look at this equation and tell me what is different you know
and tell me what is different you know this I have two terms one on the top and
this I have two terms one on the top and one on the bottom
one on the bottom alright and I remind you the extend
alright and I remind you the extend means I have to integrate on all
means I have to integrate on all variables what extent and this is what I
variables what extent and this is what I have done here but I have done it in
have done here but I have done it in some specific order so I want you to
some specific order so I want you to tell me what this is special there in
tell me what this is special there in the order and how is that different from
the order and how is that different from before so the node exchange some quality
before so the node exchange some quality on the middle somewhere there it doesn't
on the middle somewhere there it doesn't have to be in the middle but it's
have to be in the middle but it's somewhere in between
so on the first summation I am starting something from the right to the left
something from the right to the left from summing from x1 to x2 to xn minus 1
from summing from x1 to x2 to xn minus 1 so I am propagating information from X
so I am propagating information from X run all the way to excel all right and
run all the way to excel all right and look now in the summation on the bottom
look now in the summation on the bottom I have rearranged it in such a way that
I have rearranged it in such a way that the first terminal Excel then on X X
the first terminal Excel then on X X capital n the next capital n minus 1 all
capital n the next capital n minus 1 all the way to extend so I propagate
the way to extend so I propagate information from X capital n to excess
information from X capital n to excess so I propagate from the right to the
so I propagate from the right to the next step so there is a portable
next step so there is a portable propagation of information to node X N
propagation of information to node X N and there is a marker propagation of
and there is a marker propagation of information from the last node X capital
information from the last node X capital of time ok so this is not similar to
of time ok so this is not similar to what we did with the elimination
what we did with the elimination algorithm right where we start
algorithm right where we start eliminating with some order here we are
eliminating with some order here we are sending messages from the left and we
sending messages from the left and we are sending message from the right and
are sending message from the right and I'm going to define what this messages
I'm going to define what this messages are and actually the definition to start
are and actually the definition to start with the message that is being sent from
with the message that is being sent from the left to node X n is denoted here mu
the left to node X n is denoted here mu alpha of X 10 is the function of xn is
alpha of X 10 is the function of xn is basically or is the product of all the
basically or is the product of all the potentials to the left of the node X 10
potentials to the left of the node X 10 where all the other variables for the
where all the other variables for the chain have been some towers okay and if
chain have been some towers okay and if mu beta is the father of all the terms
mu beta is the father of all the terms to the right where everything has been
to the right where everything has been somehow from xn plus 1 to X capital n
somehow from xn plus 1 to X capital n except little XL okay but it is not just
except little XL okay but it is not just simple definition here right the
simple definition here right the definition implies the destinations this
definition implies the destinations this calculation happens in the proper way
calculation happens in the proper way that you see here that implies some
that you see here that implies some recursive relations for this message
recursive relations for this message this new
this new new beta and I'm gonna write those
new beta and I'm gonna write those recursive relationship one second okay
recursive relationship one second okay so look carefully at this equation earth
so look carefully at this equation earth right we define this to be mu alpha and
right we define this to be mu alpha and I denoted here is basically we call it
I denoted here is basically we call it the masters that is tenth two from the
the masters that is tenth two from the left that's alpha the notation used by
left that's alpha the notation used by bishop to the node extent and mu beta is
bishop to the node extent and mu beta is the message sent by the notes to the
the message sent by the notes to the right of return okay
right of return okay and the definition is what you see here
and the definition is what you see here and the master comes to be basically the
and the master comes to be basically the product of new alpha times mu beta
product of new alpha times mu beta divided by the normalization factor of Z
divided by the normalization factor of Z so effectively if you want to calculate
so effectively if you want to calculate with this definition the P of X then
with this definition the P of X then what you need to do is calculate this
what you need to do is calculate this message me alpha by beta of Excel and
message me alpha by beta of Excel and then multiply them and normalize them
then multiply them and normalize them and you're done
and you're done so before it's in slide that I give you
so before it's in slide that I give you the the recursive relationship from your
the the recursive relationship from your from your beta can you just you know can
from your beta can you just you know can you guess the well the recursive
you guess the well the recursive relation you can take here but what I
relation you can take here but what I was going to ask you well can you guess
was going to ask you well can you guess how this can reduce information that the
how this can reduce information that the elimination algorithm could not do I
elimination algorithm could not do I mean look at this the way that these
mean look at this the way that these messages you know when you know this
messages you know when you know this message like that right so it you also
message like that right so it you also but also I put the similar definition of
but also I put the similar definition of new Alpha X n minus 1 which will be the
new Alpha X n minus 1 which will be the product of all the potentials from the
product of all the potentials from the left alright so as I go forward from x1
left alright so as I go forward from x1 to xn minus 1 with all the variables
to xn minus 1 with all the variables eliminated but the x10 - wrong left
eliminated but the x10 - wrong left totally okay so can you see a way where
totally okay so can you see a way where somehow this one where it will be way
somehow this one where it will be way more efficient than integration are
more efficient than integration are and will allow me using this ideation of
and will allow me using this ideation of this derivation to compute the marginal
this derivation to compute the marginal of all the nodes in the graph not one
of all the nodes in the graph not one but all what will be the new algorithm
but all what will be the new algorithm that we can think about in other ways if
that we can think about in other ways if my interest is not the marginal of X 10
my interest is not the marginal of X 10 but the marginal of xn minus 1 according
but the marginal of xn minus 1 according to this derivation how do we compute the
to this derivation how do we compute the marginal of xn minus 1 according to this
marginal of xn minus 1 according to this point will be
I put some of the arrows here I haven't put all the arrows there so how do we
put all the arrows there so how do we compute the marginal of xn minus 1 will
compute the marginal of xn minus 1 will be Miller part of which the function of
be Miller part of which the function of xn minus 1 multiplied with me because
xn minus 1 multiplied with me because the nest is that goes to xn minus 1 from
the nest is that goes to xn minus 1 from the right which is an arrow that would
the right which is an arrow that would be message that goes this way correct
be message that goes this way correct this different ways
this different ways noiseless algorithm that I come to be
noiseless algorithm that I come to be more efficient what the algorithm is
more efficient what the algorithm is going to be like that will allow me to
going to be like that will allow me to compute all the marginals that was well
compute all the marginals that was well the algorithm will be complete all the
the algorithm will be complete all the messages it's forward from left right
messages it's forward from left right compute all the messages backwards from
compute all the messages backwards from right to left and then basically you go
right to left and then basically you go at any node and you actually can compute
at any node and you actually can compute the the marginals by multiplying the
the the marginals by multiplying the messages arriving the update at least
messages arriving the update at least know they often veto messages and the
know they often veto messages and the normalization factor how many times they
normalization factor how many times they have to compute it you know they scared
have to compute it you know they scared well I did not put Z annulation like
well I did not put Z annulation like that but you know the organization
that but you know the organization particle often we have the romanization
particle often we have the romanization factor actually comes here from query
factor actually comes here from query comes from here from the joint so how
comes from here from the joint so how many times you know the romanization
many times you know the romanization factor with check for this case would be
factor with check for this case would be take this product sum it up for all
take this product sum it up for all values of X 10 knots T so how often you
values of X 10 knots T so how often you have to compute
like we'd be another normalization factor for xn minus 1 4 X 1 X capital n
factor for xn minus 1 4 X 1 X capital n no so so 6 computed what okay so what we
no so so 6 computed what okay so what we need to do now is we need to see if this
need to do now is we need to see if this definition of new alpha and the
definition of new alpha and the definition of new beta can be written
definition of new beta can be written down in a way that is sort of recursive
down in a way that is sort of recursive so you can have a nice angle so let's
so you can have a nice angle so let's concentrate on me all right so on so the
concentrate on me all right so on so the new alpha here is also you know this
new alpha here is also you know this summation of everything except extend of
summation of everything except extend of all the potentials to the left of extend
all the potentials to the left of extend okay so summation of xn minus 1 and
okay so summation of xn minus 1 and somewhere here the decimation of xn
somewhere here the decimation of xn minus 2 etc I want you to think visually
minus 2 etc I want you to think visually all right looking on on this definition
all right looking on on this definition here I'm gonna have summation of xn
here I'm gonna have summation of xn minus 2 then X and minus 3 and then X 1
minus 2 then X and minus 3 and then X 1 can you tell me more about summation
can you tell me more about summation starting from xn minus 2 what is that
starting from xn minus 2 what is that what's the name of of summation if the
what's the name of of summation if the name of this is New York off Excel the
name of this is New York off Excel the deen-ul-haq
exhale minus one so basically the encapsulation for the operating system
encapsulation for the operating system right so if you want to compute me Ralph
right so if you want to compute me Ralph Excel what you need to do is sum of
Excel what you need to do is sum of extent - one of the potential the joint
extent - one of the potential the joint xn minus 1 in extender which is this you
xn minus 1 in extender which is this you remember here that's about potential
remember here that's about potential times that summation that we told me
times that summation that we told me starting with xn minus 2 all the way to
starting with xn minus 2 all the way to X - 1 and that's the message near alpha
X - 1 and that's the message near alpha text and minus 1 very easy actually to
text and minus 1 very easy actually to visualize no questions I actually when I
visualize no questions I actually when I look at this right I don't look at the
look at this right I don't look at the equation because the completeness method
equation because the completeness method it's really the message of can stream
it's really the message of can stream which is you know alpha text n minus 1
which is you know alpha text n minus 1 times this potential and then extra one
times this potential and then extra one has to be integrated out because u alpha
has to be integrated out because u alpha is a function of X N and that's it okay
is a function of X N and that's it okay and similarly if you want the message me
and similarly if you want the message me with a recursive relation with Excel
with a recursive relation with Excel would be the message coming out from the
would be the message coming out from the rival function of xn plus 1 times the
rival function of xn plus 1 times the potential of xn xn plus 1 and then we
potential of xn xn plus 1 and then we integrate out xn plus 1 and that's the
integrate out xn plus 1 and that's the recursive relation okay in this chart
recursive relation okay in this chart the chapman-kolmogorov relations that
the chapman-kolmogorov relations that sort of appear not only the context of
sort of appear not only the context of belief propagation but you know many
belief propagation but you know many other areas in automatics for those who
other areas in automatics for those who are you know study dynamic programming
are you know study dynamic programming sort of the substandard equations we
sort of the substandard equations we look over at dynamic programming
look over at dynamic programming problems
someone with me Oscar winter stack one of this recursive
winter stack one of this recursive relation requires for example two no
relation requires for example two no messages at the edges so how do I
messages at the edges so how do I calculate the message that x1 Stanwix to
calculate the message that x1 Stanwix to you I'll predict - so the idea here is
you I'll predict - so the idea here is the only thing you left is the potential
the only thing you left is the potential Taiwan - right there's no previous
Taiwan - right there's no previous message arriving unknown 1 and then what
message arriving unknown 1 and then what you need to do is to integrate on x1 and
you need to do is to integrate on x1 and similarly if you want to find the
similarly if you want to find the lessons about X capital instance
lessons about X capital instance basically you have to integrate X
basically you have to integrate X capital n from the potential Phi of xn
capital n from the potential Phi of xn plus 1 X sorry X n minus 1 extent okay
plus 1 X sorry X n minus 1 extent okay so similarly listening to what disappear
so similarly listening to what disappear so this is sort of abandoned condition
so this is sort of abandoned condition and another boundary condition for the
and another boundary condition for the North extent and then recursively you
North extent and then recursively you compute all the messages you compute all
compute all the messages you compute all the messages then you have everything
the messages then you have everything you have all the marginals you can do
you have all the marginals you can do anything you want all the information is
is inside of messages so think of this message it's right you know if some of
message it's right you know if some of these notes for example of evidence
these notes for example of evidence notes
notes it's basically information that
it's basically information that propagates from this evidence knowledge
propagates from this evidence knowledge to the query note that this case is X 10
to the query note that this case is X 10 ok and somehow what is interesting ok
ok and somehow what is interesting ok and you may want to think this way the
and you may want to think this way the marginal of its note is is this progress
marginal of its note is is this progress of the messages were coming right from
of the messages were coming right from the left and arrived define somehow what
the left and arrived define somehow what the status of node X 10 is okay
the status of node X 10 is okay so effectively you have belief
so effectively you have belief propagation if you like from x1 to xn
propagation if you like from x1 to xn and the neutralization of from X capital
and the neutralization of from X capital and physical extent and those two
and physical extent and those two messages define the stage of the Nordic
messages define the stage of the Nordic sent and it's Martin right you can do
sent and it's Martin right you can do actually lots of trivial calculations
actually lots of trivial calculations and give them as to make an e-commerce
and give them as to make an e-commerce to list mr. Arno
to list mr. Arno all right start writing but they put the
all right start writing but they put the next one massive calm works alright okay
next one massive calm works alright okay so here is the previa calculation and
so here is the previa calculation and let me go back suppose somebody tells
let me go back suppose somebody tells you I want to find the joint probability
you I want to find the joint probability distribution of any two arbitrary no I
distribution of any two arbitrary no I mean so don't look at the questions not
mean so don't look at the questions not look at the notes right the suppose you
look at the notes right the suppose you know I'll give you two nodes and I say
know I'll give you two nodes and I say find me the Joint Distribution what did
find me the Joint Distribution what did you do
you do I mean how you know just thinking of
I mean how you know just thinking of these messages that define the state
these messages that define the state that I have the joint what do you think
that I have the joint what do you think is gonna be happening
you can take the notes to be next to each other far away it doesn't really
each other far away it doesn't really matter but if you want the joint of two
matter but if you want the joint of two notes what do you think it's going to be
notes what do you think it's going to be the actual result
so in this case where they sell to you is the joint of xn minus 1 an extern
is the joint of xn minus 1 an extern okay so is the nest is coming from the
okay so is the nest is coming from the left to xn minus 1 the mess is coming on
left to xn minus 1 the mess is coming on the right times the potential between
the right times the potential between the no 6 and minus 1 an example actually
the no 6 and minus 1 an example actually if you don't believe me that this comes
if you don't believe me that this comes in right what you need to do is start
in right what you need to do is start with your elimination eliminate all the
with your elimination eliminate all the nose to the left of xn minus 1 eliminate
nose to the left of xn minus 1 eliminate all the nose to the right of xn and what
all the nose to the right of xn and what you get the first first you will get the
you get the first first you will get the only thing you will not eliminate is the
only thing you will not eliminate is the potential between xn minus 1 and xn all
potential between xn minus 1 and xn all right
right the summation on the left will give you
the summation on the left will give you this mess with the rest of the right
this mess with the rest of the right will give you that and there is the
will give you that and there is the answer okay and you can do this you know
answer okay and you can do this you know if you do lots of response the things
if you do lots of response the things that you want to compute join these
that you want to compute join these conditions the information is encoded on
conditions the information is encoded on these messages via nice everything is
these messages via nice everything is encoded on this message this once you
encoded on this message this once you have these messages
have these messages whatever query you have if you can
whatever query you have if you can resolve it so the calculation by the way
resolve it so the calculation by the way to do all of this if it's variable can
to do all of this if it's variable can take M values in heaven and you know
take M values in heaven and you know environments so
is two times this times because you have to calculate versus coming the trouble
to calculate versus coming the trouble messages and then the backward messages
messages and then the backward messages the calculation of this each of the
the calculation of this each of the messages is basically M square in heaven
messages is basically M square in heaven also nm square so the cost is two times
also nm square so the cost is two times and M Square and the important thing
and M Square and the important thing here is linear in n and this is what
here is linear in n and this is what you're interested okay
any questions with this algorithm product for change obviously you can
product for change obviously you can imagine that this can be generalized to
imagine that this can be generalized to trees right so we will see how it works
trees right so we will see how it works with this little bit it's not tricky yes
with this little bit it's not tricky yes the same idea more less and the notation
the same idea more less and the notation is the same but you know changed is they
is the same but you know changed is they just wait to see what's going on so now
just wait to see what's going on so now if we have evidence right how do you
if we have evidence right how do you account explicitly for the evidence and
account explicitly for the evidence and the answer to our question it it's
the answer to our question it it's actually the same way as what we have
actually the same way as what we have done is the so in this case that a you
done is the so in this case that a you want to compute not the marginal effects
want to compute not the marginal effects 10 but let's say the conditional of
10 but let's say the conditional of extent given X capital X so let's say
extent given X capital X so let's say our evidence is X capital F ok so the
our evidence is X capital F ok so the only modification you have to do is if
only modification you have to do is if you like is in the boundary condition of
you like is in the boundary condition of the message about X capital n sense to
the message about X capital n sense to extend capital L minus 1 which is this
extend capital L minus 1 which is this message before we said is the potential
message before we said is the potential of xn minus 1 X 10 you remember the
of xn minus 1 X 10 you remember the boundary condition instead of this what
boundary condition instead of this what we have is with a summation over all
we have is with a summation over all possible values of X capital L now
possible values of X capital L now there's no summation of X capital n we
there's no summation of X capital n we fixed X capital n to whatever value we
fixed X capital n to whatever value we have digital okay so the only change in
have digital okay so the only change in the algorithm is instead of summing over
the algorithm is instead of summing over the values of x capital n all right you
the values of x capital n all right you know fixing X capital n to a specified
know fixing X capital n to a specified value
value I mean why actually you can do is you
I mean why actually you can do is you can put remember our evidence potential
can put remember our evidence potential there you can put a delta function and
there you can put a delta function and then the channel X capital n but the
then the channel X capital n but the only value because of the Delta function
only value because of the Delta function will give you will give out and that is
will give you will give out and that is sort of the same idea
sort of the same idea ok so you the calculations of the
ok so you the calculations of the conditional to given this evidence
conditional to given this evidence suggest be the same thing as from the
suggest be the same thing as from the Monty
Monty zero change in the algorithm message
zero change in the algorithm message come from the left and right the only
come from the left and right the only difference is that in the message
difference is that in the message propagating from the evidence here you
propagating from the evidence here you have to change some of the boundary
have to change some of the boundary condition with this all right I am NOT
condition with this all right I am NOT going to do this today
going to do this today all right but I want you to we're going
all right but I want you to we're going to spent actually a collection on this
to spent actually a collection on this algorithm but I want you to see you know
algorithm but I want you to see you know everything on you can actually instead
everything on you can actually instead of doing the summation and computing
of doing the summation and computing marginals somebody will tell you in this
marginals somebody will tell you in this chain can you find us the mold of the
chain can you find us the mold of the Joint Distribution in other ways can you
Joint Distribution in other ways can you find what is the x marks that maximizes
find what is the x marks that maximizes the Joint Distribution is very
the Joint Distribution is very high-dimensional very important problem
high-dimensional very important problem but I give all this volume is defined on
but I give all this volume is defined on the chain and you want to find the mode
the chain and you want to find the mode of the Joint Distribution
of the Joint Distribution so before we have the summation alright
so before we have the summation alright and you know and so for example in the
and you know and so for example in the context of the elimination algorithm
context of the elimination algorithm right rather than coming all the
right rather than coming all the different variables the way we have it
different variables the way we have it now what we need to do is take the
now what we need to do is take the factorization of the Tori and push all
factorization of the Tori and push all the maximizations first on X capital n
the maximizations first on X capital n then xn minus 1 all the way to mark
then xn minus 1 all the way to mark small X term so we need to find an
small X term so we need to find an efficient algorithm for doing this
efficient algorithm for doing this circle by doing calculations forwards
circle by doing calculations forwards and backwards and that will lead to a
and backwards and that will lead to a very famous dynamic programming
very famous dynamic programming algorithm which is that you tell the
algorithm which is that you tell the algorithm
algorithm ok and so we will do this for hidden
ok and so we will do this for hidden markov models will spend one lecture
markov models will spend one lecture right but I want you to see that somehow
right but I want you to see that somehow destination can be replaced with
destination can be replaced with maximization the algorithm is sort of
maximization the algorithm is sort of the same but there is some details that
the same but there is some details that they are unique twists
they are unique twists Bianca and they are unique because you
Bianca and they are unique because you know you have too much moisture the
know you have too much moisture the joint not the mass goes all right and
joint not the mass goes all right and the way you do this introduce some
the way you do this introduce some little treat the someone needs to
little treat the someone needs to consider at the end of the day so his
consider at the end of the day so his tongue were even worse under much
tongue were even worse under much product rather than some product we will
product rather than some product we will revisit okay
so the sum-product algorithm that we just discussed for change you can
just discussed for change you can compute a whole homogenous for trees all
compute a whole homogenous for trees all right and I'm gonna show you again
right and I'm gonna show you again pictures all right
pictures all right our undirected graph and so they are all
our undirected graph and so they are all directed graphs leading to twist vision
directed graphs leading to twist vision you know you never when we worked with
you know you never when we worked with directed graphs we have some you know
directed graphs we have some you know even in the elimination algorithm to
even in the elimination algorithm to make them undirected so when you we make
make them undirected so when you we make them on directly do we always get three
them on directly do we always get three so what do we need to get a tree in
so what do we need to get a tree in directing job
it's something to do with the moral events in life if announce that to
events in life if announce that to parents and we transform this sort of
parents and we transform this sort of directly graph what was happening we
directly graph what was happening we will get what temp and no one with two
will get what temp and no one with two powers brightening transformational
powers brightening transformational directive what do you get
if you get them out of the moralization effect you get a look so it's not a
effect you get a look so it's not a three anymore alright but if the if
three anymore alright but if the if every knowledge in the directed graph
every knowledge in the directed graph just one pallet then we do actually get
just one pallet then we do actually get the three okay now if in the case of a
the three okay now if in the case of a directed graph that a node would say has
directed graph that a node would say has two parents that you marry and you get a
two parents that you marry and you get a loop right you can actually transform
loop right you can actually transform dot on directing love to what is called
dot on directing love to what is called a poly-tree
a poly-tree and it comes out using the sponsor of
and it comes out using the sponsor of the fact of graphs that are left behind
the fact of graphs that are left behind from my previous lecture you can if you
from my previous lecture you can if you transform than the undirected graph to
transform than the undirected graph to what is called a factor graph then we do
what is called a factor graph then we do get at three my point here is that the
get at three my point here is that the sample that algorithm can handle all of
sample that algorithm can handle all of these things with the same complexity
these things with the same complexity all right so we learning on how to do
all right so we learning on how to do inference message-passing with trish is
inference message-passing with trish is very important because it's applied to
very important because it's applied to both directed and undirected graphs and
both directed and undirected graphs and we are serving the things to discuss
we are serving the things to discuss today with pictures okay so this is this
today with pictures okay so this is this is an undirected three okay here every
is an undirected three okay here every node has one part so you know this is
node has one part so you know this is this to the direct entry and if there's
this to the direct entry and if there's no modernization so it needs to
no modernization so it needs to something like that okay
something like that okay the only thing that i emphasized here in
the only thing that i emphasized here in blue is here you know in the directed
blue is here you know in the directed love to work with conditional
love to work with conditional distributions if we start the potentials
distributions if we start the potentials their conditional distributions of not
their conditional distributions of not given its parent and these distributions
given its parent and these distributions are normalized but when you work in
are normalized but when you work in undirected
undirected twist all right the there is a
twist all right the there is a normalization factor in general okay so
normalization factor in general okay so in general is a normalization factor
in general is a normalization factor even in this case if you have some
even in this case if you have some evidence and you can solve this sort of
evidence and you can solve this sort of directed tree there
directed tree there very speed of normalization factor the
very speed of normalization factor the factor we have an evidence basically
factor we have an evidence basically introduced normalization factor so
alright then here is the case of the 43 so this guy has two pilots so if you
so this guy has two pilots so if you marry them if you connect them together
marry them if you connect them together you create a loop right so this is the
you create a loop right so this is the 43 so we will learn I think on the
43 so we will learn I think on the lecture tomorrow so I don't forget we're
lecture tomorrow so I don't forget we're going to have election tomorrow we're
going to have election tomorrow we're going to extend the ideas today to see
going to extend the ideas today to see how we're going to do influenced only 43
how we're going to do influenced only 43 using photographs okay so we're going to
using photographs okay so we're going to talk about these misters passing two
talk about these misters passing two very general trees okay and I'm going to
very general trees okay and I'm going to work with what directed and undirected
work with what directed and undirected graphs so I need to remind you some of
graphs so I need to remind you some of the notation so let's the work for
the notation so let's the work for undirected risk and what I have here
undirected risk and what I have here this is the tree and I have potential
this is the tree and I have potential for every node and I have two pair
for every node and I have two pair potentials
example right this cell potentials you don't you know in general you don't need
don't you know in general you don't need them because the clicks here what's the
them because the clicks here what's the maximum size of the clicks here - okay
maximum size of the clicks here - okay but you know if you can't think right
but you know if you can't think right but this somehow was was derived by a
but this somehow was was derived by a directed graph then you will have the
directed graph then you will have the probability of the nodes and those will
probability of the nodes and those will correspond to this self potential or if
correspond to this self potential or if you can imagine if one node is
you can imagine if one node is prescribed this would be the evidence
prescribed this would be the evidence potential so it's always good in
potential so it's always good in addition to this pair potentials but we
addition to this pair potentials but we have for the tree to plug in also itself
have for the tree to plug in also itself attends just whatever no okay so in an
attends just whatever no okay so in an undirected tree this is the general
undirected tree this is the general expression okay this is not an
expression okay this is not an approximation
approximation of the maximal cliques your potential or
of the maximal cliques your potential or you note and dissolution protections now
you note and dissolution protections now if this was the direct entry
if this was the direct entry things are a little bit easier because
things are a little bit easier because in the direct entry what you do is you
in the direct entry what you do is you start with the probability of the root
start with the probability of the root node and then you have the probability
node and then you have the probability of the notes given the product okay
of the notes given the product okay so actively if you want to take a direct
so actively if you want to take a direct entry and transform into an undirected
entry and transform into an undirected you can see the one-to-one
you can see the one-to-one correspondence between this
correspondence between this probabilities in this pair potentials
probabilities in this pair potentials and easily you can make this to
and easily you can make this to correspond to that how is that you know
correspond to that how is that you know you can say at the node are make this
you can say at the node are make this potential kayak sorry for the P of X
potential kayak sorry for the P of X star and make all the other potential
star and make all the other potential equal to one okay so so basically this
equal to one okay so so basically this is a very general expression for both
is a very general expression for both directed and undirected rich
evidence we basically the other thing you have to do if let's say the value of
you have to do if let's say the value of x is fixed at X I bar you need to change
x is fixed at X I bar you need to change the definition of the step potentials
the definition of the step potentials and so the note is not evidence now this
and so the note is not evidence now this potential is what you started with in
potential is what you started with in evidence no if you just have to plug in
evidence no if you just have to plug in this Delta function that basically says
this Delta function that basically says the value of this X I you will get a
the value of this X I you will get a nonzero contribution where X is equal to
nonzero contribution where X is equal to X I bar so if you have evidence the
X I bar so if you have evidence the previous equation that they had this is
previous equation that they had this is you know the joint now if I want to
you know the joint now if I want to write the probability of x given the
write the probability of x given the evidence the expression is the same this
evidence the expression is the same this are the self potentials for each node
are the self potentials for each node but there are the evidence potentials
but there are the evidence potentials this multiplied potential but what is
this multiplied potential but what is important note is when you have evidence
important note is when you have evidence the normalization factor now may not be
the normalization factor now may not be one so even if this graph was derived
one so even if this graph was derived from the directed graph where everything
from the directed graph where everything is normalized so you notice in this case
is normalized so you notice in this case when we talk about the ref to trace this
when we talk about the ref to trace this are normalized probability is equal to 1
are normalized probability is equal to 1 but when you have evidence the
but when you have evidence the normalization factor is not one so in
normalization factor is not one so in some cases in problems with evidence it
some cases in problems with evidence it doesn't really matter it kept directed
doesn't really matter it kept directed or undirected because the degree of
or undirected because the degree of complexity is the same just remember
complexity is the same just remember that this normalization factor is not
that this normalization factor is not one okay
[Applause] don't need this
we don't need this all right so let me remind you before I start the algorithm
remind you before I start the algorithm of somewhere so prefer not the synthetic
of somewhere so prefer not the synthetic things but sort of formal sense things
things but sort of formal sense things that usually you don't see when you
that usually you don't see when you program this directory
program this directory suppose that the actual potentials right
suppose that the actual potentials right we're coming from a directed tree and
we're coming from a directed tree and indirectly created the traditions we
indirectly created the traditions we work with are the probability of XJ
work with are the probability of XJ given its pilot so let's say the part
given its pilot so let's say the part here this run parent versus three its
here this run parent versus three its sixth I suppose now we start we have a
sixth I suppose now we start we have a query log here and we start eliminating
query log here and we start eliminating node from the bottom except from the
node from the bottom except from the league's new you may have made that if I
league's new you may have made that if I start coming or node XJ serving an 18 X
start coming or node XJ serving an 18 X a but this will come equal to 1 right
a but this will come equal to 1 right six days we are interested here and we
six days we are interested here and we scientifically the flex a it will
scientifically the flex a it will disappear because it is equal to one
disappear because it is equal to one okay alright so in assuming that you
okay alright so in assuming that you have no evidence in this unconditional
have no evidence in this unconditional case you are instincts solve that this
case you are instincts solve that this note that there is no evidence basically
note that there is no evidence basically you can eliminate them before you reach
you can eliminate them before you reach your query no you know what that means
your query no you know what that means test if I am interested in what is going
test if I am interested in what is going on here and I have a lot of knowledge
on here and I have a lot of knowledge with not only does not here what can I
with not only does not here what can I do to those now if you're interested to
do to those now if you're interested to figure out the probability of this node
figure out the probability of this node in the best together they have a lots of
in the best together they have a lots of laws below that they are not evidence
laws below that they are not evidence now what can I increase for good was now
now what can I increase for good was now considering that this is the case
we can prove them we can get rid of them because they will not contribute
because they will not contribute anything and you know what that means
anything and you know what that means that is actually if I'm interested in
that is actually if I'm interested in what is going on here and down here at
what is going on here and down here at abilities right in the ordering of
abilities right in the ordering of contamination in the only make sense to
contamination in the only make sense to assume that the leaves have what I could
assume that the leaves have what I could know here if the nodes are not
know here if the nodes are not unspecified are not part of the evidence
unspecified are not part of the evidence will disappear will be cleaned out so
will disappear will be cleaned out so the only thing we need to consider is
the only thing we need to consider is when we know the leaves are what what I
when we know the leaves are what what I was not evident okay so we only have to
was not evident okay so we only have to consider the case where the the lists
consider the case where the the lists are basically evidence okay in that case
are basically evidence okay in that case remember that normalizations g that we
remember that normalizations g that we consider it don't want to be equal to
consider it don't want to be equal to one so we can prove any subtree that
one so we can prove any subtree that contention developers that are not
contention developers that are not conditioned on by eliminating backwards
conditioned on by eliminating backwards okay so so let's see now what happens
okay so so let's see now what happens okay
okay in a case like this I am claiming if
in a case like this I am claiming if this is my evidence node but somehow
this is my evidence node but somehow this traced I can prove them and I can
this traced I can prove them and I can do inference on incident support Li so I
do inference on incident support Li so I want you to tell me why it's not the
want you to tell me why it's not the case
you don't have to read what it says there because I don't have time for
there because I don't have time for reading right so just this is my only
reading right so just this is my only evidence right here I'm not implying
evidence right here I'm not implying that you're not going to account for the
that you're not going to account for the changes let's say the potentials because
changes let's say the potentials because of the evidence but why I can actually
of the evidence but why I can actually separate this to three traced work in
separate this to three traced work in doing front separately what is they are
doing front separately what is they are fundamental this graph that allows me to
fundamental this graph that allows me to do that
for example with this evident evidence here what can you tell me on the
here what can you tell me on the probability of this note conditioned on
probability of this note conditioned on on the list
on the list I mean conditioned on the app noticed
I mean conditioned on the app noticed what can you tell me about the joint
what can you tell me about the joint probability let's say of this and this
probability let's say of this and this condition of that they are independent
condition of that they are independent okay so effectively the only thing we
okay so effectively the only thing we really have to consider is anything that
really have to consider is anything that we have observed right you prune it away
we have observed right you prune it away all right and the only notes that you're
all right and the only notes that you're going to have to believe we have to be
going to have to believe we have to be evidence leaves and everything else
evidence leaves and everything else basically has to be on themselves that
basically has to be on themselves that will be interesting to do inference okay
will be interesting to do inference okay so there is lots of things that I said
so there is lots of things that I said there but some of them basically are
there but some of them basically are sort of common strands coming in the
sort of common strands coming in the context of the direct draft from this
context of the direct draft from this relation there is no point of doing
relation there is no point of doing stations that they are equal to answer
stations that they are equal to answer what you need to do is prune leaves that
what you need to do is prune leaves that are basically unobserved and if you have
are basically unobserved and if you have evidence you have to be careful to know
evidence you have to be careful to know because evidence splits the graph and
because evidence splits the graph and then you may be able to have inference
then you may be able to have inference in like this case with three different
in like this case with three different graphs so we're going to stop doing
graphs so we're going to stop doing message passing on twist and generalize
message passing on twist and generalize the the algorithm we saw on on a chain
the the algorithm we saw on on a chain so this now would be on the tree the
so this now would be on the tree the same any are criticized know which the
same any are criticized know which the first order elimination
we're gonna have to do some elimination of the notes right then one way or
of the notes right then one way or another it's a tree I'm going to give
another it's a tree I'm going to give you an algorithm is the lecture today
you an algorithm is the lecture today and that defines first-order but in this
and that defines first-order but in this case the first order is you start
case the first order is you start basically from the left subtree which is
basically from the left subtree which is this and you start from the left to the
this and you start from the left to the right of 4 5 2 3 and 1
right of 4 5 2 3 and 1 ok so obviously in every sub 3 you have
ok so obviously in every sub 3 you have to start from the child's but always
to start from the child's but always from the left so for 5 to 3 anyone ok I
from the left so for 5 to 3 anyone ok I gave here that's gonna stack you want to
gave here that's gonna stack you want to click it but I'm going to give you the
click it but I'm going to give you the algorithm and all of this algorithms
algorithm and all of this algorithms that you would see on Three's they're
that you would see on Three's they're already cursing so I don't know if you
already cursing so I don't know if you ever programmed anything with recursive
ever programmed anything with recursive algorithms but sort of you need to get
algorithms but sort of you need to get used to when you do sort of message
used to when you do sort of message passing algorithm okay so let me we have
passing algorithm okay so let me we have a first order elimination and I'm gonna
a first order elimination and I'm gonna give you a message passing version of
give you a message passing version of the elimination algorithm so let's say
the elimination algorithm so let's say let's say that we're interested we have
let's say that we're interested we have evidence of now such 2 and X 4 and X 5
evidence of now such 2 and X 4 and X 5 right and somebody tells you compute the
right and somebody tells you compute the conditional of X 3 okay so basically
conditional of X 3 okay so basically what we need to do is we need to
what we need to do is we need to integrate X 1 here all right so let's
integrate X 1 here all right so let's say the factorization theorist myself
say the factorization theorist myself you know certain all potentials which
you know certain all potentials which are based at least evidence modify
are based at least evidence modify deafness potentials be introduced before
deafness potentials be introduced before this playoffs xixj because my colleagues
this playoffs xixj because my colleagues have maximum size is 2 so I am writing
have maximum size is 2 so I am writing least an undirected graph so I have
least an undirected graph so I have pretentious for Salford Xie for sexual
pretentious for Salford Xie for sexual onyx to explore its 385 but and I have
onyx to explore its 385 but and I have the potential 6 1 X 2 X 1 X 3 X 3 X 4
the potential 6 1 X 2 X 1 X 3 X 3 X 4 and X 3 X 5 so what I have done here is
and X 3 X 5 so what I have done here is X 2 X 4 X 5 are given right I don't need
X 2 X 4 X 5 are given right I don't need to do any modifications the only
to do any modifications the only modifications are inside the definition
modifications are inside the definition of this tie a right so there's no need
of this tie a right so there's no need to sound 1 X 2 X 4 X 5 with a delta
to sound 1 X 2 X 4 X 5 with a delta function because this is already done
function because this is already done inside sorry so the only thing I have
inside sorry so the only thing I have here is estimation of next month all
here is estimation of next month all right estimation electron but below the
right estimation electron but below the summation you see some definitions that
summation you see some definitions that I want you to look carefully on what is
I want you to look carefully on what is definitions imply in the context of
definitions imply in the context of eliminating Note one at a time so let's
eliminating Note one at a time so let's look at this last term okay so when
look at this last term okay so when interested you remember the conditional
interested you remember the conditional of X 3 given this evidence okay so the
of X 3 given this evidence okay so the last term I see changed the cell
last term I see changed the cell potential of X 5 right and then the
potential of X 5 right and then the potential effects we are expired okay
now the reason there is no solution or expired here is worth again valve is the
expired here is worth again valve is the summation of X 5 because turning it okay
summation of X 5 because turning it okay there is another function that will try
there is another function that will try SEC strive to be expired are there okay
SEC strive to be expired are there okay again if you want to put explicitly with
again if you want to put explicitly with a delta function there it will take care
a delta function there it will take care of it but you know alright so can you
of it but you know alright so can you tell me just basically what is this
tell me just basically what is this product you think doing for us is try of
product you think doing for us is try of X 5 times I of X 5 4 X 3 okay I always
X 5 times I of X 5 4 X 3 okay I always really noted this and with substrate 5 3
really noted this and with substrate 5 3 and it's a function of X 3 because X 5
and it's a function of X 3 because X 5 is just the cost so what is that
is just the cost so what is that if we are going to put some words to
if we are going to put some words to define it what is that sign here fix
define it what is that sign here fix five times the potential of X 3 X 5 what
five times the potential of X 3 X 5 what is up I mean obviously M stands for
is up I mean obviously M stands for message so what is that
is the message x5 1033 okay and this one you know what this is it is evidence
you know what this is it is evidence propagation from below to know the
propagation from below to know the extreme the fact that xx5 has some value
extreme the fact that xx5 has some value interesting thing for x3 and other
interesting thing for x3 and other implications contained from this message
so it is ready you know belief propagation okay and similarly the
propagation okay and similarly the second term side effects four times the
second term side effects four times the joint of experienced four is this
joint of experienced four is this message from four to three okay so this
message from four to three okay so this is message passing from X 4 X 3 so
is message passing from X 4 X 3 so evidence probe x4 propagates to three
evidence probe x4 propagates to three similarly the message from x3 to x1
similarly the message from x3 to x1 which is lit alright so we're rewriting
which is lit alright so we're rewriting this equation now this there's no
this equation now this there's no summation X 3 so this goes outside and
summation X 3 so this goes outside and the installation on x1 distance depend
the installation on x1 distance depend only on x2 ratio I don't touch them and
only on x2 ratio I don't touch them and there is destination x1 so let's look at
there is destination x1 so let's look at this list very carefully it says take
this list very carefully it says take the evidence on so we have two stomachs
the evidence on so we have two stomachs one ok so take the evidence of node X 1
one ok so take the evidence of node X 1 all right take the potential of x1 x3
all right take the potential of x1 x3 and take the message that is propagated
and take the message that is propagated virtual from node 2 and then get rid of
virtual from node 2 and then get rid of X 1 so I wish you'd remember when we
X 1 so I wish you'd remember when we discuss about change and and we have the
discuss about change and and we have the recasting this form of our relations and
recasting this form of our relations and result the Masters this way it is the
result the Masters this way it is the potential times the messes coming in and
potential times the messes coming in and then go integrate the previous variables
then go integrate the previous variables out so look at this it stays here if I
out so look at this it stays here if I call this m13 the testament 3 is the
call this m13 the testament 3 is the potential of x1 and the potential X 1 X
potential of x1 and the potential X 1 X 2 times the mess is coming from node 2
2 times the mess is coming from node 2 and then integrating note you are the
and then integrating note you are the only thing that is actually
only thing that is actually from what we had before is but now we
from what we had before is but now we have included itself potential nodes
have included itself potential nodes that need to carry them all right but if
that need to carry them all right but if whatever reason you wanted you could
whatever reason you wanted you could have integrate those inside aspera
have integrate those inside aspera potentials as well so the equation would
potentials as well so the equation would look identical but again the recursive
look identical but again the recursive equation says she's too tough to find
equation says she's too tough to find them 1/3 which the function of X 3
them 1/3 which the function of X 3 integrate electron the cell potential of
integrate electron the cell potential of this node the joint potential of X 1 X 2
this node the joint potential of X 1 X 2 and the message arrived in a node X bar
and the message arrived in a node X bar so the master sub base can propagate it
so the master sub base can propagate it is the message coming in times these
is the message coming in times these potentials with actual eliminate make
potentials with actual eliminate make strange sense a little bit
and again in case you know what if you look at the equation the question of
look at the equation the question of total power looks you know not
total power looks you know not complicated but you know if you get a
complicated but you know if you get a much better sense if you look at the
much better sense if you look at the graph right and you say look information
graph right and you say look information propagates from the evidence to know x3
propagates from the evidence to know x3 but the information to propagate it has
but the information to propagate it has to first go to node X 1 how does it do
to first go to node X 1 how does it do this with this message
this with this message M 2 1 okay which is this and then
M 2 1 okay which is this and then information has to go from node X 1 to
information has to go from node X 1 to node X 3 and this is the lastest and 1/3
node X 3 and this is the lastest and 1/3 how do you get them or 3 is by
how do you get them or 3 is by eliminating X 1 and how do you eliminate
eliminating X 1 and how do you eliminate X 1 you multiply the potential first one
X 1 you multiply the potential first one the joint returns to X 1 X 2 and then
the joint returns to X 1 X 2 and then coming message because all the messages
coming message because all the messages from the evidence need to be propagated
from the evidence need to be propagated through right and so together 1 3 you
through right and so together 1 3 you have to compute M 2 1 which also implies
have to compute M 2 1 which also implies that this calculation of messages has to
that this calculation of messages has to be done in the order of elimination of
be done in the order of elimination of no you cannot grow another Gration
no you cannot grow another Gration calculate M 1 3 before calculating M 2 1
calculate M 1 3 before calculating M 2 1 because you will not have enough
because you will not have enough information to do the calculation okay
information to do the calculation okay however I can tell too late the message
however I can tell too late the message from X 1 to X 3 at the same time as I
from X 1 to X 3 at the same time as I calculate the messages from 2 to 1 so
calculate the messages from 2 to 1 so actually you can do all of this in
actually you can do all of this in parallel right but you need to basically
parallel right but you need to basically have a scheme that says you can only
have a scheme that says you can only propagate if you can only calculate the
propagate if you can only calculate the message will not have to know so you can
message will not have to know so you can propagate let's say a message from road
propagate let's say a message from road 1 2 3 all the whole incoming messages to
1 2 3 all the whole incoming messages to node 1 are already there
node 1 are already there this is like doing power programming
this is like doing power programming right then you say you know if you
right then you say you know if you noticed executing and sending
noticed executing and sending information somewhere else if all the
information somewhere else if all the information
ship has arrived in that information here is this incoming messages okay all
here is this incoming messages okay all right so anything our language now
right so anything our language now practically identical to what we
practically identical to what we discussed off twist and what we
discussed off twist and what we described the last five minutes so let
described the last five minutes so let me define so if you know here is all of
me define so if you know here is all of us have cell phones actually I don't
us have cell phones actually I don't know why they should look here like
know why they should look here like ellipsis but so of this unknown okay so
ellipsis but so of this unknown okay so let's say that this is something up
let's say that this is something up there the root node this is no block aye
there the root node this is no block aye and this is J and we want to compute the
and this is J and we want to compute the message a sense to know died
message a sense to know died so the message Jason still alive again
so the message Jason still alive again don't look at the equations right it
don't look at the equations right it would be the cell potential of non-jury
would be the cell potential of non-jury right the joint potential of
right the joint potential of neuroscience a and the product of all
neuroscience a and the product of all the messages arriving today from all of
the messages arriving today from all of these neighbors except no die so are all
these neighbors except no die so are all the message to the right from below and
the message to the right from below and then gusano J or which means we
then gusano J or which means we eliminate a okay so summation J of the
eliminate a okay so summation J of the cell potential of XJ the joint potential
cell potential of XJ the joint potential clients a and all the messages arriving
clients a and all the messages arriving at node J from below from all of its
at node J from below from all of its neighbors except our you're not gonna
neighbors except our you're not gonna stand to use to no die a message you
stand to use to no die a message you received a line and actually that's a
received a line and actually that's a very philosophical statement and if
very philosophical statement and if you're interested can give you
you're interested can give you information to read about it alright so
information to read about it alright so in other ways you know if you don't you
in other ways you know if you don't you know you may like to make yourself feel
know you may like to make yourself feel good and send messages to yourself but
good and send messages to yourself but that actually it your problem
that actually it your problem letter problem okay
let's not kill ossifies because that's nothing with territory to be okay any
nothing with territory to be okay any question some of this is actually the
question some of this is actually the Iowa does can you tell me what's the
Iowa does can you tell me what's the difference of the difference from the
difference of the difference from the chain algorithm that we saw before right
chain algorithm that we saw before right just one big chain so look at this and
just one big chain so look at this and tell me what is different from before
tell me what is different from before every single term that looks different
what is different here for example in a chain what was it a little product what
chain what was it a little product what did we have if you have a chain this one
did we have if you have a chain this one no the northern or another node so how
no the northern or another node so how many neighbors except I do we have work
many neighbors except I do we have work for the nodes a so here there is only
for the nodes a so here there is only one the incoming method alright and what
one the incoming method alright and what we do not have explicitly right and you
we do not have explicitly right and you know again it makes no difference we do
know again it makes no difference we do not have this step potential that is
not have this step potential that is listen to incorporate basically evidence
listen to incorporate basically evidence okay so this was already there this was
okay so this was already there this was only one term and elimination of XJ this
only one term and elimination of XJ this relationship that's the message they
relationship that's the message they send out okay so if you want to compute
send out okay so if you want to compute so many do these calculations that say
so many do these calculations that say your interest to go on and find the
your interest to go on and find the conditional of the root node given the
conditional of the root node given the evidence in this case okay so let me
evidence in this case okay so let me because I see the calculation here
because I see the calculation here remind me when we wanted to find the
remind me when we wanted to find the marginal offending knowledge what did we
marginal offending knowledge what did we do on the chain when we want to find the
do on the chain when we want to find the marginal of any No
the in the saying you know there was left and right to have the knowledge so
left and right to have the knowledge so what do we do
what do we do we took the Masters character of the
we took the Masters character of the left the mess is coming from the right
left the mess is coming from the right in general our taste will be whatever
in general our taste will be whatever the Masters are coming if we multiply we
the Masters are coming if we multiply we get them the marginal now I try to look
get them the marginal now I try to look at the roof no don't leave any messages
at the roof no don't leave any messages coming from above good note so the
coming from above good note so the message is coming from from below so
message is coming from from below so basically what you have is all the
basically what you have is all the message is coming to the root node from
message is coming to the root node from its neighbors from below times obviously
its neighbors from below times obviously I have to put the search potential of
I have to put the search potential of the root node okay if it is not one and
the root node okay if it is not one and then if you want you to normalize this
then if you want you to normalize this the way you share the denominator
the way you share the denominator obviously this equation will apply to
obviously this equation will apply to any node which if you want to find the
any node which if you want to find the marginal of no ties you take the
marginal of no ties you take the products of all of the messages coming
products of all of the messages coming up now die from below all right and then
up now die from below all right and then just normalize here and you can get the
just normalize here and you can get the conditional of node I given the evidence
conditional of node I given the evidence and actually no that's the table
and actually no that's the table question okay well say sphere your
question okay well say sphere your similar equations to find the marginal
similar equations to find the marginal at every node okay now the bottom line
at every node okay now the bottom line and maybe as we have put this with red
and maybe as we have put this with red letters or something coloring there is
letters or something coloring there is about this now weighs it scales linearly
about this now weighs it scales linearly with the size of of the tree this is
with the size of of the tree this is basically the best you can do all right
basically the best you can do all right dunya cost Rafi okay and all the
dunya cost Rafi okay and all the equations are exactly as no there's no
equations are exactly as no there's no approximation okay so we need to do
approximation okay so we need to do actually we finished today doing
actually we finished today doing different examples because they look
different examples because they look trivial now you should've told me that
trivial now you should've told me that in the homework some of you arrived on
in the homework some of you arrived on doing calculations some calculations by
doing calculations some calculations by can you not living problems some of you
can you not living problems some of you were all down
were all down some of this and that should be the
some of this and that should be the answer right the last one option is not
answer right the last one option is not a good one we have tried the lighted by
a good one we have tried the lighted by Chen to do all the calculations or
Chen to do all the calculations or actually write a computer program to do
actually write a computer program to do this but don't say what you know what
this but don't say what you know what you multiply first and even your sound
you multiply first and even your sound and whatever comes out to be the answer
and whatever comes out to be the answer that doesn't help
that doesn't help right if I understood correctly okay
right if I understood correctly okay something like that so let's take a
something like that so let's take a simple case we are interested here to
simple case we are interested here to complete the marginals in this temple
complete the marginals in this temple tree so obviously we're going to have
tree so obviously we're going to have some post positive elimination here and
some post positive elimination here and this place will be this node and this
this place will be this node and this and this and that
and this and that okay so we're gonna start sending
okay so we're gonna start sending messages from the leaves all the way up
messages from the leaves all the way up to the root so I can send this messes up
to the root so I can send this messes up in this message simultaneously and once
in this message simultaneously and once know the tree has received this two
know the tree has received this two messages then I can send the message to
messages then I can send the message to the top two o'clock we should have right
the top two o'clock we should have right so we didn't do this all up the same
so we didn't do this all up the same step right here send one message to this
step right here send one message to this together then you can send the messages
together then you can send the messages once you have that you can turn the
once you have that you can turn the message to no one once node one has
message to no one once node one has received this message then can send them
received this message then can send them a message back you know - all right so
a message back you know - all right so so node 1 sends a message a 1 2 2 2 and
so node 1 sends a message a 1 2 2 2 and then you are ready to do what now is
then you are ready to do what now is this now ready to send the message to
this now ready to send the message to North Korea would be we need to send a
North Korea would be we need to send a message from 2 to 3
you need to know all the incoming message which is this and this which you
message which is this and this which you calculate it so then you can send the
calculate it so then you can send the message to you know from two to three
message to you know from two to three which is this message here and then what
which is this message here and then what we need to send the message before if
we need to send the message before if you need this and you need that so if
you need this and you need that so if you can send the message to the fourth
you can send the message to the fourth so effectively actually once did you get
so effectively actually once did you get this message here you can turn off any
this message here you can turn off any stunts all sending messages to walk
stunts all sending messages to walk through all three and no it's for as you
through all three and no it's for as you see here okay
see here okay once these messes are completed you can
once these messes are completed you can go and calculate anything you want the
go and calculate anything you want the marginals you can normalize conditionals
marginals you can normalize conditionals you can put evidence you can do anything
you can put evidence you can do anything you want okay now obviously when you
you want okay now obviously when you program there is the tricky part is to
program there is the tricky part is to be able to compute messages not just one
be able to compute messages not just one after the other but you have some
after the other but you have some algorithm that says you know what I can
algorithm that says you know what I can compute this by simultaneously then once
compute this by simultaneously then once you have all this message here I can
you have all this message here I can compute the outgoing message etc etc so
compute the outgoing message etc etc so you need to have some way to figure out
you need to have some way to figure out when a node is ready to send messages to
when a node is ready to send messages to its neighbors all right is this two
its neighbors all right is this two different different okay so in this
different different okay so in this graph you can see the importance
graph you can see the importance actually for having a protocol to send
actually for having a protocol to send messages notice but here I can
messages notice but here I can simultaneously end this messages that
simultaneously end this messages that you see on a figure B no promises
you see on a figure B no promises promises all at the time and I can do
promises all at the time and I can do this right because this node all right
this right because this node all right can send the message there all right the
can send the message there all right the same here same there
same here same there all right so on the second stage I do
all right so on the second stage I do notice messages with dotted lines to
notice messages with dotted lines to indicate that I calculate them
indicate that I calculate them previously but once placed no she has
previously but once placed no she has received messages from the left and the
received messages from the left and the right where they can do it can send the
right where they can do it can send the message to this node and once this node
message to this node and once this node here to receive this to West Michigan's
here to receive this to West Michigan's tell the vessels
tell the vessels so on the last step you notice I make
so on the last step you notice I make all these messages about it because they
all these messages about it because they calculated before and if if this note
calculated before and if if this note has a message from below has a message
has a message from below has a message already from the right then it can send
already from the right then it can send a message to this node similarly if this
a message to this node similarly if this node has the vessels coming in as a
node has the vessels coming in as a message from the right it can send a
message from the right it can send a message to this law okay so you never
message to this law okay so you never idea that what I mean a part of the
idea that what I mean a part of the protocol basically for sending messages
protocol basically for sending messages if you do this sequentially obviously is
if you do this sequentially obviously is not gonna be a good algorithm and
not gonna be a good algorithm and according the graph is going to be
according the graph is going to be probably if you do this right when the
probably if you do this right when the algorithm converges basically and gives
algorithm converges basically and gives you having converted it turns out what
you having converted it turns out what it finishes the cost will be two times
it finishes the cost will be two times the number of edges because basically in
the number of edges because basically in every answer you have to send the
every answer you have to send the messages going and coming back okay as
messages going and coming back okay as you see here alright so so the number of
you see here alright so so the number of steps basically the alcohol is placed
steps basically the alcohol is placed two times the number of edges in in in
two times the number of edges in in in you
I mean I think I'm really here taste this
this so the algorithm never blocks you know
so the algorithm never blocks you know for a trade without not happened but if
for a trade without not happened but if later on we will show the algorithm only
later on we will show the algorithm only have loops it's very possible you have
have loops it's very possible you have an algorithm that keeps going and
an algorithm that keeps going and Everette right
Everette right keep sending message system you have
keep sending message system you have constantly on the loop and you're in
constantly on the loop and you're in trouble all right so let me I'm gonna
trouble all right so let me I'm gonna finish this example because is in this
finish this example because is in this is the notation that I'm using is
is the notation that I'm using is basically that of you know a market on
basically that of you know a market on the field that we used before
the field that we used before okay so you know we have ten potentials
okay so you know we have ten potentials here and if you want evidence you plug
here and if you want evidence you plug in them two functions as patient
in them two functions as patient slightly different but this for the same
slightly different but this for the same idea so let's say eleven is the node
idea so let's say eleven is the node eleven is the root and we want to
eleven is the root and we want to compute the under some messages first
compute the under some messages first right and and then compute marginal and
actually let me see if we only want to compute what's going on okay well
compute what's going on okay well there is no particular node of interest
there is no particular node of interest but I will tell you what this specific
but I will tell you what this specific to this example right so let's say we
to this example right so let's say we want to compute this is the root node
want to compute this is the root node right that we want to compute all the
right that we want to compute all the message 10th on this graph so we're
message 10th on this graph so we're going to do a first order elimination
going to do a first order elimination can hear somebody spell for me what may
can hear somebody spell for me what may be a first order we'll look on this
be a first order we'll look on this graph there are many orders of
graph there are many orders of eliminating nodes but here's the optimal
eliminating nodes but here's the optimal is the first order and you remember you
is the first order and you remember you start from the left tree and then from
start from the left tree and then from the left side to outside so potentially
the left side to outside so potentially how the first order elimination will
how the first order elimination will look here 1 2 1 2 3 4
one two seven
alright so 1 mm continuum Philip 7 8 9 5 6 10 and 11 you still at ok
if you know it offenders to you but I suggest is you can look at the weekly
suggest is you can look at the weekly and Wikipedia you know there is five
and Wikipedia you know there is five different types of ordering but the
different types of ordering but the first one there is basically what is
first one there is basically what is used for bottom elimination on three so
used for bottom elimination on three so this is what we need to use here
this is what we need to use here I mean you something else it's just
I mean you something else it's just assumed that part will be higher than
assumed that part will be higher than using a posthole okay so if you were
using a posthole okay so if you were gonna do calculations basically
gonna do calculations basically analytically okay so alright the
analytically okay so alright the elimination and we're gonna start to
elimination and we're gonna start to calculate messages okay
calculate messages okay so I can calculate the message from node
so I can calculate the message from node 1 to 7 is this calculation make sense to
1 to 7 is this calculation make sense to you
you there is no incoming message to node 1
there is no incoming message to node 1 so this situation of the potential try 1
so this situation of the potential try 1 7 okay
7 okay I can do a calculation of 2 to 7 at the
I can do a calculation of 2 to 7 at the same time no problem this is I can do
same time no problem this is I can do the calculation of 3 2 8 4 2 8 5 to 10 6
the calculation of 3 2 8 4 2 8 5 to 10 6 to 10 all right so I can do the
to 10 all right so I can do the calculation the first 2 lines all
calculation the first 2 lines all simultaneously on this graph so now I
simultaneously on this graph so now I need to calculate the potential from I
need to calculate the potential from I mean the message from 7 to 9 and again
mean the message from 7 to 9 and again no equations are needed right so what
no equations are needed right so what you need to do is find all the messages
you need to do is find all the messages are coming to notes level multiplied
are coming to notes level multiplied with the potential between 7 and 9 and
with the potential between 7 and 9 and get rid of 7 eliminate them
get rid of 7 eliminate them so basically the message from 7 to 9 is
so basically the message from 7 to 9 is this potential 7 9 if you can of course
this potential 7 9 if you can of course the evidence for 7 you can but in also
the evidence for 7 you can but in also the message from 1 to 7 the message from
the message from 1 to 7 the message from 2 to 7 so obviously this requires that
2 to 7 so obviously this requires that you already have done this calculation
you already have done this calculation the first 2 lakhs similarly you can
the first 2 lakhs similarly you can calculate the message from 8 9 ok the
calculate the message from 8 9 ok the two incoming messages times this
two incoming messages times this potential and then
potential and then lay it out and then let's see and then
lay it out and then let's see and then we need to calculate the message from
we need to calculate the message from nine to eleven
nine to eleven so this again nothing special the
so this again nothing special the potential of nine and eleven course that
potential of nine and eleven course that okay
okay the incoming mr. seventy-nine becoming
the incoming mr. seventy-nine becoming less to eight to nine and then
less to eight to nine and then integrating x9 out and similarly the
integrating x9 out and similarly the message compared to 11 so this time the
message compared to 11 so this time the message is coming from the list today
message is coming from the list today okay now let me try the worst sort of
okay now let me try the worst sort of elementary way of completing this
elementary way of completing this message from nine to eleven right so
message from nine to eleven right so basically I'm going to solve this in a
basically I'm going to solve this in a different mathematical form so you can
different mathematical form so you can get a sense of what this actually does
get a sense of what this actually does right
right so the message from nine to eleven
so the message from nine to eleven effectively we start with this note we
effectively we start with this note we sell information and then we eliminate
sell information and then we eliminate the two misinformation they're in there
the two misinformation they're in there and then we eliminate two nodes and then
and then we eliminate two nodes and then from here to they are very willing in
from here to they are very willing in eight nine respectively you know what we
eight nine respectively you know what we have eliminated to send a message from
have eliminated to send a message from nine to 11 with the most can you tell me
nine to 11 with the most can you tell me to eventually be ready to sent a message
to eventually be ready to sent a message from 9 to 11 you have eliminated what
from 9 to 11 you have eliminated what you have enumerate the lots of nodes but
you have enumerate the lots of nodes but this works together some work for the
this works together some work for the subtree the comes from the left of the
subtree the comes from the left of the left
you see that I mean all of this no it says the three that really if you take
says the three that really if you take node 11 and you can't get from there all
node 11 and you can't get from there all the nodes to the left without this with
the nodes to the left without this with you demon eight so I can write this
you demon eight so I can write this compilation of the message from nine to
compilation of the message from nine to eleven estimation on all of these
eleven estimation on all of these variables of this subtree and I quote
variables of this subtree and I quote based on three the subtree that is
based on three the subtree that is derived once I remove ads 911 okay
derived once I remove ads 911 okay so this is the tree that you get once
so this is the tree that you get once you eliminate this edge from nine to
you eliminate this edge from nine to eleven
eleven okay so effectively this is the message
okay so effectively this is the message this is what we have done now what also
this is what we have done now what also this means right but this calculation
this means right but this calculation that we had from the lessons is you can
that we had from the lessons is you can start from this equation all right and
start from this equation all right and we arrange the order of estimations and
we arrange the order of estimations and then you can redefine again these
then you can redefine again these messages that are propagating from 1 and
messages that are propagating from 1 and 2 to 7 from seven to nine etcetera as
2 to 7 from seven to nine etcetera as part of this semester's there is nothing
part of this semester's there is nothing really special it's a way that we do the
really special it's a way that we do the summations so rather than doing the
summations so rather than doing the summations is one big equation you do it
summations is one big equation you do it in some elimination order right the way
in some elimination order right the way that is discussed here so we don't go
that is discussed here so we don't go and do all of the summations in one
and do all of the summations in one equation so don't write a computer
equation so don't write a computer program and say go and some on all of
program and say go and some on all of this because it's a tree of trivial toy
this because it's a tree of trivial toy problem and that's the answer you need
problem and that's the answer you need to compute you say waste all these nodes
to compute you say waste all these nodes in some order and start computing is
in some order and start computing is message this and one of these now this
message this and one of these now this master arrived compute you know the
master arrived compute you know the messages outgoing from that node to
messages outgoing from that node to another node you know and when you get
another node you know and when you get all of these things from the list to the
all of these things from the list to the root then you are ready to go backwards
root then you are ready to go backwards and here is buckled the questions from
and here is buckled the questions from awkward
awkward recalcitrant of messages identical to
recalcitrant of messages identical to what we have seen before
what we have seen before okay so let me give him
some of these equations and I put this things in blue because I think the first
things in blue because I think the first time I typed them not paying attention I
time I typed them not paying attention I had missed the loss of these terms right
had missed the loss of these terms right because some of these terms you realized
because some of these terms you realized our message the pairing from the right
our message the pairing from the right way that runs out of 11 not from the
way that runs out of 11 not from the left so let's take from node 11 to send
left so let's take from node 11 to send a message to node 9 what do I need to
a message to node 9 what do I need to know when a node can send messages to
know when a node can send messages to any other node
any other node what is the protocol that we discussed
what is the protocol that we discussed to send the message
okay - sent a masters from 11 to 9 what does not what is the protocol when can
does not what is the protocol when can 11 send the message to genomic when it
11 send the message to genomic when it only has received all messages from its
only has received all messages from its neighbors and the neighbors here except
neighbors and the neighbors here except 9 is no 10 alright so for 11 to send a
9 is no 10 alright so for 11 to send a message to 911 history see the rest is
message to 911 history see the rest is from 10 he needs to have no post message
from 10 he needs to have no post message on here all right obviously captain
on here all right obviously captain based in the picture but missed the
based in the picture but missed the message that pen sends to you ever all
message that pen sends to you ever all right so basically the message from 11
right so basically the message from 11 to 9 is this potential with the message
to 9 is this potential with the message coming from 10 to 11 and then node 11
coming from 10 to 11 and then node 11 eliminate similarly if you want to
eliminate similarly if you want to compute the lessees 11 cents to 10 would
compute the lessees 11 cents to 10 would be the potential of 11 and 10 and the
be the potential of 11 and 10 and the message coming from 9-11 etc etc okay
so the mystery of presenting and so basically if you want to say a physical
basically if you want to say a physical sort of interpretation of the
sort of interpretation of the calculation we did for sending a message
calculation we did for sending a message 11 from 11 to 9 effectively what you can
11 from 11 to 9 effectively what you can envision is if you look at the right
envision is if you look at the right subtree right the subtree basically that
subtree right the subtree basically that you get when you eliminate the X 9 to 11
you get when you eliminate the X 9 to 11 all right and then you do elimination of
all right and then you do elimination of all the nodes in the subtree okay and
all the nodes in the subtree okay and that means you some on 5 to 10 and 11 of
that means you some on 5 to 10 and 11 of the potentials corresponding to this
the potentials corresponding to this subject okay so if you do this basically
subject okay so if you do this basically what you will get is you will get this
what you will get is you will get this calculation at the end of the day okay
calculation at the end of the day okay but obviously this gives you a way to
but obviously this gives you a way to remember so I don't have time to finish
remember so I don't have time to finish this 145 but what I suggest this look at
this 145 but what I suggest this look at the algorithm because there is a stream
the algorithm because there is a stream and the local ibid sort of complicated
and the local ibid sort of complicated so the algorithm for setting the
so the algorithm for setting the postorder it's very progressive always
postorder it's very progressive always 25 lines okay and it does this correctly
25 lines okay and it does this correctly okay and the sum for the algorithms will
okay and the sum for the algorithms will describe this basically little
describe this basically little difference from elimination algorithm
difference from elimination algorithm and it is the custom in there in nature
and it is the custom in there in nature for example collecting messages before
for example collecting messages before you are ready to propagate it's a
you are ready to propagate it's a recursive algorithm even tree
recursive algorithm even tree distributing message from a node to the
distributing message from a node to the leg lifts is also a recursive algorithm
leg lifts is also a recursive algorithm so I'm really like you know you guys to
so I'm really like you know you guys to make an attempt to at least program
make an attempt to at least program something that involves inference on
something that involves inference on twist because sort of an is y'all going
twist because sort of an is y'all going okay so and as I mentioned those who are
okay so and as I mentioned those who are auditing the course if you don't really
auditing the course if you don't really program these things there is no way
program these things there is no way actually
actually you'll never figure out how this thing
you'll never figure out how this thing works now if