all right it's 12:30 so let me give you some reminders for the rest of the
some reminders for the rest of the semester the presentations for the class
semester the presentations for the class which means the report the six pages
which means the report the six pages report the PowerPoint slides you're all
report the PowerPoint slides you're all a presentation are going to be the last
a presentation are going to be the last three lectures in April okay because
three lectures in April okay because there's from past experience there's no
there's from past experience there's no way we can find another room in May so
way we can find another room in May so they're going to be during the last
they're going to be during the last week's which means plan ahead right
week's which means plan ahead right don't stop and say can I be the last
don't stop and say can I be the last because you are being called and you
because you are being called and you will be the first okay and it doesn't go
will be the first okay and it doesn't go first come first serve on this case lost
first come first serve on this case lost time to itself but can you polish which
time to itself but can you polish which means five down here from you your first
means five down here from you your first okay that's one thing the second thing
okay that's one thing the second thing is ie you know we were planning to give
is ie you know we were planning to give you six homeworks and staying there very
you six homeworks and staying there very slow process of even preparing the
slow process of even preparing the solutions of the homeworks
solutions of the homeworks you know I asked stovic to give you a
you know I asked stovic to give you a six homework but also to give you the
six homework but also to give you the solution so you can study them but we
solution so you can study them but we won't have to submit at six hormone okay
won't have to submit at six hormone okay I'm not doing this to reward anybody I
I'm not doing this to reward anybody I realized things are not going as the way
realized things are not going as the way I envisioned so I think that's the best
I envisioned so I think that's the best option for everybody all right so what
option for everybody all right so what else
else thank you helps I forgot all right so
thank you helps I forgot all right so what I'm going to do is because we went
what I'm going to do is because we went over literally eight minutes to cover
over literally eight minutes to cover variational inference for linear
variational inference for linear regression I'm going to go back today
regression I'm going to go back today and spend maybe fifteen minutes on the
and spend maybe fifteen minutes on the topic okay and in some sense if you're
topic okay and in some sense if you're not talking about linear regression
not talking about linear regression seeing this in the context of
seeing this in the context of variational algorithms is good because
variational algorithms is good because the results vary they look very close to
the results vary they look very close to the exact inference that you can do for
the exact inference that you can do for this type of problem all right and then
this type of problem all right and then once we're finished with us we will
once we're finished with us we will discuss about the Gaussian mixture
discuss about the Gaussian mixture problem which is mathematically very
problem which is mathematically very more intensive but also way more useful
more intensive but also way more useful and then maybe we'll generalize this to
and then maybe we'll generalize this to sort of any distributions from the
sort of any distributions from the exponential community and next Tuesday
exponential community and next Tuesday we start talking about approximate
we start talking about approximate methods interest methods in graphs in
methods interest methods in graphs in particularly expectation propagation
particularly expectation propagation which is sort of one of the standard
which is sort of one of the standard methods for doing inference in very
methods for doing inference in very complex systems things will get
complex systems things will get progressively more complex okay and you
progressively more complex okay and you may say but this is but this fixes is
may say but this is but this fixes is not machine learning no it is machine
not machine learning no it is machine learning it's not statistics it's not
learning it's not statistics it's not decisions don't know much about this
decisions don't know much about this machine learning people need to know
machine learning people need to know more okay so I'm saying this to avoid
more okay so I'm saying this to avoid any comments questions probation
any comments questions probation regression so we basically were given X
regression so we basically were given X Y data if you like pairs of data the Y
Y data if you like pairs of data the Y here is denoted with T so I'm using I
here is denoted with T so I'm using I think the notation is must be from this
think the notation is must be from this report guessing so the integration comes
report guessing so the integration comes we write a response t
we write a response t NEX there's no beautimous course P for P
NEX there's no beautimous course P for P is a vector basis functions you can
is a vector basis functions you can think of this being in one dimension for
think of this being in one dimension for example 1 xx square can be splines can
example 1 xx square can be splines can be regular basis functions can be
be regular basis functions can be anything okay and one side some noise
anything okay and one side some noise and if you write this in a probabilistic
and if you write this in a probabilistic form the likelihood for iid data looks
form the likelihood for iid data looks like that okay so now to make the
like that okay so now to make the analysis simple here I'm going to take
analysis simple here I'm going to take the precision in this model is null and
the precision in this model is null and I think they have two or three slides in
I think they have two or three slides in the notes where basically we can remove
the notes where basically we can remove that constrain and it doesn't have
that constrain and it doesn't have really any much difficulty to the
really any much difficulty to the problem so in this integration right the
problem so in this integration right the idea is we're going to take everything
idea is we're going to take everything to be random so W is going to come with
to be random so W is going to come with some prior distribution and the prior
some prior distribution and the prior defense of this precision alpha and you
defense of this precision alpha and you know we're going to assume and all the
know we're going to assume and all the hyper prior basically pure alpha the
hyper prior basically pure alpha the gamma distribution you should know that
gamma distribution you should know that gamma distribution comes all which is a
gamma distribution comes all which is a prior for precision you know every query
prior for precision you know every query much similar okay and I think we also
much similar okay and I think we also discussed what you can generalize this
discussed what you can generalize this where you make the softest not to be
where you make the softest not to be alpha minus one I but you can put a
alpha minus one I but you can put a different alpha in the diagonal of the
different alpha in the diagonal of the covariance and that's how you get this
covariance and that's how you get this relevance determination methods you can
relevance determination methods you can figure out which of the WS are needed to
figure out which of the WS are needed to to do the proper digression but right
to do the proper digression but right now this is what we have okay
now this is what we have okay we've seen the traditional unethical
we've seen the traditional unethical solution this problem you don't suppose
solution this problem you don't suppose to know if you know nothing about the
to know if you know nothing about the regression we will try to do this from
regression we will try to do this from scratch in the context of variational
scratch in the context of variational inference so to the variational
inference so to the variational inference we need to join like liquid
inference we need to join like liquid and here is my equations W an alpha
and here is my equations W an alpha parameters so the drawing likelihood
parameters so the drawing likelihood this written P given lovely you write it
this written P given lovely you write it doesn't depend anything but W there is a
doesn't depend anything but W there is a bit of there but I'm taking bigger to be
bit of there but I'm taking bigger to be constant you have that we give an
constant you have that we give an alternate view Papa okay and basically
alternate view Papa okay and basically this is sort of since we talked about
this is sort of since we talked about published the graphical models basically
published the graphical models basically would have found a picture like this
would have found a picture like this this defines no big questions we have
this defines no big questions we have seen up to now okay so we're going
seen up to now okay so we're going Preston we want to do all the parameters
Preston we want to do all the parameters here of W and alpha so we won't
here of W and alpha so we won't approximate the posterior of W naught
approximate the posterior of W naught forgiven t and since we're star
forgiven t and since we're star inference really brooks range like that
inference really brooks range like that okay in this claim that this is right
okay in this claim that this is right no it's not right it's an approximation
no it's not right it's an approximation that's what variation of variational
that's what variation of variational approximations are about they are
approximations are about they are approximate methods all right so we
approximate methods all right so we factorize this posterior to look like
factorize this posterior to look like this I asked you last time I'm not gonna
this I asked you last time I'm not gonna ask you this time you're going to get
ask you this time you're going to get there another headache so the each of
there another headache so the each of these distributions in the in the in the
these distributions in the in the in the in the factorization so for example the
in the factorization so for example the log of T of alpha is basically the
log of T of alpha is basically the expectation of the joining of black
expectation of the joining of black liquid with respect to all the other
liquid with respect to all the other parameters in this case since I'm
parameters in this case since I'm calculating Q foie gras the other
calculating Q foie gras the other parameters is W okay so if you need to
parameters is W okay so if you need to do in the algebra you need to expand the
do in the algebra you need to expand the joint log likelihood tell me the terms
joint log likelihood tell me the terms that depend on alpha and inverse terms
that depend on alpha and inverse terms anything that has W you have to take an
anything that has W you have to take an expectation with respect to W so if you
expectation with respect to W so if you plug in P alpha gamma distribution
plug in P alpha gamma distribution that's the log
that's the log this is a Gaussian easy to calculate so
this is a Gaussian easy to calculate so you need expectation of W transpose W
you need expectation of W transpose W and then she makes professional public
and then she makes professional public here right if you take in Gaussian and
here right if you take in Gaussian and you take the logs you supposed to get an
you take the logs you supposed to get an expectation of Bobby also why it's not
expectation of Bobby also why it's not there I mean just visually realize I
there I mean just visually realize I don't see an expectation of W there
don't see an expectation of W there right waist up because yes
why don't in expectation of W
thank you all right I mean something right in my
all right I mean something right in my eyes looks wrong I have to think myself
eyes looks wrong I have to think myself so it's good that your things up too and
so it's good that your things up too and you say oh he's paid all right but it's
you say oh he's paid all right but it's obviously not a mistake okay so when
obviously not a mistake okay so when remember the constant terms are things
remember the constant terms are things to depend for example maybe just me here
to depend for example maybe just me here and there constant times really and we
and there constant times really and we don't care because this is distribution
don't care because this is distribution on alpha the only way she will keep this
on alpha the only way she will keep this is because you want to place alpha so
is because you want to place alpha so you can email you see you can combine
you can email you see you can combine this log double dot there you can
this log double dot there you can combine this constant however this term
combine this constant however this term times alpha and basically what you get
times alpha and basically what you get is the log of it when you gamma
is the log of it when you gamma distribution with updated parameters so
distribution with updated parameters so the posterior looks like this and
the posterior looks like this and effectively you can see that one of the
effectively you can see that one of the reasons someone is using a gamma
reasons someone is using a gamma distribution for alpha is really because
distribution for alpha is really because I mean the approximate variation of
I mean the approximate variation of distribution cos alpha is the conjugate
distribution cos alpha is the conjugate it comes basically to be an advantage of
it comes basically to be an advantage of the coefficients of the pyro we help out
the coefficients of the pyro we help out right before we only have this odd
right before we only have this odd positive be 0 now you added this nice
positive be 0 now you added this nice thing so it's pretty nuts ok even gets
thing so it's pretty nuts ok even gets an approximation get Sparkle join
an approximation get Sparkle join log-likelihood he the antibodies
log-likelihood he the antibodies basically straight forward but I eroded
basically straight forward but I eroded fear rather not having these summations
fear rather not having these summations I wrote this in a matrix vector forms
I wrote this in a matrix vector forms introducing the design matrix P that
introducing the design matrix P that involves the basis functions calculated
involves the basis functions calculated at each of the given data points right
at each of the given data points right of the design matrix and just the values
of the design matrix and just the values of the function that we have given of
of the function that we have given of the given input points so this is a
the given input points so this is a Gaussian can see square you can see
Gaussian can see square you can see linear term in W so if you complete the
linear term in W so if you complete the square again you get a Gaussian
square again you get a Gaussian similar to the prior we started but with
similar to the prior we started but with updated parameters and I emphasize since
updated parameters and I emphasize since maybe you haven't seen this even in the
maybe you haven't seen this even in the context of
context of simple Bayesian analysis or even
simple Bayesian analysis or even expected and you shall depend on me well
expected and you shall depend on me well you know calculation will give you an
you know calculation will give you an alcove it up here we did the expectation
alcove it up here we did the expectation of profit okay
of profit okay there is no expectation of beta because
there is no expectation of beta because here I'm taking bigger as I mentioned to
here I'm taking bigger as I mentioned to become stock but I saw something that
become stock but I saw something that precise if you look for example in in
precise if you look for example in in the variation of expression for W you
the variation of expression for W you notice here to be able to compute this
notice here to be able to compute this you need to know the expectation of
you need to know the expectation of alpha and to know the expectation of
alpha and to know the expectation of alpha right
alpha right if you need to know the expectation of
if you need to know the expectation of lambda transpose gamma so this is an
lambda transpose gamma so this is an iterative process and actually in some
iterative process and actually in some books they because this sort of mimics
books they because this sort of mimics the expectation maximization process
the expectation maximization process right you say do this update that and
right you say do this update that and plug in it so in lots of books you will
plug in it so in lots of books you will see the presentation on this as here is
see the presentation on this as here is the history here is the m-step but it's
the history here is the m-step but it's really slightly different okay
really slightly different okay but I know this lots of machine learning
but I know this lots of machine learning books they give this algorithms as if
books they give this algorithms as if there were you can mister very important
there were you can mister very important step various approximations so the exact
step various approximations so the exact posterior so if you want I'm sorry this
posterior so if you want I'm sorry this the traditional distribution right the
the traditional distribution right the prediction posterior distribution so
prediction posterior distribution so once you train the system you say now at
once you train the system you say now at the given X I want to know what the
the given X I want to know what the response is I'm taking the response yet
response is I'm taking the response yet to be scanner and this bounty is the
to be scanner and this bounty is the data right so that's the prolific
data right so that's the prolific posterior so that's basically the
posterior so that's basically the likelihood
likelihood why would you get if you if you know W
why would you get if you if you know W times the posterior what all the
times the posterior what all the parameters are integrated out and the
parameters are integrated out and the King radium here is we are not going to
King radium here is we are not going to plug in the actual posterior
plug in the actual posterior you actually plug in the variational
you actually plug in the variational approximation which is your poppy okay
now is the exact pastino is is very easygoing Gaussian so we could about
easygoing Gaussian so we could about this but here we demonstrate this is an
this but here we demonstrate this is an example so you plug in qw and this is
example so you plug in qw and this is the marginalization you remember you
the marginalization you remember you have something best the auction has a
have something best the auction has a mean that's a linear function of gamma
mean that's a linear function of gamma nu you know and then you have x should
nu you know and then you have x should not be an integration of that view right
not be an integration of that view right so this is really a marginal
so this is really a marginal distribution on P and if you look at the
distribution on P and if you look at the progress convenient origin systems I
progress convenient origin systems I told you to have them perfect in your
told you to have them perfect in your desk all right
desk all right look at them every day because these
look at them every day because these equations you use them every day ten
equations you use them every day ten times so you don't have to search okay
times so you don't have to search okay so you look at them if you plug them in
so you look at them if you plug them in and basically you get another Gaussian
and basically you get another Gaussian and you can see the the variance so of
and you can see the the variance so of course dependent on X so it varies with
course dependent on X so it varies with X and if you put again things okay
X and if you put again things okay you will notice again that this matrix
you will notice again that this matrix is n depends on you know the expectation
is n depends on you know the expectation of alpha and the design matrix P okay so
of alpha and the design matrix P okay so obviously the expectation of power power
obviously the expectation of power power we know it assuming we have computed the
we know it assuming we have computed the the variational approximation for of the
the variational approximation for of the posterior Palko okay the thing that I'm
posterior Palko okay the thing that I'm going to remind you very quickly is
going to remind you very quickly is every time the devil external influence
every time the devil external influence is a fluctuation
is a fluctuation you always have to verify that the
you always have to verify that the calculations are correct and the only
calculations are correct and the only way you can do this is by calculating
way you can do this is by calculating the lower bound and showing that the
the lower bound and showing that the lower bound in crease is basically
lower bound in crease is basically monotonically if decomposition does
monotonically if decomposition does increase monotonically
increase monotonically there is a problem okay
there is a problem okay so I remind you the long vault is the
so I remind you the long vault is the expectation with respect to the
expectation with respect to the variation of distribution chill of the
variation of distribution chill of the name of the joint likelihood divided by
name of the joint likelihood divided by the valuation of this depletion so it's
the valuation of this depletion so it's written like that if you expand one of
written like that if you expand one of the parents you know everything so it's
the parents you know everything so it's more it's a block right you just put new
more it's a block right you just put new things but you know what if I asked you
things but you know what if I asked you to push again and give me this in half
to push again and give me this in half an hour I bet most probably none of you
an hour I bet most probably none of you will complete it okay your baby with me
will complete it okay your baby with me all right absolutely okay
all right absolutely okay and the reason one of you will complete
and the reason one of you will complete it because you can see take you out so
it because you can see take you out so you do the algebra in a very so you look
you do the algebra in a very so you look at them you say here easy no it's not
at them you say here easy no it's not easy because if you try to do it on your
easy because if you try to do it on your own for another problem you will mess it
own for another problem you will mess it up okay so there is an educational
up okay so there is an educational purpose of doing this for simple
purpose of doing this for simple problems like a regression problem
problems like a regression problem because you know if you do all the songs
because you know if you do all the songs about the plug-in and plug in and plug
about the plug-in and plug in and plug in and then connect by the miracle of
in and then connect by the miracle of nets to what is the final answer do I
nets to what is the final answer do I have a final answer somewhere
defy belief the subscribe with Alec you because the final answer comes to be
because the final answer comes to be pretty nice somebody ate my slide okay
pretty nice somebody ate my slide okay so anyways here right but when you you
so anyways here right but when you you did a very nice answer okay
did a very nice answer okay end of story okay and this is this
end of story okay and this is this rebound in connection so for example if
rebound in connection so for example if you're doing integration and you have a
you're doing integration and you have a bunch of data and you say you know let's
bunch of data and you say you know let's say you use polynomials in this case you
say you use polynomials in this case you say what's the other of polynomials that
say what's the other of polynomials that I need to use you better represent the
I need to use you better represent the data you know I'd be much more
data you know I'd be much more likelihood Maxwell's argument saying
because the will keep increasing but you will never fade okay so with variation
will never fade okay so with variation influenced and using these lower bounds
influenced and using these lower bounds of the case and you can see here it says
of the case and you can see here it says M equal trees what explains the data
M equal trees what explains the data okay and I think we already discussed
okay and I think we already discussed and I may come back today also if you do
and I may come back today also if you do notice election right and you put let's
notice election right and you put let's say some vehicle prior over the space of
say some vehicle prior over the space of the number of polynomials in essence
the number of polynomials in essence this this is you know very you know this
this this is you know very you know this population effectively gives you an
population effectively gives you an approximation to the posterior of the
approximation to the posterior of the model right so basically this is nothing
model right so basically this is nothing else but the posterior of the model with
else but the posterior of the model with when you know L 7 equal to three okay so
when you know L 7 equal to three okay so this is a very nice way to do model
this is a very nice way to do model selection
selection right and this is a very nice picture
right and this is a very nice picture from sorry I mean no picture were just
from sorry I mean no picture were just really a little awkward around this
really a little awkward around this calculations run the matter of using the
calculations run the matter of using the Kevin leftists t-bolts so basically on
Kevin leftists t-bolts so basically on the customer choice you the map of
the customer choice you the map of inaction so a calculation of the
inaction so a calculation of the posterior of these models of the
posterior of these models of the universe of polynomials given some data
universe of polynomials given some data which here we have five data points and
which here we have five data points and you can see that very few data the metro
you can see that very few data the metro bicycle devaluation reference that's you
bicycle devaluation reference that's you you know what use the lower of the
you know what use the lower of the polynomial okay the lowest model is what
polynomial okay the lowest model is what you need but when you increase the
you need but when you increase the number of data for example here it
number of data for example here it immediately puts the posterior on m
immediately puts the posterior on m equal to three very low and it tells you
equal to three very low and it tells you not select the model with M equal to two
not select the model with M equal to two this method is empirical Baggett's
this method is empirical Baggett's method basically okay and this is what
method basically okay and this is what you know products we put the question in
you know products we put the question in the tall they are reading machine
the tall they are reading machine learning looks this is basically the
learning looks this is basically the evidence approximation it doesn't do as
evidence approximation it doesn't do as well
well so you can see for example in the
so you can see for example in the evidence of observation here it puts a
evidence of observation here it puts a lot on this posterior for m equal to R
lot on this posterior for m equal to R but here basically tell mostly currently
but here basically tell mostly currently distributed we have a few data because
distributed we have a few data because in that case is the prior that dominate
in that case is the prior that dominate the
this posterior here there's no really such a thing so this is not cool evasion
such a thing so this is not cool evasion but this cool evasion
but this cool evasion
all right I am going to do this but I mentioned that you can expand this type
mentioned that you can expand this type of calculations when you take this
of calculations when you take this precision in the likelihood model also
precision in the likelihood model also to be around the body moon right so you
to be around the body moon right so you can put a plier on that and in you know
can put a plier on that and in you know you can basically repeat all the
you can basically repeat all the calculations and you can calculate so if
calculations and you can calculate so if you put a gamma prior on beta you can
you put a gamma prior on beta you can calculate an approximate posterior but
calculate an approximate posterior but this launched a gamma and you can see
this launched a gamma and you can see the formulas come very nicely in the
the formulas come very nicely in the very close call you know and and the
very close call you know and and the answer is really nothing significant and
answer is really nothing significant and you can actually calculate the
you can actually calculate the predictive distribution and it's not
predictive distribution and it's not surprising actually for example you look
surprising actually for example you look at the variance comes to be identical
at the variance comes to be identical with the previous result but this kind
with the previous result but this kind of leader you have expectation of beta
of leader you have expectation of beta okay so so much of the answers really
okay so so much of the answers really sort of are expected okay all right okay
sort of are expected okay all right okay so I'm going to switch now lecture and
so I'm going to switch now lecture and I'm going to come back remind me to
I'm going to come back remind me to write 16 after we we move from this
and very fundamental problem okay so we're going to discuss something that
we're going to discuss something that looks a trivial to lots of you but you
looks a trivial to lots of you but you will if you search the literature you
will if you search the literature you find a lots of Papers written because
find a lots of Papers written because it's an extremely fundamental problem
it's an extremely fundamental problem that comes everywhere so the idea here
that comes everywhere so the idea here is we are talking about a mixture of
is we are talking about a mixture of gaussians and what interest to do
gaussians and what interest to do approximate Bayesian inference for a
approximate Bayesian inference for a mixture of gaussians so what does that
mixture of gaussians so what does that mean you know you know become from a
mean you know you know become from a mixture of the two three four five
mixture of the two three four five gaussians I'm doing have to you I don't
gaussians I'm doing have to you I don't tell you generate the data and I'm
tell you generate the data and I'm telling you go and calculate the
telling you go and calculate the posterior of the mixing components and
posterior of the mixing components and for its component compute the mean and
for its component compute the mean and the variance okay simple ways to do and
the variance okay simple ways to do and so I'm going to pretend that you have
so I'm going to pretend that you have never seen this problem before in other
never seen this problem before in other ways you don't know other solutions okay
ways you don't know other solutions okay so we're gonna concentrate on variation
so we're gonna concentrate on variation of the interest object okay and again
of the interest object okay and again this is very fundamental in machine
this is very fundamental in machine learning it comes everywhere and
learning it comes everywhere and actually this concept of gaussians you
actually this concept of gaussians you can even put another world that make it
can even put another world that make it mixed up thousand processes okay we will
mixed up thousand processes okay we will not discuss that in this course and
not discuss that in this course and actually to make it even more relevant
actually to make it even more relevant to research the sort of mixture you can
to research the sort of mixture you can say infinite mixture of Gaussian
say infinite mixture of Gaussian processes so basically you can do sort
processes so basically you can do sort of relevance determination and trial
of relevance determination and trial infinite knowledge component and let
infinite knowledge component and let this analysis figure out which ones are
this analysis figure out which ones are named it okay and it doesn't have to be
named it okay and it doesn't have to be gaussians can be Gaussian processes and
gaussians can be Gaussian processes and this needs to be a very recent sort of
this needs to be a very recent sort of relevant results basically that some of
relevant results basically that some of you
you or someone feel their interest to
or someone feel their interest to research okay so we actually discuss the
research okay so we actually discuss the problem no need to read anything so
problem no need to read anything so remember that we have observations of
remember that we have observations of some de vita XM it's data just relate
some de vita XM it's data just relate and valuable of 2080 with it that I call
and valuable of 2080 with it that I call its GM so you can think of Zn being a
its GM so you can think of Zn being a label body blighters here it is this
label body blighters here it is this component of it is Gaussian or web
component of it is Gaussian or web browser above Gaussian so that's the
browser above Gaussian so that's the late environment it's the you know it's
late environment it's the you know it's extra information of two gaussians it's
extra information of two gaussians it's version will have its own mean and
version will have its own mean and variance all right and this local
variance all right and this local variables will be defined through some
variables will be defined through some polite other than the parameters of the
polite other than the parameters of the drive or the cold clear pie and I will
drive or the cold clear pie and I will give you the specifics on the slides to
give you the specifics on the slides to come so their joint likelihood so this
come so their joint likelihood so this is the observation this the latent
is the observation this the latent variables these are the various
variables these are the various parameters to define the priors
parameters to define the priors so basically you can save this
so basically you can save this capitalization also graphically the
capitalization also graphically the rezoning of likelihood would be the
rezoning of likelihood would be the probability of x given C and lanthanum
probability of x given C and lanthanum the probability of Z given by the
the probability of Z given by the probability of new given lambda and the
probability of new given lambda and the probability of love so this is sort of a
probability of love so this is sort of a very heavy very simple graph but the
very heavy very simple graph but the calculation you will see it's not it's
calculation you will see it's not it's painful
painful okay but it is a calculation that again
okay but it is a calculation that again if you do it once you will get the sense
if you do it once you will get the sense of what it is and how it works
of what it is and how it works okay so in my view for example in the
okay so in my view for example in the midst of noxious right if you put this
midst of noxious right if you put this joint
joint replica together this comes to be
replica together this comes to be Gaussian and if a condition actions a
Gaussian and if a condition actions a young get a gout okay
the condition excellency if I integrate thumbs D okay you're not gonna go right
thumbs D okay you're not gonna go right but the joint likelihood is a Gaussian
but the joint likelihood is a Gaussian and that's why we operate okay so I want
and that's why we operate okay so I want you to look at this distribution that
you to look at this distribution that tells me what you understand it so px
tells me what you understand it so px given Z looks like that then you tell me
given Z looks like that then you tell me everything is not okay
I mean I'm going to need to compute write this every term so P of x given Z
write this every term so P of x given Z and V other parameters is given like
and V other parameters is given like that so I have n data points I have a
that so I have n data points I have a mixed with K components so does this
mixed with K components so does this make sense so C and K takes what - what
make sense so C and K takes what - what is the one of the values in K takes Z so
is the one of the values in K takes Z so so for every data point right only
so for every data point right only assume this time see that product is
assume this time see that product is going to be a Gaussian and that would be
going to be a Gaussian and that would be only for the K equals e and k equal to 1
only for the K equals e and k equal to 1 right
we have seen this about the thousand times of denominated so close to a very
times of denominated so close to a very compact way of writing things everyone
compact way of writing things everyone is in okay you know the most we listen
is in okay you know the most we listen this tapes from home because they have
this tapes from home because they have nothing else to do right is true love
nothing else to do right is true love maybe scream once or say something
maybe scream once or say something so they think that I'm not talking to a
so they think that I'm not talking to a wall alright because you know lots of
wall alright because you know lots of professors like talking to themselves
professors like talking to themselves alright so okay I can even pass you the
alright so okay I can even pass you the microphone so weird so Z and remember so
microphone so weird so Z and remember so you know we are thinking about the next
you know we are thinking about the next another somebody find this mixing
another somebody find this mixing quotation spy and I want you to look at
quotation spy and I want you to look at this and to me it's okay that I'm either
this and to me it's okay that I'm either way we have it here remember every point
way we have it here remember every point xn3 Seussian so so what is this here the
xn3 Seussian so so what is this here the player that I am using is so over all
player that I am using is so over all the data points I would write what is
the data points I would write what is this what is this conditional
this what is this conditional distribution of Z given PI so it would
distribution of Z given PI so it would say at the given point and only one of
say at the given point and only one of those things one of the one of the case
those things one of the one of the case this would be equal to one and this will
this would be equal to one and this will give you okay all right
all right hi and that player is going to be adding a clip live okay
be adding a clip live okay and and that's what I mentioned that
and and that's what I mentioned that this a disc and easily extended to
this a disc and easily extended to infinite mixture of of gaussians by
infinite mixture of of gaussians by substituting here by using a declare
substituting here by using a declare process basically to do a special user
process basically to do a special user declare prior service list the
declare prior service list the parameters on cozinha wants to remember
parameters on cozinha wants to remember of the notation okay and you may say why
of the notation okay and you may say why did the clip prior because based is
did the clip prior because based is going to make all the posteriors to be
going to make all the posteriors to be nothing else but updates basically the
nothing else but updates basically the parameters of the distributions that you
parameters of the distributions that you see right now so basically these are
see right now so basically these are conjugate priors okay so they are going
conjugate priors okay so they are going to make the algebra easy okay the
to make the algebra easy okay the parameters mean atlanta and you may have
parameters mean atlanta and you may have seen this for evaluation you may not
seen this for evaluation you may not have seen it so basically we write this
have seen it so basically we write this as a product over all the components of
as a product over all the components of a deficient all right with the lots of
a deficient all right with the lots of unknown parameters but you know here the
unknown parameters but you know here the precision depends the precision this
precision depends the precision this condition of the precision and then the
condition of the precision and then the precision we put a reserve distribution
precision we put a reserve distribution this is you know in one dimension you
this is you know in one dimension you know how this will look like this will
know how this will look like this will be devoid of Gaussian and what will not
be devoid of Gaussian and what will not be for the precision would did we say
be for the precision would did we say who uses a prior
what should I become below the regression problem what was the point of
regression problem what was the point of the precision he was a memo said the
the precision he was a memo said the wizard mr. mission based as a
wizard mr. mission based as a generalization to multivariate variables
generalization to multivariate variables of the gamma distribution right I mean
of the gamma distribution right I mean if you think you know the wizard
if you think you know the wizard distribution is sort of a distribution
distribution is sort of a distribution although symmetric positive-definite
although symmetric positive-definite matrices okay very nice distribution I
matrices okay very nice distribution I me if you think distribution of a matrix
me if you think distribution of a matrix is less and what about symmetric
is less and what about symmetric positive matrices here is the Parthians
positive matrices here is the Parthians lambda k okay so this is again all right
lambda k okay so this is again all right so when you have that mean and precision
so when you have that mean and precision unknown okay you write like that if
unknown okay you write like that if actually he did not use the precision
actually he did not use the precision but use the variance this can you can
but use the variance this can you can write the same thing but instead of a
write the same thing but instead of a wizard distribution you put an English
wizard distribution you put an English wizard distribution
wizard distribution okay so what you use you can manipulate
okay so what you use you can manipulate you one way or another but using here
you one way or another but using here precision makes the algebra way is you
precision makes the algebra way is you so there is a lecture for notes to start
so there is a lecture for notes to start with lots of private parameters right so
with lots of private parameters right so you can plug in some reasonable value so
you can plug in some reasonable value so I indicate some of us here so so we need
I indicate some of us here so so we need to perhaps make now the posterior of
to perhaps make now the posterior of this massive unknowns and those are
this massive unknowns and those are those are the positives of the latent
those are the positives of the latent variable z the pristine of the next
variable z the pristine of the next coefficient spy the prestige of the
coefficient spy the prestige of the means mu and remember amy is a vector
means mu and remember amy is a vector but the components are having less of
but the components are having less of those all right and the pursue of this
those all right and the pursue of this variance is long time and i have a lot
variance is long time and i have a lot of okay so this is sort of a written in
of okay so this is sort of a written in a compact way and the only sort of time
a compact way and the only sort of time i when i'm gonna baste i'm normally this
i when i'm gonna baste i'm normally this is cubes if you apply give them you
is cubes if you apply give them you planta because if we I mean as a minimum
planta because if we I mean as a minimum to expect to get the conjugate you know
to expect to get the conjugate you know if you expect a bit of a stated that has
if you expect a bit of a stated that has the phone of the prior oats obviously
the phone of the prior oats obviously you're going to get let's say looking at
you're going to get let's say looking at you know long time you're going to get
you know long time you're going to get some factorization of you given long
some factorization of you given long papyrus evaluations division of real
papyrus evaluations division of real time so you want to keep them like that
time so you want to keep them like that together otherwise you're not going to
together otherwise you're not going to take advantage of these conjugate priors
take advantage of these conjugate priors that you use okay so this will it be
that you use okay so this will it be different from the cauterization this is
different from the cauterization this is going to pop your eyes and interesting
going to pop your eyes and interesting to see so basically you can think right
to see so basically you can think right but we optimized it in one of the
but we optimized it in one of the factors we have a group of variables and
factors we have a group of variables and there's a potential reaction in
there's a potential reaction in variation levels will you do this for a
variation levels will you do this for a purpose okay
purpose okay you are going to update the group of
you are going to update the group of values together
okay so and try to keep taking assuming if you give a sign what you understand
if you give a sign what you understand nothing and in that case I will click
nothing and in that case I will click twice so the number K of Z alright as
twice so the number K of Z alright as the optimal distribution is the
the optimal distribution is the expectation with respect to all the
expectation with respect to all the other variables
other variables Jaime Lanka of the log of the joint of
Jaime Lanka of the log of the joint of likelihood right okay so when one of
likelihood right okay so when one of these we're going to expand this all
these we're going to expand this all right and keep on in the terms the
right and keep on in the terms the dependency all right let's see what type
dependency all right let's see what type of distribution it comes out so the only
of distribution it comes out so the only times that depend on Z is from this
times that depend on Z is from this condition of Z given the mixing
condition of Z given the mixing coefficients and this likely Patel okay
coefficients and this likely Patel okay this depends on a and PI so these
this depends on a and PI so these expectations with respected by which
expectations with respected by which depends on in Atlanta so the expectation
depends on in Atlanta so the expectation is with respect in the Atlanta possible
is with respect in the Atlanta possible never share okay
never share okay and the reason I used to insist that you
and the reason I used to insist that you guys type this things in your homework
guys type this things in your homework when your time the answers obvious if
when your time the answers obvious if you do this by chance you you never gave
you do this by chance you you never gave option to make this to work you have a
option to make this to work you have a complete mess so if you take P of Z
complete mess so if you take P of Z given pile given like this you take the
given pile given like this you take the likelihood you know like all this have
likelihood you know like all this have the previous formulas so you remember
the previous formulas so you remember you will take it next year so it will be
you will take it next year so it will be 0 times R over PI and then will be an
0 times R over PI and then will be an expectation with respect to PI and here
expectation with respect to PI and here we're going to have Z times the end of
we're going to have Z times the end of this with sigasi so obviously it going
this with sigasi so obviously it going to give Z or throw the same thing and
to give Z or throw the same thing and that same thing is what you see here all
that same thing is what you see here all right this comes this thing comes from
right this comes this thing comes from here and all of the stones come from
here and all of the stones come from where from this guy's you can you see it
where from this guy's you can you see it yes ok so this time wasted for
yes ok so this time wasted for memorization factor we don't really care
memorization factor we don't really care about the cost of the time and okay and
about the cost of the time and okay and and they are paying to dance because now
and they are paying to dance because now this level all depends on the
this level all depends on the expectation of lava fight a write what
expectation of lava fight a write what is the dimension where you have to be
is the dimension where you have to be interested so the content is that means
interested so the content is that means you have to find the fluctuation for try
you have to find the fluctuation for try to complete this time identifying the
to complete this time identifying the various of expression for tau the point
various of expression for tau the point is you need to know the various
is you need to know the various approximation from you enter the joint
approximation from you enter the joint basically ok so we're not yet there
basically ok so we're not yet there so this is the result ok well mr. have
so this is the result ok well mr. have depends on these other posteriors but
depends on these other posteriors but obviously you can immediately see that
obviously you can immediately see that this variation of approximation for the
this variation of approximation for the posterior of G it's basically written
posterior of G it's basically written all of your power Z okay remember what
all of your power Z okay remember what was happened in the prior shared before
was happened in the prior shared before when we started in circuit well what did
when we started in circuit well what did we have when we started it was by the
we have when we started it was by the mixing coefficients okay
mixing coefficients okay there have five
all right so if you can write this with an equal sign you get basically you know
an equal sign you get basically you know divided by the summation of this result
divided by the summation of this result for every data point there so
for every data point there so distribution looks like that which is
distribution looks like that which is identical to the to the problem that we
identical to the to the problem that we started this equations to start with
started this equations to start with right now we have observed the day time
right now we have observed the day time we have updated the posterior of Z so
the responsibility okay so nice to be on tells me what's the responsibility the
tells me what's the responsibility the component K takes to explain point n
component K takes to explain point n okay and when you actually are going to
okay and when you actually are going to this responsibility every point you can
this responsibility every point you can put a bit of red depending on this
put a bit of red depending on this posterior responsibilities then actually
posterior responsibilities then actually when you do this graphs they look
when you do this graphs they look wonderful
wonderful and in the literature that's how people
and in the literature that's how people demonstrate the Costera supposed to be
demonstrate the Costera supposed to be now if you're back okay but these are
now if you're back okay but these are the post irresponsible
the post irresponsible okay and we have discussed this when we
okay and we have discussed this when we were talking about expectation
were talking about expectation maximization we spent lectures and
maximization we spent lectures and lectures on this because this is
valuable basically expectation of Z and K is our NK you remember that because
K is our NK you remember that because you can only take values 0 and 1 right
you can only take values 0 and 1 right so the expectation is equal to the
so the expectation is equal to the probability that's the posterior
probability that's the posterior probability which is R and K now up to
probability which is R and K now up to now is right that we have a nice job for
now is right that we have a nice job for this but this setting for this R depends
this but this setting for this R depends on many expectations with respect to the
on many expectations with respect to the other distributions so notice we can
other distributions so notice we can actually complete all of this we are
actually complete all of this we are going off work I mean it's nice to say
going off work I mean it's nice to say this is what it is but how do you
this is what it is but how do you compute a roll and and so we will keep
compute a roll and and so we will keep going and see how about I think we have
going and see how about I think we have seen them when we discuss about
seen them when we discuss about expectation maximization so this is the
expectation maximization so this is the point in the garbage and carry all right
point in the garbage and carry all right so basically whatever the points when
so basically whatever the points when you sum this mysterious puts benefits
you sum this mysterious puts benefits now this is the effective sample name on
now this is the effective sample name on the Gaussian K all right so you take on
the Gaussian K all right so you take on the exist you want to apply them with
the exist you want to apply them with the posterior possibilities and this is
the posterior possibilities and this is the effective area okay so basically I
the effective area okay so basically I am defining this because if you have
am defining this because if you have these definitions you will see that the
these definitions you will see that the algebra is going to simplify and one
algebra is going to simplify and one identity that you may want to pay
identity that you may want to pay attention because the terms can be not
attention because the terms can be not just on this setting but in many related
just on this setting but in many related settings will have these
settings will have these responsibilities it is very nice
responsibilities it is very nice identity that comes directly basically
identity that comes directly basically by taking the definition of SK and
by taking the definition of SK and expanding it okay
expanding it okay so somewhere in the derivations we've
so somewhere in the derivations we've not said today but when we read the
not said today but when we read the notes
notes this is a calculation or concept okay so
this is a calculation or concept okay so we want to calculate Q up by mu and
we want to calculate Q up by mu and lambda so this would be the love of that
lambda so this would be the love of that advocate pioneer lanta will be the
advocate pioneer lanta will be the expectation with respect to Z of the log
expectation with respect to Z of the log of the join the likelihood with the only
of the join the likelihood with the only times we're going to be keeping is
times we're going to be keeping is anything that depends on P near Atlanta
anything that depends on P near Atlanta and in those times anything that
and in those times anything that contains it will take expectations so
contains it will take expectations so basically what you get is you get from
basically what you get is you get from the prior to get love of the prior from
the prior to get love of the prior from the pile remember we had a joint
the pile remember we had a joint distribution of in Atlanta but Gaussian
distribution of in Atlanta but Gaussian wizard distribution there is a 0 depends
wizard distribution there is a 0 depends on PI so we can have an expectation this
on PI so we can have an expectation this Z here inside the time remember we have
Z here inside the time remember we have the Gaussian to the powers east of the
the Gaussian to the powers east of the signal comes down so we have an
signal comes down so we have an expectation times the log of the
expectation times the log of the Gaussian plus constants okay and
Gaussian plus constants okay and interestingly enough right when you look
interestingly enough right when you look at this distribution okay my thing just
at this distribution okay my thing just died okay alright so when you look on on
died okay alright so when you look on on the does anybody else with you that's a
the does anybody else with you that's a very stupid question right it's like
very stupid question right it's like asking if you have any an entire forest
asking if you have any an entire forest walking right something like that okay
walking right something like that okay so you have no batteries how can you
so you have no batteries how can you leave home without batteries that's
leave home without batteries that's unacceptable
unacceptable okay so you can circle the equation they
okay so you can circle the equation they are right but the certainly over K right
are right but the certainly over K right because you can see the two summations
because you can see the two summations from Kelly and we have no joy when you
from Kelly and we have no joy when you get rid of the log basically you get the
get rid of the log basically you get the factorization over K so 29
factorization over K so 29 okay so so tsunamis I'm gonna put in the
okay so so tsunamis I'm gonna put in the the probably shall we have the condition
the probably shall we have the condition of Z given pi we know expectations from
of Z given pi we know expectations from exists of the post irresponsibility so
exists of the post irresponsibility so we planned in all of this together all
we planned in all of this together all right
right actually sometimes fathers have life if
actually sometimes fathers have life if you versatility the okay this the bottom
or I need to change okay all right okay all right let me try
okay have to learn than you think yeah
all right right so this croissant okay this good
right so this croissant okay this good oh I see okay oh this is heavy lighting
oh I see okay oh this is heavy lighting nice this is extra powerful it comes
nice this is extra powerful it comes from Beijing you know when planes fly
from Beijing you know when planes fly you go up on the skies right let me use
you go up on the skies right let me use it outside the classroom okay
it outside the classroom okay all right it's very powerful I will
all right it's very powerful I will confiscate it right this here this is
confiscate it right this here this is what we get we need to substitute versed
what we get we need to substitute versed in there all right
in there all right actually the expectations and let's see
actually the expectations and let's see okay let's see what we get
okay let's see what we get okay again I don't want to give you all
okay again I don't want to give you all the algebra but there are some tricky
the algebra but there are some tricky things that come all the time
things that come all the time so if I notice them I need to tell you
so if I notice them I need to tell you what's going on so basically we start
what's going on so basically we start killed in this expectation of respect to
killed in this expectation of respect to zero the joint of likelihood okay and
over carry as decisions with some precision that then comes with some way
precision that then comes with some way start so you don't have to take the one
start so you don't have to take the one service and you may say well the usual
service and you may say well the usual distribution of a distribution or posted
distribution of a distribution or posted definite matrices well yeah you have to
definite matrices well yeah you have to do it because of this character right
do it because of this character right you have to do this so you take most
you have to do this so you take most launched etc etc and and you get
launched etc etc and and you get basically you look at the terms that
basically you look at the terms that they were warning me
they were warning me Lanta and he looked at the optimal
Lanta and he looked at the optimal distribution so out of this you can
distribution so out of this you can extract phoneme in London you can see
extract phoneme in London you can see lower to start up in Atlanta is
lower to start up in Atlanta is basically this two lines here alright
surprising okay alright so this is the
okay for example okay and if you with in this expression
okay and if you with in this expression you basically get a Gaussian in new all
you basically get a Gaussian in new all right you can see it if you place the
right you can see it if you place the square and that's the mastership
square and that's the mastership alright so from this again if you and
alright so from this again if you and now how do you defend the posterior is
now how do you defend the posterior is the conditional for several times the
the conditional for several times the variation distribution of Ishita so if
variation distribution of Ishita so if you take an action that you can actually
you take an action that you can actually compute the I'll keep going backwards if
compute the I'll keep going backwards if you take the function that you can
you take the function that you can actually compute the approximation of
actually compute the approximation of the posterior of lambda and so if you do
the posterior of lambda and so if you do the algebra you get many different weird
the algebra you get many different weird terms okay and if you have patience and
terms okay and if you have patience and you actually homophobe has disappear all
you actually homophobe has disappear all the things cancel out and you get their
the things cancel out and you get their wonderful approximation for the love of
wonderful approximation for the love of the key of lambda k that looks like that
the key of lambda k that looks like that okay well this wk inversed comes to be
okay well this wk inversed comes to be this which you may think it's a
this which you may think it's a complicated expression okay and UK comes
complicated expression okay and UK comes to be u 0 plus 10 K and you know that I
to be u 0 plus 10 K and you know that I prefer this is the relative distribution
prefer this is the relative distribution effect so when you look at this right
effect so when you look at this right you can still submit additional under K
you can still submit additional under K but what type of distribution is this
but what type of distribution is this exponential you think I get so what you
exponential you think I get so what you gets a wizard distribution and here's
gets a wizard distribution and here's the answer okay alright so the combined
the answer okay alright so the combined basically distribution formula lanta is
basically distribution formula lanta is a Gaussian wizard okay so the Gaussian
a Gaussian wizard okay so the Gaussian the precision lambda comes with the
the precision lambda comes with the wizard next to it and kill all the
wizard next to it and kill all the parameters selectively the approximation
parameters selectively the approximation to the posterior of new claim of decay
to the posterior of new claim of decay it is the same 12 as the priors that we
it is the same 12 as the priors that we use from your lambda
use from your lambda the only differences the parameters
the only differences the parameters because 0 and mu 0 etc or nu 0 w0 have
because 0 and mu 0 etc or nu 0 w0 have been updated now and this have sort of
been updated now and this have sort of the updates of the parameters so
the updates of the parameters so basically using conjugate priors gave a
basically using conjugate priors gave a similar variation approximation that is
similar variation approximation that is the same identical for all right so this
the same identical for all right so this is very nice
okay and all right so we're gonna keep going back reports again all right so
going back reports again all right so tell me is the conversation here
tell me is the conversation here we need to go back to another question
we need to go back to another question over the responsibilities and I'm gonna
over the responsibilities and I'm gonna put all of these things up so to say
put all of these things up so to say that the relationship immediately
that the relationship immediately algebra so remember the of this
algebra so remember the of this responsibilities this out we are
responsibilities this out we are normalized us from civilities requires
normalized us from civilities requires the expectation of the log of I claim
the expectation of the log of I claim requires the expectation of the line of
requires the expectation of the line of this matrices lambda K and the
this matrices lambda K and the expectation with respect to me along to
expectation with respect to me along to exist okay so you know what you need to
exist okay so you know what you need to have taught us to do this algebra so
have taught us to do this algebra so let's complete this you need the
let's complete this you need the expectation respect to me Atlanta which
expectation respect to me Atlanta which is fundamental basically do every time
is fundamental basically do every time you see this form and you have an
you see this form and you have an expectation I have written this as the
expectation I have written this as the parish of lambda times xx transpose
parish of lambda times xx transpose have you seen that before it's a
have you seen that before it's a fundamental take basic and everywhere
fundamental take basic and everywhere when you get this you write it when you
when you get this you write it when you have X transpose lambda times X you I
have X transpose lambda times X you I this as the trace of lambda X X
this as the trace of lambda X X transpose okay and then we need
transpose okay and then we need expectation with the posterior of
expectation with the posterior of mylanta we use the variational
mylanta we use the variational approximation of those so we're gonna
approximation of those so we're gonna first an integration McCadden an
first an integration McCadden an integration in you need this you need to
integration in you need this you need to know the mean of the ways of
know the mean of the ways of distribution to do that so this
distribution to do that so this basically if you use the properties of
basically if you use the properties of the wizard distribution are no problem
the wizard distribution are no problem and it remains we need to calculate this
and it remains we need to calculate this expectation of the lava pie PA all right
expectation of the lava pie PA all right okay so all right you can I am NOT going
okay so all right you can I am NOT going to elaborate on this okay for this if
to elaborate on this okay for this if you study in Wikipedia the declared this
you study in Wikipedia the declared this tradition this expectation of a lot of
tradition this expectation of a lot of Pi clay comes to be basically the body
Pi clay comes to be basically the body gamma function computed on alpha t minus
gamma function computed on alpha t minus the sonographer case this is the by
the sonographer case this is the by gamma function and and then we have to
gamma function and and then we have to complete this pain prepare but you never
complete this pain prepare but you never satanic or in any machine landing book
satanic or in any machine landing book actually remember he has this
actually remember he has this calculations explicitly but you will
calculations explicitly but you will never take a discussion of how you
never take a discussion of how you compute the expectation with respect to
compute the expectation with respect to ways of distribution of the love of the
ways of distribution of the love of the determinant of a wizard distribution all
determinant of a wizard distribution all right okay so so there is we are think
right okay so so there is we are think okay and I am NOT going to am I going
okay and I am NOT going to am I going backwards yeah no okay so so this is
backwards yeah no okay so so this is what we need we need to calculate the
what we need we need to calculate the expectation of this lovicott determinant
expectation of this lovicott determinant by the Council of the Gaussian with
by the Council of the Gaussian with respect to this the balanced addition of
respect to this the balanced addition of lambda which the wizard okay and I
lambda which the wizard okay and I remember when I first open this you know
remember when I first open this you know three years ago you know the miracles of
three years ago you know the miracles of Google okay I came across a reference
Google okay I came across a reference but basically you can approximate this
but basically you can approximate this as a sum of beauty square distributions
as a sum of beauty square distributions and with some trivial answer actually
and with some trivial answer actually which is on this slide that I'm not
which is on this slide that I'm not going to elaborate you can actually
going to elaborate you can actually compute analytically the expectation of
compute analytically the expectation of value
value the determinant of Lanka and this is the
the determinant of Lanka and this is the expression well again this is the by
expression well again this is the by gamma distribution obviously here my
gamma distribution obviously here my parentheses should be inside the
parentheses should be inside the argument they're gonna miss it so
argument they're gonna miss it so everything on this okay can be
everything on this okay can be calculated and I'm going to give you a
calculated and I'm going to give you a very compact oh and the very compact
very compact oh and the very compact point is what you see on the bottom okay
point is what you see on the bottom okay so this involves this cherry pie which
so this involves this cherry pie which we define it here to be the exponential
we define it here to be the exponential of this expectation this charaluta that
of this expectation this charaluta that we define to be the exponential of this
we define to be the exponential of this expectation and then this term inside
expectation and then this term inside we're Nikkei is mu 0 plus n K all right
we're Nikkei is mu 0 plus n K all right which are this idea so basically I can
which are this idea so basically I can find this line that is a summary of
find this line that is a summary of everything this is you can program it in
everything this is you can program it in in a few minutes okay right somebody
in a few minutes okay right somebody gives you we actually passed any of this
gives you we actually passed any of this result I would know okay now this is
result I would know okay now this is written as an easter time step because
written as an easter time step because of the similarities with the expectation
of the similarities with the expectation maximization so in the easter you have
maximization so in the easter you have become a basically the responsibilities
become a basically the responsibilities and to give make the responsibilities
and to give make the responsibilities you need these expectations this cherry
you need these expectations this cherry pie and the can be lambda K and this is
pie and the can be lambda K and this is the formula for these responsibilities
the formula for these responsibilities whereas we have the responsibilities we
whereas we have the responsibilities we can bring the m-step calculate the
can bring the m-step calculate the attractive number of points on its
attractive number of points on its Gaussian carry the effective mean values
Gaussian carry the effective mean values and variance and update all the
and variance and update all the parameters and then you keep iterating
parameters and then you keep iterating and human converts okay you win converts
and again as I mentioned this compressions have been extended to
compressions have been extended to anything he makes Raghava processes and
anything he makes Raghava processes and variation have been extended also to an
variation have been extended also to an infinite in thousand distributions and
infinite in thousand distributions and alternately makes mixture of Gaussian
alternately makes mixture of Gaussian processes okay
processes okay an example is a Python code okay I'm
an example is a Python code okay I'm gonna pass this right actually on this
gonna pass this right actually on this slide some of the equations but I'm not
slide some of the equations but I'm not gonna show you today they somehow don't
gonna show you today they somehow don't show very well because they were typed
show very well because they were typed on there on a Mac so they I need to sort
on there on a Mac so they I need to sort of revive some of their questions but
of revive some of their questions but you know we will fix it today so
you know we will fix it today so hopefully so who's that so an example
hopefully so who's that so an example that has an issue of 6,000 so these are
that has an issue of 6,000 so these are my data points and the ellipses that you
my data points and the ellipses that you will see is basically one side of the
will see is basically one side of the nation density controls each of the
nation density controls each of the parents I caused that has already
parents I caused that has already alright that inside it's eclipse that
alright that inside it's eclipse that corresponds to the main content of the
corresponds to the main content of the mix equation and this is when you start
mix equation and this is when you start alright so these are the prior makes
alright so these are the prior makes partitions but as we we will continue
partitions but as we we will continue this this will be the color will be
this this will be the color will be based on the posterior responsibilities
based on the posterior responsibilities so this is this is not okay this is
so this is this is not okay this is iteration 15 okay on this are the
iteration 15 okay on this are the different Gaussian basically but you
different Gaussian basically but you compute this situation 60 and this
compute this situation 60 and this situation 120 so basically the model
situation 120 so basically the model collapse from 2000 now you know what
collapse from 2000 now you know what happened you know you say I have a
happened you know you say I have a mixture
mixture collapse on on two gaussians well yeah
collapse on on two gaussians well yeah because this players that we have used
because this players that we have used for you know they enforce with the
for you know they enforce with the buzzword supposed to do okay so the
buzzword supposed to do okay so the spires we use basically kills some of
spires we use basically kills some of the components okay
the components okay and the misny that's why he gives the
and the misny that's why he gives the same ideas right for the name cream
same ideas right for the name cream actually remember I have and into a
actually remember I have and into a mixed so you say hundred you well 1200
mixed so you say hundred you well 1200 would go down to five ten you know so
would go down to five ten you know so here it goes down to to 120 without you
here it goes down to to 120 without you having to do so the city is Islam sort
having to do so the city is Islam sort of not in in a sort of violent way say
of not in in a sort of violent way say use two components it's mostly the two
use two components it's mostly the two components are not coming because the
components are not coming because the responsibilities taken for the data
responsibilities taken for the data points are basically zero alright
points are basically zero alright there's zero these block okay this is
and again alright survives you to describe look at
alright survives you to describe look at this code right thing works okay so
component survived all right and it takes so much of it relations ninety
takes so much of it relations ninety iterations you notice this is the an in
iterations you notice this is the an in opposite monotonically increases okay
opposite monotonically increases okay and this is this would work here
so this time if you know of this different basically I supposed this
different basically I supposed this isn't the postilion values of alpha
isn't the postilion values of alpha chainsaw
chainsaw okay the Brazilian values of alpha K and
okay the Brazilian values of alpha K and you notice eventually you know after
you notice eventually you know after interation 94 so this is some
interation 94 so this is some intermediate response iteration after
intermediate response iteration after iteration 912 only 2000 volunteers
iteration 912 only 2000 volunteers survived okay so this actually may be
survived okay so this actually may be the same data set as the one I saw you
the same data set as the one I saw you with the Python code just a few seconds
with the Python code just a few seconds ago
don't want to say anything about okay
let me see what else I know where what I need to tell you
need to tell you so we need to you may ask me since you
so we need to you may ask me since you got very excited with this you may say
got very excited with this you may say an evaluation all right who is the
an evaluation all right who is the distribution is there any hope drops
distribution is there any hope drops recompute any of them telling me I've no
recompute any of them telling me I've no example slide 47 because obviously
example slide 47 because obviously what's the perfect ultra-light would say
what's the perfect ultra-light would say here is how the data fit you know in so
here is how the data fit you know in so many components where I'm interested to
many components where I'm interested to know is can actually compute the
know is can actually compute the posterior of a new data point okay so
posterior of a new data point okay so this equation so this is the posterior
this equation so this is the posterior distribution tell me exactly everything
distribution tell me exactly everything you see on this equation isopropyl
you see on this equation isopropyl integrates information on Z so tell me
integrates information on Z so tell me exactly what's going on their
exactly what's going on their distribution
what's the predictive distribution
parameters and length and variables so these are the parameters right and this
these are the parameters right and this C heart is the latent variable
C heart is the latent variable corresponding to X heart in other words
corresponding to X heart in other words if I knew that that component you know
if I knew that that component you know complain to the mixture of generates the
complain to the mixture of generates the point X 1/2 all right this would be the
point X 1/2 all right this would be the likelihood or not right that's what we
likelihood or not right that's what we must be an integration on all the
must be an integration on all the unknowns including Z bar and I picked as
unknowns including Z bar and I picked as a summation because the bar takes what
a summation because the bar takes what values it's a it's a it's a
values it's a it's a it's a you know so so I'm going it said this
you know so so I'm going it said this country which I'm going to pick the
country which I'm going to pick the Grantham Z alright okay okay
generated by this version the next coefficient by K and this will become
coefficient by K and this will become this Gaussian and obviously this mistake
this Gaussian and obviously this mistake is very complicated so we're going to
is very complicated so we're going to approximate it with a variational
approximate it with a variational distribution so Q PI Q mu K lambda K so
distribution so Q PI Q mu K lambda K so this the distribution we welcome this
this the distribution we welcome this remember we got this restrictor izing of
remember we got this restrictor izing of Delta and Kelly and this came to be
Delta and Kelly and this came to be optimization of the K of thousand wizard
optimization of the K of thousand wizard distributions okay
distributions okay and of course what they are now trying
and of course what they are now trying to perform this integration right now
to perform this integration right now what that means you never give up right
what that means you never give up right because if the least a closed-form
because if the least a closed-form solution and you go and you say now my
solution and you go and you say now my references computer program to do this
references computer program to do this people would be laughing is like you
people would be laughing is like you must be kidding you know when we read
must be kidding you know when we read the book starts because there is a
the book starts because there is a mythical solution this can you guess I
mythical solution this can you guess I mean before I show you anything can you
mean before I show you anything can you guess you know it's just from your birth
guess you know it's just from your birth time scale what type of distribution
time scale what type of distribution this may come to be I mean just yes so
this may come to be I mean just yes so again we have a browse unique slots
again we have a browse unique slots heart rate right okay components and now
heart rate right okay components and now we try to produce from you X you know
we try to produce from you X you know what's the probability what do you think
what's the probability what do you think is going to happen I mean just give you
is going to happen I mean just give you some choices
some choices let me account so the level is just
let me account so the level is just again it collapse to some mixed of some
again it collapse to some mixed of some capital K components so what will the
capital K components so what will the predictive distribution look like at the
predictive distribution look like at the end of the day
I'm not surprised you know anyways
well discipline is sing to you through it becomes to the mix of gaussians
mixture of gaussians no I mean it will not surprise me
not surprise me and that's how it doesn't come to be a
and that's how it doesn't come to be a minister of gaussians unless you have a
minister of gaussians unless you have a lots of data but it goes to the next
lots of data but it goes to the next third of what distribution what what is
third of what distribution what what is very close to browse it didn't take this
very close to browse it didn't take this to be a okay so it comes to be a mixture
to be a okay so it comes to be a mixture of didn t distributions and only on the
of didn t distributions and only on the limit of you only have a lots of data so
limit of you only have a lots of data so the prior effects basically disappear
the prior effects basically disappear this qt- becomes a Gaussian it and okay
the answer bar is actually it's not as painful as I make it to look like right
painful as I make it to look like right so you will you need basically the
so you will you need basically the expectations of this coefficients YK
expectations of this coefficients YK coming from the declare distribution you
coming from the declare distribution you will need basically to work with this
will need basically to work with this okay and so you can see actually we know
okay and so you can see actually we know it comes that the predictive
it comes that the predictive distribution is an integration of the
distribution is an integration of the lambda of the for each K lambda K over
lambda of the for each K lambda K over diffusion okay but we precision that you
diffusion okay but we precision that you see here that's a wizard distribution
see here that's a wizard distribution okay so again it is an integration of
okay so again it is an integration of Atlanta of gaussians with Wizards you
Atlanta of gaussians with Wizards you know actually mattresses and actually I
know actually mattresses and actually I should have given you this is a homework
should have given you this is a homework right in an ideal environment because
right in an ideal environment because seeing even in bishops book it it has a
seeing even in bishops book it it has a little example that
little example that you know when the hint reduces for
you know when the hint reduces for remember we all like chapter 2
remember we all like chapter 2 introduces the student t distribution
introduces the student t distribution you know how he introduces it as a
you know how he introduces it as a mixture of gaussians for the precision
mixture of gaussians for the precision in the mixture so that components in the
in the mixture so that components in the mixture of what they are gamma
mixture of what they are gamma distributions
distributions so actually obviously you can see here
so actually obviously you can see here if you have a multivariate Gaussian
if you have a multivariate Gaussian right and you take for this for this
right and you take for this for this precision a wizard you know you will get
precision a wizard you know you will get a student T distribution a multivariate
a student T distribution a multivariate unity distribution okay if you don't
unity distribution okay if you don't believe me look on chapter 2 where she
believe me look on chapter 2 where she introduces a student P you know with
introduces a student P you know with sort of this construct that in one
sort of this construct that in one dimension I think so basically here
dimension I think so basically here we'll we have this exact the same thing
we'll we have this exact the same thing we you know student eat some trivial
we you know student eat some trivial algebra basically looking on how much
algebra basically looking on how much the distribution looks like
okay okay the membership today comes from the display posterior and we write
from the display posterior and we write the coefficients in the Dirac
the coefficients in the Dirac distribution I have times the sum of
distribution I have times the sum of application so these are the mixture
application so these are the mixture components and then I have the student T
components and then I have the student T with a precision basically that is given
with a precision basically that is given by this formula and the bomb in your
by this formula and the bomb in your case we had completed them before from
case we had completed them before from these labs and wizard distribution okay
these labs and wizard distribution okay so very nice formula okay all right I
so very nice formula okay all right I don't know why so negative put okay so
don't know why so negative put okay so this is it's an approximation obviously
this is it's an approximation obviously of the predicted
of the predicted tribution it's an approximation because
tribution it's an approximation because the percent of the parameters we use was
the percent of the parameters we use was not the exact posterior it was the
not the exact posterior it was the variation approximation okay so these
variation approximation okay so these exercises in in the notes so you're
exercises in in the notes so you're interested what you can do this and
interested what you can do this and again it's a very nice exercise if you
again it's a very nice exercise if you look at this formula and take let me
look at this formula and take let me look at the other parameters what
look at the other parameters what happens when I have a lots of data so
happens when I have a lots of data so when you take have to go to infinity or
when you take have to go to infinity or I usually have a lots of data you can
I usually have a lots of data you can say with some trivial calculations
say with some trivial calculations basically that this predicting posterior
basically that this predicting posterior distribution comes to be a mixture of
distribution comes to be a mixture of options okay and you could have some
options okay and you could have some even have just this officer alright
even have just this officer alright because you know if you have a list to
because you know if you have a list to data to get all the powers forget
data to get all the powers forget everything you know what then you think
everything you know what then you think so every dollar cell is defined by the
so every dollar cell is defined by the averages of the points like when we play
averages of the points like when we play Nia that belongs to the Gaussian with
Nia that belongs to the Gaussian with this covariance okay and then basically
this covariance okay and then basically the mixing questions is the persons
the mixing questions is the persons having that component there's the total
having that component there's the total number of points okay I mean you know
number of points okay I mean you know you could have you know if you can its
you could have you know if you can its money to predict what's to know this
money to predict what's to know this answer this is a price they did promise
answer this is a price they did promise me if you try to do the answer block and
me if you try to do the answer block and then you get some water and when you
then you get some water and when you have a lots of vapor you don't bother to
have a lots of vapor you don't bother to say is this correct in other ways is it
say is this correct in other ways is it going to give me a bit if it is not
going to give me a bit if it is not going to give you that you know
going to give you that you know something is very wrong with the algebra
something is very wrong with the algebra okay so in this case when you take the
okay so in this case when you take the limit to lots of data the algebra comes
limit to lots of data the algebra comes to be correct to do this limit you have
to be correct to do this limit you have and I
and I you know encourage you to try I mean no
you know encourage you to try I mean no everything's in the nose at least pull
everything's in the nose at least pull it and then get dizzy okay so if you
it and then get dizzy okay so if you follow the algebra you have to use nice
follow the algebra you have to use nice approximations you know I can see
approximations you know I can see because there's run of actions you have
because there's run of actions you have you Steve thinks approximation formula
you Steve thinks approximation formula and approximation kolento paste it
and approximation kolento paste it consists of basically all the posterior
consists of basically all the posterior distribution because you are the limit
distribution because you are the limit of many data become Delta functions and
of many data become Delta functions and at the end of the day without the
at the end of the day without the function you get right up okay
function you get right up okay all right I don't really have any
all right I don't really have any minutes so we might tell you we need to
minutes so we might tell you we need to do we need to go back whistling was it
do we need to go back whistling was it 16 thank you continue you can generalize
16 thank you continue you can generalize this and okay okay
because rate and the likes you can actually generalize this for many many
actually generalize this for many many problems for situations where the joint
problems for situations where the joint affection Z or I come from the
affection Z or I come from the exponential problem okay and I think
exponential problem okay and I think it's many distributions so wherever here
it's many distributions so wherever here is I expand the joint likelihood alright
is I expand the joint likelihood alright in the form of an exponential family
in the form of an exponential family distribution so these are the sufficient
distribution so these are the sufficient statistics it are the natural parameter
statistics it are the natural parameter this organization factor this the
this organization factor this the function fraction is d right so so
function fraction is d right so so actually in the new knowledge okay that
actually in the new knowledge okay that when I gave you you can use so that this
when I gave you you can use so that this creative innovation will hang on the
creative innovation will hang on the next slide actually Nations we did for
next slide actually Nations we did for the multi body of value alright because
the multi body of value alright because this is a very general problem okay so
the results from the exponential family so you talk to the information from
so you talk to the information from there alright so the statistics here
there alright so the statistics here really become new 0 X 0 ok this museum
really become new 0 X 0 ok this museum becomes your prior and an f of X 0 u 0
becomes your prior and an f of X 0 u 0 okay so you can read bishops you can
okay so you can read bishops you can look at my notes in the fall formal
look at my notes in the fall formal information of the exponential family
information of the exponential family but basically you can put in this for
but basically you can put in this for many distributions right so the question
many distributions right so the question is can you actually divide by a small
is can you actually divide by a small difference approximations this general
difference approximations this general scenario if we can
scenario if we can we have seen about 50 problems all in
we have seen about 50 problems all in one slide and the answer yes you can
one slide and the answer yes you can so what you have to do to be put on
so what you have to do to be put on everything up because the time is over
okay okay you have to use exactly the same ideas as before right
same ideas as before right so you capitalize this as Q of Z times Q
so you capitalize this as Q of Z times Q fitnah and you are looking for kids in
fitnah and you are looking for kids in your people to be the exponential colony
your people to be the exponential colony and surprise surprise cubes it'll be
and surprise surprise cubes it'll be optimal comes to be exactly exponential
optimal comes to be exactly exponential family the only thing you need is the
family the only thing you need is the expectation of the parameters and QP
expectation of the parameters and QP become so should be the exponential
become so should be the exponential family and you can see the updates are
family and you can see the updates are standard and the only thing you need is
standard and the only thing you need is the expectation with respect to Z of the
the expectation with respect to Z of the sufficient statistics here affection and
sufficient statistics here affection and Xia okay so basically the problem where
Xia okay so basically the problem where this distribution is the exponential
this distribution is the exponential family conflicting with in this
family conflicting with in this variation of observation in a certain
variation of observation in a certain area in step where you compute this
area in step where you compute this expectation using P of Z N and then you
expectation using P of Z N and then you plug this same here and you compute this
plug this same here and you compute this variation distribution actually the only
variation distribution actually the only thing you need is you need the
thing you need is you need the expectation of beta so you eat the rate
expectation of beta so you eat the rate and you can get you know height you can
and you can get you know height you can get two results for multi variate
get two results for multi variate thousand you can get the result any
thousand you can get the result any distribution any example that we see in
distribution any example that we see in the literature you can use this prognost
the literature you can use this prognost and it will fit in all right so I'm
and it will fit in all right so I'm gonna leave and we're gonna use the
gonna leave and we're gonna use the enjoy Friday happy Easter and see you on
enjoy Friday happy Easter and see you on Tuesday
I like it