all right before we start some announcements on the next lecture
announcements on the next lecture actually we're going to camp the scary
actually we're going to camp the scary CICS seminar because the speaker
CICS seminar because the speaker couldn't come on Monday so if you show
couldn't come on Monday so if you show up on the first thing you see the lots
up on the first thing you see the lots of strangers just keep in mind they're
of strangers just keep in mind they're strangers to me as well because I would
strangers to me as well because I would have never seen them before
have never seen them before but because of the particular talk they
but because of the particular talk they will show up ok so that's not a reason
will show up ok so that's not a reason to hide because there's going to be a
to hide because there's going to be a big crowd
big crowd ok so the top is going to be learning
ok so the top is going to be learning member the exact title about uncertainty
member the exact title about uncertainty qualification in some applications
qualification in some applications related community knowledge but the
related community knowledge but the theme obviously would be very general so
theme obviously would be very general so be very much related at least to a
be very much related at least to a subject of this class all right
subject of this class all right we haven't really finished with a hidden
we haven't really finished with a hidden Markov model there's way too much stuff
Markov model there's way too much stuff to do but they decided to just take a
to do but they decided to just take a break and move a little bit forward to
break and move a little bit forward to cover database models to be sure that we
cover database models to be sure that we don't stay behind and if there is time
don't stay behind and if there is time we're going to come back to cover
we're going to come back to cover basically to remind you that all this
basically to remind you that all this mess is passing algorithms we did they
mess is passing algorithms we did they give you the same result or the
give you the same result or the alpha-beta messed resistors we cover
alpha-beta messed resistors we cover them in in the last two lectures and
them in in the last two lectures and also I wanted to give you
also I wanted to give you generalizations of hmm which are very
generalizations of hmm which are very practical lots of applications and I
practical lots of applications and I don't any of you is doing any project in
don't any of you is doing any project in that area but somehow you know somehow I
that area but somehow you know somehow I know there is to analyze to do very
know there is to analyze to do very complicated projects and they don't like
complicated projects and they don't like the simple thing because in the simple
the simple thing because in the simple things you can find the truth in the
things you can find the truth in the complicated things you are lost
complicated things you are lost all right I like simple things right I
all right I like simple things right I can see smile there so I like simple
can see smile there so I like simple project and every time even from the
project and every time even from the distances sorry my colonic I say I want
distances sorry my colonic I say I want something trivial for Donnelly's you
something trivial for Donnelly's you know people want to design bridges that
know people want to design bridges that by bit because it looks good right
by bit because it looks good right correct are you designing any bridge any
correct are you designing any bridge any fire rising building no all right okay
fire rising building no all right okay so we've discussed some of state-space
so we've discussed some of state-space models today as an introduction this is
models today as an introduction this is part sort of this general theme of using
part sort of this general theme of using probabilistic graphical models for data
probabilistic graphical models for data oriented problems and this concept is so
oriented problems and this concept is so fundamental basically you know maybe the
fundamental basically you know maybe the problem has nothing to do with
problem has nothing to do with state-space models but you can transform
state-space models but you can transform it in a way that you can utilize some of
it in a way that you can utilize some of these algorithms and I'm gonna show you
these algorithms and I'm gonna show you a little example of doing Bayesian
a little example of doing Bayesian inference to find the posterior of some
inference to find the posterior of some parameters with no dynamics and we can
parameters with no dynamics and we can these things we are going to learn today
these things we are going to learn today to do Bayesian inference you can even do
to do Bayesian inference you can even do near things you can do time integration
near things you can do time integration of all these using state space projects
of all these using state space projects and actually that's a very interesting
and actually that's a very interesting area even even accurate research alright
area even even accurate research alright show the slides I'm not done yet but
show the slides I'm not done yet but actually be hmm sliced but hopefully you
actually be hmm sliced but hopefully you got from by email am almost three slides
got from by email am almost three slides left to detect the three slides okay I
left to detect the three slides okay I don't want to post them because every
don't want to post them because every time I look there's another mistake I
time I look there's another mistake I have to correct okay so there are three
have to correct okay so there are three slides and I will post a stand and the
slides and I will post a stand and the missing lectures have very short so this
missing lectures have very short so this state space what those lectures are
state space what those lectures are almost done
almost done so if not posted I will send you an
so if not posted I will send you an email with them all right
hmm versus SSM basically the graphical model is identical would have an
model is identical would have an evolving state Z so that's how a
evolving state Z so that's how a dynamical system and then we have some
dynamical system and then we have some noisy observations that there why the
noisy observations that there why the only difference chromate some enemies in
only difference chromate some enemies in the hmm model like you know in the
the hmm model like you know in the simulator Gaussian mixture model
simulator Gaussian mixture model dismissive oliver's will discrete here
dismissive oliver's will discrete here the C variables are continuous that's
the C variables are continuous that's the only difference
the only difference okay so in addition to just make things
okay so in addition to just make things a little bit more interesting we have
a little bit more interesting we have sort of introduced in both the dynamical
sort of introduced in both the dynamical and the observation model some impede
and the observation model some impede variable you that you can think of it
variable you that you can think of it being sort of some crossing term that
being sort of some crossing term that you prescribe alright the hotel is not
you prescribe alright the hotel is not there there is nothing that it falls
there there is nothing that it falls back to the previous models we had so
back to the previous models we had so the general assistant model we have the
the general assistant model we have the dynamic described by this equation in a
dynamic described by this equation in a very general form we're going to
very general form we're going to simplify of course so that this is some
simplify of course so that this is some easy function to work
easy function to work so here is the input city - one of the
so here is the input city - one of the state that the - Rana and some noise and
state that the - Rana and some noise and the observations basically also has a
the observations basically also has a u-turn it depends only on Z at the same
u-turn it depends only on Z at the same time T it has its own noise as well so
time T it has its own noise as well so really very so this is identical to what
really very so this is identical to what we did with hmm actually hmm we said you
we did with hmm actually hmm we said you can put there's an observation anything
can put there's an observation anything you want to and we did the case for
you want to and we did the case for example with a Gaussian model but right
example with a Gaussian model but right now this can be a Gaussian and this can
now this can be a Gaussian and this can be a Gaucher all right okay sort of a
be a Gaucher all right okay sort of a number of problems that they are started
number of problems that they are started in the context of data simulation and
in the context of data simulation and best ones are identical for SSM okay so
best ones are identical for SSM okay so the what's the name we gave to
the what's the name we gave to estimating this how do we call this
estimating this how do we call this distribution
what's the name we gave to that and it's universal name I mean you need to know
universal name I mean you need to know this because it comes to everywhere so
this because it comes to everywhere so what they did we call how do we call
what they did we call how do we call this distribution
this distribution it's a posterior of the stage right but
it's a posterior of the stage right but we gave a name we call it something in
we gave a name we call it something in the little children you will see it with
the little children you will see it with the name what's the name it's not the
the name what's the name it's not the name of neutral you know it's a name
name of neutral you know it's a name that defines in words what this
that defines in words what this distribution is about so what was it
uh-huh exactly
is the filtering distribution all right so this distribution is known as the
so this distribution is known as the filtering distribution okay
filtering distribution okay we discuss about the smoking
we discuss about the smoking distribution I think I'm going to come
distribution I think I'm going to come back to it so in the in this morning
back to it so in the in this morning distribution is basically the estimation
distribution is basically the estimation of ZT but instead of using data up to
of ZT but instead of using data up to time T you have all the data up to the
time T you have all the data up to the end
end capital T okay so this is the filtering
capital T okay so this is the filtering distribution and of course this is the
distribution and of course this is the prediction distribution where you don't
prediction distribution where you don't really care about Z by making a lots of
really care about Z by making a lots of promise but you want to know what's the
promise but you want to know what's the probability of your next measurement if
probability of your next measurement if you already have data up to time T right
you already have data up to time T right so there's all the points we did for hmm
so there's all the points we did for hmm are basically the same problems in any
are basically the same problems in any data stimulation case okay if it is hmm
data stimulation case okay if it is hmm masters time or anything else the same
masters time or anything else the same sort of problems with power printers
sort of problems with power printers okay the most standard problem all right
okay the most standard problem all right and maybe any students from Electrical
and maybe any students from Electrical Engineering maybe you guys have taking
Engineering maybe you guys have taking the cost on linear filtering or
the cost on linear filtering or something is there any quote from linear
something is there any quote from linear systems there is something common
systems there is something common filtering is anybody teaching us alright
filtering is anybody teaching us alright so so when you spend very little time to
so so when you spend very little time to discuss this of this today the good news
discuss this of this today the good news right is the previous equations that are
right is the previous equations that are implied by the color filtering for
implied by the color filtering for linear systems you can actually derive
linear systems you can actually derive them with belief propagation and in the
them with belief propagation and in the case of belief propagation you can
case of belief propagation you can derive all the equations for all the
derive all the equations for all the filtering both in distributions
filtering both in distributions everything you're interested even if the
everything you're interested even if the dynamics are nonlinear even if you
dynamics are nonlinear even if you observation model is non Gaussian so you
observation model is non Gaussian so you can do anything you want to okay but
can do anything you want to okay but today we're going to be very elementary
today we're going to be very elementary with a little bit of course a
with a little bit of course a probabilistic graphical taste to discuss
probabilistic graphical taste to discuss a linear Gaussian model now it's linear
a linear Gaussian model now it's linear you notice the evolution of the dynamics
you notice the evolution of the dynamics is the unit of this matrix a and B
is the unit of this matrix a and B they're functions of time that they
they're functions of time that they don't depend on the state C we will
don't depend on the state C we will actually discuss this after Spring Break
actually discuss this after Spring Break on how we're going to extend this 1
on how we're going to extend this 1 billion be a function of Z the
billion be a function of Z the observation model again it's linear and
observation model again it's linear and the noise is Gaussian you can ask you
the noise is Gaussian you can ask you meant right on if you can just looking
meant right on if you can just looking at this equation if the noise but lives
at this equation if the noise but lives this is Gaussian then we're all good
this is Gaussian then we're all good chances all distributions of interest
chances all distributions of interest will be Gaussian all right now if you
will be Gaussian all right now if you can assume that and actually forced a
can assume that and actually forced a methodology to give you the mean and the
methodology to give you the mean and the variance or the different distributions
variance or the different distributions and say oh that's the filtering
and say oh that's the filtering distribution that's the smoothing
distribution that's the smoothing distribution but it would be nicer if
distribution but it would be nicer if you actually you know do some algebra to
you actually you know do some algebra to show that the distributions of interest
show that the distributions of interest are gouging now in some formulas these
are gouging now in some formulas these matrices don't have a subscript T which
matrices don't have a subscript T which means the don't depend on the index P or
means the don't depend on the index P or tying the tray so in this case this V a
tying the tray so in this case this V a Gaussian model is especially our problem
Gaussian model is especially our problem right
sanitation maybe I need to have this expression in the slides when we hide
expression in the slides when we hide distributions and if we serve today in
distributions and if we serve today in the lecture everything is going to be
the lecture everything is going to be Gaussian
Gaussian when can I use to describe means and
when can I use to describe means and variances to subscribe
variances to subscribe the first one will refer to what time we
the first one will refer to what time we do the estimation of the state so in
do the estimation of the state so in this case you know this is time T and
this case you know this is time T and the central index will refer to the time
the central index will refer to the time scale where we have data so in this case
scale where we have data so in this case is from time 1 to T
is from time 1 to T all right so for example if this little
all right so for example if this little P was a capital T that will be the
P was a capital T that will be the smoking distribution you see it all
smoking distribution you see it all right so the notation the indices here
right so the notation the indices here are very important if the indices
are very important if the indices changed with values for this mu and
changed with values for this mu and Sigma are completely different
Sigma are completely different again the first T is the estimation time
again the first T is the estimation time we have to make here the fear of City
we have to make here the fear of City the second T is the time that after
the second T is the time that after which we have collection of data in this
which we have collection of data in this case want to community okay so obviously
case want to community okay so obviously for this linear system the the problem
for this linear system the the problem is known as the Kalman filtering problem
is known as the Kalman filtering problem but is that so secondary importance to
but is that so secondary importance to to our lecture today
to our lecture today so let's know some trivial examples I
so let's know some trivial examples I mean literally you can find books on the
mean literally you can find books on the subject you know and you
I don't know probabilistic robotics or something the whole subject area is
something the whole subject area is about this the same festival ok so this
about this the same festival ok so this is an example of object marking so let's
is an example of object marking so let's say you're tracking and a missile and
say you're tracking and a missile and you're interested on a state that is
you're interested on a state that is defined basically by the location of the
defined basically by the location of the missile
missile this is sort of a Miss I won't even a
this is sort of a Miss I won't even a plane another stupid problem in the
plane another stupid problem in the rotation here but Z 1 T and Z 2 T you
rotation here but Z 1 T and Z 2 T you can think being X my location and 0 1
can think being X my location and 0 1 and 0 to being the speeds in the x and y
and 0 to being the speeds in the x and y direction okay you are really
direction okay you are really interesting to compute all of this
interesting to compute all of this independently because you have to
independently because you have to calculate somehow let's say to the
calculate somehow let's say to the lastest and then you try to do
lastest and then you try to do integration on this you're not going to
integration on this you're not going to get very accurate results right because
get very accurate results right because then we are going to have to worry about
then we are going to have to worry about error of integration of differentiation
error of integration of differentiation depending what variables we take country
depending what variables we take country so kills these both the location and the
so kills these both the location and the speed of the object but what we need to
speed of the object but what we need to talk so the dynamical problem looks like
talk so the dynamical problem looks like this ok and I'm going to give you
this ok and I'm going to give you explicitly so you can convince
explicitly so you can convince yourselves that there's nothing really
yourselves that there's nothing really complicated so again 0 1 let's forget
complicated so again 0 1 let's forget that busy one is the explication the Y
that busy one is the explication the Y location so if you look at the the first
location so if you look at the the first equation this one
equation this one this Plus this knowledge it stays that
this Plus this knowledge it stays that the actual location is the X location of
the actual location is the X location of the previous time plus Delta which is
the previous time plus Delta which is the time step you can film of
the time step you can film of integration times the velocity of the
integration times the velocity of the previous time
previous time this is like an explicit time
this is like an explicit time integration scheme okay and then you
integration scheme okay and then you have some Gaussian noise and in the
have some Gaussian noise and in the context of the velocities you don't do
context of the velocities you don't do anything you say this velocity is the
anything you say this velocity is the previous velocity plus some notes okay
and the observations again it's a linear model like that so let's see exactly
model like that so let's see exactly what are the observations look like so
what are the observations look like so let's say you are observing the location
let's say you are observing the location of the missile so you basically want
of the missile so you basically want from this to Z vector to X plus Z 1 2
from this to Z vector to X plus Z 1 2 and Z 2 T so you basically have 1 1 and
and Z 2 T so you basically have 1 1 and the rest to 0 plus some noise okay a
the rest to 0 plus some noise okay a visit for that when I start that
visit for that when I start that everything is Gaussian right you have to
everything is Gaussian right you have to start with a distribution of the state
start with a distribution of the state also what is Gaussian because if I put
also what is Gaussian because if I put for the probability of G want to be
for the probability of G want to be somewhere distribution then good luck
somewhere distribution then good luck nothing is going to come to the Gaussian
nothing is going to come to the Gaussian ok so in this case P of Z 1 is Gaussian
ok so in this case P of Z 1 is Gaussian and again naught is the notation what
and again naught is the notation what this 1 0 means care in 1 0 winding is a
this 1 0 means care in 1 0 winding is a 0 there in this expression based on our
0 there in this expression based on our rotation
so left the pie - what's the previous this is what we start with
this is what we start with what's the prior was there the Buddhist
what's the prior was there the Buddhist okay all right so there's a zero there
okay all right so there's a zero there okay and if your same basically but you
okay and if your same basically but you don't really have any information for
don't really have any information for the location of the missile to start
the location of the missile to start with right before you collect any data
with right before you collect any data you can assume that this is sort of an
you can assume that this is sort of an infinite if you like volumes from
infinite if you like volumes from basically the Sun can be anywhere so
basically the Sun can be anywhere so just to give you some preview results
just to give you some preview results and again you may want to go actually
and again you may want to go actually this is a homework and you guys have to
this is a homework and you guys have to extract this and program it you may want
extract this and program it you may want to actually run this trivial examples
to actually run this trivial examples from math is toolbox we take exactly
from math is toolbox we take exactly five seconds to look at the program and
five seconds to look at the program and see five lines you can actually
see five lines you can actually implement the equations we will discuss
implement the equations we will discuss today so the problem is basically
today so the problem is basically figuring out the part of a mistrial we
figuring out the part of a mistrial we have some knowledge of salvations which
have some knowledge of salvations which are this green circles all right this is
are this green circles all right this is the true path so it's more or less you
the true path so it's more or less you know the straight path in for y equal to
know the straight path in for y equal to ten but you try to estimate this from
ten but you try to estimate this from this noisy measurement so this is this
this noisy measurement so this is this little process you see are basically the
little process you see are basically the results of this filtering distribution
results of this filtering distribution okay so it looks knology actually if you
okay so it looks knology actually if you look at you know it goes up and down
look at you know it goes up and down etcetera this is way more smooth there
etcetera this is way more smooth there so an obviously you notice when you
so an obviously you notice when you start because you don't have any data
start because you don't have any data you know you rely on the prior basically
you know you rely on the prior basically the first step you're a little bit away
the first step you're a little bit away from well this is what you supposed to
from well this is what you supposed to be but it picks up quite fast okay so
be but it picks up quite fast okay so this is the filtering distributions of
this is the filtering distributions of sq if you assume that the data come
sq if you assume that the data come one of the time you can update that stay
one of the time you can update that stay for the Messiah list and and this is
for the Messiah list and and this is with the cities this crosses there if he
with the cities this crosses there if he does more thing actually you get very
does more thing actually you get very nice results so this is assuming picture
nice results so this is assuming picture of the swapping you know and you can
of the swapping you know and you can there is no you know there's no
there is no you know there's no salacious basically the results they
salacious basically the results they look pretty good
look pretty good okay so that's you know what if we call
okay so that's you know what if we call this more think you are basically
this more think you are basically stabilizing the problem by using nope
stabilizing the problem by using nope any current data but Twitter
any current data but Twitter observationally as well so this is this
observationally as well so this is this is the smoking distribution so let me
is the smoking distribution so let me discuss about this robotic slump problem
discuss about this robotic slump problem it's a standard problem and there's a
it's a standard problem and there's a whole book actually on the subject area
whole book actually on the subject area for those interested again if I asked is
for those interested again if I asked is anybody doing any project from this I
anybody doing any project from this I know the answer is no so let me define
know the answer is no so let me define the project for you so I put these
the project for you so I put these things all up well actually let me use
things all up well actually let me use this picture I'm gonna go backwards okay
this picture I'm gonna go backwards okay so that is moving right it does whatever
so that is moving right it does whatever tasks you have assigned to do it but it
tasks you have assigned to do it but it tries to identify brought location is at
tries to identify brought location is at this time and we denote this location as
this time and we denote this location as X okay abigai ting you have to put some
X okay abigai ting you have to put some markings and say there's a role player
markings and say there's a role player Subic is that don't work roles you know
Subic is that don't work roles you know a little student very I mean you need to
a little student very I mean you need to get some like you see this marking time
get some like you see this marking time this capital else okay
this capital else okay so literally that's how this little
so literally that's how this little robots that captain last work right we
robots that captain last work right we provide some markets in in your yard and
provide some markets in in your yard and there are more basically learns what it
there are more basically learns what it is and where it needs to go
is and where it needs to go to navigate through the space so this
to navigate through the space so this mark this long modest capital L and one
mark this long modest capital L and one L till they're a fixed location okay and
L till they're a fixed location okay and you provide them so the robot is trying
you provide them so the robot is trying to us to make quality satisfied by
to us to make quality satisfied by measuring its distance from this fixed
measuring its distance from this fixed long box so basically this is where it
long box so basically this is where it is right when it's around makes this
is right when it's around makes this realm want me to get elected this so in
realm want me to get elected this so in this case for example a time one it's
this case for example a time one it's just love mark one and one mark let's
just love mark one and one mark let's say to all the time to which this from
say to all the time to which this from the M 2 and x 3 l1 etc okay so the
the M 2 and x 3 l1 etc okay so the location is estimated using those
location is estimated using those yourselves now
yourselves now the observations right y1 y2 are these
the observations right y1 y2 are these distances from the landmarks okay and
distances from the landmarks okay and notice on the trying mark here the
notice on the trying mark here the observations to indicate that this is
observations to indicate that this is evidence notice something that N 1 and L
evidence notice something that N 1 and L 2 are not conditionally independent
2 are not conditionally independent given the evidence can you see that so
given the evidence can you see that so even though the landmarks of fixed right
even though the landmarks of fixed right they are not conditionally independent
they are not conditionally independent given the evidence and can you
given the evidence and can you I mean it's taste they are gonna read
I mean it's taste they are gonna read the Easter let me cover it right let me
the Easter let me cover it right let me put my body here all right so why n 1
put my body here all right so why n 1 and M 2 are not what you can read it
and M 2 are not what you can read it there
there so I don't help very much yl1 and help
so I don't help very much yl1 and help you are not independent given the watch
you use the biggest ball algorithm and look at this probabilistic graphical
look at this probabilistic graphical model and tell me what makes l1 l2
model and tell me what makes l1 l2 dependent with the biggest ball angle
to do to prove conditional independence what is the biggest one tells you we
what is the biggest one tells you we need to do
take the ball and following some rules state there is a path connecting and 112
state there is a path connecting and 112 - so don't have a cop collecting l1 and
- so don't have a cop collecting l1 and l2 okay right snot blob there
with me the best the explained away situation right we have two causes all
situation right we have two causes all right that explain this all right so
right that explain this all right so actually given varus and 1 and X 1
independent okay so effectively the ball can go through
so effectively the ball can go through here can go through there can reach
here can go through there can reach there so this makes this problem study
there so this makes this problem study more complicated so given why these
more complicated so given why these elves are not conditional independent
elves are not conditional independent actually and when I'm gonna do this
actually and when I'm gonna do this unless someone decides or it has
unless someone decides or it has submitted a project from this an Isis
submitted a project from this an Isis ability to actually handle this and use
ability to actually handle this and use linear Gaussian systems is to write the
linear Gaussian systems is to write the probability of the prestigious let's say
probability of the prestigious let's say hotel not only given Y but assuming that
hotel not only given Y but assuming that you given you are given X as well so
you given you are given X as well so then they become independent then you
then they become independent then you can use ideas from carbon filtering and
can use ideas from carbon filtering and sort of part of filter methods to come
sort of part of filter methods to come up with a very easy solution of this
up with a very easy solution of this okay I mean this is a little bit like a
okay I mean this is a little bit like a trivial problem right to handle but in
trivial problem right to handle but in the context of robotics but work on
the context of robotics but work on warehouses amazon.com you know where
warehouses amazon.com you know where they take books themselves here and find
they take books themselves here and find the next book and they navigate not
the next book and they navigate not hitting each other you know this is
hitting each other you know this is basically a trivial what implemented
basically a trivial what implemented maybe 10-15 years ago and those who did
maybe 10-15 years ago and those who did implement those became very rich okay
implement those became very rich okay and that includes want of my very young
and that includes want of my very young colleagues a few years ago to solve
colleagues a few years ago to solve basically his one-man company to observe
basically his one-man company to observe okay so you can these are very simple
okay so you can these are very simple algorithms but simple thing to pay
algorithms but simple thing to pay complicated things that don't pay
complicated things that don't pay because they're complicated and
because they're complicated and right alright so the observation model
right alright so the observation model right is the probability of Y given Z
right is the probability of Y given Z right so this motion model is the
right so this motion model is the probability of X this two dynamics okay
probability of X this two dynamics okay and so this is basically this filtering
and so this is basically this filtering distribution together with the other
distribution together with the other bars because this is a two dimensional
bars because this is a two dimensional problem right you get and and the you
problem right you get and and the you know the spilling distribution is a
know the spilling distribution is a Gaussian so basically you can draw an
Gaussian so basically you can draw an ellipse
ellipse all right around the mean of this
all right around the mean of this filtering distribution and you notice so
filtering distribution and you notice so you start from one location for you know
you start from one location for you know where you are and then the uncertainty
where you are and then the uncertainty actually grows but then as you come
actually grows but then as you come closer to something that we have seen
closer to something that we have seen before the uncertainties reduced
before the uncertainties reduced now if you don't even approach on the
now if you don't even approach on the same power because you are ready you not
same power because you are ready you not have collected a lot of data this is the
have collected a lot of data this is the smoothing problem this smoothing
smoothing problem this smoothing uncertainties will become very small all
uncertainties will become very small all right all the way back to the initial
right all the way back to the initial stage the implementation residual it was
stage the implementation residual it was literally ten large
literally ten large okay ten right
now let me just say a computation right because this sort of introduces the
because this sort of introduces the ideas also of dynamic graphical models
ideas also of dynamic graphical models that I dont we will discuss before the
that I dont we will discuss before the end of the semester but so what
end of the semester but so what so let me go back to this picture okay
so let me go back to this picture okay so you are measuring Y right and we try
so you are measuring Y right and we try to estimate this and the location
to estimate this and the location basically X we are basically at every
basically X we are basically at every instant so Ellen X is your state see
instant so Ellen X is your state see here the two things together is a thing
here the two things together is a thing Z and you try the stratum given Y all
Z and you try the stratum given Y all right let some locations you know what
right let some locations you know what there is you know can you tell me how
there is you know can you tell me how this diagram is going to involve with
this diagram is going to involve with time sorry what do you thing is is going
time sorry what do you thing is is going to happen but you see L 1 and L 2 so
to happen but you see L 1 and L 2 so your inference will involve L 1 and L 2
your inference will involve L 1 and L 2 then if you have some class the only
then if you have some class the only thing that you see is L to show your
thing that you see is L to show your state will involve only and 2 down there
state will involve only and 2 down there it will involve and 1 you know etc etc
it will involve and 1 you know etc etc so what happens is you move what happens
so what happens is you move what happens to so if you think that you a big
to so if you think that you a big correlation matrix that connects all
correlation matrix that connects all your elves and your axis what can you
your elves and your axis what can you tell me about that correlation matrix as
tell me about that correlation matrix as given to anything in time is it short of
given to anything in time is it short of everything correlates with everything or
everything correlates with everything or something happens as you move in I mean
something happens as you move in I mean you notice here again PI 1 and 1 and L 2
you notice here again PI 1 and 1 and L 2 are there time to and to here then L 1
are there time to and to here then L 1 so what can you tell me about the
so what can you tell me about the correlations that you have between the
correlations that you have between the tray the outs and the axis or even the
tray the outs and the axis or even the URLs themselves as you move with
URLs themselves as you move with are they changing
you remember that makes a little late it is the observations that you make well
is the observations that you make well sure you observe some pain that connects
sure you observe some pain that connects to the odd marks right so the
to the odd marks right so the correlation is very high you don't see a
correlation is very high you don't see a lot of life there is no correlation
lot of life there is no correlation whatsoever so you can think of the
whatsoever so you can think of the dynamical biscuit that represents what
dynamical biscuit that represents what you see here where the strength of the
you see here where the strength of the correlations moves with the girls
correlations moves with the girls so it's time some things that they were
so it's time some things that they were highly correlated become uncorrelated
highly correlated become uncorrelated writing they're basically significant
writing they're basically significant okay so so this basically falls in the
okay so so this basically falls in the category of a system that is it doesn't
category of a system that is it doesn't in with time so graph that is evolving
in with time so graph that is evolving with tiring so if you want to read more
with tiring so if you want to read more about this I recommend basically to read
about this I recommend basically to read this book on probabilistic slump so
this book on probabilistic slump so there is a reference on codeine in the
there is a reference on codeine in the north of this crisis card on this topic
and so you can see you know this is sort of a snapshot of the correlation matrix
of a snapshot of the correlation matrix that you get for the printing
that you get for the printing distribution you can see there's lots of
distribution you can see there's lots of zeroes there all right
zeroes there all right sixteen is parts so whatever happens
sixteen is parts so whatever happens with lament mister calculus part sitting
with lament mister calculus part sitting on the correlation matrix right
and obviously the people who became rich with this concept that actually that's
with this concept that actually that's the book I was referring to let me go
the book I was referring to let me go back alright so this is the book for
back alright so this is the book for those interested you actually download
those interested you actually download the whole PDF of redirected from the
the whole PDF of redirected from the author's website okay
author's website okay all right so let me convince you before
all right so let me convince you before we discuss anything in determining what
we discuss anything in determining what a state-space models are simple very
a state-space models are simple very powerful and you should make use of them
powerful and you should make use of them even if there is nothing that has
even if there is nothing that has anything to do with dynamics and
anything to do with dynamics and evolutions of faith and knowledge
evolutions of faith and knowledge observationally new business so let's
observationally new business so let's consider a Bayesian inference problem
consider a Bayesian inference problem well it doesn't matter what it is but
well it doesn't matter what it is but you try this made given some date of the
you try this made given some date of the posterior of some parameter theta in
posterior of some parameter theta in your motive okay can be anything okay
your motive okay can be anything okay there's no dance mixture okay so some is
there's no dance mixture okay so some is the wave you didn't base and things
the wave you didn't base and things you're going to put some prior bordeaux
you're going to put some prior bordeaux right so here's my prior and of course
right so here's my prior and of course we have some reservations and we're
we have some reservations and we're going to fly somehow to address this
going to fly somehow to address this problem with state space sort of
problem with state space sort of thinking now to do a state space
thinking now to do a state space thinking you have to pretend that there
thinking you have to pretend that there is dynamics of the problem and serve an
is dynamics of the problem and serve an address I am going to pretend that the
address I am going to pretend that the engagement is a dynamical evolution of
engagement is a dynamical evolution of the parameters theta so I'm going to
the parameters theta so I'm going to make theta to have a subscript P even
make theta to have a subscript P even though it is not me but you know I'm
though it is not me but you know I'm going to take this sort of as a an
going to take this sort of as a an iterative process in some index p and
iterative process in some index p and the dynamical problem is going to look
the dynamical problem is going to look like that the probability of P that be
like that the probability of P that be given to the t minus one is really that
given to the t minus one is really that the fraction of size P that this should
the fraction of size P that this should never change does not is how reasonable
never change does not is how reasonable to give right I mean if you have to do a
to give right I mean if you have to do a Bayesian inference and want us to make
Bayesian inference and want us to make parameters theta I mean you can't waste
parameters theta I mean you can't waste the time and assume that this term
the time and assume that this term dynamical problem for the parameters
dynamical problem for the parameters never change right so nobody killed it's
never change right so nobody killed it's like you're on again
like you're on again you may say I'm wasting my time
you may say I'm wasting my time let's see what a waste of time if it
let's see what a waste of time if it pays off
pays off okay now in I'm going to show you now
okay now in I'm going to show you now right if you take the Sigma zero to be
right if you take the Sigma zero to be infinity the estimation for the
infinity the estimation for the parameter test here all right I'm not
parameter test here all right I'm not going to calculate the full posterior
going to calculate the full posterior we're going to get the point estimate of
we're going to get the point estimate of the parameters theta but if this Sigma 0
the parameters theta but if this Sigma 0 is basically infinity but wealth
is basically infinity but wealth provided metrics exactly we're going to
provided metrics exactly we're going to get a maximum likelihood estimate from
get a maximum likelihood estimate from this approach okay
this approach okay otherwise we're going to go directly and
otherwise we're going to go directly and get the solution to the linear system of
get the solution to the linear system of equations right so I'm giving you this
equations right so I'm giving you this sort of it as a demonstration of what is
sort of it as a demonstration of what is coming so when I tell your lots of
coming so when I tell your lots of questions crap you have to believe me
questions crap you have to believe me this is what's gonna come in okay so
this is what's gonna come in okay so we're going to cover today in the
we're going to cover today in the lecture the exact time of filtering
lecture the exact time of filtering equations of how we computed the
equations of how we computed the filtering distribution so the postilion
filtering distribution so the postilion of Z given data from 1 to T the feeding
of Z given data from 1 to T the feeding distribution etc but I won't question
distribution etc but I won't question that I know somehow those equations and
that I know somehow those equations and I want to know what are they gonna do
I want to know what are they gonna do for me on this Bayesian inference
for me on this Bayesian inference problem in updating the parameters theta
problem in updating the parameters theta and XI some magic comes out of it so the
and XI some magic comes out of it so the linear observation model was that YT is
linear observation model was that YT is equal to CT x ZT plus there was no you
equal to CT x ZT plus there was no you here plus some Gaussian noise with this
here plus some Gaussian noise with this barrier you remember there was a
barrier you remember there was a symmetry okay so all right so so this is
symmetry okay so all right so so this is observational basically right so the
observational basically right so the observation order
observation order is a Gaussian okay and because this
is a Gaussian okay and because this noise is Gaussian the male is st. times
noise is Gaussian the male is st. times Z alright C times C and the variance is
Z alright C times C and the variance is Sigma square and so to see what I'm
Sigma square and so to see what I'm trying to do okay very specific case but
trying to do okay very specific case but actually can be very generous ya think
actually can be very generous ya think that somehow some parameters in the
that somehow some parameters in the regression model okay
and then you want sort of to compute the parameters in some linear regression
parameters in some linear regression problems that will allow you to compute
problems that will allow you to compute Y for any X so we can do any specific
Y for any X so we can do any specific okay think so if you want to compute the
okay think so if you want to compute the the observation model will depend on
the observation model will depend on what the input is and so the C matrix
what the input is and so the C matrix that I take here is X transpose all
that I take here is X transpose all right so X 2 is Pacific you know what it
right so X 2 is Pacific you know what it reminds you think of the regression
reminds you think of the regression model that is basically you know people
model that is basically you know people transpose x y4 v transpose X usually
transpose x y4 v transpose X usually when you write regression models you
when you write regression models you think of y equal W transpose X plus some
think of y equal W transpose X plus some noise so my darling is typically the
point is here right but why in the linear version in the linear system
linear version in the linear system model is three times Z plus a Gaussian
model is three times Z plus a Gaussian noise alright so I am taking Z this this
noise alright so I am taking Z this this way and now taking a state to the
way and now taking a state to the departmental stripped out but they make
departmental stripped out but they make them demonic this is what about
my symmetric system X - Parris is my eight my expression is to say because
eight my expression is to say because I'm going shopping as melody okay okay
I'm going shopping as melody okay okay in the linear regression model in verse
in the linear regression model in verse 4 let's say when the input is Malta it's
4 let's say when the input is Malta it's not one bit about the dimensional
not one bit about the dimensional problems right the external sports times
problems right the external sports times theta plus noise Sigma square so this is
theta plus noise Sigma square so this is my observation model basically okay so
my observation model basically okay so if I know the input the response depends
if I know the input the response depends on the state and the state is Theta I am
on the state and the state is Theta I am going to pretending now that the problem
going to pretending now that the problem is dynamic all right and this tucupi has
is dynamic all right and this tucupi has evolved dynamics somebody can write down
the distribution the distribution which is analytically know and we will derive
is analytically know and we will derive it today so it comes to be basically the
it today so it comes to be basically the meaning at the previous time remember
meaning at the previous time remember time here is dummy
time here is dummy alright times L transpose what is a
alright times L transpose what is a prosperous my problem
remember she comes into the mission of the dynamical problem X equal a times Z
the dynamical problem X equal a times Z P miles wrong but when the mental
P miles wrong but when the mental problem is the mental function alright
problem is the mental function alright so here basically like an identity okay
so here basically like an identity okay so new T times so if I know the main at
so new T times so if I know the main at the previous time and I know this matrix
the previous time and I know this matrix to disk all the time and gain matrix
to disk all the time and gain matrix that we will derive gonna wanna give me
that we will derive gonna wanna give me an exact expression truthfully I can
an exact expression truthfully I can write the updated mean with this
write the updated mean with this expression expression okay so Sigma P is
expression expression okay so Sigma P is what so in so in the filtering
what so in so in the filtering distribution here that the share rights
distribution here that the share rights of Sigma T will be the covariance matrix
of Sigma T will be the covariance matrix okay will be the cabarrus projection I
okay will be the cabarrus projection I am NOT listing what it is alright
am NOT listing what it is alright actually because I realized I would
actually because I realized I would forgotten index so this should be Sigma
forgotten index so this should be Sigma T given they have to pee okay another
T given they have to pee okay another explicitly because doesn't really matter
explicitly because doesn't really matter what it is so I am going to take this
what it is so I am going to take this equation that we derived today and I'm
equation that we derived today and I'm gonna write it for the update of the
gonna write it for the update of the unknown parameters and this is the form
unknown parameters and this is the form that it takes and I want it to be you
that it takes and I want it to be you know twenty details over the symbols
know twenty details over the symbols there but on the functional form of this
there but on the functional form of this equation tells me everything that
equation tells me everything that somehow you remind it right this
somehow you remind it right this actually when I look at least in the
actually when I look at least in the functional integration problem what is
functional integration problem what is not see the military we have training
not see the military we have training the problem with my table to find the -
the problem with my table to find the - Ron so I decided to build up to two
Ron so I decided to build up to two minus one and I did you know
minus one and I did you know hierarchical if you like every time I
okay default right this is sort of a standard term when you do supervisor not
standard term when you do supervisor not supervise to everything one data point
supervise to everything one data point at the time
at the time it's the drives so this here use the
it's the drives so this here use the previous form a disturbed a thing times
previous form a disturbed a thing times the error that you do other things
the error that you do other things okay now business okay I do know this
okay now business okay I do know this comes in in every quality machine
comes in in every quality machine learning what else what are the
learning what else what are the buzzwords this thing reminds you online
buzzwords this thing reminds you online landing that you should know up and down
landing that you should know up and down because this sort of the standard update
because this sort of the standard update formula any names
most probably it never came in the lecture in this course but in the fall
lecture in this course but in the fall and any other machine learning course
and any other machine learning course feedback maybe not what is this equation
feedback maybe not what is this equation looking like does it remind you anything
looking like does it remind you anything at all in the context of anything else
at all in the context of anything else come on mr. Nick what is the reminding
come on mr. Nick what is the reminding you this
and and now
you mean on an end maybe out of them you know wow that's a miracle of nature
yes
you're not implying their organs for no I'll do it
I'll do it yes all right all right thank you
yes all right all right thank you they're not bees going around good okay
they're not bees going around good okay but I'm also surprised that you are
but I'm also surprised that you are thinking of the Robbins Baraka very cool
thinking of the Robbins Baraka very cool and you don't think update or parameters
and you don't think update or parameters that say you have networks or equal else
that say you have networks or equal else has this forward anything anyone
has this forward anything anyone algorithm is exactly this for okay
algorithm is exactly this for okay the point here is right when you do this
the point here is right when you do this integration you one pilots a point just
integration you one pilots a point just another parameter you take all the data
another parameter you take all the data you show the Miss quested seven say
you show the Miss quested seven say that's my MA past with et cetera here
that's my MA past with et cetera here will be due by making this problem as
will be due by making this problem as dynamical we compute this online one day
dynamical we compute this online one day the point of the time okay and and we
the point of the time okay and and we start with some parameters and they may
start with some parameters and they may have made them based on this error okay
have made them based on this error okay now usually what you do online learning
now usually what you do online learning with problems for algorithm or you know
with problems for algorithm or you know any sort of idea of course to have to
any sort of idea of course to have to grade in this channel usually what you
grade in this channel usually what you have here is some question that is the
have here is some question that is the learning rate for your problem and
learning rate for your problem and usually because of learning later sort
usually because of learning later sort of arbitrarily you have to go three
of arbitrarily you have to go three times two hundred a distress together
times two hundred a distress together mr. Contreras okay now it happens
mr. Contreras okay now it happens because here this comes to be exact
because here this comes to be exact if you destroy the data you get actually
if you destroy the data you get actually the exact estimate
the exact estimate for dinner for this problem okay
paternity but is precise sure if you put the question Croatian for Sigma and
the question Croatian for Sigma and Sigma square and you go through another
Sigma square and you go through another dataset once then you will converge to
dataset once then you will converge to the exact answer the depending on what
the exact answer the depending on what you use for prior it would be either
you use for prior it would be either your Emily or your map estimate so the
your Emily or your map estimate so the point here is right you need to imagine
point here is right you need to imagine three and if you imagine that somehow
three and if you imagine that somehow you can transpose something to a dynamic
you can transpose something to a dynamic problem you get interesting algorithms
problem you get interesting algorithms you get an online learning
you get an online learning my destination or Emily estimation that
my destination or Emily estimation that vision back sort of to stand up ideas of
vision back sort of to stand up ideas of machine learning for the error drives
machine learning for the error drives the updates in the parameters now so
the updates in the parameters now so that so this is what I was saying
that so this is what I was saying basically before I put the few stops to
basically before I put the few stops to do this with some generic rate that you
do this with some generic rate that you sort of first select with practical
sort of first select with practical training you know justified different
training you know justified different values this is what is called the list
values this is what is called the list mean squares algorithm all right so this
mean squares algorithm all right so this you have to iterate one should last of
you have to iterate one should last of the data sets to make it to convert the
the data sets to make it to convert the algorithm that I just discussed it's
algorithm that I just discussed it's called the recursively squares algorithm
called the recursively squares algorithm basically converges to the exact
basically converges to the exact solution once you go through all the
solution once you go through all the data so this is an interesting thing and
data so this is an interesting thing and by the way if you surf the little
by the way if you surf the little children and again because these are the
children and again because these are the easy problems so for this lazy problems
easy problems so for this lazy problems you can use these ideas to do some very
you can use these ideas to do some very interesting things even you know as I
interesting things even you know as I said you can even take deterministic of
said you can even take deterministic of the east and somehow prescribe the
the east and somehow prescribe the problem to dynamical problems and use
problem to dynamical problems and use this ideas to the time integration you
this ideas to the time integration you can do whatever you want okay so and
can do whatever you want okay so and again this progress will be derive today
again this progress will be derive today there are analytical for the general
there are analytical for the general Gaussian linear dynamical system we
Gaussian linear dynamical system we don't need this okay so this is
don't need this okay so this is basically the desktop folder let's
basically the desktop folder let's actually have a linear regression in one
actually have a linear regression in one dimension right so this is your
dimension right so this is your observation model alright
observation model alright the parameters theta basically w0 w1 and
the parameters theta basically w0 w1 and so this is Theta and the real thing that
so this is Theta and the real thing that we do is we assume that theta changes
we do is we assume that theta changes with time the time really is not x in
with time the time really is not x in iteration saddam index to allow us to
iteration saddam index to allow us to come up with a nice recursive discourse
come up with a nice recursive discourse algorithm ok very nice idea and again
algorithm ok very nice idea and again you want to implement this the club's
you want to implement this the club's really where it's thin lines right you
really where it's thin lines right you can look at it alright and and play with
can look at it alright and and play with it as well okay so let me before we go
it as well okay so let me before we go to become a filter can give you some
to become a filter can give you some other things that somehow they don't
other things that somehow they don't look like state-space models so for
look like state-space models so for example if you type in the predictions
example if you type in the predictions from the stock price is right so you
from the stock price is right so you follow that particular step you know
follow that particular step you know that what the value on Wall Street was
that what the value on Wall Street was every day and you want to do the
every day and you want to do the prediction what the price may be
prediction what the price may be tomorrow based on historical data right
tomorrow based on historical data right so you want to find let's say that Y at
so you want to find let's say that Y at P plus one if you know the date of time
P plus one if you know the date of time one and P so in this case there's no Z
one and P so in this case there's no Z there's no relevant variable so even if
there's no relevant variable so even if you don't have latent variables you can
you don't have latent variables you can assume that somehow that they come
assume that somehow that they come generated by some stories change the
generated by some stories change the variables right but capture the dynamics
variables right but capture the dynamics of the problem but capture this this you
of the problem but capture this this you know the represent accurately this
know the represent accurately this revolution of the observe a shoe that
revolution of the observe a shoe that you have but since you don't care about
you have but since you don't care about resist is not a big deal because at the
resist is not a big deal because at the end of the day since this models come to
end of the day since this models come to the GAO severe models you can integrate
the GAO severe models you can integrate Z out completely so this can lead to
Z out completely so this can lead to famously there so Z is used because it
famously there so Z is used because it can give this sort of community
can give this sort of community relations in my wires right that there
relations in my wires right that there long or short-range as I desire right
long or short-range as I desire right but since I'm only interesting why I
but since I'm only interesting why I think just where to make this prediction
think just where to make this prediction to predict this I can integrate wise
to predict this I can integrate wise this out so years you may not even exist
this out so years you may not even exist but in traditional in your model may
but in traditional in your model may assist you actually to get this
assist you actually to get this distribution alright so don't have
distribution alright so don't have something that says well but I have any
something that says well but I have any latent variables not something you to
latent variables not something you to make them late environments because how
make them late environments because how you represent the dynamics in a good way
you represent the dynamics in a good way to represent the dynamics you system is
to represent the dynamics you system is with one or two or multiple chains of
with one or two or multiple chains of latent variables so consider that to be
latent variables so consider that to be an approach so let me give you some
an approach so let me give you some simple models so so the observation
simple models so so the observation models is this local level available to
models is this local level available to sit here and what you do is introduce
sit here and what you do is introduce some dynamics on this local level okay
some dynamics on this local level okay so Y is equal 80 plus some Gaussian
so Y is equal 80 plus some Gaussian noise an eighty eighty minus one person
noise an eighty eighty minus one person of the Gaussian noise okay so the
of the Gaussian noise okay so the probability graphical model for this is
probability graphical model for this is basically Y depends only on eighty but
basically Y depends only on eighty but you're saying some dynamics from eighty
you're saying some dynamics from eighty that in this case they are Markovian so
that in this case they are Markovian so eighty depends only on 80 minus one okay
eighty depends only on 80 minus one okay so if you can actually what interesting
so if you can actually what interesting data you can generate with this right
data you can generate with this right and why beside this are very powerful
and why beside this are very powerful when you play with with data so from
when you play with with data so from this level model that you see here you
this level model that you see here you can actually try completely different
can actually try completely different scenarios you can have a system where as
scenarios you can have a system where as noisy observations but as deterministic
noisy observations but as deterministic dynamics you can take a system where as
dynamics you can take a system where as noisy dynamics but the domestic
noisy dynamics but the domestic observations and then you can make
observations and then you can make everything noisy and you can speak out
everything noisy and you can speak out by playing a little bit with the
by playing a little bit with the parameters the results can be live day
parameters the results can be live day and night
and night okay if you can write I mean you can
okay if you can write I mean you can this code again is a few lines to do
this code again is a few lines to do this predictions so this is you know
this predictions so this is you know something that you will use in
something that you will use in econometrics
econometrics you know predicting earthquakes so I can
you know predicting earthquakes so I can sound like civil engineer right and
sound like civil engineer right and things like that
things like that now during the wind speed right now must
now during the wind speed right now must be relevant as well okay all right
be relevant as well okay all right and so canister sort of any bit more
and so canister sort of any bit more complicated graphical mode them who are
complicated graphical mode them who are the observations why depend on this
the observations why depend on this local level a but this local level a
local level a but this local level a depends on the B that has its own
depends on the B that has its own dynamics okay and if you do actually
dynamics okay and if you do actually exist you can control even the sphere if
exist you can control even the sphere if you like in in your observations so for
you like in in your observations so for example if you if you take think of this
example if you if you take think of this model as it is now right and take that
model as it is now right and take that this no bumping dynamics here so BT
this no bumping dynamics here so BT minus 1 equal to BT so every time you
minus 1 equal to BT so every time you calculate they take you getting
calculate they take you getting accustomed amount of me
accustomed amount of me Chalmers you have be attempted to be
Chalmers you have be attempted to be before big so this B is going to come to
before big so this B is going to come to be is part of the train if you have in
be is part of the train if you have in the evolution of the observations so we
the evolution of the observations so we have sort of some linear trend plus
have sort of some linear trend plus noise around it okay so this can allows
noise around it okay so this can allows you to very easily to actually more than
you to very easily to actually more than you know where the behaviors you like of
you know where the behaviors you like of dynamical data and you see here the gang
dynamical data and you see here the gang the three cases where you play as to
the three cases where you play as to what is the deterministic noise obscures
what is the deterministic noise obscures observations the system or more okay all
observations the system or more okay all right so let me I'm going to finish
right so let me I'm going to finish because this is the most important
because this is the most important problem that in the context of
problem that in the context of statistical machine learning modeling
statistical machine learning modeling but also it comes a require in physics
but also it comes a require in physics this is what's called the album of them
this is what's called the album of them the auto regressive autoregressive
the auto regressive autoregressive moving average model you may have seen
moving average model you may have seen it in different contexts so the
it in different contexts so the excellent thing okay there's not here
excellent thing okay there's not here observations on Z right I'm just writing
observations on Z right I'm just writing this model like that and it's happy
this model like that and it's happy to interpret it as to what is the state
to interpret it as to what is the state what you observe and things like that so
what you observe and things like that so actually here depends on this P previous
actually here depends on this P previous values of X T XT minus 1 to X 3 minus P
values of X T XT minus 1 to X 3 minus P but also depends on this parameters W
but also depends on this parameters W but you can tell them as T the very most
but you can tell them as T the very most so from 1 to Q and the question this
so from 1 to Q and the question this think you can model this modeling
think you can model this modeling because you try to shape it can tell how
because you try to shape it can tell how the exes correlate you know in firing
the exes correlate you know in firing the tree we have short life correlations
the tree we have short life correlations you know we have long term correlations
you know we have long term correlations we have mode and so this all about
we have mode and so this all about the shorter regressive moving average
the shorter regressive moving average model allows you to do that so for
model allows you to do that so for example I'm taking the case here when T
example I'm taking the case here when T is equal to 0 so this term is not there
is equal to 0 so this term is not there and take a proven case should be equal
and take a proven case should be equal to 1 immediately you can see that this
to 1 immediately you can see that this is the population model one so for
is the population model one so for treatment one is your first municipal
treatment one is your first municipal chain right so one of the things we
chain right so one of the things we learned about Markov chains few weeks
learned about Markov chains few weeks ago basically you can model them to
ago basically you can model them to dissolve about you now if you take the P
dissolve about you now if you take the P to be equal to you know this time not to
to be equal to you know this time not to be there and you only have this Q
be there and you only have this Q they're basically the dependencies for Q
they're basically the dependencies for Q equal to 1
equal to 1 they look like that alright so somehow
they look like that alright so somehow now if you introduce collisions between
now if you introduce collisions between the axis because they come from the
the axis because they come from the spinal cord which 1xq depend on W 1 X 2
spinal cord which 1xq depend on W 1 X 2 X 3 for gamma D 2 so here we have
X 3 for gamma D 2 so here we have short-range correlations okay so and
short-range correlations okay so and again this is only for Q equal to 1 and
again this is only for Q equal to 1 and if you just critical to 1 and P 1 to 1
if you just critical to 1 and P 1 to 1 you can get the provide least graphical
you can get the provide least graphical models looks like this so it becomes
models looks like this so it becomes basically correlations in time that are
basically correlations in time that are both both
for example you can see here from my ex - depends on X 1 but then should you
- depends on X 1 but then should you know that this connection is between W
know that this connection is between W but you get extra sugar for natural
but you get extra sugar for natural correlation on on this model this is a
correlation on on this model this is a huge huge area for attempt if you if
huge huge area for attempt if you if your work has anything to do with
your work has anything to do with dynamic data then this is a subject area
dynamic data then this is a subject area on its own people do PhD theses actually
on its own people do PhD theses actually on this on this topic okay so don't
on this on this topic okay so don't consider central quad because this looks
consider central quad because this looks simple are only for a lecture all right
simple are only for a lecture all right simple things you know what it means
simple things you know what it means there are clickable everywhere and if
there are clickable everywhere and if there are people everywhere there are
there are people everywhere there are impact is enormous and everybody cares
impact is enormous and everybody cares about what you do okay if you have any
about what you do okay if you have any on the wings you know with engineering
on the wings you know with engineering then basically as they say as the strong
then basically as they say as the strong choice is going to the wind right ok so
choice is going to the wind right ok so here it is it's a little bit more
here it is it's a little bit more complicated than that
complicated than that ok so let's say we have 23 minutes so we
ok so let's say we have 23 minutes so we have about 20 minutes to you I will need
have about 20 minutes to you I will need to cover the Kalman filtering because
to cover the Kalman filtering because sort of a little part of the course but
sort of a little part of the course but you need basically to see the equation
you need basically to see the equation and then convince you in the next
and then convince you in the next lecture that you can actually get the
lecture that you can actually get the same equations with with you know
same equations with with you know master's passing in in gloves okay we
master's passing in in gloves okay we want to complete the filtering
want to complete the filtering distribution of Z T the posted of city
distribution of Z T the posted of city given by date of the time T and giving
given by date of the time T and giving this incubator here from entity ok so my
this incubator here from entity ok so my invitation that I'm going to use see
invitation that I'm going to use see there's no reason to put mu T plus T
there's no reason to put mu T plus T because everything is P so we have two
because everything is P so we have two subscripts that they are the same I am
subscripts that they are the same I am use
use basically this nuclear Sigma T I want
basically this nuclear Sigma T I want you to remember the notation because the
you to remember the notation because the questions when you may get a little bit
questions when you may get a little bit more complicated okay so remember the
more complicated okay so remember the notation we use what meaty and Sigma
notation we use what meaty and Sigma theories is for this filtering
theories is for this filtering distribution this procedure of simply
distribution this procedure of simply given my observations okay invents a
given my observations okay invents a bunch of very fundamental equations but
bunch of very fundamental equations but maybe you guys have loved chain the
maybe you guys have loved chain the fears are semester vampire of using this
fears are semester vampire of using this equations they thought that was news to
equations they thought that was news to them but this is the questions that have
them but this is the questions that have nothing Lewis statistics if you do
nothing Lewis statistics if you do machine learning this equations come
machine learning this equations come everywhere so there are those equations
everywhere so there are those equations for if you have an a Gaussian in effect
for if you have an a Gaussian in effect with this meaner variance and you have
with this meaner variance and you have another condition and a variance of Y
another condition and a variance of Y given X which is there's a mean that is
given X which is there's a mean that is linear in X right this is what we call a
linear in X right this is what we call a linear value model then you can actually
linear value model then you can actually use business rule to invert this and
use business rule to invert this and from the probability of Y given X and P
from the probability of Y given X and P of X you can get the probability of x
of X you can get the probability of x given Y and the purpose in Bishop is a
given Y and the purpose in Bishop is a nice blue you know and - first semester
nice blue you know and - first semester you can visit them in learning on their
you can visit them in learning on their first software or second there's miss
first software or second there's miss equations ok so if you want to compute
equations ok so if you want to compute from big defects given Y you basically
from big defects given Y you basically have to comb the journey from this to
have to comb the journey from this to okay and then from the joint basically
okay and then from the joint basically go back and find the posterior of x
go back and find the posterior of x given one okay so it comes to be like
given one okay so it comes to be like this alright so I'm going to move this
this alright so I'm going to move this equations about 10 times today a notion
equations about 10 times today a notion that if you can do mister if you
that if you can do mister if you multiply them and you form the joint
multiply them and you form the joint affection Y actually what you can do if
affection Y actually what you can do if you can integrate X out and basically
you can integrate X out and basically close
close and come up with their Gaussian
and come up with their Gaussian distribution describe B of Y 7,000 the
distribution describe B of Y 7,000 the tradition is actually given by this nice
tradition is actually given by this nice simple for group so when you piay with
simple for group so when you piay with dodgems look at the problem is a
dodgems look at the problem is a Gaussian lineal if you have something
Gaussian lineal if you have something that the mean is to their function
that the mean is to their function affection and the the distribution of X
affection and the the distribution of X is down shell then if you know
is down shell then if you know everything else this Gaussian and this
everything else this Gaussian and this time the formulas that can take you from
time the formulas that can take you from X from Y given X D X given Y and it can
X from Y given X D X given Y and it can take you from P of X to P of what all
take you from P of X to P of what all right so this progress I'm going to use
right so this progress I'm going to use this extensively and the next time
this extensively and the next time longer uses something if we have used it
longer uses something if we have used it the infinitely time chance declines in
the infinitely time chance declines in machine learning every time you have to
machine learning every time you have to invert big matrices you need to think if
invert big matrices you need to think if there is some sort of factorization or a
there is some sort of factorization or a way to rewrite the matricis in this form
way to rewrite the matricis in this form so you can use what's called the Woodman
so you can use what's called the Woodman edema or this metric Sebastian Lima okay
edema or this metric Sebastian Lima okay and I am NOT gonna go the details but
and I am NOT gonna go the details but here you notice this inverse matrix can
here you notice this inverse matrix can be written as like that so if it happens
be written as like that so if it happens the best B matrix if this matrix here is
the best B matrix if this matrix here is M by M where m is much less than this n
M by M where m is much less than this n by n matrix obviously this pays off
by n matrix obviously this pays off computationally and in lots of times you
computationally and in lots of times you don't see this result but if you try to
don't see this result but if you try to do it's a Gaussian processes you will
do it's a Gaussian processes you will immediately even if you don't use this
immediately even if you don't use this you'll be investing a million by million
you'll be investing a million by million matrices rather 100 by 100 okay so the
matrices rather 100 by 100 okay so the whole Ummah
whole Ummah it is always there so when it's
it is always there so when it's something like that it screams at you
something like that it screams at you and says you sleep okay matrix inversion
and says you sleep okay matrix inversion lemma okay to complete these filtering
lemma okay to complete these filtering distribution
distribution it's easy in a sense that we have to be
it's easy in a sense that we have to be exactly the same identical steps we did
exactly the same identical steps we did with it for the filter and distribution
with it for the filter and distribution for the hidden Markov model so you
for the hidden Markov model so you remember a hidden Markov model to get
remember a hidden Markov model to get the content distribution first things we
the content distribution first things we have to do is to get the one-step
have to do is to get the one-step percent prediction for Z all right so
percent prediction for Z all right so given back up to time t minus 1 all
given back up to time t minus 1 all right the first time
right the first time we will use the product we will compute
we will use the product we will compute the predicted distribution of Z T and
the predicted distribution of Z T and here notice but I know here's you from
here notice but I know here's you from one to three minus one because one of
one to three minus one because one of the prediction of the complexity I'm
the prediction of the complexity I'm going to use the input that I have which
going to use the input that I have which goes to want to t just given it's not
goes to want to t just given it's not the forcing term okay it's the next
the forcing term okay it's the next we're talking about using the odds of
we're talking about using the odds of catching time so we know if you
catching time so we know if you obviously we're going to use it so the
obviously we're going to use it so the derivation of you see here it's exactly
derivation of you see here it's exactly the same as for hidden Markov models
the same as for hidden Markov models effectively what has happen is you can
effectively what has happen is you can paint your plug in here is a 2-1 and
paint your plug in here is a 2-1 and then we integrate in ZT minus 1 and then
then we integrate in ZT minus 1 and then what you do is you use Vegas rule to
what you do is you use Vegas rule to write this as this probability times
write this as this probability times this probability and this is easy
this probability and this is easy because this Michele you know what the
because this Michele you know what the test this is not the right what is this
test this is not the right what is this distribution it's immersion defined by
distribution it's immersion defined by this rayon demon and what is this this
this rayon demon and what is this this is the probability of this type of t
is the probability of this type of t minus 1 given the date of the t minus 1
minus 1 given the date of the t minus 1 i actually don't make the youthful 1/2
i actually don't make the youthful 1/2 thing because i'm retired he of the t
thing because i'm retired he of the t minus 1 so this would be u 1 t minus 1
minus 1 so this would be u 1 t minus 1 really so and remember we said we're
really so and remember we said we're gonna guess we are going to denote the
gonna guess we are going to denote the mean and the variance with the subscript
mean and the variance with the subscript 1 subscript only so this are the mean
1 subscript only so this are the mean and the variance at time t minus 12 so
and the variance at time t minus 12 so recursively and we'll assume that I know
recursively and we'll assume that I know this distribution
this distribution and I'm going to try to get adventure
and I'm going to try to get adventure this is what we try to get right we try
this is what we try to get right we try to the first write this our notation so
to the first write this our notation so obviously of list would be at this
obviously of list would be at this distribution yes recursively question
distribution yes recursively question you know this and then we will complete
you know this and then we will complete this distribution and using this
this distribution and using this distribution we would try to find that
distribution we would try to find that the Philippine distribution city given
the Philippine distribution city given data from 150 as a second step the
data from 150 as a second step the equations don't mean anything unless you
equations don't mean anything unless you have a sense when they come and and how
have a sense when they come and and how you actually do the algebra so if you
you actually do the algebra so if you look at equations algebra it's an
look at equations algebra it's an important but it's important to know
important but it's important to know yeah I can do this because it reminds me
yeah I can do this because it reminds me this problem so look at this now we want
this problem so look at this now we want to integrate in three my ZT minus 1 of
to integrate in three my ZT minus 1 of something a distribution of CP that has
something a distribution of CP that has remained that is a linear function of z
remained that is a linear function of z t minus 1 last emergency p minus 1 and
t minus 1 last emergency p minus 1 and we need to dominate to complete the
we need to dominate to complete the management of the business within
management of the business within various state city does not remind a
various state city does not remind a formula does this is my very founder
formula does this is my very founder whatever the linear browser more than
whatever the linear browser more than invest is functional you know prior VFX
invest is functional you know prior VFX and we need to compute the modulo
right this princess just me you know now idiot leg day you know
idiot leg day you know this is Italian okay you can look
this is Italian okay you can look at the previous 12 us two slides ago and
at the previous 12 us two slides ago and you said you know rap business leaders
you said you know rap business leaders sure we have visit me I'm just popping
sure we have visit me I'm just popping the formulas chambers members based
the formulas chambers members based listening a metric Susanna there's a big
listening a metric Susanna there's a big layer of this me - wanna stick with it -
layer of this me - wanna stick with it - no so this is the answer and I of the
no so this is the answer and I of the variance here between this is to remind
variance here between this is to remind me the wristlet predictable time T but I
me the wristlet predictable time T but I only have date up to P minus one deliver
only have date up to P minus one deliver we don't here is between this is if what
we don't here is between this is if what times are the staying basically okay but
times are the staying basically okay but here this is the predictive distribution
here this is the predictive distribution having data t minus 12 and this is the
having data t minus 12 and this is the predict you'll time take again have been
predict you'll time take again have been nothing but copy the formulas for
nothing but copy the formulas for minions systems but I saw you before so
minions systems but I saw you before so this one step ahead prediction of Z T
this one step ahead prediction of Z T given my data BT minus 1 is a Gaussian
given my data BT minus 1 is a Gaussian with this mean of the variance
with this mean of the variance nicely so how do we compute now the
nicely so how do we compute now the probability how do we compute actually
probability how do we compute actually the filtering distribution which if I
the filtering distribution which if I have data from 1 to T how do i compute
have data from 1 to T how do i compute the posterior of CP this cable is rule
the posterior of CP this cable is rule ok so I split my evidence from 1 to t 2
ok so I split my evidence from 1 to t 2 evidence from 1 to t minus 1 and I put
evidence from 1 to t minus 1 and I put like this separately and then I like
like this separately and then I like this proportional that the you know the
this proportional that the you know the denominator is unimportant
denominator is unimportant I like this as Y P given C T so that's
I like this as Y P given C T so that's my observation love them and what
my observation love them and what distribution is this it's a garden that
distribution is this it's a garden that has a mean mu theta minus R and a
has a mean mu theta minus R and a variance Sigma T females for now I am
variance Sigma T females for now I am looking at
looking at them and without showing to their
them and without showing to their questions can you tell me if you can
questions can you tell me if you can actually compute analytically now this
actually compute analytically now this product and why based on this linear
product and why based on this linear guys are models in other ways if I go
guys are models in other ways if I go back to three slides can you tell me
back to three slides can you tell me what is their demeanor says yes I can do
what is their demeanor says yes I can do this so can you tell me what is this
this so can you tell me what is this distribution of light the given state
distribution of light the given state they give us some symbols I mean what is
they give us some symbols I mean what is very clear is a function of city from
very clear is a function of city from our browser linear model for a system of
our browser linear model for a system of the first line is the metrics say let's
the first line is the metrics say let's say 50 times the city plus B times u T
say 50 times the city plus B times u T which we don't care plus notice the
which we don't care plus notice the Guardian notes so this distribution is I
Guardian notes so this distribution is I mean we basically this may be here all
mean we basically this may be here all right is a Gaussian okay and we know
right is a Gaussian okay and we know exactly what the main work the variances
exactly what the main work the variances everything okay
everything okay kind of this this distribution can you
kind of this this distribution can you tell me what you know what can you tell
tell me what you know what can you tell me about this distribution
no it's good all right so there's miss the dish especially another Gulf Stream
the dish especially another Gulf Stream okay so let me just write them love okay
okay so let me just write them love okay so this we know this we computed on the
so this we know this we computed on the previous slide and so basically what you
previous slide and so basically what you have this if you have a custom solution
have this if you have a custom solution to this problem that is a little bit
to this problem that is a little bit complicated all right so I'm going to
complicated all right so I'm going to show you a quarter the algebra count
show you a quarter the algebra count okay and so this distribution has this
okay and so this distribution has this mean and this covariance matrix so the
mean and this covariance matrix so the mean is basically the mean of this
mean is basically the mean of this distribution all right because this
distribution all right because this metric scary but you will see explicit
metric scary but you will see explicit in a second time some residual are okay
in a second time some residual are okay and the Sigma T is the gain defined
and the Sigma T is the gain defined through this gain matrix K times this
through this gain matrix K times this matrix that comes here Sigma T 2 minus 1
so this matrix again you will see one fly this motivation by the way is not
fly this motivation by the way is not too severe
too severe all right this product okay it takes
all right this product okay it takes some algebra
some algebra ok you factor you have the product of
ok you factor you have the product of two bonds and so we're gonna have to see
two bonds and so we're gonna have to see how this calculation works some runner
how this calculation works some runner before I give you the reversal have to
before I give you the reversal have to give you all the symbols this current
give you all the symbols this current gain gain matrix is given basically by
gain gain matrix is given basically by the providers that we computed on the
the providers that we computed on the one stamp that had predicted
one stamp that had predicted distribution times C transpose times
distribution times C transpose times this matrix s inverse and this matrix
this matrix s inverse and this matrix has seen versed discuss the scale what
has seen versed discuss the scale what this is given by an analytical
this is given by an analytical expression all right you know the stree
expression all right you know the stree matrix this again comes from the
matrix this again comes from the variance of the of the Z given the date
variance of the of the Z given the date of the t minus 1 and this is the noise
of the t minus 1 and this is the noise in the observation model so everything
in the observation model so everything is known right if this calculation if
is known right if this calculation if this formulas make any sense what we
this formulas make any sense what we need to best take
need to best take the mean from the one step ahead
the mean from the one step ahead predictive distribution and corrective
predictive distribution and corrective using this residual are all right
using this residual are all right multiplied with Kalman gain metrics and
multiplied with Kalman gain metrics and the residual are is basically the
the residual are is basically the observation of time t minus this entity
observation of time t minus this entity here and so what is this this is the
here and so what is this this is the mean of what
a competitive we completely lose that I had predicted distribution sheep a given
had predicted distribution sheep a given day the right to t minus 1 this is not
day the right to t minus 1 this is not the same this is the predicted
the same this is the predicted distribution of the observe Asian given
distribution of the observe Asian given data 1 to P minus 1 but that's an easy
data 1 to P minus 1 but that's an easy distribution because YT is 3 times Z P
distribution because YT is 3 times Z P plus the input plus some noise of the
plus the input plus some noise of the distribution which is worse because DT
distribution which is worse because DT times DT I'm not giving any variation of
times DT I'm not giving any variation of this product right
this product right anything on 13 years he told me in a
anything on 13 years he told me in a distribution which is nice on city and
distribution which is nice on city and I'm sure he you know eclairisse 2000 and
I'm sure he you know eclairisse 2000 and this is also not the middle city now
right so this is a linger in modern city like this is you know so thousand times
like this is you know so thousand times a Gaussian and somehow is a miracle of
a Gaussian and somehow is a miracle of manipulations we should be using the
manipulations we should be using the identities that I gave you we get this
identities that I gave you we get this nice results okay so the question is
nice results okay so the question is where do we get this result
let me put everything here so perfect I get this result
I needed an 808 the fabulous with an innovation system to give you a piece of
innovation system to give you a piece of this camera filtering updates from the
this camera filtering updates from the predictive distribution where do we get
predictive distribution where do we get this result
so she would I have this white they given City right can you tell me is his
given City right can you tell me is his church a Gaussian is the limit of
church a Gaussian is the limit of Gaussian linear density so this Agartha
Gaussian linear density so this Agartha right is the mean of the Gaussian and in
right is the mean of the Gaussian and in a function of Z T the middle area system
a function of Z T the middle area system that equals two times 3t plus lane to
that equals two times 3t plus lane to pass the lowest all right so yes there
pass the lowest all right so yes there is a symmetric there so this is a
is a symmetric there so this is a Gaussian that doesn't mean three times
Gaussian that doesn't mean three times the Z plane is going to pass the
the Z plane is going to pass the Gaussian noise okay so basically what
Gaussian noise okay so basically what you have is you have a distribution of
you have is you have a distribution of ZK that we have computed and here
ZK that we have computed and here another notion that is really city and
another notion that is really city and what do we want to compute we want
what do we want to compute we want basically to complete the postilions if
basically to complete the postilions if you given all of my wife this data here
you given all of my wife this data here right from 1/2 times T so basically what
right from 1/2 times T so basically what you need to do is I don't want to go
you need to do is I don't want to go back to any slides right you need need
back to any slides right you need need to use the browser some updates but I
to use the browser some updates but I gave you the court and it comes out that
gave you the court and it comes out that the covariance matrix inverse okay of
the covariance matrix inverse okay of this matrix is given by this nice
this matrix is given by this nice formula and the mean is given by this
formula and the mean is given by this problem trust me I have not done
problem trust me I have not done anything the mystery cut and paste the
anything the mystery cut and paste the previous formulas with the new symbols
previous formulas with the new symbols that come in the context of the question
that come in the context of the question on the top when I plug in what Gaussian
on the top when I plug in what Gaussian I have terror web browser have there and
I have terror web browser have there and then money nian Gao Xiang
then money nian Gao Xiang update equations look exactly the way
update equations look exactly the way that you have there
now applications this for questions that I cut and pasted from the lien Gaussian
I cut and pasted from the lien Gaussian system they don't look like the camera
system they don't look like the camera filtering your questions that they saw
filtering your questions that they saw with you in terms of this caring metrics
with you in terms of this caring metrics so the question is ways the Kalman gain
so the question is ways the Kalman gain metrics come strong because it's not
metrics come strong because it's not there alright so obviously the sir
there alright so obviously the sir questions will not be very sort of
questions will not be very sort of efficient way to program this because I
efficient way to program this because I see English eh if you want to probably
see English eh if you want to probably the covariance means you're going to
the covariance means you're going to have to calculate the inverse of this
have to calculate the inverse of this huge matrix here okay so this will not
huge matrix here okay so this will not be very good when smart way to do things
be very good when smart way to do things so let's look at different terms
so let's look at different terms okay so I am cloning here the first
okay so I am cloning here the first equation can actually be invented in
equation can actually be invented in this nice form that you see here
this nice form that you see here can you guess without again saying that
can you guess without again saying that any derivation from whether the question
any derivation from whether the question may be coming can you guess that somehow
may be coming can you guess that somehow if I take this and I invert it that
if I take this and I invert it that Sigma T is actually given by this does
Sigma T is actually given by this does it visually
it visually anything that we have seen like a few
anything that we have seen like a few slides back the matrix inversion name
slides back the matrix inversion name are the Woodbury identity okay so
are the Woodbury identity okay so basically to try to invert this
basically to try to invert this basically you get captain page change of
basically you get captain page change of symbols you get this nice you know
symbols you get this nice you know equation here and if you noticed the
equation here and if you noticed the wrist okay there is a steep PT minus 1
wrist okay there is a steep PT minus 1 so this is the covariance of the
so this is the covariance of the predictive one step ahead using date
predictive one step ahead using date only of the t minus 1 we have computed
only of the t minus 1 we have computed that so I can put this outside and this
that so I can put this outside and this whole matrix of the city I'm sorry this
whole matrix of the city I'm sorry this whole matrix there is what we defined to
whole matrix there is what we defined to be the Kalman gain matrix
be the Kalman gain matrix okay okay so Gaussian linear
okay okay so Gaussian linear equation manipulation to give us these
equation manipulation to give us these two equations and then we can see Sigma
two equations and then we can see Sigma T so we get this terminal update
T so we get this terminal update basically directly in terms of Sigma T
basically directly in terms of Sigma T and I'm going to give you the update now
and I'm going to give you the update now for the mean because before when I can
for the mean because before when I can go back all right should we write this
go back all right should we write this nice update for Sigma now I have to give
nice update for Sigma now I have to give you the update from you
you the update from you the student deriving the Kalman equation
the student deriving the Kalman equation is also a trivial task okay so crazy
is also a trivial task okay so crazy update for me so the let me just go back
update for me so the let me just go back to be sure that we are talking about
to be sure that we are talking about okay so then I now have know from you
okay so then I now have know from you know from this multiplication here this
know from this multiplication here this is what you get from the linear dowser
is what you get from the linear dowser system right so we need to manipulate
system right so we need to manipulate this to get within a much more tractable
this to get within a much more tractable flow so I'm going to rewrite this
flow so I'm going to rewrite this equation that you see here so I can
equation that you see here so I can start working it so this equation is has
start working it so this equation is has two terms some when I work on each of
two terms some when I work on each of these two terms technically okay so the
these two terms technically okay so the first equation that looks painful
first equation that looks painful all right now let's say Y is not bad so
all right now let's say Y is not bad so there is a sigma theta minus 1 inverse x
there is a sigma theta minus 1 inverse x nu t t minus 1 I need it exist and for
nu t t minus 1 I need it exist and for Sigma I use the update in terms of a
Sigma I use the update in terms of a power gain matrix K that we just like
power gain matrix K that we just like okay so the first term immediately is
okay so the first term immediately is written in terms of the carbon game
written in terms of the carbon game ethics play in a very nice form very
ethics play in a very nice form very convenient update okay
convenient update okay very we need to update the stigma T
very we need to update the stigma T times T transpose where is it so we need
times T transpose where is it so we need of data tab and again Sigma T is written
of data tab and again Sigma T is written by this nice thing times this times YP
by this nice thing times this times YP and what I have done is now I
do anything if I put them aside they invest okay
invest okay it comes out the you can write this
it comes out the you can write this whole thing here
whole thing here there's no mill and then to do anything
there's no mill and then to do anything like that you can write it this this
like that you can write it this this matrix and this matrix is really to come
matrix and this matrix is really to come up in the metric scale so the update
up in the metric scale so the update committee is basically new P P minus 1
committee is basically new P P minus 1 plus this Kalman gain metrics times
plus this Kalman gain metrics times basically internal methods that
basically internal methods that attention you will stand between the
attention you will stand between the observation right P and the distribution
observation right P and the distribution for y -1 okay so basically those are the
for y -1 okay so basically those are the updates okay and you actually phase with
updates okay and you actually phase with a comma filtering equations right if you
a comma filtering equations right if you look but looks the mystery chapters from
look but looks the mystery chapters from this but really playing with with their
this but really playing with with their identity and the guys earlier systems
identity and the guys earlier systems the questions the derivation is
the questions the derivation is basically a few slides okay if you don't
basically a few slides okay if you don't actually this and we will do this using
actually this and we will do this using message passing it will look pain
message passing it will look pain through the derivation that interesting
through the derivation that interesting is that message passing algorithm can
is that message passing algorithm can actually extend the Kalman filter to all
actually extend the Kalman filter to all sort of distributions all sort of
sort of distributions all sort of dynamics and observation model so if you
dynamics and observation model so if you like you could model is noisy to know
like you could model is noisy to know Gaussian supports on the street