okay hello everyone my name is Cody Baker and a third year student in the
Baker and a third year student in the Department of a fighting computational
Department of a fighting computational mathematics and statistics and I study
mathematics and statistics and I study in computational neuroscience and
in computational neuroscience and particular the problem of inferring
particular the problem of inferring neuronal network structure specifically
neuronal network structure specifically with data coming from extracellular
with data coming from extracellular recording techniques so before we start
recording techniques so before we start to talk about results we also do a
to talk about results we also do a little bit of background in neuroscience
little bit of background in neuroscience and the models that we use now you don't
and the models that we use now you don't have to know too much but you do have to
have to know too much but you do have to know that the brain is an organ
know that the brain is an organ comprised of very large numbers of
comprised of very large numbers of individual computing unit cells known as
individual computing unit cells known as neurons and neurons are able to connect
neurons and neurons are able to connect to one another by way of a synapse which
to one another by way of a synapse which is when the axon extension of one neuron
is when the axon extension of one neuron attaches to the dendrites of another and
attaches to the dendrites of another and they share information across the
they share information across the synapse by way of electrochemical
synapse by way of electrochemical impulses known as spikes these are brief
impulses known as spikes these are brief transients observable via voltage traces
transients observable via voltage traces from the inside of a neuron you see the
from the inside of a neuron you see the spikes are the two big events there and
spikes are the two big events there and they decay very quickly Dunn's back to
they decay very quickly Dunn's back to the resting potential
the resting potential now neurons come in two types excitatory
now neurons come in two types excitatory and inhibitory the important difference
and inhibitory the important difference is that the effect of spiking and a
is that the effect of spiking and a presynaptic cell can either cause more
presynaptic cell can either cause more or less light in the postsynaptic cell
or less light in the postsynaptic cell and intelligent behavior people like you
and intelligent behavior people like you and me are thought to arise by complex
and me are thought to arise by complex very complex interactions of spiking
very complex interactions of spiking events in very large networks now there
events in very large networks now there are a lot of different computational
are a lot of different computational theories that can explain very specific
theories that can explain very specific tasks such as memory visual
tasks such as memory visual classification District in making go on
classification District in making go on but we don't have enough real data to
but we don't have enough real data to confirm that of actual brains follow any
confirm that of actual brains follow any specific theory and a big part of this
specific theory and a big part of this is because in the past people had been
is because in the past people had been able to report from my hands
able to report from my hands neurons simultaneously at a time there
neurons simultaneously at a time there recently and this has been developing
recently and this has been developing almost analogous to Moore's law every
almost analogous to Moore's law every few years we find a way to record from
few years we find a way to record from twice as many neurons as before in
twice as many neurons as before in recent years we have developed
recent years we have developed techniques that can record from hundreds
techniques that can record from hundreds thousands I think now they're starting
thousands I think now they're starting to push tens of thousands and we're
to push tens of thousands and we're going to focus on one in particular on
going to focus on one in particular on that that called calcium imaging now
that that called calcium imaging now active imaging you have a central laser
active imaging you have a central laser hub is gaining gaining some cubic volume
hub is gaining gaining some cubic volume of neural space and a whole bunch of
of neural space and a whole bunch of post processing machine learning based
post processing machine learning based techniques you can identify the location
techniques you can identify the location in space of every individual neuron and
in space of every individual neuron and then you can extract a measure of
then you can extract a measure of fluorescence that indicates how active
fluorescence that indicates how active and individual neuron is and this is
and individual neuron is and this is actual real data you're looking at here
actual real data you're looking at here and you can see some neurons are spiking
and you can see some neurons are spiking very frequently that's like that one
very frequently that's like that one that's always colored Thurmont spiking
that's always colored Thurmont spiking at all and others are going very
at all and others are going very sporadically according to what's on top
sporadically according to what's on top of these and so in the context of the
of these and so in the context of the data what does it look like it looks
data what does it look like it looks like a bunch of calcium sorry it looks
like a bunch of calcium sorry it looks like a bunch of Gaussian Prophecy you
like a bunch of Gaussian Prophecy you get traces of relative fluorescence for
get traces of relative fluorescence for every pixel in the face these are the
every pixel in the face these are the cameras
cameras constant optical beam splitter you
should automatically learn to the next thing to follow that video so I my goal
thing to follow that video so I my goal here is to look at these traces as
here is to look at these traces as Gaussian processes and to try to guess
Gaussian processes and to try to guess which neurons are connected to one
which neurons are connected to one another and we can statistically maulvis
another and we can statistically maulvis data in a number of different ways we
data in a number of different ways we can use stochastic differential equation
can use stochastic differential equation for linear dynamical systems we talked
for linear dynamical systems we talked about in class general auto regressive
about in class general auto regressive processes or any sort of time series
processes or any sort of time series model and since we're trying to go a
model and since we're trying to go a little faster today I probably won't
little faster today I probably won't talk too much about the gel on models
talk too much about the gel on models okay so in the context of everything
okay so in the context of everything we're going to talk about today we're
we're going to talk about today we're always going to be referencing an
always going to be referencing an adjacency matrix or our probabilistic
adjacency matrix or our probabilistic graphical models shown by this network
graphical models shown by this network now it is decomposable into two distinct
now it is decomposable into two distinct parts it has a weighted part that is
parts it has a weighted part that is random and normally distributed and it
random and normally distributed and it has a structure driven by what's called
has a structure driven by what's called further journey which has means it's
further journey which has means it's random binary at some level it's party
random binary at some level it's party so this is an example adjacency matrix
so this is an example adjacency matrix remember it's back wise because we have
remember it's back wise because we have excitatory and inhibitory neurons in our
excitatory and inhibitory neurons in our model and here you continue inhibitory
model and here you continue inhibitory ones always have negative weights so you
ones always have negative weights so you have random winding and spar structure
have random winding and spar structure on top of that and explicitly stating
on top of that and explicitly stating the problem we're interested in
the problem we're interested in differing the sparse structure Omega or
differing the sparse structure Omega or the undirected case of Omega plus Omega
the undirected case of Omega plus Omega transpose
transpose and the quick note on this topic before
and the quick note on this topic before we go on stability is a very important
we go on stability is a very important issue with these networks and you need
issue with these networks and you need very specific set of constraints to
very specific set of constraints to guarantee that your system is always
guarantee that your system is always stable and you do that by applying a 1
stable and you do that by applying a 1 over square root and scaling on the
over square root and scaling on the normally distributed snap express that
normally distributed snap express that constrains a vast majority of the
constrains a vast majority of the eigenvalues to the unit circle and but
eigenvalues to the unit circle and but then you'll notice you have these two
then you'll notice you have these two big eigen values that are conjugate
big eigen values that are conjugate pairs those are related to the Kurdish
pairs those are related to the Kurdish for any structure the sparsity and those
for any structure the sparsity and those you can keep to the right simply by
you can keep to the right simply by these two jury conditions the
these two jury conditions the determinant of the trace on the block
determinant of the trace on the block lies average for the network and
lies average for the network and throughout this we're going to be
throughout this we're going to be quantifying the performance of various
quantifying the performance of various algorithms using policy analysis and
algorithms using policy analysis and whether than first time seeing it or
whether than first time seeing it or just need a little refresher the ROC
just need a little refresher the ROC curve is a parametric function of false
curve is a parametric function of false positive rate versus true positive rate
positive rate versus true positive rate as the threshold of a linear classifier
as the threshold of a linear classifier is buried and so this is an example
is buried and so this is an example Piracy curve for some stuff we're going
Piracy curve for some stuff we're going to talk about in just a bit
to talk about in just a bit and you can see you get very high true
and you can see you get very high true positives for very low false positives
positives for very low false positives but overall we will often be interested
but overall we will often be interested only in the area under this curve which
only in the area under this curve which is a nice talented measure between 1/2
is a nice talented measure between 1/2 and 1 corresponding to just random
and 1 corresponding to just random guessing and perfect classification
guessing and perfect classification respectively okay so the case model
respectively okay so the case model we'll talk briefly about is the
we'll talk briefly about is the stochastic differential equation which
stochastic differential equation which is a Wilson cowan rate model which can
is a Wilson cowan rate model which can be expressed as this equation in terms
be expressed as this equation in terms of the stochastic differential of the
of the stochastic differential of the white noise which is just the
white noise which is just the differential of ear profit process but
differential of ear profit process but if you just back up and look at it it's
if you just back up and look at it it's really just an arrow one process in
really just an arrow one process in continuous time so we know how to deal
continuous time so we know how to deal with this
with this and you know the most useful thing that
and you know the most useful thing that we will use this equation for is the
we will use this equation for is the fact that has analytical solutions to
fact that has analytical solutions to stuff like the cross cross covariance
stuff like the cross cross covariance and in particular the cross spectrum
and in particular the cross spectrum which is the Fourier transform of that
which is the Fourier transform of that the specific algebraic form of the zero
the specific algebraic form of the zero frequency cross spectrum can be
frequency cross spectrum can be explicitly expanded to give a one-to-one
explicitly expanded to give a one-to-one relationship between bi-directional
relationship between bi-directional connectivity and precision so this is
connectivity and precision so this is kind of like an analogous to all the
kind of like an analogous to all the stuff we talked about with Gaussian
stuff we talked about with Gaussian graphical models except this is a
graphical models except this is a process that's varying in time and so
process that's varying in time and so you can equivalently express as a loan
you can equivalently express as a loan process and disclose form as an LDS that
process and disclose form as an LDS that we've seen a lot of throughout this
we've seen a lot of throughout this class and there are a lot of different
class and there are a lot of different sub problems related to sub ideal
sub problems related to sub ideal observations you can have more
observations you can have more observations than neurons in the model
observations than neurons in the model that's a great problem to have because
that's a great problem to have because then you have multiple samples from
then you have multiple samples from every neuron but it's often not the case
every neuron but it's often not the case often times you have fewer observations
often times you have fewer observations than you do neurons in which case you
than you do neurons in which case you pretty much have to shift the entire
pretty much have to shift the entire argument around not talking about
argument around not talking about inferring single neuron connectivity but
inferring single neuron connectivity but other connectivity between multiple
other connectivity between multiple neurons local and space I know the
neurons local and space I know the really hard problem is you can have
really hard problem is you can have different numbers of observations
different numbers of observations throughout time whenever you apply
throughout time whenever you apply calcium imaging you're applying it to a
calcium imaging you're applying it to a live subject and so they are sometimes
live subject and so they are sometimes anesthetized to try to minimize knowing
anesthetized to try to minimize knowing but there's always a little bit of
but there's always a little bit of jitter a little bit of movement and so
jitter a little bit of movement and so you always have to be able to try to
you always have to be able to try to identify the set of neurons that you are
identify the set of neurons that you are somehow reporting from constantly
somehow reporting from constantly throughout time and write together all
throughout time and write together all the data samples from that but my focus
the data samples from that but my focus today is on a more fundamental
today is on a more fundamental difficulty so justr simplicity let's
difficulty so justr simplicity let's assume we have near-perfect observations
assume we have near-perfect observations for the LDL
for the LDL so we're gonna do when we have a linear
so we're gonna do when we have a linear dynamical system well the best way to
dynamical system well the best way to get inference of parameters is
get inference of parameters is expectation-maximization right you've
expectation-maximization right you've run the Kalman filtering and smoothing
run the Kalman filtering and smoothing by Muslims passing and then you get a
by Muslims passing and then you get a rate DM algorithm on some initial
rate DM algorithm on some initial guesses and after the few iterations
guesses and after the few iterations it'll converge and this is an example
it'll converge and this is an example application of it you see a true network
application of it you see a true network there up on the left and then you have
there up on the left and then you have an estimate given out a fixed false
an estimate given out a fixed false positive ratio so this estimate of the
positive ratio so this estimate of the network was chosen to be right about
network was chosen to be right about there on the ROC curve to live there to
there on the ROC curve to live there to have a similar level of sparsity and a
have a similar level of sparsity and a fairly high degree of confidence that
fairly high degree of confidence that the selected edges are in fact true
the selected edges are in fact true edges but the most important thing here
edges but the most important thing here is the fact that the area under the ROC
is the fact that the area under the ROC curve monotonically increases that you
curve monotonically increases that you feed it more and more data in near will
feed it more and more data in near will on the scale of tens to hundreds of
on the scale of tens to hundreds of thousands of data samples that will
thousands of data samples that will become very important just a second and
become very important just a second and you can also see that it converging to a
you can also see that it converging to a perfect classifier for it these simple
perfect classifier for it these simple networks now why is it we know that if
networks now why is it we know that if you just have a ggm there's a standard
you just have a ggm there's a standard time invariant graph we can explicitly
time invariant graph we can explicitly get to a set of conditional
get to a set of conditional independencies from the precision maker
independencies from the precision maker we know that but the precision matrix is
we know that but the precision matrix is just one type of a general idea that's
just one type of a general idea that's called partial correlation and particle
called partial correlation and particle relations are really just pairwise
relations are really just pairwise correlations conditioned on from set of
correlations conditioned on from set of the network and precision is in fact the
the network and precision is in fact the largest type of partial correlation in
largest type of partial correlation in the sense of you condition on everything
the sense of you condition on everything else on the network besides the parity
else on the network besides the parity that you're looking at but expectation
that you're looking at but expectation maximization can also be viewed as a
maximization can also be viewed as a type of partial correlation if you look
type of partial correlation if you look at the values we derived in homework 5
at the values we derived in homework 5 or in the equivalent common estimate
or in the equivalent common estimate you can see you have quantities that are
you can see you have quantities that are essentially proportional to the 0 large
essentially proportional to the 0 large sample per student being projected in
sample per student being projected in the direction of the live 1 cross
the direction of the live 1 cross covariance because remember eeehm gives
covariance because remember eeehm gives us a directed measure whereas precision
us a directed measure whereas precision is a symmetric value you have to impose
is a symmetric value you have to impose some sort of directionality in some way
some sort of directionality in some way and there are a lot of other different
and there are a lot of other different methods but I thought that was kind of
methods but I thought that was kind of interesting that p.m. is really just a
interesting that p.m. is really just a special case of correlation okay we
special case of correlation okay we talked about directly estimating the
talked about directly estimating the precision instead of doing the common
precision instead of doing the common stuff a big issue with empirical data is
stuff a big issue with empirical data is you have very short duration of trials
you have very short duration of trials typically in the order of seconds to
typically in the order of seconds to minutes if that aware is the plot that I
minutes if that aware is the plot that I was just showing you where
was just showing you where expectation-maximization converged to a
expectation-maximization converged to a really good area under the ROC curve you
really good area under the ROC curve you needed hundreds of thousands of data
needed hundreds of thousands of data samples that would equate to having you
samples that would equate to having you know trials that lasted for several
know trials that lasted for several hours now not just impractical no living
hours now not just impractical no living subject wants to sit there and watching
subject wants to sit there and watching movies with three hours these typically
movies with three hours these typically might have to deal with so we have very
might have to deal with so we have very little data and so to make better use of
little data and so to make better use of what little data we have we will use the
what little data we have we will use the buzzword of regularization and so the
buzzword of regularization and so the beijing of perspective regularization is
beijing of perspective regularization is really just like applying a prior
really just like applying a prior distribution to the coefficients for
distribution to the coefficients for some regression model and concerning the
some regression model and concerning the model in that way really makes better
model in that way really makes better use of what data you have they it gives
use of what data you have they it gives you a higher-quality estimate for
you a higher-quality estimate for comfortable amounts of data and so the
comfortable amounts of data and so the specific estimation approach for
specific estimation approach for proceeding that I will use is graphical
proceeding that I will use is graphical lasso a very popular approach very
lasso a very popular approach very popular algorithm and if the solution of
popular algorithm and if the solution of this optimization equation where you'll
this optimization equation where you'll notice here we're using an l1 norm on
notice here we're using an l1 norm on our regularization that is
our regularization that is like imposing a sparse flyer on our
like imposing a sparse flyer on our precision matrix and the regularization
precision matrix and the regularization strength Ram that can be chosen a number
strength Ram that can be chosen a number of different ways the simplest way is to
of different ways the simplest way is to cross validated against target bono
cross validated against target bono sparsity the far more interesting
sparsity the far more interesting approach is to use something called the
approach is to use something called the Stars algorithm which uses all sorts of
Stars algorithm which uses all sorts of measures like kitv icy sports-based
measures like kitv icy sports-based criterion and it runs all these to
criterion and it runs all these to various iterations to kind of produce a
various iterations to kind of produce a target level of expected sparsity and so
target level of expected sparsity and so if you a pie graph Galasso and in
if you a pie graph Galasso and in combination with a number of other
combination with a number of other measures you'll notice that by far it
measures you'll notice that by far it always surpasses every other measure for
always surpasses every other measure for in terms of structure in these types of
in terms of structure in these types of networks and here are notice the
networks and here are notice the difference in the scale of T previously
difference in the scale of T previously we were talking about tens hundreds of
we were talking about tens hundreds of thousands of data points now we're
thousands of data points now we're talking about hundreds which is why our
talking about hundreds which is why our you know it recovery isn't that great
you know it recovery isn't that great but the point is still that crossover
but the point is still that crossover does a far better job than any other
does a far better job than any other algorithm including the naive estimate
algorithm including the naive estimate of precision which is just the inverse
of precision which is just the inverse of sample covariance okay but there's a
of sample covariance okay but there's a big unrealistic assumption that we've
big unrealistic assumption that we've made throughout all the models so far
made throughout all the models so far and that's a lack of external input now
and that's a lack of external input now in in empirical studies you never have
in in empirical studies you never have observations of these things and so they
observations of these things and so they take on the role of latent variables
take on the role of latent variables which makes them very difficult to deal
which makes them very difficult to deal with and the way to interpret the
with and the way to interpret the external inputs is typically in cortex
external inputs is typically in cortex you have multiple recurrent layers where
you have multiple recurrent layers where one subject's feed-forward offers
one subject's feed-forward offers heapsort projections onto the other
heapsort projections onto the other and typically it's only excitatory
and typically it's only excitatory neurons that do that as well so they
neurons that do that as well so they take on the role of latent variables and
take on the role of latent variables and so you can update the FTEs and
so you can update the FTEs and transition models as follows you add a
transition models as follows you add a mean drive from some external adjacent
mean drive from some external adjacent we made church so it's very similar in
we made church so it's very similar in structure to the recurrent but typically
structure to the recurrent but typically rectangular could you typically have
rectangular could you typically have more or less number of neurons and then
more or less number of neurons and then you also now have correlated noise terms
you also now have correlated noise terms where B is the trusty decomposition of
where B is the trusty decomposition of the external covariance matrix gamma and
the external covariance matrix gamma and so there's been some proposals on the
so there's been some proposals on the literature that you can at least in the
literature that you can at least in the case of low rank external input where
case of low rank external input where you just have a handful of neurons in
you just have a handful of neurons in the external population there there's
the external population there there's been proposed that you can use Gaussian
been proposed that you can use Gaussian process factor analysis to fit those
process factor analysis to fit those lighting dimensions and that should
lighting dimensions and that should improve your estimate unfortunately I
improve your estimate unfortunately I tried and tried and tried to get this to
tried and tried and tried to get this to work unfortunately it appears is it
work unfortunately it appears is it using GP FA over fits the process if
using GP FA over fits the process if it's not only the latent variables but
it's not only the latent variables but some of the valuable information from
some of the valuable information from the stochastic process itself and so he
the stochastic process itself and so he written C Grasso used on the residuals
written C Grasso used on the residuals before and after an application of GP FA
before and after an application of GP FA and the overfitting from GP FA causes it
and the overfitting from GP FA causes it to decay a little lower it's also very
to decay a little lower it's also very very slow algorithms for larger networks
very slow algorithms for larger networks so it's not considered practical
so it's not considered practical currently
currently okay and a quick note the problem at
okay and a quick note the problem at least of having a mean constant rise can
least of having a mean constant rise can be solved in the context of a linear
be solved in the context of a linear dynamical system this is a Homer problem
dynamical system this is a Homer problem and vicious machine learning books
and vicious machine learning books section 13 basically you just add some
section 13 basically you just add some additional rows to your hidden States
additional rows to your hidden States fix them at unity now you can absorb
fix them at unity now you can absorb additional columns as the main input
additional columns as the main input onto your new network W and that
onto your new network W and that districts the whole problem but your ovm
districts the whole problem but your ovm estimates would still be perfectly fine
estimates would still be perfectly fine unfortunately it doesn't appear to work
unfortunately it doesn't appear to work either and we'll explain why in just a
either and we'll explain why in just a second okay we're back to the level
second okay we're back to the level where we have tens of thousands of data
where we have tens of thousands of data samples so they should be doing better
samples so they should be doing better right but they're not this is in the
right but they're not this is in the presence of external input Hackney has a
presence of external input Hackney has a latent variables and so why is not a
latent variables and so why is not a single measure giving us good influence
single measure giving us good influence it's because we are now receiving biased
it's because we are now receiving biased external input covariance that in fact
external input covariance that in fact shares terms with the main input drive
shares terms with the main input drive so at least expectation-maximization you
so at least expectation-maximization you have to completely redo the end step now
have to completely redo the end step now I've tried to do this analytically
I've tried to do this analytically unfortunately there is one specific part
unfortunately there is one specific part that is essentially intractable and so
that is essentially intractable and so you would need to implement generalize
you would need to implement generalize DM to a box made a local pollution but
DM to a box made a local pollution but now generally none of the other measures
now generally none of the other measures work well either sample precision
work well either sample precision covariance even they are fit none of
covariance even they are fit none of them did a good job because they're all
them did a good job because they're all somehow functions of the precision for
somehow functions of the precision for this process which in the presence of an
this process which in the presence of an external input takes on the following
external input takes on the following form where you have additive terms going
form where you have additive terms going from the external input covariance and
from the external input covariance and remember this is the part that gives us
remember this is the part that gives us two one-to-one relationship with
two one-to-one relationship with bi-directional network connectivity it's
bi-directional network connectivity it's now being scrambled projected in all
now being scrambled projected in all sorts of different directions by the XR
sorts of different directions by the XR 1 for covariance and you're also getting
1 for covariance and you're also getting more very
more very from the triple product term so it's
from the triple product term so it's just not a good problem and then yeah I
just not a good problem and then yeah I just we just started to get systems
just we just started to get systems we're going a little faster today quick
we're going a little faster today quick plug my collaborators on a lot of this
plug my collaborators on a lot of this research at Rice University in Houston
research at Rice University in Houston is headed by the lab of Ginevra Allen
is headed by the lab of Ginevra Allen they were exploring a couple other cases
they were exploring a couple other cases of time dependence which are really
of time dependence which are really interesting that I don't have to talk
interesting that I don't have to talk about just as an upcoming talk next
about just as an upcoming talk next Friday May 4th that's a part of a team
Friday May 4th that's a part of a team that's colloquium but I think it's
that's colloquium but I think it's sponsored by IBM he really goes there
sponsored by IBM he really goes there interested in dealing with high
interested in dealing with high dimensional data as she does a lot of
dimensional data as she does a lot of other projects and biostatistics not
other projects and biostatistics not just neuroscience and so here are many
just neuroscience and so here are many other references that allow this is
other references that allow this is based on the first two were kind of
based on the first two were kind of joint publications by Allen and this is
joint publications by Allen and this is just a general background on the problem
just a general background on the problem in general and simply gonna talk about
in general and simply gonna talk about GL and say if you want to learn more
GL and say if you want to learn more about what genomes can offer any
about what genomes can offer any publication hospital lab is the way to
publication hospital lab is the way to go it's work is supported under multiple
go it's work is supported under multiple NSF grants not like to thank everyone in
NSF grants not like to thank everyone in the Rosenbaum lab for their feedback on
the Rosenbaum lab for their feedback on the early versions of this presentation
the early versions of this presentation so thank you for listening and do you
so thank you for listening and do you have any questions
yes
okay so everything he asked how many neurons do I look at so I looked at beta
neurons do I look at so I looked at beta test containing hundreds but everything
test containing hundreds but everything you saw in this presentation had was 30
you saw in this presentation had was 30 so very small Network now I have with
so very small Network now I have with that hundreds and thousands plug neuron
that hundreds and thousands plug neuron of neurons in the context of in silico
of neurons in the context of in silico modeling and you the only thing is it's
modeling and you the only thing is it's harder to get really clear results to
harder to get really clear results to show you you can crank up the data that
show you you can crank up the data that you feed the model do really like
you feed the model do really like millions of data points and that's
millions of data points and that's what's required to get really good
what's required to get really good inference for life you know a thousand
inference for life you know a thousand neurons or something like that so yeah I
neurons or something like that so yeah I looked at fairly small networks in this
looked at fairly small networks in this context but the goal is to develop
context but the goal is to develop methods but there the reason there is
methods but there the reason there is computational time glosso doesn't even
computational time glosso doesn't even converge if you have more than a few
converge if you have more than a few hundred neurons there's a certain step
hundred neurons there's a certain step in the lasso algorithm where you have to
in the lasso algorithm where you have to do a kind of shooting thing and it just
do a kind of shooting thing and it just it takes forever to not converge if you
it takes forever to not converge if you have a few hundred neurons and very
have a few hundred neurons and very small amounts of data
but the hope is to one day spend all of our methods to the case where we can
our methods to the case where we can look at tens of thousands simultaneously
look at tens of thousands simultaneously and still perform this level of
and still perform this level of inference we're just not there yet good
inference we're just not there yet good question and the others right thank you
so good afternoon everybody my talk is about web-based tree-structured
about web-based tree-structured compressive sensing with variation of
compressive sensing with variation of Bayesian analysis so and wavelet based
Bayesian analysis so and wavelet based transform can be used to decompose a
transform can be used to decompose a given signal or function that we have in
given signal or function that we have in terms of some basic functions called
terms of some basic functions called wavelets and then we can study these the
wavelets and then we can study these the structure of these wavelet coefficients
structure of these wavelet coefficients proper to fill data that we have so
proper to fill data that we have so imagine that we have a signal and we
imagine that we have a signal and we apply whether the composition on this
apply whether the composition on this the results are two types of data one is
the results are two types of data one is the scaling coefficients the other ones
the scaling coefficients the other ones are the favorite coefficient scaling
are the favorite coefficient scaling coefficients give an approximation of
coefficients give an approximation of the function that we have in some lower
the function that we have in some lower resolution space and the other
resolution space and the other coefficient provides us with the detail
coefficient provides us with the detail that we need to reconstruct the original
that we need to reconstruct the original data that we have from those that
data that we have from those that approximation now we can apply the
approximation now we can apply the wavelet decomposition as many at times
wavelet decomposition as many at times as we want and each time we need to take
as we want and each time we need to take the product mission that we have why the
the product mission that we have why the composition on that and then we end up
composition on that and then we end up with another set of reverberate
with another set of reverberate coefficient and even lower resolution of
coefficient and even lower resolution of the approximation so to reconstruct the
the approximation so to reconstruct the data which and
we can take these Kelvin coefficients and sum them with the weather conditions
and sum them with the weather conditions that we have for all the levels of
that we have for all the levels of decomposition and we reconstruct our
decomposition and we reconstruct our original data so for most ignores the
original data so for most ignores the wavelet coefficients are part and
wavelet coefficients are part and they're compressible and that means that
they're compressible and that means that we can set to zero many of the waiver
we can set to zero many of the waiver coefficients that we have many of them
coefficients that we have many of them have negligible value and we can neglect
have negligible value and we can neglect them and we can reconstruct the function
them and we can reconstruct the function from the modified wavelet coefficients
from the modified wavelet coefficients and end up with a good very accurately
and end up with a good very accurately because the measurements that we have
because the measurements that we have might not might not always be easy and
might not might not always be easy and cheap to acquire for example in MRI
cheap to acquire for example in MRI image imaging it's very tedious faster
image imaging it's very tedious faster it's time-consuming imaging we need to
it's time-consuming imaging we need to take image in many spiritual bands so
take image in many spiritual bands so one might think that it's the useful way
one might think that it's the useful way to only measure the informative data
measurements that we need to have so the incompressible testing we assume that
incompressible testing we assume that the signal we have is compressible
the signal we have is compressible instant basis and then we can exactly we
instant basis and then we can exactly we construct the originals are underlying
construct the originals are underlying original signal with a number of
original signal with a number of appropriately designed projected
appropriately designed projected measurement and we can be theta where
measurement and we can be theta where theta is over bed with coefficient and T
theta is over bed with coefficient and T is the matrix rows of which are the
is the matrix rows of which are the random with the time projected
random with the time projected projection vector
projection vector so we would like if we assume that this
so we would like if we assume that this V is n dimensional ended based with one
V is n dimensional ended based with one x and and dimensional n elements and
x and and dimensional n elements and theta is the has n elements we would
theta is the has n elements we would like the number of measurements to be as
like the number of measurements to be as low as possible conditions that we have
we have these theta coefficients we can reconstruct our image or signal that we
reconstruct our image or signal that we have using an image transport but we
have using an image transport but we measure it is a projection it is a
measure it is a projection it is a projection this problem is undetermined
projection this problem is undetermined and it still posed and a good way to
and it still posed and a good way to approach this problem is using Bayesian
approach this problem is using Bayesian Setia conversion so some structures and
Setia conversion so some structures and we can incorporate this structure of
we can incorporate this structure of this wave with to have our coefficients
this wave with to have our coefficients to in order to reduce the number of
to in order to reduce the number of required measurements that we have if we
required measurements that we have if we want to apply the treatment web
want to apply the treatment web transform on airsick given signal we can
transform on airsick given signal we can define this as deploying the series the
define this as deploying the series the high-pass and low-pass filters and that
high-pass and low-pass filters and that would result in a quadtree here H stands
would result in a quadtree here H stands for the high-pass and L stands for Lopes
for the high-pass and L stands for Lopes we have a signal with labels will end up
we have a signal with labels will end up with two types of results began on each
with two types of results began on each of these we apply these two
of these we apply these two levan filters at the end we end up with
levan filters at the end we end up with three stop bands of death coefficients
three stop bands of death coefficients if this one is the details in the
if this one is the details in the horizontal Direction vertical and
horizontal Direction vertical and diagonal region and this part is the
diagonal region and this part is the scoring conditions that we have which
scoring conditions that we have which gives us the formation in the universe
gives us the formation in the universe space now
space now this can again will be composed again
this can again will be composed again from wavelet coefficients and from
from wavelet coefficients and from killing coefficient and again and again
is called the last one is the weak note the parent-child relationship between
the parent-child relationship between the coefficients across each each of
the coefficients across each each of these have four other children until we
would like to use this structure that we have an incorporated in the prior in
have an incorporated in the prior in order to reduce
order to reduce of measurement that are required for a
of measurement that are required for a basically a good accuracy reconstruction
basically a good accuracy reconstruction of the signal this has been previously
of the signal this has been previously used in other jobs like compressing
used in other jobs like compressing email compressing data or texture
email compressing data or texture synthesis or image denoising and we
synthesis or image denoising and we would like to take this product exploit
would like to take this product exploit the structure of these wavelet countries
the structure of these wavelet countries and use them in our vision inversion one
and use them in our vision inversion one thing about the weblog coefficients is
thing about the weblog coefficients is that the nuke digital web web
that the nuke digital web web coefficient tend to cluster together and
coefficient tend to cluster together and they apparently a negligible coefficient
they apparently a negligible coefficient it children with high probability would
it children with high probability would be 0 trees it means that the parent is
be 0 trees it means that the parent is doing children is do as 200 so forth and
we can structure using hidden markov trees in multiple trees we can say that
trees in multiple trees we can say that all right
all right so we have two types of coefficients one
so we have two types of coefficients one unintelligible coefficient you ever try
unintelligible coefficient you ever try for the significant coefficients we can
for the significant coefficients we can draw the color negligible coefficient
draw the color negligible coefficient from Adelphia with a low variance and we
from Adelphia with a low variance and we can draw the coefficient significant
can draw the coefficient significant coefficients we will from a Gaussian
coefficients we will from a Gaussian with a larger variance and to define
with a larger variance and to define this parent-child relationship we can
this parent-child relationship we can use a markup representation across the
use a markup representation across the skills so this mark appropriate
skills so this mark appropriate transition can be defined using a two by
transition can be defined using a two by two matrix P IJ where I stands for the
two matrix P IJ where I stands for the state of the
state of the pick up the child so tij for example kid
pick up the child so tij for example kid Lolo is the probability of child and
Lolo is the probability of child and parents both being in the new state
parents both being in the new state which is a high probability so we show
which is a high probability so we show it with one - extra everyone being a
it with one - extra everyone being a small positive number if parent
small positive number if parent coefficients is negligible its children
coefficients is negligible its children would be negligible as well in the tree
would be negligible as well in the tree we are assuming that our observations
we are assuming that our observations are our coefficients but in compressive
are our coefficients but in compressive sensing our measurements are the random
sensing our measurements are the random projections of these weather
projections of these weather coefficients and we don't observe these
coefficients and we don't observe these coefficients directively directly
coefficients directively directly alright assuming our signal is called X
alright assuming our signal is called X we and we have a match basically bevit
we and we have a match basically bevit the composition make sure it matrix Phi
the composition make sure it matrix Phi we apply this and we get overridden with
we apply this and we get overridden with coefficients and our measurements are
coefficients and our measurements are random projections of theta M which
random projections of theta M which includes the significant coefficients
includes the significant coefficients the negligible ones are set to zero and
the negligible ones are set to zero and the other one is theta e where the
the other one is theta e where the natural significant ones are set to zero
natural significant ones are set to zero and it only has the negligible one and
and it only has the negligible one and we also assume that we have noise in our
we also assume that we have noise in our measurement so we can start this to our
measurement so we can start this to our and right there at n which is the noise
and right there at n which is the noise it can be it is represented with a
it can be it is represented with a Gaussian with some precision is the
Gaussian with some precision is the significant wavelet coefficients first
significant wavelet coefficients first their locations second their values and
[Applause] so the posterior distribution of this
so the posterior distribution of this would be inferred using the updated
would be inferred using the updated measurement we now this structure is a
measurement we now this structure is a structure information that we would like
structure information that we would like to incorporate in the prior our two
to incorporate in the prior our two things
things the parent-child relationship second one
the parent-child relationship second one this person's of the wavelet coefficient
this person's of the wavelet coefficient one can define it using these functions
one can define it using these functions that prior which is a combined
that prior which is a combined distribution and which combined
distribution and which combined attribution which is a built in here is
attribution which is a built in here is a match point and and and is a Gaussian
a match point and and and is a Gaussian so we are saying that our rebel
so we are saying that our rebel coefficients are drawn from there are
coefficients are drawn from there are either zero with probability one minus
either zero with probability one minus PI I or they are drawn from a Gaussian
PI I or they are drawn from a Gaussian distribution with some variance with
distribution with some variance with probability PI okay so
probability PI okay so this first part represents the zero
this first part represents the zero coefficient and this part represents the
coefficient and this part represents the significant nonzero coefficient so each
significant nonzero coefficient so each of these where are corresponds with one
of these where are corresponds with one of the guardians that really defined we
of the guardians that really defined we were talking about in the hidden markov
were talking about in the hidden markov tree and here the coefficients in the
tree and here the coefficients in the low state are set to zero as opposed to
low state are set to zero as opposed to hidden markov tree model which is what
hidden markov tree model which is what each was drawn from a Gaussian with low
each was drawn from a Gaussian with low variance now the children will be zero
variance now the children will be zero using some dependences across on the
using some dependences across on the mixing way spike and prior in terms of
mixing way spike and prior in terms of using hot water which is element product
using hot water which is element product we have W equals W times W is the
we have W equals W times W is the coefficient drawn from a Gaussian
coefficient drawn from a Gaussian distribution as Z is a Bernoulli
distribution as Z is a Bernoulli distribution which is the one or series
distribution which is the one or series the one says that
the one says that okay the rebel coalition is in a high
okay the rebel coalition is in a high state and co-state status to low state
state and co-state status to low state instead set to zero and the power in our
instead set to zero and the power in our model we would like to define this
model we would like to define this mixing waste their precision parameter
mixing waste their precision parameter and precision for the noise we can
and precision for the noise we can summarize the model as following we have
summarize the model as following we have our theta it is the product of WS d / w
our theta it is the product of WS d / w is valid position from from a Gaussian
is valid position from from a Gaussian distribution
distribution z
z is defining whether they are in high or
is defining whether they are in high or low and it's the Bernoulli distribution
low and it's the Bernoulli distribution and pies are the over basically mixing
and pies are the over basically mixing mixing waste now we can divide the types
mixing waste now we can divide the types of mixing weights into four categories
of mixing weights into four categories one is the mixing rate for the filling
one is the mixing rate for the filling coefficient second one is the mixing
coefficient second one is the mixing rate for their real note and third one
rate for their real note and third one is the mixing weight toward the all
is the mixing weight toward the all other river conditions that have nonzero
other river conditions that have nonzero basically parents and lastly is the ones
basically parents and lastly is the ones that have zero parent each of these are
that have zero parent each of these are defined using from hyper trenchers which
defined using from hyper trenchers which like to by choosing these hyper
like to by choosing these hyper parameters they would like to say okay
parameters they would like to say okay what idea we have about the scaling
what idea we have about the scaling coefficient normally nonzero and we
coefficient normally nonzero and we would like something clustered around
would like something clustered around for the same type of distribution so the
for the same type of distribution so the ones that have zero parent we would like
ones that have zero parent we would like them to be clustered around 0 and for
them to be clustered around 0 and for the other ones we that have nonzero
the other ones we that have nonzero parents we don't impose any prior
parents we don't impose any prior information they can be anything here is
information they can be anything here is a graphical representation of the
a graphical representation of the problem dr. model see these are the
problem dr. model see these are the hyper temperatures that we have with
hyper temperatures that we have with this hyper parameters are used basically
this hyper parameters are used basically to define the mixing rate and these are
to define the mixing rate and these are for defining the per station and V is
for defining the per station and V is our observation here so I describe these
our observation here so I describe these clips right on
clips right on formulations like all right so the
formulations like all right so the posterior distribution parameter here is
posterior distribution parameter here is Theta and this is improv using the
Theta and this is improv using the observed data from overseas measurements
observed data from overseas measurements and we can find the posterior
and we can find the posterior distribution for this using some method
distribution for this using some method like a variational Bayesian method
like a variational Bayesian method Markov chain Monte Carlo in a Markov
Markov chain Monte Carlo in a Markov chain Monte Carlo gives a more accurate
chain Monte Carlo gives a more accurate solution and it is basically
solution and it is basically computationally very expensive on the
computationally very expensive on the other hand variational based give us a
other hand variational based give us a sum and good approximation to the
sum and good approximation to the solution and it's fast and it has
solution and it's fast and it has convergence criterion and defined which
convergence criterion and defined which approximate the true posterior and we
approximate the true posterior and we have some lower bound f which
have some lower bound f which approximates the what the trail of
approximates the what the trail of likelihood and we do iterations until
likelihood and we do iterations until our little about approaches the DP one
our little about approaches the DP one and the relative reconstruction error is
and the relative reconstruction error is calculating is calculated using this
alright so here's the first image it's a hundred 28 128 image and thousand
hundred 28 128 image and thousand measurements have been used we can't
measurements have been used we can't basically it's decomposed and then the
basically it's decomposed and then the first coefficient story we constructed
first coefficient story we constructed and the image is recovered and this is
and the image is recovered and this is the relative error second image is
the relative error second image is tilted forward by support estimate and
tilted forward by support estimate and 2500 measurements have been used for
2500 measurements have been used for this test
this test and the last one is a 32 by 32 image
and the last one is a 32 by 32 image which has been decomposed using two
which has been decomposed using two chocolate reconstructed and then this is
chocolate reconstructed and then this is the error and we have used 600
the error and we have used 600 measurements for this all right these
measurements for this all right these are the references and thank you very
are the references and thank you very much any question
hello all visit Tina and I am doing my present
present on the pairwise chose Michael Chang
on the pairwise chose Michael Chang actually I produced a paper by the
actually I produced a paper by the grooving the Stanford University awarded
grooving the Stanford University awarded more than they published it in to me
more than they published it in to me next compliment 2016 which is a you know
next compliment 2016 which is a you know the model the model discrete choice
the model the model discrete choice models and there are developing gates
models and there are developing gates now in California
now in California Caltech used to Berkeley example
Caltech used to Berkeley example University and you will see actually I
University and you will see actually I want to first of all to I want to bring
want to first of all to I want to bring the motivation about because models
the motivation about because models actually the growing the dataset
actually the growing the dataset captaining the choice capturing the
captaining the choice capturing the human children in television especially
human children in television especially some motivation and some cost for the
some motivation and some cost for the increase meant of the
increase meant of the choice model in order to escape from the
choice model in order to escape from the traditional choice period accent for
traditional choice period accent for example regularity or stochastic and
example regularity or stochastic and Lucius church action so I want to
Lucius church action so I want to discuss the motivations for introducing
discuss the motivations for introducing this model prepare watch was Markov
this model prepare watch was Markov chain is gently model it is inferential
chain is gently model it is inferential interactive graphical model and it does
interactive graphical model and it does not show me mention axiom producer
not show me mention axiom producer active and insisted upon the foundation
active and insisted upon the foundation of action extraction so this discrete
of action extraction so this discrete choice models destroyed and actually
choice models destroyed and actually predicted the decision between victim
alternatives and the applications or consumer purchasing decisions and
consumer purchasing decisions and community changes in the mode for
community changes in the mode for transportation to long available options
transportation to long available options so there is a pressing need for
so there is a pressing need for practical model capable of is describing
practical model capable of is describing and predicting the choice behaviour
so one of the volunteer very actually arguably one of the most important of
arguably one of the most important of these excellent to our solutions Church
these excellent to our solutions Church axiom which is known as the independence
axiom which is known as the independence of irrelevant alternatives
so it's example we applied this axiom on the substance alternatives and Smith
the substance alternatives and Smith even broader universe you we want to
even broader universe you we want to define some probabilities let pas PD
define some probabilities let pas PD process a chosen from the best beginner
process a chosen from the best beginner as the best with the substrate view and
as the best with the substrate view and peds the problem chosen a fine chosen
peds the problem chosen a fine chosen from these eight events for example we
from these eight events for example we have two elements there are two
have two elements there are two important statement English exam each P
important statement English exam each P AV is equal to zero then pas will be 0
AV is equal to zero then pas will be 0 for all contain and B the progress of
for all contain and B the progress of choosing and from you condition on the
choosing and from you condition on the choice line is equal to 3/8 so another
choice line is equal to 3/8 so another another model easy
another model easy Bradley turn loose model actually did
Bradley turn loose model actually did this model I referred it it's got some
this model I referred it it's got some idea about the rank blocking in detail
idea about the rank blocking in detail comparison so it has been published in
comparison so it has been published in 1956 it actually define the PAE
1956 it actually define the PAE and gamma I over gamma a plus gamma
and gamma I over gamma a plus gamma before latent quality parameters London
before latent quality parameters London gamma I and he resulting
gamma I and he resulting logit model employee
logit model employee Visconti parameter gamma i for each i
Visconti parameter gamma i for each i has the number of you so any model that
has the number of you so any model that satisfied the dilution axiom is a cool
satisfied the dilution axiom is a cool inequities
inequities mmm model so one consequence
mmm model so one consequence actually I am talking about the
actually I am talking about the different models traditional models and
different models traditional models and the consequences and then I want to
the consequences and then I want to preach the efficiency and to say that
preach the efficiency and to say that pigeons is doing a better job and a
pigeons is doing a better job and a great job in comparison to the
great job in comparison to the traditional choice model one consequence
traditional choice model one consequence of these lucious action model is a
of these lucious action model is a stochastic transitivity between
stochastic transitivity between alternatives chance dignity means for
alternatives chance dignity means for example we have two elements we have an
example we have two elements we have an a has a connection with the BBC we can
a has a connection with the BBC we can say that there is music relation between
say that there is music relation between a and C alternative so it's the
a and C alternative so it's the probability of PID greater than equals
probability of PID greater than equals 1/2 and also the for P then th means
1/2 and also the for P then th means equal to or greater than the marketing
equal to or greater than the marketing world ta bian BC a broad important class
world ta bian BC a broad important class of models in a study of the trade shows
of models in a study of the trade shows in this ranch house or us or random
in this ranch house or us or random utility models its affiliates each I at
utility models its affiliates each I at the member of the broader universe you
the member of the broader universe you and a random variable each I and it
and a random variable each I and it defines the probability of our children
defines the probability of our children from s as this expression probability of
from s as this expression probability of X greater than or equal to XJ for any J
X greater than or equal to XJ for any J at all um
at all um don't neither choice as in north the
don't neither choice as in north the Catholic transitivity so now the PNC
Catholic transitivity so now the PNC model it is computationally imple
model it is computationally imple conceptually and complicated simple and
conceptually and complicated simple and in fresh a tractable model there are
in fresh a tractable model there are some parameters we have some parameters
some parameters we have some parameters in this model the afterburner induced Qi
in this model the afterburner induced Qi generates matrix Q index value and also
generates matrix Q index value and also if this defines the P is the collection
if this defines the P is the collection probability of alternatives as the
probability of alternatives as the probability mass of the genetic eye of
probability mass of the genetic eye of take station and distribution of the
take station and distribution of the continuous time Markov chain the
continuous time Markov chain the stationary distribution actually the
stationary distribution actually the stationary distribution in the Mark of
stationary distribution in the Mark of change the probability which can be
change the probability which can be shown between Mexico and the in this
shown between Mexico and the in this virtual we have some problems with
virtual we have some problems with distribution coming to one and if if you
distribution coming to one and if if you multiply the Phi transpose to DQ between
multiply the Phi transpose to DQ between the rate matrix you get the you get
the rate matrix you get the you get depart so
depart so the station is the reason change to
the station is the reason change to found to satisfy the stationary
found to satisfy the stationary condition of the eminent likelihood
condition of the eminent likelihood function and establishing a strong
function and establishing a strong connection between another model and
connection between another model and though the pcrc model generalizes
though the pcrc model generalizes disconnection between terminal
disconnection between terminal remarketing this is the Shema did the
remarketing this is the Shema did the left side is the schematic view of the
left side is the schematic view of the markov chains four choices a and b BN c
markov chains four choices a and b BN c EST those arrows the thickness of those
EST those arrows the thickness of those arrows are the rate the rate of
arrows are the rate the rate of transition the right side is the
transition the right side is the assembly of these exactly these choices
assembly of these exactly these choices in the descrition triangle shape Vince
in the descrition triangle shape Vince transition rates so we define some
transition rates so we define some actually imposed some constraint here
actually imposed some constraint here which is a Qi they've lived through plus
which is a Qi they've lived through plus QJ r is equal to greater than 1 for all
QJ r is equal to greater than 1 for all fills IJ which is the reducibility in
fills IJ which is the reducibility in short the irreducibility in our model so
short the irreducibility in our model so given a set s and remember as a
given a set s and remember as a substitute view we want to know we can
substitute view we want to know we can control the Cure's constructors by
control the Cure's constructors by restricting you can do that but
restricting you can do that but retraining the rows and columns of q 2
retraining the rows and columns of q 2 elements instead and set the Q III as
elements instead and set the Q III as this expression and peopIe of us is
this expression and peopIe of us is these
these reaching the stationary distribution of
reaching the stationary distribution of people
people to change so the running the choice
to change so the running the choice probability P is which is equal to PI of
probability P is which is equal to PI of I we now want to show that the piece
I we now want to show that the piece density model is the del define so
density model is the del define so proposition one we want to show that
proposition one we want to show that these nice choice probabilities are
these nice choice probabilities are well-defined for the I as a member of as
well-defined for the I as a member of as an all-access as some of you this is
an all-access as some of you this is some sort of problem that in order to
some sort of problem that in order to prove it B we need to assume something
prove it B we need to assume something against the target that we want to prove
against the target that we want to prove and continually some contradiction so in
and continually some contradiction so in order to prove that this is well-defined
order to prove that this is well-defined I need to show that it there is just
I need to show that it there is just only one communication class we know
only one communication class we know that s finite so there must be on just
that s finite so there must be on just one communication class here so I know
one communication class here so I know that to me more than one through
that to me more than one through experimentation class but I know that
experimentation class but I know that face under a disability link constraint
face under a disability link constraint imposing a disability I know that Q I J
imposing a disability I know that Q I J plus 2 J I is greater than or equal to 1
plus 2 J I is greater than or equal to 1 and so at least one of these q IJ or two
and so at least one of these q IJ or two jurors should be strictly positive and
jurors should be strictly positive and this implies that there is there is some
this implies that there is there is some screeching distinct communication
screeching distinct communication classes and so
classes and so this is undetermined which would be done
this is undetermined which would be done through the transmission
through the transmission it's tricky positively which is the
it's tricky positively which is the contradictory and some note here is that
contradictory and some note here is that for the irreducibility argument this
for the irreducibility argument this expression should be positive not
expression should be positive not necessarily one as I as we brought in
necessarily one as I as we brought in the proof of our proposition so it could
the proof of our proposition so it could be some constrain like this and for some
be some constrain like this and for some positive it's belong and we can multiply
positive it's belong and we can multiply by the one origin as a constant and it
by the one origin as a constant and it does not affect our patient distribution
proposition to let gamma be the parameter of the detail mothering you to
parameter of the detail mothering you to chew IJ equal to gamma over gamma plus
chew IJ equal to gamma over gamma plus gamma J please can see progress
gamma J please can see progress experience or consistent because even
experience or consistent because even our model so we want to show that Pius s
our model so we want to show that Pius s is equal to gamma over the Manhattan
is equal to gamma over the Manhattan norm of the gamma which is the summation
norm of the gamma which is the summation of the gamma a gamma R for I equal to 1
of the gamma a gamma R for I equal to 1 to N so we want to show that sorry we
to N so we want to show that sorry we want to show that that pi is
want to show that that pi is interpretation distribution of
interpretation distribution of the chance to change but I will I want
the chance to change but I will I want to reach that PS transmission is equal
to reach that PS transmission is equal to zero so for this expression I have
to zero so for this expression I have this one so we can pull out this lambda
this one so we can pull out this lambda I and so we know the values of q ji q ji
I and so we know the values of q ji q ji and here so this is equal to zero that
and here so this is equal to zero that PI RS is always the additional
PI RS is always the additional distribution of the chain now I want to
distribution of the chain now I want to talk about some properties of this piece
talk about some properties of this piece unity we want to demonstrate that
unity we want to demonstrate that pigeons he exists this structure of the
pigeons he exists this structure of the fourth contract ability which implies
fourth contract ability which implies uniform expansion so for the universe
uniform expansion so for the universe slash and we should talk about two
slash and we should talk about two definitions first of all first of all it
definitions first of all first of all it is the definition of the copies for I
is the definition of the copies for I and J in a structure view we take that
and J in a structure view we take that iron general cookies with each other if
iron general cookies with each other if for all K as the member of s minus I
for all K as the member of s minus I minus J we have these two expressions
minus J we have these two expressions so because there are upper of example
so because there are upper of example choice of memories for K I didn't have
choice of memories for K I didn't have stuff perfectly identified tough stuff
stuff perfectly identified tough stuff he and K identical glands of milk so
he and K identical glands of milk so they say it's her niche content that the
they say it's her niche content that the probability that the reader uses a type
probability that the reader uses a type of beverage in this scenario it is the
of beverage in this scenario it is the same as if they was shown just only one
same as if they was shown just only one cup of some sort of the beverage and
cup of some sort of the beverage and regardless of the the values of k equal
regardless of the the values of k equal to or greater than one definition to is
to or greater than one definition to is the uniform expansion because there a
the uniform expansion because there a choice between an element in a set as
choice between an element in a set as one from Iowa one to iron one and
one from Iowa one to iron one and another choice promise that okay
another choice promise that okay containing K cookie love each of those
containing K cookie love each of those and n elements the axiom of uniform
and n elements the axiom of uniform expansion States as put each M and all K
expansion States as put each M and all K greater than or equal to 1 we have this
greater than or equal to 1 we have this expression
so we conclude that PTSD model only exhibiting more general property of
exhibiting more general property of contract ability which it's always
contract ability which it's always exhibit uniform expansion so me I want
exhibit uniform expansion so me I want to hear bring the preposition tree for
to hear bring the preposition tree for given gamma which is the lambda IJ let
given gamma which is the lambda IJ let a1 to a2 be a contractible partition for
a1 to a2 be a contractible partition for to PT and similar than you represented
to PT and similar than you represented by Q and Q Prime with the station
by Q and Q Prime with the station distribution Python then for any AI we
distribution Python then for any AI we have this expression or equivalently we
have this expression or equivalently we say that PI AI is equal to - hey Ari so
say that PI AI is equal to - hey Ari so for the proof these patrols that Q has
for the proof these patrols that Q has partition a 1 to a K with respect to
partition a 1 to a K with respect to gamma if it be composed the balanced
gamma if it be composed the balanced equation each law of the future virtue
equation each law of the future virtue which is equal to 0 for each member of a
which is equal to 0 for each member of a 1 without loss of generality we can
1 without loss of generality we can obtain these expression so
here noting that for the a small area in India the member of Capital Area and gay
India the member of Capital Area and gay and AJ is equal to lambda IJ here we can
and AJ is equal to lambda IJ here we can we can actually decompose it
we can actually decompose it multivariate each coil 60 each of these
multivariate each coil 60 each of these terms in this expression and then coming
terms in this expression and then coming over act as a member of a one we we will
over act as a member of a one we we will reach this this long expression the
reach this this long expression the leftmost Titanic II studies equal so
leftmost Titanic II studies equal so this one and this one so we have we can
this one and this one so we have we can get the PA one which which makes the pay
get the PA one which which makes the pay feed upon a one as the solution to
balanced equation the above proposition and the concert the contract the ability
and the concert the contract the ability of efficiency model so it implies that
of efficiency model so it implies that the PDMP model exhibits uniform
the PDMP model exhibits uniform expansion
Indians inference and prediction part our ultimate goal is through berating it
our ultimate goal is through berating it model to make predictions using past
model to make predictions using past choices from different subsets to
choices from different subsets to predict future choices there are three
predict future choices there are three part three accept India in the
part three accept India in the prediction part leaving the no blank
prediction part leaving the no blank function which is the rate matrix Q
function which is the rate matrix Q given a choice data collection of the
given a choice data collection of the form T where the I K is the member of SK
form T where the I K is the member of SK was the eyes and chosen from escaped
was the eyes and chosen from escaped investigating the ability of learnt each
investigating the ability of learnt each day and tomorrow to make choice
day and tomorrow to make choice prediction on empirical data benchmark
prediction on empirical data benchmark against learn ml and then interpreting
against learn ml and then interpreting the informative promises to have for the
the informative promises to have for the muscular fluids
muscular fluids let's define T is as the number of items
let's define T is as the number of items number of times in the data that I was
number of times in the data that I was chosen from the success I also see it as
chosen from the success I also see it as the number of times that X was chosen
the number of times that X was chosen for each as discussed above you so there
for each as discussed above you so there are two recordings here for each as if P
are two recordings here for each as if P is a Q is the probability for the
is a Q is the probability for the selection of s as a function of the rate
selection of s as a function of the rate market q and after dropping all the
market q and after dropping all the constants the loaf likely would have Q
constants the loaf likely would have Q given the data T which have been here
given the data T which have been here derived from the probability
derived from the probability function of the multinomial distribution
function of the multinomial distribution which is and we get this expression and
which is and we get this expression and for the recording to the 45th entry
for the recording to the 45th entry model we have we want to be we have D
model we have we want to be we have D the purifier is the attention
the purifier is the attention distribution for the continuous time
distribution for the continuous time Markov chain and actually they have they
Markov chain and actually they have they have used the non taped problem
have used the non taped problem optimization problem and if anyone is
optimization problem and if anyone is interested just for the informational
interested just for the informational thing that they have used the SLS Q
thing that they have used the SLS Q programming the credential it is for
programming the credential it is for programming in order to optimize them
programming in order to optimize them they use the type file that minimize a
they use the type file that minimize a function in the Python or you can use
function in the Python or you can use the minimize the method the security
there the empirical data results they evaluate the procedure and three
evaluate the procedure and three empirical data sets from surveillance
empirical data sets from surveillance survey of Transportation around the San
survey of Transportation around the San Francisco Bay Area
Francisco Bay Area the San Francisco war is contained
the San Francisco war is contained twelve thousand twenty nine of the
twelve thousand twenty nine of the relation consists of community options
relation consists of community options and the choice mode on a given community
and the choice mode on a given community and as we shall contain 3157
and as we shall contain 3157 observations each consistent choice set
observations each consistent choice set of transportation alternatives available
of transportation alternatives available to individuals traveling and returning
to individuals traveling and returning from a shopping center
for the training for turning our modern observation she trained and evaluate
observation she trained and evaluate unattested
unattested teachers this is be the bearer of
teachers this is be the bearer of teacher and teachers that we want to
teacher and teachers that we want to evaluate actually comparative kitchens
evaluate actually comparative kitchens amount of a conditional be others model
amount of a conditional be others model beach in in this expression the Q
beach in in this expression the Q hottest teacher an estimate for view
hottest teacher an estimate for view obtained from observation of kitchen and
obtained from observation of kitchen and P tilde is theta is equal to cos
P tilde is theta is equal to cos teachers who were skilled as of today
teachers who were skilled as of today which is the empirical probability of I
which is the empirical probability of I was selected from as among of the ratio
was selected from as among of the ratio cheetahs this is actually I have done it
cheetahs this is actually I have done it for first of all for some Frances to
for first of all for some Frances to work data and first the number of
work data and first the number of simulations wrong it's ten this is the
simulations wrong it's ten this is the comparison between the error versus the
comparison between the error versus the percentage of data used for training
percentage of data used for training from five to seventy five percent
from five to seventy five percent nineteen seventy five percent of the
nineteen seventy five percent of the data for training and 25 for the test
data for training and 25 for the test and fifteen see model is doing great job
and fifteen see model is doing great job hearing in comparison to mmm a nano
hearing in comparison to mmm a nano mixer manner and his are they the heat
mixer manner and his are they the heat match for the forty probability for each
match for the forty probability for each side actually horizontal and vertical we
side actually horizontal and vertical we have dick
have dick we have picked pale of the options which
we have picked pale of the options which are driving alone and sharing around
are driving alone and sharing around with one another first to work in public
with one another first to work in public transit biking and carpooling with at
transit biking and carpooling with at least two others and we are showing the
least two others and we are showing the probability of need relative risk rate
probability of need relative risk rate between pairs of items as well as how
between pairs of items as well as how the total rates between first and
the total rates between first and personal tutor editing other page here I
personal tutor editing other page here I did the simulation for number of equal
did the simulation for number of equal to 50 so when we activate when we
to 50 so when we activate when we increase the number of stimulation it
increase the number of stimulation it will be so in the previous one with the
will be so in the previous one with the tenth simulation we see here that first
tenth simulation we see here that first of our TNT model starts with little more
of our TNT model starts with little more but then we increase the increase the
but then we increase the increase the number of simulations they start on
number of simulations they start on something the same but after that
something the same but after that efficiency model in comparison to other
efficiency model in comparison to other mothers during the great job so even in
mothers during the great job so even in data with violations of iia that was the
data with violations of iia that was the that was known for the lucia first axiom
that was known for the lucia first axiom that i talked about lately which is the
that i talked about lately which is the independence relevant of alternatives
independence relevant of alternatives PMT does 20 to 30 percent better at
PMT does 20 to 30 percent better at prediction out-of-sample without
prediction out-of-sample without violations PT and is followed back to a
violations PT and is followed back to a manner and is it for san francisco shock
manner and is it for san francisco shock data and again visit for eight of eight
data and again visit for eight of eight actually ordered options and previous
actually ordered options and previous almost 60 so here again the 15 T model
almost 60 so here again the 15 T model is doing better than two other models
so which we can say that error on the data as the learning procedures applied
data as the learning procedures applied to increase the amount of data the
to increase the amount of data the results are averaged over 1,000
results are averaged over 1,000 different permutations of the data to be
different permutations of the data to be in the 7520 upon strain and text data
in the 7520 upon strain and text data prediction error on a 25 percent hold of
prediction error on a 25 percent hold of the data for the PNC M&amp;L and mmm mix
the data for the PNC M&amp;L and mmm mix terminal models have been shown and 50
terminal models have been shown and 50 mg mother's these improvement of thirty
mg mother's these improvement of thirty five point nine percent and twenty four
five point nine percent and twenty four point five percent in prediction error
point five percent in prediction error over M&amp;L and mix terminal respectively
over M&amp;L and mix terminal respectively when training on seven five percent as a
when training on seven five percent as a danger for this summary we introduced a
danger for this summary we introduced a very wise choice Markov chain models and
very wise choice Markov chain models and the speed choice which define selection
the speed choice which define selection properties according to the assertion
properties according to the assertion distribution of a continuous time Markov
distribution of a continuous time Markov chains the flexibility for which the
chains the flexibility for which the flexibility we demonstrate that tthe
flexibility we demonstrate that tthe model exhibits desirable structure was
model exhibits desirable structure was preceding the uniform expansion property
preceding the uniform expansion property previously found only in the M&amp;L model
previously found only in the M&amp;L model and elimination by aspects model the
and elimination by aspects model the working on states that the kitchen
working on states that the kitchen remodel exhibits concern
remodel exhibits concern constructability which implies uniform
constructability which implies uniform expansion we have to show that the
expansion we have to show that the pigeons amount of offers
pigeons amount of offers thenceforward inference through Emily
thenceforward inference through Emily and that will learn the agency model
and that will learn the agency model predicts
predicts improve her choice it will be
improve her choice it will be significantly higher utility the respect
significantly higher utility the respect to two other models
to two other models for the future because this is a very
for the future because this is a very novel idea by the sample group the
novel idea by the sample group the possibility and tractability of the PCs
possibility and tractability of the PCs the model opens up many computing
the model opens up many computing research directions the efficiency of
research directions the efficiency of the TMC model suggests exploring other
the TMC model suggests exploring other effective parameterization for q the
effective parameterization for q the rate matrix including developing L
rate matrix including developing L special methods which excludability
special methods which excludability there are two open computational
there are two open computational questions such as extremely large lining
questions such as extremely large lining the large Luud maximization using
the large Luud maximization using gradients of the implicit function
gradients of the implicit function definitions and these are the references
definitions and these are the references for for this room thank you
[Applause]