all right we're changing subject today we're gonna talk more on variational
we're gonna talk more on variational methods but there are some new methods
before I start the lectures from the last from last Thursday and Tuesday
last from last Thursday and Tuesday they're updated there on the web
they're updated there on the web it took me lots of times to fix about
it took me lots of times to fix about the 1000 formulas so I hope someone will
the 1000 formulas so I hope someone will reach them okay they have a lots of
reach them okay they have a lots of valuable information some things we do
valuable information some things we do not cover so please take a look all
not cover so please take a look all right so maybe they because today I'm
right so maybe they because today I'm gonna be jumping on this particular
gonna be jumping on this particular lecture now I am NOT going to emphasize
lecture now I am NOT going to emphasize the biggest end of what exactly the
the biggest end of what exactly the local variation left to start but I will
local variation left to start but I will give you some sort of new ideas okay
give you some sort of new ideas okay excuse me a review so we can deviate a
excuse me a review so we can deviate a little bit from what we know so we the
little bit from what we know so we the key ingredient in variational method was
key ingredient in variational method was we have some data we have some of the
we have some data we have some of the ativ latent variables with each data
ativ latent variables with each data point and we wrote the this is the point
point and we wrote the this is the point fundamental identity the long likelihood
fundamental identity the long likelihood being the lower bound lost the distance
being the lower bound lost the distance between Q and P and what is important to
between Q and P and what is important to remember is both the definition of the
remember is both the definition of the lower bound to have the path that
lower bound to have the path that clearly have the KL distance between Q
clearly have the KL distance between Q and P because this distance is not
and P because this distance is not symmetric okay
symmetric okay so Q is the variational approximation of
so Q is the variational approximation of the posterior of the latent variables
the posterior of the latent variables okay P is this distribution and the
okay P is this distribution and the lower bound basically is the expectation
lower bound basically is the expectation with respect to the validation of
with respect to the validation of distribution of this block here that
distribution of this block here that involves the joining of likelihood and
involves the joining of likelihood and the variation distribution and we have
the variation distribution and we have seen that this is an easy way to to work
seen that this is an easy way to to work with because the joint log likelihood is
with because the joint log likelihood is usually a very
usually a very you know it's an illusion or the
you know it's an illusion or the exponential primal poverty of
exponential primal poverty of distributions but if you must analyze
distributions but if you must analyze throughout the distribution you get to
throughout the distribution you get to be a Gaussian mix for example something
be a Gaussian mix for example something that is not computationally easy to work
that is not computationally easy to work with
with okay so this is the lower bound this is
okay so this is the lower bound this is the KL distance I'm going to come back
the KL distance I'm going to come back to this equation shortly but you know in
to this equation shortly but you know in some ways you can also consider the
some ways you can also consider the joint log likelihood as being the UH
joint log likelihood as being the UH normalized version of the posterior okay
normalized version of the posterior okay so if you see it like this then you can
so if you see it like this then you can immediately see and I have this for
immediately see and I have this for another slide but you can write this as
another slide but you can write this as minus the KL distance between Q and they
minus the KL distance between Q and they are normalized posterior usually you
are normalized posterior usually you don't see that in the literature but I
don't see that in the literature but I think I'm going to make use about in the
think I'm going to make use about in the lectures today all right okay so this
lectures today all right okay so this methodology basically we apply to lots
methodology basically we apply to lots of problems okay and it comes with
of problems okay and it comes with different names but basically
different names but basically variational base is what you see in the
variational base is what you see in the literature so today we're going to try
literature so today we're going to try to introduce some new methods where
to introduce some new methods where instead of minimizing the distance
instead of minimizing the distance between Q and P or maximizing this we
between Q and P or maximizing this we will try to minimize the opposite KL
will try to minimize the opposite KL distance the distance between P and Q
distance the distance between P and Q you say why not right I mean it's
you say why not right I mean it's distant and acceptable distance okay you
distant and acceptable distance okay you may argue about that why not
may argue about that why not minimize the opposite distance between P
minimize the opposite distance between P and Q some writing this explicitly here
and Q some writing this explicitly here as minus the actual posterior and this
as minus the actual posterior and this is the variation on distribution
is the variation on distribution obviously you can see that this is not
obviously you can see that this is not an easy integral to calculate because if
an easy integral to calculate because if you have to basically to take the
you have to basically to take the expectations of this with respect to the
expectations of this with respect to the exact posterior well right that's a
exact posterior well right that's a mistake here
mistake here that's right thank you so this is the
that's right thank you so this is the stone basically here we'll collect this
stone basically here we'll collect this right so effectively you have to take an
right so effectively you have to take an expectation with extract it with respect
expectation with extract it with respect to the exact posterior which you don't
to the exact posterior which you don't know that's what we need to approximate
know that's what we need to approximate however we're going to do some
however we're going to do some one-stroke a list and we will see that
one-stroke a list and we will see that it leads to a whole category of
it leads to a whole category of algorithms that they're extremely
algorithms that they're extremely popular in the velocity of problems
popular in the velocity of problems especially in graphs that go the name
especially in graphs that go the name expectation propagation and and very
expectation propagation and and very various variants of love okay so we will
various variants of love okay so we will see that today I think I have shown you
see that today I think I have shown you this trivial example so that you can
this trivial example so that you can keep your eyes on so this is sort of a
keep your eyes on so this is sort of a distribution that it's a man-made
distribution that it's a man-made distribution some gaussian terms some
distribution some gaussian terms some sigmoid thing and we try to approximate
sigmoid thing and we try to approximate this with different things that we have
this with different things that we have seen up to now in the class so let's say
seen up to now in the class so let's say this is the actual distribution this
this is the actual distribution this dark region this is the Laplace
dark region this is the Laplace approximation that we already have
approximation that we already have discussed it center around the mold and
discussed it center around the mold and this is I suppose this is the
this is I suppose this is the distribution that you get with
distribution that you get with variational based by minimizing the
variational based by minimizing the distance between Q and P and I'm going
distance between Q and P and I'm going to show you later on the literature on
to show you later on the literature on the top of this graph the same plot
the top of this graph the same plot but minimizing the distance between P
but minimizing the distance between P and Q and your set of things looking to
and Q and your set of things looking to be different I'm going to twist to the
be different I'm going to twist to the fundamental problem in variational
fundamental problem in variational methods we want to minimize the distance
methods we want to minimize the distance of Q from P over to maximized right to
of Q from P over to maximized right to maximize the lower bound and I just
maximize the lower bound and I just mentioned before
mentioned before that the lower bound is really nothing
that the lower bound is really nothing else but the KL distance between Q and V
else but the KL distance between Q and V are normalized for stereo debris does
are normalized for stereo debris does this look to you like the lower bound
this look to you like the lower bound without the minus I is that the lower
without the minus I is that the lower bound
bound without the - time so I plug in a minus
without the - time so I plug in a minus sign there right you can see that really
sign there right you can see that really this is the distance between Q and
this is the distance between Q and Kelvin EP for curly piece basically in a
Kelvin EP for curly piece basically in a normalize for stereo so this is just
normalize for stereo so this is just another way to look at it but I'm going
another way to look at it but I'm going to make use of this here if you expand
to make use of this here if you expand actually this problem if you basically
actually this problem if you basically get but this is equal to the distance
get but this is equal to the distance between Q and P plus some some constant
between Q and P plus some some constant term okay in organization tau so
term okay in organization tau so remember that with the lower bound you
remember that with the lower bound you can actually itself you can write it as
can actually itself you can write it as as you know as the KL distant and
as you know as the KL distant and introduced I'm going to jump a lot of
introduced I'm going to jump a lot of slides since you don't have a copy of
slides since you don't have a copy of the slides it doesn't matter so I'm
the slides it doesn't matter so I'm going to go long way down the road all
going to go long way down the road all right so we will discuss
right so we will discuss approximating procedures but in problems
approximating procedures but in problems that sort of graph theory thick so I'm
that sort of graph theory thick so I'm going to give you a simple setup where
going to give you a simple setup where we try that let's say we are coming from
we try that let's say we are coming from a Gaussian and we want to compute the
a Gaussian and we want to compute the unknown mean of the Gaussian and we put
unknown mean of the Gaussian and we put some prior on that main stroke basically
some prior on that main stroke basically the posterior is written as the prior
the posterior is written as the prior times the likelihood which is looking
times the likelihood which is looking like that so basically rocky elliptic
like that so basically rocky elliptic version of this problem is using a
version of this problem is using a factor graph you have
factor graph you have the fact of knowledge that encodes the
the fact of knowledge that encodes the probability of the prior yard and then
probability of the prior yard and then for its likely to tell me have another
for its likely to tell me have another factor that connects this is a meal with
factor that connects this is a meal with the data X I that you get okay so we
the data X I that you get okay so we have something I Gotham and this would
have something I Gotham and this would be fundamental flow problems today when
be fundamental flow problems today when you try to estimate here now we'll try
you try to estimate here now we'll try to approximate this notice that the
to approximate this notice that the example still utilizes alright so
example still utilizes alright so basically here compensates for prices
basically here compensates for prices because we collect data one at the time
because we collect data one at the time so P of x1 given n P of x2 given M but
so P of x1 given n P of x2 given M but you can think almost in every proven BC
you can think almost in every proven BC graphical model thing there is a
graphical model thing there is a factorization so in in directed graphs
factorization so in in directed graphs maybe we fertilized on the probability
maybe we fertilized on the probability of the nodes given their parents in you
of the nodes given their parents in you know in undirected graphs we factorize
know in undirected graphs we factorize as potential server connected
as potential server connected specification and at least now can we
specification and at least now can we actually figure out a way to come up
actually figure out a way to come up with some approximation of this
with some approximation of this posteriors in a way that somehow mimics
posteriors in a way that somehow mimics this factorization right obviously if
this factorization right obviously if the exact distribution looks like that
the exact distribution looks like that maybe it only makes sense to have some
maybe it only makes sense to have some in this factorization for the variation
in this factorization for the variation of distribution so this is what we're
of distribution so this is what we're going to try to take advantage today
going to try to take advantage today okay telling me it will issue an example
okay telling me it will issue an example which we will play with later this again
which we will play with later this again estimating the mean of the distribution
estimating the mean of the distribution so we sample from a Gaussian this is the
so we sample from a Gaussian this is the Gaussian but actually we the actual
Gaussian but actually we the actual distribution we show we want to compute
distribution we show we want to compute this mean theta like in the previous
this mean theta like in the previous problem but actually the distribution we
problem but actually the distribution we sample is not just clean Gaussian but
sample is not just clean Gaussian but this Gaussian plus some
this Gaussian plus some all right so this is what's called the
all right so this is what's called the clattering problem so if you can think
clattering problem so if you can think of you having this Gaussian you really
of you having this Gaussian you really want to escalate this rain but the
want to escalate this rain but the samples you get are basically either
samples you get are basically either going to come from the actual Gaussian
going to come from the actual Gaussian what we're going to just noise he went
what we're going to just noise he went to the estimation of the parameter theta
to the estimation of the parameter theta so in this problem ranges to compute the
so in this problem ranges to compute the first order is basically the
first order is basically the unnormalized posterior as the prior
unnormalized posterior as the prior times the likelihood and H of an active
times the likelihood and H of an active in terms is a Gaussian mixture so if you
in terms is a Gaussian mixture so if you have n data points and you expand this
have n data points and you expand this product there you're going to get 2 to
product there you're going to get 2 to the N so the state can be very
the N so the state can be very complicated okay so can we actually do
complicated okay so can we actually do with variational methods in a way that
with variational methods in a way that this is computationally easy to work
this is computationally easy to work with
with okay so we will discuss this problem
okay so we will discuss this problem today which fella is like okay this has
today which fella is like okay this has lots of substance and I think what's
lots of substance and I think what's probably the only theoretical slide in
probably the only theoretical slide in the North today
the North today stop trying to pay attention we remove
stop trying to pay attention we remove the skin or everything we're going to do
the skin or everything we're going to do today approximations we using can be the
today approximations we using can be the whole distribution or maybe some factor
whole distribution or maybe some factor in the approximation we're going to
in the approximation we're going to assume that those factors are coming
assume that those factors are coming from the exponential family so in this
from the exponential family so in this particular case I write the distribution
particular case I write the distribution Q of G given some natural parameters
Q of G given some natural parameters theta in the generic form of the
theta in the generic form of the exponential form distributions G of Z of
exponential form distributions G of Z of the sufficient statistics and the rest
the sufficient statistics and the rest of basically you know some normalization
of basically you know some normalization term and H of Z term Vista is the form
term and H of Z term Vista is the form we used for the exponential family okay
we used for the exponential family okay a lot includes a lot of different
a lot includes a lot of different distributions
distributions all right so let's go to the new problem
all right so let's go to the new problem which is the minimization of the
which is the minimization of the distance from the actual distribution P
distance from the actual distribution P and the various distribution Q but here
and the various distribution Q but here we assume that fewest experience a
we assume that fewest experience a family distribution so remember the case
family distribution so remember the case distance is minus P that can repeat all
distance is minus P that can repeat all right so what is this coming so I have
right so what is this coming so I have to calculate this you have to take - the
to calculate this you have to take - the expectations with respect to P or the
expectations with respect to P or the norm of K over V right and not pay the
norm of K over V right and not pay the denominator basically with this P will
denominator basically with this P will give me a constant because it doesn't
give me a constant because it doesn't depend on Q so I'm going to get my nose
depend on Q so I'm going to get my nose the expression of the love of this so
the expression of the love of this so and we're looking at all the terms that
and we're looking at all the terms that depend you know here on Z and ether so
depend you know here on Z and ether so we're going to have minus log of Z and
we're going to have minus log of Z and the exponential will give me e 2
the exponential will give me e 2 transpose and the expectation with
transpose and the expectation with respect to P of Z that's the exact
respect to P of Z that's the exact distribution of you see we agree that
distribution of you see we agree that this is basically the kale this one's a
this is basically the kale this one's a lot using that view
right again in the film distance there's a minus sign so - be a global queue
a minus sign so - be a global queue avert this or you're going to get minus
avert this or you're going to get minus the expectation of the scripted to pee
the expectation of the scripted to pee or belongeth - all right so we take
or belongeth - all right so we take global queue expectation with a minus
global queue expectation with a minus sign you get that okay so we want to
sign you get that okay so we want to find the parameters theta that minimizes
find the parameters theta that minimizes this - reverse camber verbs and so
this - reverse camber verbs and so you're going to take the derivative with
you're going to take the derivative with respect to it and you're going to set
respect to it and you're going to set them equal to zero so you're going to
them equal to zero so you're going to have the gradient of this term with
have the gradient of this term with respect to e theta so this is dragon
respect to e theta so this is dragon again respect to theta and this will
again respect to theta and this will give you the expectation of U of Z with
give you the expectation of U of Z with respect to P of Z and object forgot to
respect to P of Z and object forgot to put here the expectation of U of T okay
put here the expectation of U of T okay so actually equate this equation here
so actually equate this equation here should look like no actually this is
should look like no actually this is something different
something different so here we have to put brackets of U of
so here we have to put brackets of U of Z okay the calculation of theta is start
Z okay the calculation of theta is start out the optimal ETA is such that the
out the optimal ETA is such that the gradient - the gradient of the love of G
gradient - the gradient of the love of G is the expectation of U with respect to
is the expectation of U with respect to the exact B of Z and the exactly of Z of
the exact B of Z and the exactly of Z of course is not know and I'm not going to
course is not know and I'm not going to prove it
prove it you can look at the notes from last
you can look at the notes from last semester you can go to Wikipedia for
semester you can go to Wikipedia for exponential family distributions you
exponential family distributions you include is an exponential family
include is an exponential family distribution you can show for any Q in
distribution you can show for any Q in this family that - the gradient of the
this family that - the gradient of the log of G is the expectation of the
log of G is the expectation of the sufficient statistics with respect to
sufficient statistics with respect to key of G
key of G anybody knows
the combination is literally one line okay so for any district there's no
okay so for any district there's no approximation here if I have
approximation here if I have distribution from the exponential comedy
distribution from the exponential comedy and you take the expectation of the
and you take the expectation of the sufficient statistics with respect to Q
sufficient statistics with respect to Q alright this comes to me minus the
alright this comes to me minus the gradient of the log of G and you can
gradient of the log of G and you can extend this actually to higher
extend this actually to higher derivatives as well you know for
derivatives as well you know for calculating all the moments for any
calculating all the moments for any distribution from the exponential
distribution from the exponential probability and this is an identity that
probability and this is an identity that we computed by minimizing this reversed
we computed by minimizing this reversed km diversity okay this is a problem we
km diversity okay this is a problem we want to find all right so that we
want to find all right so that we minimize the diversity elevator so you
minimize the diversity elevator so you can see this is minus gradient of log of
can see this is minus gradient of log of G minus gradient of G so you can put
G minus gradient of G so you can put this expectation perspective P of Z of
this expectation perspective P of Z of the uz the term that was here all right
the uz the term that was here all right equal to the expectation of U of Z with
equal to the expectation of U of Z with respect to Q of Z and then you get this
respect to Q of Z and then you get this nice identity here which is our final
nice identity here which is our final result and that result says that the
result and that result says that the expectation of U of Z with respect to
expectation of U of Z with respect to the approximate distribution is the same
the approximate distribution is the same as the expectation of U of Z with
as the expectation of U of Z with respect to the exact distribution and
respect to the exact distribution and obviously you can push it further and
obviously you can push it further and you use second order moment you can
you use second order moment you can solve at the variant of your Z with
solve at the variant of your Z with respect to Q of Z equal to the variance
respect to Q of Z equal to the variance of Y or Z with respect to P of Z etc etc
of Y or Z with respect to P of Z etc etc so the conclusion is that when you try
so the conclusion is that when you try to minimize the care they start from a
to minimize the care they start from a distribution P from another distribution
distribution P from another distribution Q in the exponential family all right
Q in the exponential family all right then
then the moments of P and Q must okay so the
the moments of P and Q must okay so the distribution is P and Q have the same
distribution is P and Q have the same office now if you may say so does not
office now if you may say so does not mean that because the moments of an
mean that because the moments of an exponential distribution really define
exponential distribution really define the distribution
the distribution but B is an exponential distribution of
but B is an exponential distribution of the various we're going to approximate
the various we're going to approximate to you whatever pierced with the family
to you whatever pierced with the family from the exponential distribution but we
from the exponential distribution but we know that family is going to be such
know that family is going to be such that the moments of the sufficient
that the moments of the sufficient statistics we have to map the moments
statistics we have to map the moments that we get with respect to the exact
that we get with respect to the exact distribution P of C now that's why you
distribution P of C now that's why you will see this in the literature
will see this in the literature sometimes people call this moment
sometimes people call this moment matching okay
matching okay we must be correct from what we have
we must be correct from what we have seen in afternoon support if you may
seen in afternoon support if you may keep safe because this exponential part
keep safe because this exponential part need to be a Gaussian right and you
need to be a Gaussian right and you trying to persuade with a Gaussian with
trying to persuade with a Gaussian with a Gaussian any distribution P of Z then
a Gaussian any distribution P of Z then then get surprised that Neil has to be
then get surprised that Neil has to be the mean of P of Z and that Sigma has to
the mean of P of Z and that Sigma has to be the variance of P of Z in a remind
be the variance of P of Z in a remind you sample actually in the earlier notes
you sample actually in the earlier notes very quickly lectures to go with right
very quickly lectures to go with right approximate the distribution P with a
approximate the distribution P with a Gaussian and I want you to go back and
Gaussian and I want you to go back and see when we minimize the distance of Q
see when we minimize the distance of Q from P not P from Q we will actually get
from P not P from Q we will actually get this result we got something else
this result we got something else you know if we minimize the distance of
you know if we minimize the distance of P until me and the moon will have to be
P until me and the moon will have to be the mean of Till's
the mean of Till's you know of P of Z and the signal have
you know of P of Z and the signal have to be the variance of beauty so changed
to be the variance of beauty so changed for example if you try to compute some
for example if you try to compute some parameters you know take the mean of the
parameters you know take the mean of the Gaussian right and this is the dark blue
Gaussian right and this is the dark blue is the exact distribution so when you
is the exact distribution so when you minimized with normal matching you will
minimized with normal matching you will get a Gaussian but basically looks like
get a Gaussian but basically looks like that okay so you get this with normal
that okay so you get this with normal much
much five let's make things are more
five let's make things are more difficult not by design but just you
difficult not by design but just you know like difficult things to be done
know like difficult things to be done guys before to sleep so we're going to
guys before to sleep so we're going to apply this idea moment watching
apply this idea moment watching basically and come up with a new method
basically and come up with a new method a very powerful method for doing
a very powerful method for doing inference in graph which is called
inference in graph which is called expectation propagation and you can make
expectation propagation and you can make this out envisioning what what the word
this out envisioning what what the word expectation propagation means the same
expectation propagation means the same way we did message passing in graphs
way we did message passing in graphs right the idea here that you see that
right the idea here that you see that wealth expectation maybe what we pass in
wealth expectation maybe what we pass in the graph for moment right because the
the graph for moment right because the local operation somehow we are going to
local operation somehow we are going to be doing would be minimization of some
be doing would be minimization of some variational exponential family
variational exponential family distribution ki Q so we would passing
distribution ki Q so we would passing moments and that's why the map is called
moments and that's why the map is called expectation propagation so we you know
expectation propagation so we you know this is the data we collected some
this is the data we collected some unknown parameter I'm going to do a
unknown parameter I'm going to do a different versions of this type of
different versions of this type of problems it's introducing sort of
problems it's introducing sort of different algorithms but right now in a
different algorithms but right now in a typical interest problem equal update of
typical interest problem equal update of the defense of our meters theta so this
the defense of our meters theta so this is basically Joint Distribution like
is basically Joint Distribution like that maybe the first term or the zero
that maybe the first term or the zero term you can make the prior and all the
term you can make the prior and all the other terms to likely to terms okay so
other terms to likely to terms okay so the idea here is we're going to assume
the idea here is we're going to assume basically that this likelihood temps for
basically that this likelihood temps for example okay they're easy to work
example okay they're easy to work distribution of gaussians right that's
distribution of gaussians right that's the whole idea of approximating
the whole idea of approximating something with a Gaussian is it's not
something with a Gaussian is it's not Gaussian start with so the exact
Gaussian start with so the exact posterior looks like this one over P of
posterior looks like this one over P of D times these factors and again I have
D times these factors and again I have incorporated here the prioritized part
incorporated here the prioritized part of themselves so remember that we're
of themselves so remember that we're going to be using that the first term in
going to be using that the first term in the consolidation especially the prior
the consolidation especially the prior the rest of the
the rest of the like adults this is the the
like adults this is the the normalization time okay I look at this
normalization time okay I look at this equation and we're gonna say well if you
equation and we're gonna say well if you know what we're gonna find approximate
know what we're gonna find approximate this with some various turn distribution
this with some various turn distribution we shall take advantage of this
we shall take advantage of this polarization and maybe postulate some
polarization and maybe postulate some variation distribution of theta but
variation distribution of theta but there's a similar factorization
there's a similar factorization okay maybe not significant interest
okay maybe not significant interest because this is an easy problem you
because this is an easy problem you notice that when I ask you this
notice that when I ask you this polarization each of these factors
polarization each of these factors depends all the same amount theta so
depends all the same amount theta so this is where a classical Bayesian
this is where a classical Bayesian inference problem so you can think if
inference problem so you can think if you know you have various type of
you know you have various type of parameters main I insist you know these
parameters main I insist you know these are the filters so with the care depends
are the filters so with the care depends on theta okay we will see later but
on theta okay we will see later but maybe have an appreciation for these
maybe have an appreciation for these factors then involve the same unknowns
factors then involve the same unknowns theta but right now that's what we have
theta but right now that's what we have okay so we perpetuate this distribution
okay so we perpetuate this distribution that this computation intractable will
that this computation intractable will is approximation can you give me a pass
is approximation can you give me a pass on this is possible algorithm you may
on this is possible algorithm you may come up with you know to approximate
come up with you know to approximate this without I mean just tell me
this without I mean just tell me everything that this potentially if this
everything that this potentially if this blogger
I'm going to the most obvious thing someone to say when you try to
someone to say when you try to participate this without I mean so for
participate this without I mean so for example you can think here right if you
example you can think here right if you collect data 1 data at the time so maybe
collect data 1 data at the time so maybe one comes somebody may say oh you know
one comes somebody may say oh you know I'm going to go and do an approximation
I'm going to go and do an approximation fifth one they took on so I'm going to
fifth one they took on so I'm going to go and do an approximation of her too
can we approximate basically it's popular independently of the over the
popular independently of the over the thing it will work is right but the
thing it will work is right but the emphasis is not to make its individual
emphasis is not to make its individual heart firm well the objective is to
heart firm well the objective is to approximate this whole thing well so the
approximate this whole thing well so the factors individually maybe are good who
factors individually maybe are good who cares because the purpose will be lost
cares because the purpose will be lost okay so for example let's consider I
okay so for example let's consider I think this this I don't whether this
think this this I don't whether this pictorial comes but let's consider an
pictorial comes but let's consider an exact distribution the first one is a
exact distribution the first one is a mixture of two thousands
mixture of two thousands okay that's f 1 and let's say we're
okay that's f 1 and let's say we're going to approximate this factor with
going to approximate this factor with this missing person because just to be
this missing person because just to be in the exponential family now she'll so
in the exponential family now she'll so the second factor of two looks like a
the second factor of two looks like a Gaussian so we get an extra
Gaussian so we get an extra approximation all right so if you take
approximation all right so if you take so this is the just product of F 1 and F
so this is the just product of F 1 and F 2 this is really what we want
2 this is really what we want approximate well and now this is the
approximate well and now this is the product of the two approximation and
product of the two approximation and your faith is not a very good
your faith is not a very good calculation because mainly we screw it
calculation because mainly we screw it up there okay all right we don't know
up there okay all right we don't know how you're gonna tell me you get this
how you're gonna tell me you get this model approximation of needs to be very
model approximation of needs to be very good so the addition is when you
good so the addition is when you approximate that one right
approximate that one right he put and also a lot of probability
he put and also a lot of probability mass in the approximation to match that
mass in the approximation to match that one but you really have forgot that the
one but you really have forgot that the probability mass effective here is zero
probability mass effective here is zero so like you're investing a lot of money
so like you're investing a lot of money to approximate well at one in a region
to approximate well at one in a region that doesn't
you have to do in the we don't approach to make these factors in the penny of
to make these factors in the penny of each other but so we try to to do
each other but so we try to to do something better than that so I just
something better than that so I just have an idea verse for this algorithm
have an idea verse for this algorithm and again it is not very complicated but
and again it is not very complicated but you need to pay attention the algebra
you need to pay attention the algebra you know may be a little bit confusing
you know may be a little bit confusing it is really not okay so I'm going to
it is really not okay so I'm going to make only the Z and I remind you this
make only the Z and I remind you this kind of thing because the approximation
kind of thing because the approximation the approximate distribution if you pick
the approximate distribution if you pick up so this is part of J so we because we
up so this is part of J so we because we won't approximate now right like in the
won't approximate now right like in the approximation so okay to be close to
approximation so okay to be close to this F J we're going to try to make
this F J we're going to try to make distribution as close as possible to the
distribution as close as possible to the pj x this manga folio verifies for the
pj x this manga folio verifies for the surprise of the approximate apart so
surprise of the approximate apart so again when we compute that 126 to coming
again when we compute that 126 to coming it's coming here so we're going to be
it's coming here so we're going to be approximating alright
approximating alright this whole distribution to be as close
this whole distribution to be as close as possible to that all right well this
as possible to that all right well this is the exact factor all right but this
is the exact factor all right but this is we use the approximation of for the
is we use the approximation of for the other factors that we have gained up to
other factors that we have gained up to now again we're gonna do this
now again we're gonna do this iteratively right so whatever particles
iteratively right so whatever particles we have toward the others within
we have toward the others within approximation so this is what we use as
approximation so this is what we use as the background okay
the background okay the first we will be have an
the first we will be have an approximation for that j that is
approximation for that j that is accurate in regions where very
significant probability marched right if they're 0 who cares we are not going to
they're 0 who cares we are not going to count for them we don't want to to
count for them we don't want to to invest resources from other proximity to
invest resources from other proximity to you say on the bus was here you know we
you say on the bus was here you know we have this product of the brown
have this product of the brown distributions all but the term tray so
distributions all but the term tray so longer this i am going to define this
longer this i am going to define this amount to ask you for the key factors
amount to ask you for the key factors except total j so effectively the skill
except total j so effectively the skill theta divided by this approximation fo j
theta divided by this approximation fo j okay this chance in physics comes with a
okay this chance in physics comes with a particular name alright because even
particular name alright because even this idea comes from physics but we
this idea comes from physics but we leave everything out so this is another
leave everything out so this is another factor the product from the pastors
factor the product from the pastors Bugsy okay all right
to me this distribution here as natural at a times this distribution Q minus J
at a times this distribution Q minus J okay and situation is a normalization
okay and situation is a normalization factor okay so Z Jake here's the final
factor okay so Z Jake here's the final icon alright so what we noticed we want
icon alright so what we noticed we want to make this alright as close as
to make this alright as close as possible to dock so here is the problem
possible to dock so here is the problem we want to find an update of the
we want to find an update of the distribution Q and notice I am NOT
distribution Q and notice I am NOT asking an update of the factor at J of
asking an update of the factor at J of theta where the next thing is an update
theta where the next thing is an update of the whole queue of paper
let's agree to make the active today but I'm posing the problem not for cute yeah
I'm posing the problem not for cute yeah we're going to take this faster if they
we're going to take this faster if they filled up right but I'm posing the
filled up right but I'm posing the problem find me this ablative clear
problem find me this ablative clear paper so that it matches that okay so
paper so that it matches that okay so the problem is fine cupid i'd like orvis
the problem is fine cupid i'd like orvis q nu theta so that the distance between
q nu theta so that the distance between this and this is me might and you notice
this and this is me might and you notice this very well scale distance because
this very well scale distance because the two popular FJ comes to the left
the two popular FJ comes to the left attack this very important all right so
attack this very important all right so it's what we discussed today alright so
it's what we discussed today alright so this is the through factor okay this
this is the through factor okay this problem is can you tell me with words
problem is can you tell me with words they say what is the distribution people
they say what is the distribution people all right that does solve this
all right that does solve this minimization problem and of course we're
minimization problem and of course we're going to constrain theta theta is in the
going to constrain theta theta is in the exponential family so the problem of
exponential family so the problem of exponential distribution which is an
exponential distribution which is an exponential form a distribution channel
exponential form a distribution channel exact answer to this problem that is
exact answer to this problem that is basically coming out of the optimization
it stays hot right
when we're watching so basically the moments of cure Flippa have to march
moments of cure Flippa have to march through the moments to go okay all right
through the moments to go okay all right so let's say it first is Gaussian is
so let's say it first is Gaussian is like I'm going to live with the mean
like I'm going to live with the mean ology used in practice right like taking
ology used in practice right like taking the distribution on the left hand side
the distribution on the left hand side and projecting it to Gaussian say some
and projecting it to Gaussian say some  to be the ocean and we're studying
to be the ocean and we're studying those moments to an affiliated Gaussian
those moments to an affiliated Gaussian okay an operation this can you achieve
okay an operation this can you achieve written in the literature there's a
written in the literature there's a projection operator so think of this you
projection operator so think of this you know whatever distribution you have
know whatever distribution you have you're going to approach range with a
you're going to approach range with a Gaussian through this one with marching
Gaussian through this one with marching and so you've trapped the moment and
and so you've trapped the moment and then you assign them to a Gaussian so
then you assign them to a Gaussian so that's the projections that we computed
that's the projections that we computed new distribution Q of theta and then we
new distribution Q of theta and then we want to update the software at J and I
want to update the software at J and I remind you that this mission P of C is
remind you that this mission P of C is written as left J times this
approximation factors so basically XA of theta would be some
so basically XA of theta would be some normalization factor that you need times
normalization factor that you need times a normalized distribution Q that you
a normalized distribution Q that you compute for this problem you should not
compute for this problem you should not because one need to update know that the
because one need to update know that the update of the fact of J so addition is
update of the fact of J so addition is approximate the whole chain of theta
approximate the whole chain of theta okay
okay and another one that is done with more
and another one that is done with more and matching if we divide it by the
and matching if we divide it by the products of the approximations the
products of the approximations the factorization q of x from j we're going
factorization q of x from j we're going to get that check okay and you can tell
to get that check okay and you can tell it's a normalization constant so we ask
it's a normalization constant so we ask you
you the people's one so you get K so k is basically this normalization factor
is basically this normalization factor alright and we call this actually ZJ
alright and we call this actually ZJ should be a big formulas for the
should be a big formulas for the expectation propagation algorithm is
expectation propagation algorithm is what you see on the bottom alright so
what you see on the bottom alright so the idea is when the moment marching
the idea is when the moment marching okay computer home you two divided by Q
okay computer home you two divided by Q minus a multiplied with the
minus a multiplied with the normalization factor must be a plate of
normalization factor must be a plate of us today what's it
okay so I am going to emphasize again the key to key points right we compute
the key to key points right we compute its factor
its factor all right not independent of the other
all right not independent of the other factors but in a way that the the
factors but in a way that the the probability of your actresses accounted
probability of your actresses accounted in the approximation and we do this by
in the approximation and we do this by not matching FJ this FJ Academy with the
not matching FJ this FJ Academy with the exact FJ but my matching Q theta with
exact FJ but my matching Q theta with this okay and so we don't have made the
this okay and so we don't have made the factor of J to start with will be the
factor of J to start with will be the whole distribution P of theta and from
whole distribution P of theta and from that we can update the factor of J once
that we can update the factor of J once we're done and and the approximation
we're done and and the approximation again is given on the bottom so I had
again is given on the bottom so I had services so think of this as you know
services so think of this as you know let's say that this is the exact J
let's say that this is the exact J alright and this is what the you know
alright and this is what the you know doing so can you imagine a liberal and
doing so can you imagine a liberal and you try to master so this is sort of an
you try to master so this is sort of an right Victoria here if you try to
right Victoria here if you try to optimize a terribly to mark this blue
optimize a terribly to mark this blue distribution giving it something that
distribution giving it something that looks like a bombshell but the
looks like a bombshell but the distribution is this far away from her
distribution is this far away from her essay okay so now what that does is
essay okay so now what that does is impose the approximation of the factor
impose the approximation of the factor today to be closer sampling between
today to be closer sampling between alright and the approximation for the
alright and the approximation for the food distribution basically terms it is
food distribution basically terms it is you know the probability you know the
you know the probability you know the nonzero probability domain of this Q
nonzero probability domain of this Q minus a distribution so by the way you
minus a distribution so by the way you can see here the notation that I told
can see here the notation that I told you it is very common that abhorrest
you it is very common that abhorrest million you know in describing what is
million you know in describing what is going on so when you you know remember
going on so when you you know remember we we are matching we compute a new to
we we are matching we compute a new to narrow the manipulation of matching
narrow the manipulation of matching moments with the distribution of you see
moments with the distribution of you see here inside the brackets is for the
here inside the brackets is for the projection operator okay
projection operator okay so again you know you are extracting the
so again you know you are extracting the moments and you try to match this to the
moments and you try to match this to the corresponding Gaussian distribution okay
corresponding Gaussian distribution okay okay
okay and so I will show you an example
and so I will show you an example actually where this distribution here
actually where this distribution here can be lets say Poisson distribution
can be lets say Poisson distribution when you have approximated with this
when you have approximated with this projection operator to a Gaussian
a complexity that maybe you haven't thought about this before okay and when
thought about this before okay and when here over this angle is this can be the
here over this angle is this can be the blessing but also it can be stable a
blessing but also it can be stable a very painful process this exponential
very painful process this exponential form just gives them ownership all right
form just gives them ownership all right that's the most other example of
that's the most other example of exponential distribution
exponential distribution occasionally thousand obviously this
occasionally thousand obviously this protection will give you the cue but is
protection will give you the cue but is also going to be Gaussian what happens
also going to be Gaussian what happens when he divide to gossip having
when he divide to gossip having discussed an equal in class before I
discussed an equal in class before I will not have provided through no
will not have provided through no marginalization this conditional now we
marginalization this conditional now we have a relative to Gaussian do you see
have a relative to Gaussian do you see any problem
are you happy dividing into thousands
what can happen
such as or what type of new medical a shift
because this one exponents this actually I don't think the division by zero will
I don't think the division by zero will be a problem here okay because they're
be a problem here okay because they're Exponential's
Exponential's but because you know functions you know
interested to enforce this right but at the end of the day but this is a
the end of the day but this is a Gaussian but some of the factors may
Gaussian but some of the factors may come to here actually a negative value
come to here actually a negative value okay and and you see this and you know
okay and and you see this and you know you may want to actually take this
you may want to actually take this former so didn't have time this morning
former so didn't have time this morning to verify them again fifteen thank
to verify them again fifteen thank relationship the two gaussians okay you
relationship the two gaussians okay you can you basically get a gas and Gaussian
can you basically get a gas and Gaussian right but you notice the variance is 1
right but you notice the variance is 1 over V 1 minus 1 over V to the want of
over V 1 minus 1 over V to the want of the vision of the balances of numerator
the vision of the balances of numerator and denominator and obviously this can
and denominator and obviously this can be negative obviously can be negative
be negative obviously can be negative okay so again it is not an issue but how
okay so again it is not an issue but how you program this is something you need
you program this is something you need to be sort of very careful alright so
to be sort of very careful alright so these are not your everyday couch
so you a novice schematic on this participation of expectation propagation
participation of expectation propagation on the tester problem that I introduced
on the tester problem that I introduced and I'm going to discuss this problem
and I'm going to discuss this problem expensively and the topics is basically
expensively and the topics is basically the Soviet approximation that you get
the Soviet approximation that you get when the context for the support of X 2
when the context for the support of X 2 minus J distribution that reduces the
minus J distribution that reduces the bar down distribution could you do the
bar down distribution could you do the computation in the top two pictures is
computation in the top two pictures is narrow all right so you can see the this
narrow all right so you can see the this this distribution here is the context
this distribution here is the context this is the Q minus J okay
this is the Q minus J okay and you can depending here to show is
and you can depending here to show is that the actual approximation of the
that the actual approximation of the factor of J that we do eventually with
factor of J that we do eventually with expectation propagation it is only good
expectation propagation it is only good in the region where the support of Q
in the region where the support of Q minus J is nonzero okay so you can see
minus J is nonzero okay so you can see everywhere else
everywhere else right the approximation is very large
right the approximation is very large this is a very this is you know okay so
this is a very this is you know okay so here the approximation is good and the
here the approximation is good and the same you know the support here is
same you know the support here is nonzero there you can see how good the
nonzero there you can see how good the approximation looks the blue and what is
approximation looks the blue and what is it the the red they basically coincide
it the the red they basically coincide here now you have a mug out the context
here now you have a mug out the context that is much wider so you notice the
that is much wider so you notice the approximation that it's not anymore is
approximation that it's not anymore is good right because this is very wide
good right because this is very wide this is to be expected
this is to be expected all right and similarly here yeah the
all right and similarly here yeah the approximation starts deviating basically
approximation starts deviating basically it's not very good over the support so
it's not very good over the support so if you have a narrow support right
if you have a narrow support right assuming you do inference right if your
assuming you do inference right if your problems all over the space and you have
problems all over the space and you have no data the issue that you get in
no data the issue that you get in posterior estimation
posterior estimation all right for the last time all the
all right for the last time all the other
other we're going to be moving away from this
we're going to be moving away from this okay so this is what it looks
okay so this is what it looks if you initialize all the factors right
if you initialize all the factors right you have to start with something usually
you have to start with something usually if you can just put them all the big
if you can just put them all the big aliens with some in and violence's so
aliens with some in and violence's so this is your approximation for the whole
this is your approximation for the whole posterior distribution then you start
posterior distribution then you start updating one faster at the time you
updating one faster at the time you remember to twelve this cavity
remember to twelve this cavity distribution Q minus J okay by dividing
distribution Q minus J okay by dividing Q freedom with a factor of Jake you do
Q freedom with a factor of Jake you do one with matching two completely new you
one with matching two completely new you compute this normalization part for the
compute this normalization part for the update part of them is given by what you
update part of them is given by what you see instead be you picked all the
see instead be you picked all the factors okay obviously you know if
factors okay obviously you know if you're gonna keep iterating multiple
you're gonna keep iterating multiple runs to be sure that let's efficient
runs to be sure that let's efficient advances that the main of the variances
advances that the main of the variances of this approximation is don't change
of this approximation is don't change with iteration and once you're done you
with iteration and once you're done you can actually calculate the mobile
can actually calculate the mobile evidence as well for free right so this
evidence as well for free right so this would be something useful for model
would be something useful for model selection and the likes that you may be
selection and the likes that you may be interested to do the magnets is there is
interested to do the magnets is there is no proof of this will ever work okay and
it will chasten right but it's not proof okay
there's a lot of theory that goes under the expectation propagation but you know
the expectation propagation but you know you know so if you tomorrow come with a
you know so if you tomorrow come with a new PA statistics and you demonstrate
new PA statistics and you demonstrate something about the convergence of the
something about the convergence of the metals everybody will be reading your
metals everybody will be reading your paper because this is sort of still a
paper because this is sort of still a very important research topic in the
very important research topic in the literature all right so I think that
literature all right so I think that that would show you the expectation
that would show you the expectation propagation result so if I remember
propagation result so if I remember again we are approximating this darker
again we are approximating this darker region this is the Laplace appreciation
minimization we got variational based
the plants okay so in the EP so this is the variation of values which I know
the variation of values which I know what color is all right and the blue is
what color is all right and the blue is the one that we get with expectation
the one that we get with expectation propagation the trusox are different
propagation the trusox are different tonight but in this particular case if I
tonight but in this particular case if I see correctly right the support of the
see correctly right the support of the EP solution is much broader than the one
EP solution is much broader than the one you get with variational values okay so
you get with variational values okay so depending on and of course this is an AC
depending on and of course this is an AC distribution if you try to do this for
distribution if you try to do this for complicated province the answers may be
complicated province the answers may be completely different
okay I'm gonna give you this as a clock the proof is given on this slide so
the proof is given on this slide so suppose you know you so you have a
suppose you know you so you have a customization of your posterior so you
customization of your posterior so you have the four times each of the
have the four times each of the likelihood temps as you collect data
likelihood temps as you collect data right so for the prior that you started
right so for the prior that you started with so let this pass it shows you if
with so let this pass it shows you if you start an approximation the exact
you start an approximation the exact value will not change that just a sister
value will not change that just a sister and it gives you something else
and it gives you something else not sure will be public so here if you
not sure will be public so here if you know let's say the prior you can set
know let's say the prior you can set this equal to the prior and you don't
this equal to the prior and you don't have to worry you can fit all the
have to worry you can fit all the factors the same because the algorithm
factors the same because the algorithm will not update effectively this factor
will not update effectively this factor of zero you know I mean it will have
of zero you know I mean it will have needed but it would still give you the
needed but it would still give you the same answer
now there is the metal about gold maybe 20 years ago but they are not actually
20 years ago but they are not actually in any expectation propagation
in any expectation propagation algorithms but the sort of try to take
algorithms but the sort of try to take advantage of this factorization to do
advantage of this factorization to do some similar type of approximations and
some similar type of approximations and the metal overhead with amounts of
the metal overhead with amounts of references is this assumed density
references is this assumed density filtering method of unity in machine
filtering method of unity in machine learning books but they're not exactly
learning books but they're not exactly EP story P is basically the nearest
EP story P is basically the nearest approximation and okay the website which
approximation and okay the website which is the guy that actually the expectation
is the guy that actually the expectation propagation is disbelief is but MIT many
propagation is disbelief is but MIT many years ago this thesis was like 30 pages
years ago this thesis was like 30 pages we have been about play revisions of
we have been about play revisions of this business after graduation you know
this business after graduation you know what you must have carrots to revise
what you must have carrots to revise your taste after you graduate right you
your taste after you graduate right you usually you hide under the table no he's
usually you hide under the table no he's not hiding because he knows people are
not hiding because he knows people are reading it he goes and correct formulas
reading it he goes and correct formulas improved here there it's always existed
improved here there it's always existed okay
okay you can obviously refer to either
you can obviously refer to either actually if you sent on the web you will
actually if you sent on the web you will find very high numbers of citations for
find very high numbers of citations for this work but the only thing I wanted to
this work but the only thing I wanted to tell you is very much of promise lots of
tell you is very much of promise lots of toy problems the AP metal source
toy problems the AP metal source comparison straight basically that there
comparison straight basically that there are stupid or twenty of the other
are stupid or twenty of the other methods we have seen up to now including
methods we have seen up to now including that many metrics including that include
that many metrics including that include particle or MCMC type approximation
particle or MCMC type approximation so you can see here the petal in the
so you can see here the petal in the approximation would be P is the best
approximation would be P is the best basically for you know variation of a is
basically for you know variation of a is something most important something in
something most important something in the light system analysis papers domain
the light system analysis papers domain kosoul's that you can actually pose this
kosoul's that you can actually pose this problem of expectation and maximization
problem of expectation and maximization as the problem of minimizing energy
as the problem of minimizing energy function right and so it's very nice
function right and so it's very nice alright so the result of an optimization
alright so the result of an optimization version of state you know this is what
version of state you know this is what the problem is is minimization of some
the problem is is minimization of some function unfortunately there is no such
function unfortunately there is no such a thing as working with the lower bound
a thing as working with the lower bound that we saw you may be realized but the
that we saw you may be realized but the measurement we need the latest increase
measurement we need the latest increase so here if you do here's his energy
so here if you do here's his energy function where you do if iterations this
function where you do if iterations this absolutely no proof no reason why that
absolutely no proof no reason why that energy function will actually be
energy function will actually be maximized and it will be monotonically
converges then you reach the stationary of this energy constant so if you get a
of this energy constant so if you get a solution that's the right solution what
solution that's the right solution what happens in between its mayor Fox okay
so very big to show you possibly API which works for face daunting problem
which works for face daunting problem and then we will love definitely we have
and then we will love definitely we have a few minutes so I can tell you on
a few minutes so I can tell you on extending this to to publish the
extending this to to publish the graphical models so we can make
graphical models so we can make connections with other algorithms so I
connections with other algorithms so I know that the problem is we only want to
know that the problem is we only want to compute the the mean of this Gaussian so
compute the the mean of this Gaussian so we collect data but the data basically
we collect data but the data basically are noisy because some of the data may
are noisy because some of the data may be coming from this three bit dollars in
be coming from this three bit dollars in the submission but some of them can be
the submission but some of them can be coming from the squatter distribution so
coming from the squatter distribution so it can be completely relevant to the
it can be completely relevant to the mean that you want to estimate okay so
mean that you want to estimate okay so that's why this is called the clattering
that's why this is called the clattering problem we're going to put some prior on
problem we're going to put some prior on the parameters theta
the parameters theta obviously the UH normalized posterior
obviously the UH normalized posterior looks like this it's like if we turbine
looks like this it's like if we turbine is a Gaussian mixture so you have 2 to
is a Gaussian mixture so you have 2 to the N terms so this is not something if
the N terms so this is not something if you can work with so you can see here if
you can work with so you can see here if this is the to really Gaussian that you
this is the to really Gaussian that you want to extract the mean a lots of data
want to extract the mean a lots of data concentrate here but you have a lots of
concentrate here but you have a lots of data but have nothing to do with this
data but have nothing to do with this particular means so you want to be able
particular means so you want to be able to do inference so I that I recommend
to do inference so I that I recommend that you make this problem because you
that you make this problem because you know we mentioned things becoming
know we mentioned things becoming Gaussian like distributions with
Gaussian like distributions with negative variance if you can you know if
negative variance if you can you know if you look at the bra on this problem and
you look at the bra on this problem and you try to implement it then we have a
you try to implement it then we have a Python code you will see why there are
Python code you will see why there are problems there so I want you to actually
problems there so I want you to actually move algebra at the algebra is not very
move algebra at the algebra is not very difficult the proofs are in the slides
difficult the proofs are in the slides so what we are going to do is I'm just
so what we are going to do is I'm just gonna summarize the results we are going
gonna summarize the results we are going to take an approximation of pure theta
to take an approximation of pure theta to be a multivariate Gaussian okay
to be a multivariate Gaussian okay obviously this means the factors will be
obviously this means the factors will be also
also thousands but in the spirit of what we
thousands but in the spirit of what we discussed about Dodgers with negative
discussed about Dodgers with negative audience we are aggressive response of
audience we are aggressive response of stamina meditation care and and the
stamina meditation care and and the square exponential here for effectively
square exponential here for effectively that variance bien can be negative so
that variance bien can be negative so this notion I have been looking at them
this notion I have been looking at them on distribution would be upside down
on distribution would be upside down okay so you need to start this away from
okay so you need to start this away from with some initialization and for example
with some initialization and for example you can say of this factors to be equal
you can say of this factors to be equal to one
to one that's what is discussed here okay this
that's what is discussed here okay this assume immensely metal does the same
assume immensely metal does the same thing in approximating the fastest when
thing in approximating the fastest when you stop so you need to have something
you stop so you need to have something to start with okay you follow the Eiger
to start with okay you follow the Eiger if you're going to update would say one
if you're going to update would say one factor you form this cavity this
factor you form this cavity this condition you computer organization you
condition you computer organization you do moment marching you point in you and
do moment marching you point in you and then you have there is a factor so the
then you have there is a factor so the question is if you have beta factor what
question is if you have beta factor what will be the mean and the variance of a
will be the mean and the variance of a factor and the ancestors are the five
factor and the ancestors are the five carat ring slide maybe giving this
give me one second okay sterically the you know I thought there's two dreams
you know I thought there's two dreams like having all the answers so if you
like having all the answers so if you compute first the cavity the
compute first the cavity the distribution it comes to be a Gaussian
distribution it comes to be a Gaussian like this is the inverse variance is the
like this is the inverse variance is the precision how it looks like okay this is
precision how it looks like okay this is the main okay the normalization factor
the main okay the normalization factor you can compute as well and and then you
you can compute as well and and then you have to update you okay and you can so
have to update you okay and you can so actually the updates of can you they
actually the updates of can you they look and actually they updates you know
look and actually they updates you know I'm looking on top will end here so the
I'm looking on top will end here so the updates of June you look the way that
updates of June you look the way that you see them here very nice clean
you see them here very nice clean formula where actually this coefficient
formula where actually this coefficient looks like the probability of the point
looks like the probability of the point X and not being a plotter okay
X and not being a plotter okay so again an analytical expression for
so again an analytical expression for this these mean of the community
this these mean of the community distribution is knowing the variance of
distribution is knowing the variance of the kayuu distribution is also known a
the kayuu distribution is also known a little early to page slides of the
little early to page slides of the relation or the calculation start in
relation or the calculation start in right and and if you you have the
right and and if you you have the distribution you know gaussians like you
distribution you know gaussians like you can update it after and the updates of
can update it after and the updates of the part of them are spirits potentials
the part of them are spirits potentials like that as before the mean is given by
like that as before the mean is given by this nice expression the precision
this nice expression the precision variance is given like this so the
variance is given like this so the police jumped on the total problem or
police jumped on the total problem or analytical so actually you can see sort
analytical so actually you can see sort of this equation you know
of this equation you know in with written Amish there are no perks
in with written Amish there are no perks maesters non-medical approximation okay
maesters non-medical approximation okay you can actually calculate the model
you can actually calculate the model evidence as well analytically at the end
evidence as well analytically at the end of the day one of the whole thing
of the day one of the whole thing converges and the resilient item code
converges and the resilient item code that you can allow for this type of
that you can allow for this type of problem
problem and mr. t Rizal Park sorry that what you
and mr. t Rizal Park sorry that what you seek here this can you motion for you
seek here this can you motion for you upside down all right why not I mean you
upside down all right why not I mean you get the henna guys and all there was why
get the henna guys and all there was why not okay
again this is FN this is the approximation factor offense so you're
approximation factor offense so you're not this year it's not really that you
not this year it's not really that you are trying to monitor this with a pen
are trying to monitor this with a pen you are trying to actually concentrate
you are trying to actually concentrate in the region where the support of this
in the region where the support of this cavity distribution is which is here and
cavity distribution is which is here and that's what the approximation it's good
that's what the approximation it's good the rest there's nothing you can do
the rest there's nothing you can do about okay and in some sense you don't
about okay and in some sense you don't really care and similarly in this case
really care and similarly in this case the convict is here that you can see the
the convict is here that you can see the two approximation is not very well
two approximation is not very well almost they coincide in that region so
almost they coincide in that region so it's actually for the clutter problem
it's actually for the clutter problem they are in part of the Python code so
they are in part of the Python code so you can if you do variation of a is you
you can if you do variation of a is you use Laplace approximation you can push
use Laplace approximation you can push it to as many days as you want to
it to as many days as you want to basically it's proficient propagation
basically it's proficient propagation through this problem performance the
through this problem performance the best okay
best okay institutional coming around this
institutional coming around this grappling problem because he was very
grappling problem because he was very easily programming they need to be
easily programming they need to be completing everything was analytical and
completing everything was analytical and it was also a problem quite if he comes
it was also a problem quite if he comes to some of the best okay maybe you can
to some of the best okay maybe you can do a problem that it becomes this for
do a problem that it becomes this for you are not the best
okay we have because we basically be updating information related to
updating information related to variables X 1 and X 2 ok nothing else
variables X 1 and X 2 ok nothing else so can somehow envision that there is no
so can somehow envision that there is no expectation propagation language that's
expectation propagation language that's why the title of the presentation today
why the title of the presentation today was local variation fluctuations where
was local variation fluctuations where somehow the whole thing collapses to
somehow the whole thing collapses to allow us to do an update here and update
allow us to do an update here and update there and update their etc and even
there and update their etc and even further actually if you so let's say
further actually if you so let's say a theorist function of x1 x2 maybe you
a theorist function of x1 x2 maybe you can even fertilize this 2 factor of x 1
can even fertilize this 2 factor of x 1 so you can have a polyester
so you can have a polyester approximation as 1/4 - 20 X 1 and in all
approximation as 1/4 - 20 X 1 and in all factor of X 2 and similarly here did you
factor of X 2 and similarly here did you have something else on a function of X 2
have something else on a function of X 2 the function of X 4 can you update each
the function of X 4 can you update each of them separately
of them separately ok can you update each of them
ok can you update each of them separately - it's amazing you will say
separately - it's amazing you will say that I can figure the answer is yes you
that I can figure the answer is yes you can and then we will see everything we
can and then we will see everything we learn about influencing graphs in
learn about influencing graphs in particularly ideas of you know master
particularly ideas of you know master spacing and propagation all of these
spacing and propagation all of these cases are
ok ok just to make things simple you can be factorized or groups of animals but
be factorized or groups of animals but right now let's take you to the top four
right now let's take you to the top four eyes and using a monkey - of Z to attack
eyes and using a monkey - of Z to attack alright so we want to minimize this
alright so we want to minimize this Traverse K of distance of P and Q so I'm
Traverse K of distance of P and Q so I'm writing this the definition - P of
writing this the definition - P of longer pupae
longer pupae right or like be longer Peele
right or like be longer Peele / cured us about there okay Scott
/ cured us about there okay Scott so we need less time doing ads about now
so we need less time doing ads about now the mission of a life is living as a
the mission of a life is living as a poet with two eyes that are conscious of
poet with two eyes that are conscious of Zi so because I have a monk here you
Zi so because I have a monk here you agree with me that there Nathan would
agree with me that there Nathan would give me minus B of Z summation of the
give me minus B of Z summation of the level choice of Zi all right yes
level choice of Zi all right yes - babe love opium gives me the entropy I
- babe love opium gives me the entropy I don't care there is no dependence on you
don't care there is no dependence on you so I am going to identify only the
so I am going to identify only the proper QJ because this is what I am
proper QJ because this is what I am going to update while you are going to
going to update while you are going to see what is the effective to j1 we
see what is the effective to j1 we minimize this listen so I am only take
minimize this listen so I am only take 2j the rest of the terms don't depend on
2j the rest of the terms don't depend on the situation I don't care or I Trump
the situation I don't care or I Trump I'm going to rewrite this nice thing as
I'm going to rewrite this nice thing as - fitzy all right and I'm going to
- fitzy all right and I'm going to integrate all the Bible since the except
integrate all the Bible since the except J so can you tell me this distribution
J so can you tell me this distribution this integral what this tribution is it
this integral what this tribution is it so when you take P of Z and you
so when you take P of Z and you integrate everything out but sorry
integrate everything out but sorry what do you get so when you take P of 0
what do you get so when you take P of 0 integrate all the variables for J
the Monsuno you get the mountain on you know ZJ mr. Fontenot
know ZJ mr. Fontenot alright so ridiculous dimanche though
alright so ridiculous dimanche though alright so this is really the moments
alright so this is really the moments ago fine okay and so now we need to
ago fine okay and so now we need to minimize this it's a functional of the
minimize this it's a functional of the optimization problem you cannot just
optimization problem you cannot just take the river to respective use a so
take the river to respective use a so you need to and of course but QJ is
you need to and of course but QJ is normalized
okay okay makes sense to have approximation for its factors like you
approximation for its factors like you know if a caveat because it's a trap
know if a caveat because it's a trap secretly and in actually the individual
secretly and in actually the individual component inside is part of so a very
component inside is part of so a very one of its one of a 232 FB 252 f p3 of X
one of its one of a 232 FB 252 f p3 of X 3 etcetera okay so that way we have a
3 etcetera okay so that way we have a twenty factorized
okay so we want to minimize the distance between birth distribution and Q of X
and then from there we're going to come up with an update for this part by
up with an update for this part by dividing by the cavity distribution an
dividing by the cavity distribution an optimization problem is we need to bring
optimization problem is we need to bring this distribution as close as possible
this distribution as close as possible to this distribution right
to this distribution right okay can you pay me based on what we saw
okay can you pay me based on what we saw here let's listen to my optimization
here let's listen to my optimization problem
so if you missed the minimize missed from the mention of distribution
operations that come out that they have to be able to work so this they have to
to be able to work so this they have to be equal to given as you know the
be equal to given as you know the motivation the modular submit original
motivation the modular submit original this the Mazda mx-5 is just this stuff
this the Mazda mx-5 is just this stuff alright what's the marginal effects
alright what's the marginal effects customers extra fee RS the X 2 this is X
customers extra fee RS the X 2 this is X 3 so if is this for with someone X 3
3 so if is this for with someone X 3 what is the mountain X 3 I see on in
what is the mountain X 3 I see on in this term here so we have to integrate
this term here so we have to integrate no extreme twist anything else
I'm sorry I wasn't paying attention
[Music]
okay anything that will disappear so make sure that we get this we get the
make sure that we get this we get the update that is the summation X 3 of f DX
update that is the summation X 3 of f DX 2 3 all right which is this down all
2 3 all right which is this down all right and then this their FB 3 ok FP 3
right and then this their FB 3 ok FP 3 is a decreased this summation here
we get the update of being this and the date of FB 3
date of FB 3 being done now let's concentrate because
being done now let's concentrate because we only have two minutes on this
we only have two minutes on this equation tells me if it reminds you
equation tells me if it reminds you anything at all so by doing this if P
anything at all so by doing this if P and effectively moment maps interesting
[Music]
this is no sense to know X 2 dot this down here and this part the sense to
down here and this part the sense to know X 2 which is various and then I
know X 2 which is various and then I take this factor which is a function of
take this factor which is a function of X 2 and X 3 and it's a great house X 2
X 2 and X 3 and it's a great house X 2 you know what I get I get the message
you know what I get I get the message that is propagated to excrete okay so
that is propagated to excrete okay so basically belief propagation comes as a
basically belief propagation comes as a trivial exercise of expectation
trivial exercise of expectation propagates okay you know not just really
propagates okay you know not just really expect it right but it's just one of
expect it right but it's just one of these miracles of
these miracles of of mathematics and ingenuity and stimuli
of mathematics and ingenuity and stimuli you can shop or view all the terror okay
you can shop or view all the terror okay I suggest that you look at the slides I
I suggest that you look at the slides I don't have time to discuss this further
don't have time to discuss this further you can extend this this two very
you can extend this this two very important maybe this key needs to be
important maybe this key needs to be discussed on Thursday but basically if
discussed on Thursday but basically if you can extend this to general belief
you can extend this to general belief propagation okay and you can share that
knowledge and this dysfunction so where the bottom edge of each note separatory
the bottom edge of each note separatory all right you can update this variable
all right you can update this variable amount for example and the wave length
amount for example and the wave length is variable along when we did you know
is variable along when we did you know passing we took all of the messages that
passing we took all of the messages that are coming from this factor to the
are coming from this factor to the neighbors of this particle collective
neighbors of this particle collective not to this node L and so one of those
not to this node L and so one of those message is coming in you multiply with
message is coming in you multiply with of J and then you integrate all of the
of J and then you integrate all of the variables except L and that gives you
variables except L and that gives you the update of the F of T pile and it
the update of the F of T pile and it comes with expectation propagation gives
comes with expectation propagation gives you exactly same answer okay if you
you exactly same answer okay if you don't believe me leave the notes but we
don't believe me leave the notes but we will come back on this on Thursday to
will come back on this on Thursday to see the miracles of expectation
see the miracles of expectation propagation