why so we left the previous lecture so this is for those that was based on
this is for those that was based on lying this is the earlier lecture on
lying this is the earlier lecture on introduction to approximate Bayesian
introduction to approximate Bayesian inference what's right was the other one
inference what's right was the other one I had you forgot okay we locate it so
I had you forgot okay we locate it so we're going to continue on that every
we're going to continue on that every lecture there was this icing example
lecture there was this icing example that I went rapidly so let's review it
that I went rapidly so let's review it because it's very fundamental to lots of
because it's very fundamental to lots of areas all right so obviously you have
areas all right so obviously you have worked on lists in the homework we
worked on lists in the homework we assume here we have some observations
assume here we have some observations why but are defined let's say pixel wise
why but are defined let's say pixel wise and X maybe the tradition image this is
and X maybe the tradition image this is some noisy version of the image and
some noisy version of the image and these are the original pictures we try
these are the original pictures we try to estimate so there is no see here so
to estimate so there is no see here so you can think the unknowns basically are
you can think the unknowns basically are X this is what we want to do an
X this is what we want to do an inference and so we've worked with the
inference and so we've worked with the joint and the posterior with with some
joint and the posterior with with some prior the prior is basically standard
prior the prior is basically standard for this type of payments is is gift
for this type of payments is is gift like distribution e to the minus e0 some
like distribution e to the minus e0 some energy functional that accounts for
energy functional that accounts for nearest neighbors basically interactions
nearest neighbors basically interactions okay this is sort of very typical of
okay this is sort of very typical of massaging models these are some
massaging models these are some coefficients given here excited day
coefficients given here excited day they're binary variables plus minus one
they're binary variables plus minus one okay all right so we like the likelihood
okay all right so we like the likelihood locally is the product for all eyes on
locally is the product for all eyes on why I given the probability of Y given X
why I given the probability of Y given X I and we write this probability so we
I and we write this probability so we can
can make the algebra to look nice has to get
make the algebra to look nice has to get to the power a lie so the total
to the power a lie so the total likelihood basically is the exponential
likelihood basically is the exponential of the summation of this energy cell I
of the summation of this energy cell I of X I okay so that way we can write the
of X I okay so that way we can write the posterior as if to the mind of some
posterior as if to the mind of some energy for the energies these little
energy for the energies these little miners destination of the local evidence
miners destination of the local evidence which okay so what we want is we want to
which okay so what we want is we want to compute an approximation to this
compute an approximation to this posterior all right that's our objective
posterior all right that's our objective I mean you can this turn is an easy
I mean you can this turn is an easy problem you can directly work with it so
problem you can directly work with it so you don't really need an approximation
you don't really need an approximation this chain is a going distribution but
this chain is a going distribution but we say well you know we want to
we say well you know we want to factorize QX in a nice form that is
factorize QX in a nice form that is factorizable i alright so for each i
factorizable i alright so for each i we're going to have the corresponding Q
we're going to have the corresponding Q I of X I and because X I is plus minus 2
I of X I and because X I is plus minus 2 R is discrete the only thing we need to
R is discrete the only thing we need to describe it with distributions is the
describe it with distributions is the mean value okay the fundamental equation
mean value okay the fundamental equation that we derived for each of this factor
that we derived for each of this factor so if you have to remind me
so if you have to remind me so we did the derivation or elliptically
so we did the derivation or elliptically and we sell it factor qi or the longer
and we sell it factor qi or the longer fits not the dry is equal to what the
fits not the dry is equal to what the expectation of
police response was this fundamental to fire some problems is faster Qi is limit
fire some problems is faster Qi is limit Y is equal to
I mean I can go outside they don't take a break for one hour until you guys tell
a break for one hour until you guys tell me what the formula is whatever works
solution Qi I'm a chef with an index there Qi but it told this from the
there Qi but it told this from the arguments the log of G is equal to the
arguments the log of G is equal to the expectation of what
you know as you get older you hear less but is by design you want to remove on
but is by design you want to remove on the knowledge all right so the rumble Qi
the knowledge all right so the rumble Qi equal to the expectation
why you look at me I mean either it's better or not
most of what distribution we have the expectation of the love of what
expectation of the love of what distribution before one with the other
distribution before one with the other in general right we had observable X and
in general right we had observable X and we had less enviable Z so what
we had less enviable Z so what distribution the right-hand side what
distribution the right-hand side what the question was referring to the joint
the question was referring to the joint was a likelihood right that was the
was a likelihood right that was the starting point so the joint of like
starting point so the joint of like leave it here especially could've missed
leave it here especially could've missed all right so we started the of
all right so we started the of this factor really is nothing at the
this factor really is nothing at the language of these factors is the
language of these factors is the expectation or please doing log
expectation or please doing log likelihood which is basically minus this
likelihood which is basically minus this energy you take the logs this is we're
energy you take the logs this is we're talking about the UH normalized thing
talking about the UH normalized thing clear so it's minus the energy effects
clear so it's minus the energy effects so so the number of the joint of
so so the number of the joint of likelihood is obviously easier as this
likelihood is obviously easier as this right so with the - time it will be
right so with the - time it will be external times the summation of all the
external times the summation of all the neighbors of I plus ally of X I and I is
neighbors of I plus ally of X I and I is many many problems and I think this
many many problems and I think this reflects I to be a problem because I'm
reflects I to be a problem because I'm gonna said the Qi which is a function of
gonna said the Qi which is a function of X I write equal to what the expectation
X I write equal to what the expectation of this and I want to identify only the
of this and I want to identify only the terms the depend on X I write the main
terms the depend on X I write the main things that they wouldn't make any
things that they wouldn't make any difference in the context of excise all
difference in the context of excise all right and now we have to take to define
right and now we have to take to define the longer fly when you have to take the
the longer fly when you have to take the expectation of this with respect to work
we equation a variational methods driving the lava pits variation
driving the lava pits variation distribution dry is the expectation of
distribution dry is the expectation of this joint of likelihood with respect to
this joint of likelihood with respect to what horrible mean field approximation
reversed mother sorry so when the pain expectation of this with respect to all
expectation of this with respect to all other body most
other body most you're not going to datsuk tie right
you're not going to datsuk tie right because it's a lot of re most part istic
because it's a lot of re most part istic days you have been a substitute them
days you have been a substitute them with what my definition with there are
with what my definition with there are many values because their expressions
many values because their expressions are what is the mean values of XJ is
are what is the mean values of XJ is near J alright so we said that the
near J alright so we said that the longer Qi was equal to that sir Qi is
longer Qi was equal to that sir Qi is the exponential of next high times
the exponential of next high times destination over the neighbors of I plus
destination over the neighbors of I plus the local evidence will depend on your
the local evidence will depend on your exile alright because X I can only take
exile alright because X I can only take values plus one and minus one there so
values plus one and minus one there so I'm introducing two different
I'm introducing two different definitions here Li plus is the value
definitions here Li plus is the value for life when X is equal to one Li minus
for life when X is equal to one Li minus the value of a life when exhale equal to
the value of a life when exhale equal to minus one and the reason I do this is
minus one and the reason I do this is because since X is the discrete
because since X is the discrete distribution I am going to calculate the
distribution I am going to calculate the variational approximation Qi at X equal
variational approximation Qi at X equal to one so with this formula William this
to one so with this formula William this uh normalized distribution right that's
uh normalized distribution right that's why you have this symbol here do you
why you have this symbol here do you believe that - I for example - 1 is
believe that - I for example - 1 is equal to really let's call this whole
equal to really let's call this whole summation here mi alright so this
summation here mi alright so this conservation work all is mi so we agreed
conservation work all is mi so we agreed that qi 4 x equals 1 is this would be 1
that qi 4 x equals 1 is this would be 1 so you need to the mi + x I equal 1 plus
so you need to the mi + x I equal 1 plus li plus divided by this normalization
li plus divided by this normalization factor
right okay if I write this I can do it like this
if I write this I can do it like this and immediately you see that this
and immediately you see that this traffic cycles one comes to be employed
traffic cycles one comes to be employed okay so that's a very nice result
okay so that's a very nice result okay and and similarly the body of july
okay and and similarly the body of july 4 ik cycle -1 comes to be this 2.4
4 ik cycle -1 comes to be this 2.4 argument - - AI for AI is this nice
argument - - AI for AI is this nice there appear a my that we said this
there appear a my that we said this distillation known because these are the
distillation known because these are the means of the neighbors plus 0.5 li plus
means of the neighbors plus 0.5 li plus -2 ly - also know so the main view of
-2 ly - also know so the main view of the discrete the various on distribution
the discrete the various on distribution of X I is basically pure high when X - 1
of X I is basically pure high when X - 1 times the volume which 1 plus this time
times the volume which 1 plus this time from the values minus 1 and if you such
from the values minus 1 and if you such gives you all of these things you get to
gives you all of these things you get to the mean values is dong is the hyperbola
the mean values is dong is the hyperbola target basically of AI ok also very nice
target basically of AI ok also very nice result and so the update formulas
result and so the update formulas basically if I can write verse
basically if I can write verse explicitly is that the mean value of
explicitly is that the mean value of every variable I is the hyperbolic
every variable I is the hyperbolic tangent of what you see inside these
tangent of what you see inside these parentheses obviously to update the UI
parentheses obviously to update the UI you need to know the mean of the
you need to know the mean of the neighborhood so this equation can only
neighborhood so this equation can only be solved
be solved instead constant right so you have to
instead constant right so you have to iterate and obviously you can do this
iterate and obviously you can do this with a lots of color nice tricks you can
with a lots of color nice tricks you can go through each of the pixels and repeat
go through each of the pixels and repeat this until basically converges or you
this until basically converges or you can do it even in a synchronous model ok
can do it even in a synchronous model ok the so the interrelations look like this
the so the interrelations look like this so if you put an index stick here for
so if you put an index stick here for the iterations you use the previous
the iterations you use the previous whatever values you have the update mi
whatever values you have the update mi and you keep going and then
and you keep going and then more often you will see this in if you
more often you will see this in if you download programs that do this you
download programs that do this you actually apply this equation with some
actually apply this equation with some relaxation so rather than using this
relaxation so rather than using this value for new I you use a convex sound
value for new I you use a convex sound basically of the previous values plus
basically of the previous values plus the value that is predicted to
the value that is predicted to variational networks okay so this is
variational networks okay so this is sort of way more stable and avoids a
sort of way more stable and avoids a number of effects but usually are common
number of effects but usually are common in uniting models when I try give you an
in uniting models when I try give you an example and the example is basically you
example and the example is basically you can run it it's in math crystal box do I
can run it it's in math crystal box do I have to do is once you install it you
have to do is once you install it you just with a nice thing a Mazda noise
just with a nice thing a Mazda noise demo and it will get your results and
demo and it will get your results and you can save the nice program only ten
you can save the nice program only ten lines that can solve this little problem
lines that can solve this little problem okay so this is you start with a noisy
okay so this is you start with a noisy image you know obviously you have used
image you know obviously you have used need to use some parameters for example
need to use some parameters for example this part a long time in this relaxation
this part a long time in this relaxation method that's how you know but you can
method that's how you know but you can see mmediately the methodologies are
see mmediately the methodologies are able to recognize what the actual image
able to recognize what the actual image is and so this is the mean of the
is and so this is the mean of the posterior of the violation posterior
posterior of the violation posterior after a number of 15 strips purity all
after a number of 15 strips purity all the pixels in the image
all right
so I'm going to be you know there is way too much material to be covered here and
too much material to be covered here and this is an important topic I need to be
this is an important topic I need to be sure that we discussed more or less the
sure that we discussed more or less the most important things
most important things so let me I'm going to jump on the slide
so let me I'm going to jump on the slide and go to slides at the age of any
and go to slides at the age of any remind me to come back to slide 31 once
remind me to come back to slide 31 once we're done so let me do another very
we're done so let me do another very simple example unless we already have
simple example unless we already have done it if you would do this example
done it if you would do this example with the Gaussian okay if it's the unit
with the Gaussian okay if it's the unit to to get out but we did it just let me
to to get out but we did it just let me know okay because I'm doing too much
know okay because I'm doing too much jumping here all right so let's suppose
jumping here all right so let's suppose we from a Gaussian but here's a
we from a Gaussian but here's a precision tau and a mean mu but we don't
precision tau and a mean mu but we don't know okay and typical vision inference
know okay and typical vision inference problem is to calculate the posterior of
problem is to calculate the posterior of MU and tau and again for what we have
MU and tau and again for what we have taken Bayesian inference cost is like
taken Bayesian inference cost is like the cost there is an analytical
the cost there is an analytical calculation basically gives you the
calculation basically gives you the posteriors exactly but what I want to do
posteriors exactly but what I want to do is I want sort of to use the variational
is I want sort of to use the variational method so we can see how they work and
method so we can see how they work and how good they do so I'm going to take
how good they do so I'm going to take the Paris Commune tau to be what's
the Paris Commune tau to be what's called a normal gamma distribution so
called a normal gamma distribution so given tau the distribution of MU is a
given tau the distribution of MU is a Gaussian and then for the precision of
Gaussian and then for the precision of comes from showing the in this
comes from showing the in this distribution you put a gamma
distribution you put a gamma distribution as a supplier okay so this
distribution as a supplier okay so this is the priors and for this priors and
is the priors and for this priors and it's likely with the reasonable ethical
it's likely with the reasonable ethical solution for the posterior we pretend we
solution for the posterior we pretend we don't know where our solution is we
don't know where our solution is we don't really care right now and what we
don't really care right now and what we want to do is we want to
want to do is we want to you know we want to calculate the
you know we want to calculate the variation posterior and using the mean
variation posterior and using the mean field approximation we're going to
field approximation we're going to fertilize it the joint is going to be
fertilize it the joint is going to be written as somebody s and distribution
written as somebody s and distribution Emil and somebody s in distribution of
Emil and somebody s in distribution of how but we immediately see that this is
how but we immediately see that this is going to be an approximation right
going to be an approximation right because for those who have looked at
because for those who have looked at this problem before the exact solution
this problem before the exact solution you expect basically if the pious look
you expect basically if the pious look like that this is to the exponential
like that this is to the exponential family the posterior is going to be on
family the posterior is going to be on the exponents it's going to be a
the exponents it's going to be a Gaussian in the ocean gamma for example
Gaussian in the ocean gamma for example for here tau so you expect the
for here tau so you expect the prosthetics for me and how to have this
prosthetics for me and how to have this for well in terms of mu 0 lambda 0 and
for well in terms of mu 0 lambda 0 and alpha 0 MV 0 you have some mu and
alpha 0 MV 0 you have some mu and Atlanta and an alpha N and B n for n
Atlanta and an alpha N and B n for n data points obviously business and state
data points obviously business and state in that form because the distribution of
in that form because the distribution of you does not involve tau so
you does not involve tau so approximation so it you know we need to
approximation so it you know we need to see you know if things make sense right
see you know if things make sense right obviously you are not going to do this
obviously you are not going to do this in reality okay but in this class
in reality okay but in this class there's no reality formula the optimal
there's no reality formula the optimal KJ is the expectation is where all the
KJ is the expectation is where all the other variables of the log of the joint
other variables of the log of the joint of likelihood so I am going to start
of likelihood so I am going to start playing with this in this calculation
playing with this in this calculation you need to get really understand it all
you need to get really understand it all right because you know if you know the
right because you know if you know the study you will never see you will not
study you will never see you will not make any sense of these derivations
make any sense of these derivations little children many infinite settings
little children many infinite settings okay so you have to work through these
okay so you have to work through these little problems okay so let's change we
little problems okay so let's change we want let's update the variation
want let's update the variation distribution for me oh okay so we're
distribution for me oh okay so we're gonna take expectation with respect to
gonna take expectation with respect to all the
all the varam loose there's only one or the
varam loose there's only one or the bottom which is tau so here the joint
bottom which is tau so here the joint look like we could it would be the
look like we could it would be the likelihood of the data all right which
likelihood of the data all right which is Gaussian and these remember disappear
is Gaussian and these remember disappear and there's a problem you given tau and
and there's a problem you given tau and prior on tau but since we are interested
prior on tau but since we are interested in the distribution of Mew
in the distribution of Mew anything that does not depend on you we
anything that does not depend on you we don't play with okay so the prior and
don't play with okay so the prior and tau is with a constant so if you expand
tau is with a constant so if you expand this if you're going to get something
this if you're going to get something like this right
like this right this ranges from you that's the only
this ranges from you that's the only time we get if we expand let you come
time we get if we expand let you come can somebody tell it's important if this
can somebody tell it's important if this thing have drop quiz this term target
so this came from the the likelihood there all right
there all right okay and the query is to this time
okay and the query is to this time counting from you given top okay which
counting from you given top okay which is Gaussian okay so and you remember the
is Gaussian okay so and you remember the precision of that it was lambda 0 times
precision of that it was lambda 0 times tau so obviously you're gonna get 1 2 0
tau so obviously you're gonna get 1 2 0 times tau but the Tau became expectation
times tau but the Tau became expectation of tau Y because every queries any time
of tau Y because every queries any time we need to take expectations okay
we need to take expectations okay and again the rest terms that depend
and again the rest terms that depend only on on the don't depend on view we
only on on the don't depend on view we don't include them okay so you look at
don't include them okay so you look at this nice whatever distribution do you
this nice whatever distribution do you think you will get here if you play for
think you will get here if you play for five minutes with this calculation I
five minutes with this calculation I mean we need a distribution of you know
mean we need a distribution of you know and I stream u square a new square and a
and I stream u square a new square and a linear term in una Linea Turing new plus
linear term in una Linea Turing new plus constant so obviously closing the square
constant so obviously closing the square we're gonna get a Gaussian distribution
we're gonna get a Gaussian distribution of this garden tradition you can so with
of this garden tradition you can so with zero time has this mean and has this
zero time has this mean and has this precision okay and so X is the sample
precision okay and so X is the sample mean basically this is for the data come
mean basically this is for the data come from this comes from the prior lambda n
from this comes from the prior lambda n involves the precision of tau in
involves the precision of tau in immediately that reminds you because we
immediately that reminds you because we don't know that the posterior but
don't know that the posterior but somehow we're gonna need to do
somehow we're gonna need to do iterations so basically to compute this
iterations so basically to compute this distribution you need to know what the
distribution you need to know what the mean of tau it's okay so we need to go
mean of tau it's okay so we need to go and compute off
so similarly left the power again we have big expectation with respect to all
have big expectation with respect to all the other variables which dearest meal
the other variables which dearest meal of the likelihood the prior of being
of the likelihood the prior of being given tau and the prior of power has to
given tau and the prior of power has to be included because we're interested of
be included because we're interested of the distribution of tau so this term
the distribution of tau so this term comes from the data likelihood so
comes from the data likelihood so obviously didn't be an ex-professional
obviously didn't be an ex-professional expecting you this comes from this so
expecting you this comes from this so it's going to be an expectation respect
it's going to be an expectation respect to meal where is this thing coming from
to meal where is this thing coming from one of those two terms the first two
one of those two terms the first two terms coming from the prior of power I
terms coming from the prior of power I PI of tau which is a gamma distribution
PI of tau which is a gamma distribution all right and where are those two terms
all right and where are those two terms coming from
remember when before we play with this distribution okay we only kept the terms
distribution okay we only kept the terms but involve me do you have to keep all
but involve me do you have to keep all the terms that involve Tao so can you
the terms that involve Tao so can you tell me where let's say there is it
tell me where let's say there is it there what is this then coming from
so let me go back for you to remind you all everything so when a nobler to do
all everything so when a nobler to do with power comes from from the
with power comes from from the likelihood and you notice there is
likelihood and you notice there is another person coming from there
another person coming from there all right so for is it okay so we have
all right so for is it okay so we have this term Plus this term so effectively
this term Plus this term so effectively what you need to do if you look at it
what you need to do if you look at it carefully it is the log of the gamma
carefully it is the log of the gamma distribution alright so in the normal
distribution alright so in the normal distribution when you take logs you get
distribution when you take logs you get a lot of tau and a powder so that you
a lot of tau and a powder so that you put all the locks of tau together and
put all the locks of tau together and all the power terms together alright
all the power terms together alright what you will get is you will get a
what you will get is you will get a gamma distribution for this type of
gamma distribution for this type of alpha 0 you have our fire and instead of
alpha 0 you have our fire and instead of bazzill you have beta N and again here
bazzill you have beta N and again here you need to have expectation with
you need to have expectation with respect to MU and don't need to do all
respect to MU and don't need to do all of this so basically this distribution
of this so basically this distribution summary of everything qfm is a Gaussian
summary of everything qfm is a Gaussian feel power is a gamma distribution the
feel power is a gamma distribution the parameters are defined the way you see
parameters are defined the way you see them here you can see to define the mean
them here you can see to define the mean the variance of Q Prem you need to know
the variance of Q Prem you need to know the mean of tau in the ministry remember
the mean of tau in the ministry remember for a normal distribution which the mean
for a normal distribution which the mean if you have gamma distribution of the
if you have gamma distribution of the stop and beta would the mean anybody
stop and beta would the mean anybody remembers alpha divided by beta all
remembers alpha divided by beta all right so you can see immediately that
right so you can see immediately that the mean of tau depends on Alpha and
the mean of tau depends on Alpha and Beta n which again depends on moments of
Beta n which again depends on moments of alright so we need to know the
alright so we need to know the distribution of you so what you need to
distribution of you so what you need to do is you need to iterate ok it's like
do is you need to iterate ok it's like you start with somebody's vest then you
you start with somebody's vest then you compute gamma then you find the moments
compute gamma then you find the moments you know whatever that the expectation
you know whatever that the expectation of star
of star you go back you to calculators keep
you go back you to calculators keep going i fiddle basically convert sense
going i fiddle basically convert sense and and here is sort of a little example
and and here is sort of a little example I don't know yes so there is a Python
I don't know yes so there is a Python code written by the promise didn't again
code written by the promise didn't again but you can download and I think I you
but you can download and I think I you know this link is corrected but some of
know this link is corrected but some of the links I need to double check that
the links I need to double check that they're making sense so okay so this is
they're making sense so okay so this is one of the estimation of this cube meal
one of the estimation of this cube meal with cue update if you update your power
with cue update if you update your power and then when it converges in the
and then when it converges in the process is the actual distribution that
process is the actual distribution that history with this I am assuming red or
history with this I am assuming red or green care okay alright so this again
green care okay alright so this again it's a female example by we know the
it's a female example by we know the analytical solution but if you think
analytical solution but if you think about it you know the test of greenness
about it you know the test of greenness calculation is trivial and but you know
calculation is trivial and but you know if the reason is the solution
if the reason is the solution unfortunately you cannot go by but using
unfortunately you cannot go by but using only the analytical solution and if
only the analytical solution and if there is an analytical solution you
there is an analytical solution you pretend you don't really know that's
pretend you don't really know that's very bad for you like actually you need
very bad for you like actually you need to know okay but this problem with is
to know okay but this problem with is sort of exit exit exit ops okay
right
in sorry I want to make a position that I'm gonna repeat for other prompts as
I'm gonna repeat for other prompts as well right when you remember we we when
well right when you remember we we when we started the variational methods right
we started the variational methods right we solve that we define what's going to
we solve that we define what's going to know about all right and this was amount
know about all right and this was amount to what the entity to the right legal
to what the entity to the right legal effects okay one of the things you need
effects okay one of the things you need to do when you're I this Court's right
to do when you're I this Court's right is to sexually complete the lower bound
is to sexually complete the lower bound because the objective invariants are
because the objective invariants are inferences to do what you want to much
inferences to do what you want to much tomorrow is the log-likelihood right and
tomorrow is the log-likelihood right and because you don't need too much to my
because you don't need too much to my eyes well below bow so you know you
eyes well below bow so you know you really have no choice but to compute a
really have no choice but to compute a lot of also in other ways if you do all
lot of also in other ways if you do all of the situation's right you go from one
of the situation's right you go from one iteration to another this question is
iteration to another this question is can you show me for no amount actually
can you show me for no amount actually increases during iterations because if
increases during iterations because if it does then whatever interests is you
it does then whatever interests is you do it's magic is not science you need to
do it's magic is not science you need to show that the lower body continuously
show that the lower body continuously increases okay so we need to compute the
increases okay so we need to compute the lower now that's the standard
lower now that's the standard calculation you have to do in this
calculation you have to do in this approximate variational method so let's
approximate variational method so let's try to do the lower bound for the simple
try to do the lower bound for the simple case of the Gaussian so I'm going to
case of the Gaussian so I'm going to remind you the calculation it's also bad
remind you the calculation it's also bad but its standard it will do it two or
but its standard it will do it two or three or four problems you will be able
three or four problems you will be able to actually do this in research related
to actually do this in research related problems in machine learning
problems in machine learning okay so the I remind you it's the
okay so the I remind you it's the expectation with respect to the
expectation with respect to the variational distribution to guarantee
variational distribution to guarantee which we factorize it and of the log of
which we factorize it and of the log of the joint initiative hood and I wrote it
the joint initiative hood and I wrote it here explicitly this is my date of the
here explicitly this is my date of the MU and power divided by the variance
MU and power divided by the variance the tradition and then I mean how is the
the tradition and then I mean how is the great power
great power alright this is the definition we use
alright this is the definition we use that's a little bomb so to exceed this
that's a little bomb so to exceed this alright so I'm going to make this Q and
alright so I'm going to make this Q and substituted with expectation of the
substituted with expectation of the arguments right this is the expectation
arguments right this is the expectation of Islam with respect to this variation
of Islam with respect to this variation distribution Q so that's what II refers
distribution Q so that's what II refers here so I have the expectation of the
here so I have the expectation of the log of the numerator which I can write
log of the numerator which I can write it the log of the likes we've given the
it the log of the likes we've given the parameters and then I have the prior log
parameters and then I have the prior log of the prior given tower level of the
of the prior given tower level of the prior power you see that this counts by
prior power you see that this counts by writing this as the life of the time
writing this as the life of the time supplier
supplier all right nothing else and then Bill
all right nothing else and then Bill denominator because this is factorize I
denominator because this is factorize I have expectations and all these
have expectations and all these expectations of the law of pure fair and
expectations of the law of pure fair and a lot of rooftop really all right so if
a lot of rooftop really all right so if you need to do you need to go and and
you need to do you need to go and and compute all of the steps okay it makes a
compute all of the steps okay it makes a massive task and this is only a
massive task and this is only a univariate gaussians so you should be
univariate gaussians so you should be able to to live with it okay so let's
able to to live with it okay so let's see let's pick up the easy terms if you
see let's pick up the easy terms if you take one more fuel and what type of
take one more fuel and what type of distribution self you feminists
it came to be a Gaussian viscount's and clear right so when you have the
clear right so when you have the expected obviously there is not here
expected obviously there is not here alright so the expectation was with
alright so the expectation was with respect to me on power but this now
respect to me on power but this now becomes expectation expecting you so
becomes expectation expecting you so leave me what you have here is nothing
leave me what you have here is nothing else not the entropy of this Gaussian
else not the entropy of this Gaussian distribution so you can look in
distribution so you can look in Wikipedia and say entropy list there's
Wikipedia and say entropy list there's the answer okay alright so this is the
the answer okay alright so this is the entropy of QP would be the entropy of
entropy of QP would be the entropy of the gamma distribution you can again
the gamma distribution you can again look at Wikipedia 75 minutes when I
look at Wikipedia 75 minutes when I check these things right there is
check these things right there is information everywhere around you in
information everywhere around you in case you don't remember this is what's
case you don't remember this is what's called the my gamma distribution that
called the my gamma distribution that appears in the gamma distribution sin it
appears in the gamma distribution sin it also appears in the distribution so this
also appears in the distribution so this is it so this is the by gamma
is it so this is the by gamma distribution okay I'm not gonna tell you
distribution okay I'm not gonna tell you what it is you can look and I trust
what it is you can look and I trust there is a link there of India and they
there is a link there of India and they were not really computers there was no
were not really computers there was no Wikipedia there were no books they were
Wikipedia there were no books they were not PDFs of Chinese origin or anything
not PDFs of Chinese origin or anything like that everything was nice and clean
like that everything was nice and clean some with some library and you have to
some with some library and you have to go and spend five hours to locate it in
go and spend five hours to locate it in a library here are you know two minutes
a library here are you know two minutes where it is alright but obviously you're
where it is alright but obviously you're given something immediately means the
given something immediately means the expectations that you do something with
expectations that you do something with other are higher all right because this
other are higher all right because this information area you need to do user
information area you need to do user information no excuses for not
information no excuses for not fixed all right so complicated terms we
fixed all right so complicated terms we need now the expectation of the logo PI
need now the expectation of the logo PI of T with respect to Q of T so I keep
of T with respect to Q of T so I keep the expectation outside I'm expanding
the expectation outside I'm expanding the log of gamma distribution so there
the log of gamma distribution so there is nothing here bizarre from the
is nothing here bizarre from the normalization terms okay
normalization terms okay this comes from you know remember the
this comes from you know remember the gamma distribution is tower 12 plus 0
gamma distribution is tower 12 plus 0 minus 1 tau 2 minus B you got 2 minus
minus 1 tau 2 minus B you got 2 minus beta 0 right or biggest deal to minus
beta 0 right or biggest deal to minus tau which was it yeah okay something
tau which was it yeah okay something something you know something like that
something you know something like that okay so okay so let me see there must be
okay so okay so let me see there must be a missing term here so I need to dig
a missing term here so I need to dig expectations this with respect to Q P
expectations this with respect to Q P okay and this term is constant this term
okay and this term is constant this term is constant
is constant okay what we need to do now is you need
okay what we need to do now is you need the expectation of the longest power
the expectation of the longest power with respect to Q tau and cube time is
with respect to Q tau and cube time is for distribution is gamma surprised
for distribution is gamma surprised there's a very famous formula becomes
there's a very famous formula becomes very often actually in machine learning
very often actually in machine learning it's not as a gamma distribution we have
it's not as a gamma distribution we have expectations with respect to the gamma
expectations with respect to the gamma distribution of the love of tau the
distribution of the love of tau the result is the by gamma distribution
result is the by gamma distribution calculated on so if the Nama
calculated on so if the Nama distribution starts a and B so this
distribution starts a and B so this triangle trace of a minus log of theta
triangle trace of a minus log of theta okay and some course you need to compute
okay and some course you need to compute the mean of a gamma distribution which
the mean of a gamma distribution which is a over beta so basically you're done
is a over beta so basically you're done with this term as well this is premium
with this term as well this is premium because this Gaussian
because this Gaussian this is Gaussian so
this is Gaussian so I am just giving you the results that
I am just giving you the results that you expose okay
you expose okay and you yours the sufficient statistics
and you yours the sufficient statistics of the day to simplify you get this nice
of the day to simplify you get this nice results stimulus for this is a Gaussian
results stimulus for this is a Gaussian okay you expand and this is the final
okay you expand and this is the final formula okay
formula okay it looks very complicated and you may
it looks very complicated and you may ask me I'm like so kind to you putting
ask me I'm like so kind to you putting all these things in different colors no
all these things in different colors no you know why I put them in colors
you know why I put them in colors because when I was deriving this I keep
because when I was deriving this I keep doing mistakes so I wanted to know that
doing mistakes so I wanted to know that combines with what so I will bring it
combines with what so I will bring it for myself because you know this is the
for myself because you know this is the only way I can learn all right now if
only way I can learn all right now if you want to take advance of the course -
you want to take advance of the course - and if together why they work there okay
and if together why they work there okay so this time something would be the same
so this time something would be the same color combined and when you're finished
color combined and when you're finished if you get let me see if there is a you
if you get let me see if there is a you did actually an extremely trivial
did actually an extremely trivial formula okay I'm surprised myself
formula okay I'm surprised myself - obviously lots of cancellations the
- obviously lots of cancellations the loan amount is - well half of ll of long
loan amount is - well half of ll of long tenure okay Plus local programmer
tenure okay Plus local programmer function computer the N minus a and log
function computer the N minus a and log of BN and I remind you this a N and B
of BN and I remind you this a N and B else we defined them when we computed
else we defined them when we computed the variational distributions so
the variational distributions so basically L of Q it's all kind of a
basically L of Q it's all kind of a formula so what you need to do is as you
formula so what you need to do is as you update these lambdas and alphas and
update these lambdas and alphas and betas in the two bodies and
betas in the two bodies and distributions you actually have to plot
distributions you actually have to plot this out - and disturb that is
this out - and disturb that is monotonically increasing if it is not
monotonically increasing if it is not either
either the calculation of the the distributions
the calculation of the the distributions is wrong or basically your calculations
is wrong or basically your calculations of the lower bound is incorrect okay
this is very essential you have to do this in every problem
well I'd solution since we talked about for the single Gaussian about computing
for the single Gaussian about computing the lower bound right to say that we
the lower bound right to say that we optimized properly let's discuss her a
optimized properly let's discuss her a bit rational influenced many variation
bit rational influenced many variation of box missions in the context of model
of box missions in the context of model selection of a belief in in this case I
selection of a belief in in this case I am not at all about model selection but
am not at all about model selection but we spend a lot of times
we spend a lot of times lots of lectures on in the fall to
lots of lectures on in the fall to discuss about model selection so the
discuss about model selection so the idea here is you know you may have
idea here is you know you may have different models that you label them
different models that you label them with them all right maybe you put some
with them all right maybe you put some Flyers of this models and you have some
Flyers of this models and you have some date and you want to figure out what is
date and you want to figure out what is the best model all right what's the best
the best model all right what's the best model so the question is can you
model so the question is can you actually use variation optimization
actually use variation optimization variation our interest to find the best
variation our interest to find the best model so in principle what I'm asking is
model so in principle what I'm asking is will be possible
will be possible let's say you start with some prior that
let's say you start with some prior that this given the telling formative you put
this given the telling formative you put the same probability in all the models
the same probability in all the models can you calculate gears from data a
can you calculate gears from data a variation of posterior of M where m is a
variation of posterior of M where m is a model so let's have models you know
model so let's have models you know what's the best model right and we will
what's the best model right and we will do this you know in the context of
do this you know in the context of regression I think possibly today all
regression I think possibly today all right but I wanted to do sort of a very
right but I wanted to do sort of a very feeble calculation to see the
feeble calculation to see the variational calculations can actually be
variational calculations can actually be used to compute the posterior of that
used to compute the posterior of that okay so so basically we're looking here
okay so so basically we're looking here is if we have some data X right can we
is if we have some data X right can we calculate the posterior of the mountain
calculate the posterior of the mountain the beta example affirmative say it's
the beta example affirmative say it's regression may be negative equal to 1/s
regression may be negative equal to 1/s you use linear concepts maybe different
you use linear concepts maybe different person use quadratic functions model
person use quadratic functions model equal three cubic functions or maybe you
equal three cubic functions or maybe you know more than one is you use one basis
know more than one is you use one basis function or the to two basis functions
function or the to two basis functions three based processes which man who does
three based processes which man who does the best all right but you have to sit
the best all right but you have to sit for money how these calculations come in
for money how these calculations come in the context of this variational method
the context of this variational method so we'll do some simple trivial nothing
so we'll do some simple trivial nothing sophisticated yet so wanna do is let's
sophisticated yet so wanna do is let's say that every model has its own local
say that every model has its own local variables
so you know so when I try to define a variation approximation of the posterior
variation approximation of the posterior of znm I am gonna write it as follows
of znm I am gonna write it as follows somebody a tional distribution of Z
somebody a tional distribution of Z given M so this is an approximation the
given M so this is an approximation the posterior of the super hyper score model
posterior of the super hyper score model M times the posterior on the left
M times the posterior on the left alright so nothing so some calculations
alright so nothing so some calculations here to see how this whole thing's come
here to see how this whole thing's come to the others are approximation to the
to the others are approximation to the low black we would without any
low black we would without any discussion of model terror all right so
discussion of model terror all right so what I have done is I give the
what I have done is I give the definition of the lower bound
definition of the lower bound alright and then I suppose you remember
alright and then I suppose you remember what the expectation with respect to the
what the expectation with respect to the latent power also in this case the
latent power also in this case the latent variables really CNN they are
latent variables really CNN they are both unknowns
both unknowns okay and I put the posterior this is my
okay and I put the posterior this is my approximate posterior this is the
approximate posterior this is the expectation part and then I have the log
expectation part and then I have the log the joint look likelihood noticed a
the joint look likelihood noticed a little active with this my vapors
little active with this my vapors detects my ZN my model because I how
detects my ZN my model because I how does that have put the motive to be and
does that have put the motive to be and I know this is basically about models
I know this is basically about models okay and then of the denominator
okay and then of the denominator obviously have the same foreign
obviously have the same foreign distribution so you can write the same
distribution so you can write the same as before so here what I do is I write
as before so here what I do is I write the exact post fear of ZN m given the
the exact post fear of ZN m given the data times few effects and this like
data times few effects and this like that okay and and in this last line with
that okay and and in this last line with like this I take this P effects and I
like this I take this P effects and I remove it out because doesn't depend on
remove it out because doesn't depend on M and D respectively what I get is this
M and D respectively what I get is this nice thing plus log of P of X and you
nice thing plus log of P of X and you probably might if you love of the
probably might if you love of the effects is basically the lower bound
effects is basically the lower bound - this okay does this remind you
- this okay does this remind you anything what is remember the one we
anything what is remember the one we have the fundamental identity that the
have the fundamental identity that the log likelihood is different the lower
log likelihood is different the lower bound and Wiggins was there became of
bound and Wiggins was there became of dimensions the only difference here is
dimensions the only difference here is instead of a sphere of Z I have the
instead of a sphere of Z I have the proof CNN right solution has changed
proof CNN right solution has changed okay very much imperative to tell you on
okay very much imperative to tell you on how you compute for your friends so
how you compute for your friends so let's see what we can do this so long
let's see what we can do this so long ado this is let's say you can maybe go
ado this is let's say you can maybe go in addition approximations on each model
in addition approximations on each model and if you can then calculate
and if you can then calculate below the bar for its problem so L M is
below the bar for its problem so L M is the lower bathroom of the length and I
the lower bathroom of the length and I write it like that everybody agrees I
write it like that everybody agrees I mean you can see here what is that is
mean you can see here what is that is the joint alive you could form on the
the joint alive you could form on the level there's nothing fancy
level there's nothing fancy okay my conditioner to your embassy
okay my conditioner to your embassy right so the question is once I have
right so the question is once I have this can I come up with a novel lower
this can I come up with a novel lower bound basically for my whole problem for
bound basically for my whole problem for mothers have been integrate doubt so
mothers have been integrate doubt so let's see how the calculation looks like
let's see how the calculation looks like it's actually very interesting in Sabra
it's actually very interesting in Sabra this is what we started before all right
this is what we started before all right this is having a variation of
this is having a variation of distribution models and all disease for
distribution models and all disease for each model so what I do is I write the
each model so what I do is I write the actual join of lack of it here as the
actual join of lack of it here as the probability of Z and X given M plus the
probability of Z and X given M plus the prior of them all right and then on the
prior of them all right and then on the denominator I have minus log of Q of Z M
denominator I have minus log of Q of Z M and if you alright
and if you alright I let's see I shake here I'm going to
I let's see I shake here I'm going to put two of them outside okay
put two of them outside okay so cute n goes to the whole thing so I'm
so cute n goes to the whole thing so I'm going to put Q of em outside so I have P
going to put Q of em outside so I have P of M and then of p.m. nice Ln of QM nice
of M and then of p.m. nice Ln of QM nice I have obviously the summation of M will
I have obviously the summation of M will been outside then I have a summation on
been outside then I have a summation on Z and this thing right depends on G so
Z and this thing right depends on G so I'm going to have cube CM and then of P
I'm going to have cube CM and then of P of Z comma X given them and we have this
of Z comma X given them and we have this curve as well will you agree the fiscal
curve as well will you agree the fiscal think it is really ll compelling to God
think it is really ll compelling to God is it
is it it is right all right sorry I'm writing
it is right all right sorry I'm writing this whole thing then qfm love of
this whole thing then qfm love of theater - love of children and I should
theater - love of children and I should have LM so if I did this love of it -
have LM so if I did this love of it - the 11 right nothing spectacular there's
the 11 right nothing spectacular there's a reason for this I arrived it like that
a reason for this I arrived it like that because then I can write this whole the
because then I can write this whole the overall lower bound I can write this
overall lower bound I can write this ship m ln of pfm times C to the LM / q /
ship m ln of pfm times C to the LM / q / and so look at this nice now the
and so look at this nice now the relation of the lower bounds and tell me
relation of the lower bounds and tell me what is this nice quantity now that that
what is this nice quantity now that that remind you by definition
come on I Sakura Sakura Venice is something
I Sakura Sakura Venice is something there it doesn't have to remind you this
there it doesn't have to remind you this question today was something we have
question today was something we have mentioned maybe something would have not
mentioned maybe something would have not mentioned but what is this by definition
the work
I'm here thank you remember noise filtering and it's a nonlinear filtering
filtering and it's a nonlinear filtering all right so what is that entity is -
all right so what is that entity is - the word
now it looks like an expectation but there is a better definition of what is
there is a better definition of what is this is - I gave you half of the story -
this is - I gave you half of the story - out of the KL divergence between Q and P
out of the KL divergence between Q and P of 10 times e to the 11 all right so the
of 10 times e to the 11 all right so the objective is to maximize the overall
objective is to maximize the overall lower bound then you have to minimize
this and we know the exact answer right this will be optimised when qfm equal to
this will be optimised when qfm equal to PM e to the LM where the ram is equal
PM e to the LM where the ram is equal like that so really now for the first
like that so really now for the first time you no need to slide you have seen
time you no need to slide you have seen a variational posterior of a model in
a variational posterior of a model in two slides okay so you can I mean this
two slides okay so you can I mean this can be extremely useful if you want to
can be extremely useful if you want to do model selection in regression
do model selection in regression classification just mention it which
classification just mention it which model does the best alright so this
model does the best alright so this gives you an approximation give it the
gives you an approximation give it the data of the posterior over models and if
data of the posterior over models and if you plot this for model 1 2 &amp; 3 etc you
you plot this for model 1 2 &amp; 3 etc you know you will eventually be able to do
know you will eventually be able to do model selection figure out what's the
model selection figure out what's the best model that interprets the data okay
best model that interprets the data okay so this is a very nice calculation using
so this is a very nice calculation using variational methods of expense basically
variational methods of expense basically this concept for computing distribution
this concept for computing distribution of related variables now computing
of related variables now computing distributions over latent variables and
distributions over latent variables and models
models alright so very nice
so
the 1990 pastula so they decide on this actually where I can if there is a new
actually where I can if there is a new tactic that's a little bit more
tactic that's a little bit more complicated than the topics to come but
complicated than the topics to come but because I need somehow put them together
because I need somehow put them together let me let me finish it up right and try
let me let me finish it up right and try to do our best to understand it again
to do our best to understand it again this will be by Sheriff Tom it's a bit
this will be by Sheriff Tom it's a bit more difficult than some of the problems
more difficult than some of the problems we will see next but let's get get out
we will see next but let's get get out of the way okay well first what the
of the way okay well first what the macaronis is about so what you see here
macaronis is about so what you see here is a model where you know I mean it
is a model where you know I mean it snows here in earlier lectures the
snows here in earlier lectures the difference from what we discussed in
difference from what we discussed in most of the presentations from hmm is
most of the presentations from hmm is but we have multiple chains but they're
but we have multiple chains but they're linked together and they're linked
linked together and they're linked together as you can see because the
together as you can see because the observations of every time dependent on
observations of every time dependent on the state of all the change okay so if
the state of all the change okay so if you try to actually messaging and you
you try to actually messaging and you know the cell phone data messages to do
know the cell phone data messages to do it because the chains are coupled okay
it because the chains are coupled okay the list would be a serious limitation
the list would be a serious limitation of the things we learned in the context
of the things we learned in the context of what's called proctorial hidden
of what's called proctorial hidden Markov models okay so then I don't
Markov models okay so then I don't highlight basically today it can somehow
highlight basically today it can somehow reduce some ideas from variational
reduce some ideas from variational method and the star approximation of the
method and the star approximation of the posterior of this stage of the different
posterior of this stage of the different change in a way that somehow uncouples
change in a way that somehow uncouples them in
them in in a manner that somehow allow us to use
in a manner that somehow allow us to use forward my first Masters propagation the
forward my first Masters propagation the way we have seen it for one chain in the
way we have seen it for one chain in the past or you know for independent text so
past or you know for independent text so let's determine deed to see if Malaysia
let's determine deed to see if Malaysia Metis actually are any views on this
Metis actually are any views on this problem
problem I mean violation weapons we will see
I mean violation weapons we will see there of use for everything okay the
there of use for everything okay the approximate method for everything first
approximate method for everything first example if you can think here my
example if you can think here my syllabus is really act alright this is
syllabus is really act alright this is the unknown states the data why you can
the unknown states the data why you can stick here much so if the joining
stick here much so if the joining likelihood is basically my transition
likelihood is basically my transition model from t minus one two three okay
model from t minus one two three okay and the observation model okay and you
and the observation model okay and you notice there is a copy here and I'm
notice there is a copy here and I'm gonna show you here explicitly because
gonna show you here explicitly because why P depends on the axis of all these
why P depends on the axis of all these state X M alright and this the profit
state X M alright and this the profit the Jane looked like I mean John like
the Jane looked like I mean John like liquids a product over the change and
liquids a product over the change and all the time instances teeth okay so the
all the time instances teeth okay so the definition is very very similar to what
definition is very very similar to what we have seen from the exact logs on a
we have seen from the exact logs on a log likelihood that we have seen the
log likelihood that we have seen the trap so a we give a for the
trap so a we give a for the transition matrix we have some
transition matrix we have some probabilities for the initial space
probabilities for the initial space which is better from what we have done
which is better from what we have done before years but there is an index well
before years but there is an index well there is a named exam because this
there is a named exam because this transition probabilities and initial
transition probabilities and initial probabilities have to refer to its chain
probabilities have to refer to its chain K from k 1 to M okay so the likelihood
K from k 1 to M okay so the likelihood model this is departure from what we
model this is departure from what we have done in the hmm presentations it is
have done in the hmm presentations it is now the moon is defined to be estimation
now the moon is defined to be estimation of the
of the raishin basically a linear weighted sum
raishin basically a linear weighted sum of the states at this time and the
of the states at this time and the coefficients here we take them to be
coefficients here we take them to be given to start with okay so the mean is
given to start with okay so the mean is given some linear interpolation between
given some linear interpolation between the values of X's all the change
the values of X's all the change mm remember me from little n equal to R
mm remember me from little n equal to R to capital M okay so this is alright and
to capital M okay so this is alright and it's computationally very difficult to
it's computationally very difficult to work with because of this equation so
work with because of this equation so this equation constraint so you won't be
this equation constraint so you won't be able you know if you do expectation
able you know if you do expectation maximization for example and compute the
maximization for example and compute the sufficient statistic you won't be able
sufficient statistic you won't be able to use for the backward message passing
to use for the backward message passing because these messages are coupled so it
because these messages are coupled so it will be computationally very big okay so
will be computationally very big okay so I am I think the exact posterior
I am I think the exact posterior basically using the exact joint local
basically using the exact joint local article so expanding it basically this
article so expanding it basically this is the name of the probability value
is the name of the probability value shown in the previous slide so this
shown in the previous slide so this comes from the data likelihood that's
comes from the data likelihood that's for the coupling is okay it's a Gaussian
for the coupling is okay it's a Gaussian and we have thinking lungs so this
and we have thinking lungs so this vector here is the log of the
vector here is the log of the probabilities of the initial States for
probabilities of the initial States for its chain m and this is the launch of
its chain m and this is the launch of the transition probabilities for each
the transition probabilities for each state and there is really nothing near
state and there is really nothing near from what we discussed with hmm except
from what we discussed with hmm except the fact now that I have instead of
the fact now that I have instead of having one chain I have a summation of
having one chain I have a summation of each state of all the change with their
each state of all the change with their own profit initial probabilities and in
own profit initial probabilities and in the transitions have another summation
the transitions have another summation then for all the transition
then for all the transition probabilities right so we need to find
probabilities right so we need to find some way to
some way to just approximate inference to solve this
just approximate inference to solve this problem okay and the idea is the
problem okay and the idea is the difference like the world is approximate
difference like the world is approximate so miss can you have to use your
so miss can you have to use your intuition or you say I'm gonna try
intuition or you say I'm gonna try something that looks like that and let's
something that looks like that and let's hope for the best
hope for the best all right so the situation we will
all right so the situation we will discuss is an approximation that will
discuss is an approximation that will decouple the change okay so somehow we
decouple the change okay so somehow we decouple them so that way we can become
decouple them so that way we can become messages back and forth basically change
messages back and forth basically change independently now to the couple of them
independently now to the couple of them let me just tell you what the idea is
let me just tell you what the idea is obviously so if we try to approximate
obviously so if we try to approximate them it's independent can you imagine in
them it's independent can you imagine in the context of maintained approximations
the context of maintained approximations something we need to do to get rid of
something we need to do to get rid of this term here this is the evidence for
this term here this is the evidence for typos everything together
typos everything together can you think of some sort of you know
can you think of some sort of you know idea with a backward message passing on
idea with a backward message passing on its same but we're going to be able to
its same but we're going to be able to account mission is I mean it's insane
account mission is I mean it's insane does really does but in the average
does really does but in the average sentence to detect so we need to abuse
sentence to detect so we need to abuse some concept of evidenced not miss
some concept of evidenced not miss evidence but some local evidence that is
evidence but some local evidence that is introduced in every chain that comes
introduced in every chain that comes from the fact of all the change make
from the fact of all the change make sense
sense all right so we're gonna run them
all right so we're gonna run them independently but there must be some
independently but there must be some things that influences would say train
things that influences would say train one because this change had in some
one because this change had in some state okay so here right actually one of
state okay so here right actually one of the questions you need on the on those
the questions you need on the on those three lines so this evidence at this
three lines so this evidence at this time I call it c PM k alright and time T
time I call it c PM k alright and time T it refers to chain M okay and tell them
it refers to chain M okay and tell them because listen hmm can be in state K is
because listen hmm can be in state K is what stated this so tell us what is c TM
what stated this so tell us what is c TM k trying to do in this equation here
there's no evidence there's no the release will disappear from the picture
release will disappear from the picture there's no evidence or anything like
there's no evidence or anything like that
that right when the evidence comes from this
right when the evidence comes from this exists so we'll do this test really are
exists so we'll do this test really are trying to accomplish the way that you
trying to accomplish the way that you see them on the slide
so for example you know this is a transition for train em from time t
transition for train em from time t minus 1 t 2 t but you notice I'm
minus 1 t 2 t but you notice I'm conditioning it on Shion
so register we don't mean a word discussed this man so not meaning are
discussed this man so not meaning are you going to attach to this chaps
hosted a seminar I was well they have to complete them we have no idea where they
complete them we have no idea where they are but we're trying to mimic something
are but we're trying to mimic something whether we're trying to mimic here a
mixture of gaussians
I remember like this this clay thing here is because I have unchain them
right so this is the only place that will allow me to introduce local
will allow me to introduce local evidence in the model all right so in
evidence in the model all right so in essence getting rid of all of these
essence getting rid of all of these things right we're going to do a
things right we're going to do a variation approximation getting rid of
variation approximation getting rid of this cutting here all right so this
this cutting here all right so this would be a body mole that accounts for
would be a body mole that accounts for the effect of all the other change from
the effect of all the other change from China okay we have no idea what G of K
China okay we have no idea what G of K is so we're gonna have to go in
is so we're gonna have to go in computation or you know is written
computation or you know is written basically like this okay this is for the
basically like this okay this is for the initial state so as we know is for every
initial state so as we know is for every chain from M 1 to M so this is for the
chain from M 1 to M so this is for the initial state in every train them and
initial state in every train them and this is for the for each type for each
this is for the for each type for each chain M the transition from t minus 1 to
chain M the transition from t minus 1 to t ok this is thunder what is different
t ok this is thunder what is different here is that we conditions is these
here is that we conditions is these things of local evidence 3 okay and the
things of local evidence 3 okay and the definition of the two variation
definition of the two variation distributions is what you see here okay
distributions is what you see here okay this is the same as before this is the
this is the same as before this is the same as before this is now we plug it in
same as before this is now we plug it in helping to account for the main craft if
helping to account for the main craft if you like or probably other change from
you like or probably other change from its chain em alright
so the you know when you calculate basically you take the joint look like
basically you take the joint look like they could do the variation
they could do the variation approximation can believe that in a
approximation can believe that in a gives form into some some energy EQ and
gives form into some some energy EQ and this energy basically has an extremely
this energy basically has an extremely simple fall alright so obviously you are
simple fall alright so obviously you are going to get you're going to get long
going to get you're going to get long survey and long supply so this carrying
survey and long supply so this carrying entities are basically the this log okay
entities are basically the this log okay so let's add all the terms come where is
so let's add all the terms come where is this Pam coming from let's have mr. what
this Pam coming from let's have mr. what is this term coming from
what is this time can be problem
I mean we have this is what we're looking right and I'm taking logs what
looking right and I'm taking logs what them here will give me the stuff I
them here will give me the stuff I contain the game discs Academy is the
contain the game discs Academy is the number of districts II support that idea
number of districts II support that idea that will come from there from this and
that will come from there from this and there
when you take your sis okay so this term comes from this term this term will be
comes from this term this term will be coming from latter
coming from latter okay well this curvy area is the log of
okay well this curvy area is the log of this a this term here will come when you
this a this term here will come when you take logs or come Lister and the
take logs or come Lister and the incorporation of the loads from Lister
incorporation of the loads from Lister is accounted already in the summation
is accounted already in the summation here starting from T equal to one
here starting from T equal to one okay approximation right and the change
okay approximation right and the change is there anything that is explicit that
is there anything that is explicit that this same depends on all the other
this same depends on all the other change and I remind you what coupling is
change and I remind you what coupling is coupling at the following movin up so
coupling at the following movin up so the action for scalar is e to the minus
the action for scalar is e to the minus C and E alright you can see all the
C and E alright you can see all the stage couple together okay alright so
stage couple together okay alright so what you need to do is so we have the
what you need to do is so we have the actual energy and the action per student
actual energy and the action per student but we won't approximate it with this
but we won't approximate it with this and actively what you need to do is you
and actively what you need to do is you need to form the KL distance between Q
need to form the KL distance between Q and P and minimize the vehicle distance
and P and minimize the vehicle distance with respect to what a long variable I'm
with respect to what a long variable I'm going to show you that the transition
going to show you that the transition probabilities and initial probabilities
probabilities and initial probabilities are known so the only unknown on this
are known so the only unknown on this problem is going to be well so in this
problem is going to be well so in this model that is going to be beyond y'know
the truth - and again access will be the the
- and again access will be the the events and approximation of the local
events and approximation of the local evidence coming to train em from
evidence coming to train em from whatever checked so that's the only
whatever checked so that's the only unknown alright we're gonna trim the
unknown alright we're gonna trim the parameters B being a there are unit for
parameters B being a there are unit for simplicity minimization between the
simplicity minimization between the exact P and Q and you do the algebra I
exact P and Q and you do the algebra I strongly recommend that you do it
strongly recommend that you do it because I did it and it may have some
because I did it and it may have some typos maybe not okay so if you do this
typos maybe not okay so if you do this and you do it carefully it comes out
and you do it carefully it comes out that you need an extremely simple
that you need an extremely simple formula that they obeyed we also have
formula that they obeyed we also have removed state K the update of this
removed state K the update of this record to see is this exponential of
record to see is this exponential of this WM metrics that comes to remember
this WM metrics that comes to remember in the likelihoods and the covariance
in the likelihoods and the covariance minus one and this is the evidence the
minus one and this is the evidence the data that is written like that okay and
data that is written like that okay and this
this vente is is a vector that is formed
vente is is a vector that is formed basically by taking the diagonal
basically by taking the diagonal elements of this matrix the calculation
elements of this matrix the calculation is perfect for an infinitely but you
is perfect for an infinitely but you know there is really nothing else except
know there is really nothing else except you know that you have to calculate the
you know that you have to calculate the derivatives of the partition functions
derivatives of the partition functions of the normalization factors with
of the normalization factors with respect to sis so that's sort of the
respect to sis so that's sort of the only tricky part
only tricky part you cannot allow basically you to work
you cannot allow basically you to work with Q and P that are not normalized so
with Q and P that are not normalized so you need to normalize them and that's
you need to normalize them and that's why you get these locks of zq and locks
why you get these locks of zq and locks of Z but apart from that the rest is
of Z but apart from that the rest is just history this is a very simple
just history this is a very simple formula all right and in other
formula all right and in other circumstances I will have asked you to
circumstances I will have asked you to write a little computer program to
write a little computer program to actually change to check this portfolio
actually change to check this portfolio key the Markov model
key the Markov model it really works it really works
it really works it really works eben we're here has lots of intuition
eben we're here has lots of intuition they're on the way we decouple the
they're on the way we decouple the evidence is that you worked quite well
evidence is that you worked quite well okay and again if you think about it the
okay and again if you think about it the only things you have to do is a simple
only things you have to do is a simple update formula okay and the rest is
update formula okay and the rest is basically you know the rest is basically
basically you know the rest is basically have to do a forward and backward mess
have to do a forward and backward mess the propagation the way we have done
the propagation the way we have done earlier with one chain and hidden Markov
earlier with one chain and hidden Markov model
I only have ten minutes sorry basically I can only I can only start something so
I can only I can only start something so we need I'm going to go to a slightly
we need I'm going to go to a slightly different topic for those that are
different topic for those that are familiar with regression
obviously all of this will be posted on the website so let me let me show you
the website so let me let me show you and maybe we can actually finish it in
and maybe we can actually finish it in 10 minutes if we can be linear
10 minutes if we can be linear regression using okay now again I am I'm
regression using okay now again I am I'm going to be talking about regression
going to be talking about regression assuming everybody in the audience knows
assuming everybody in the audience knows with regression
with regression okay here's some basis functions here a
okay here's some basis functions here a linear regression model so you can think
linear regression model so you can think that the response of the system that
that the response of the system that you've indicated here with is let me
you've indicated here with is let me respond some with regular basis
respond some with regular basis functions that you can calculate at any
functions that you can calculate at any point X plus some noise the defined here
point X plus some noise the defined here by the precision data so basically I'm
by the precision data so basically I'm taking that the likelihood of data is a
taking that the likelihood of data is a product of thousands it's authorized
product of thousands it's authorized over the iid day okay so a standard okay
over the iid day okay so a standard okay usually what you do in in Bayesian
usually what you do in in Bayesian regression you're going to put some
regression you're going to put some primer on the dummy here given some
primer on the dummy here given some precision alpha alright and then you put
precision alpha alright and then you put some prior on that is taking I'll see
some prior on that is taking I'll see you at within this you can make this a
you at within this you can make this a vector of alphas and you can do
vector of alphas and you can do relevance determination and all the this
relevance determination and all the this very nice things for modern selection
very nice things for modern selection but right now there's only one alpha
but right now there's only one alpha alright and
alright and and so what a bad review a laptop is the
and so what a bad review a laptop is the prior and fearful toys and other hyper
prior and fearful toys and other hyper prior asking the posterior distribution
solution we have done it ok and become Scouts for any X so and this tradition
Scouts for any X so and this tradition where you know so basically an internet
where you know so basically an internet if you think of the livelihood at any
if you think of the livelihood at any location X you know times the posterior
location X you know times the posterior of W integrand of the solutions to all
of W integrand of the solutions to all of this but we pretend we don't know any
of this but we pretend we don't know any of this and we really want to see
of this and we really want to see Bayesian inference will actually is the
Bayesian inference will actually is the data decide the observations think I'm
data decide the observations think I'm corresponding axis right so I only did
corresponding axis right so I only did that this year but remember this is
that this year but remember this is conditional on the axis as well okay
conditional on the axis as well okay it's not important to mess up the
it's not important to mess up the notation so the the likelihood is nice
notation so the the likelihood is nice exactly like that right no W I know what
exactly like that right no W I know what is the probability of T plus a prior or
is the probability of T plus a prior or value given applause all right and
value given applause all right and that's the probabilistic after model in
that's the probabilistic after model in a simple sense looks like this okay a
a simple sense looks like this okay a plate rotation for the iid data and
plate rotation for the iid data and basically W open here
basically W open here remind me must be the high
remind me must be the high parameter coming inside of gamma
parameter coming inside of gamma distribution occasional vaccinations six
distribution occasional vaccinations six days to go we've been assume that cube W
days to go we've been assume that cube W and alpha fertilize director whenever
and alpha fertilize director whenever you have a knowledge of the exact
you have a knowledge of the exact solution we'll pretend we never read the
solution we'll pretend we never read the books so you see now and we want
books so you see now and we want something that basically says that this
something that basically says that this issue of WN always give W times P of
issue of WN always give W times P of alpha we have no idea what this
alpha we have no idea what this distribution should be okay
you clearly to death and you kill it there funny if you try to do it by can't
there funny if you try to do it by can't otherwise looking at it means nothing
otherwise looking at it means nothing I remind us so the novel by Q powerful
I remind us so the novel by Q powerful for example will be the expectation with
for example will be the expectation with respect to all the other very most so
respect to all the other very most so whether you are the variables here
what are the unknowns in this problem so you know when we computed the here what
you know when we computed the here what are the announces that we are not
are the announces that we are not probably still so the expectation or
probably still so the expectation or when I the join of market we're not
when I the join of market we're not going to be taking expectations here
going to be taking expectations here with respect to EE you okay so obviously
with respect to EE you okay so obviously was applied a long time there was a
was applied a long time there was a prior on da be given alpha and alpha
prior on da be given alpha and alpha doesn't come in the liquid so you know
doesn't come in the liquid so you know constant so this is a gamma alright
constant so this is a gamma alright this we took it as a Gaussian sham
this we took it as a Gaussian sham taking the terms that depend on alpha
taking the terms that depend on alpha all right the rest I don't care and the
all right the rest I don't care and the expectation carries with respect to W
expectation carries with respect to W all right so the distribution you think
all right so the distribution you think you get for cute outfit here look I mean
you get for cute outfit here look I mean it was much like a little drama
it was much like a little drama distribution what do you think this is
what's the distribution for coupons
if as long as the gamma distribution arrived with updated parameters because
arrived with updated parameters because you can see never fast but here local
you can see never fast but here local populace so you have a zero plus M over
populace so you have a zero plus M over 2 minus 1 so the first coefficient is a
2 minus 1 so the first coefficient is a zero plus 10 over 2 and BN is equal to
zero plus 10 over 2 and BN is equal to that so T of a is a gamma distribution
that so T of a is a gamma distribution not a putz you do the same thing with
not a putz you do the same thing with Dario the expectation now have to be
Dario the expectation now have to be respect to alpha so no surprise actually
respect to alpha so no surprise actually this distribution comes from be a
this distribution comes from be a Gaussian so that this is the main this
Gaussian so that this is the main this is the variance and no surprise by the
is the variance and no surprise by the way every foot of water is alpha you get
way every foot of water is alpha you get an expectation and the okay okay this is
an expectation and the okay okay this is making you know for basing the
making you know for basing the regression and the difference is there
regression and the difference is there was an alpha now we have the expression
okay so this only having okay this we need to check it out but you notice the
need to check it out but you notice the coupling right to compute the
coupling right to compute the distribution of variation of alpha you
distribution of variation of alpha you need to know the moment W of the
need to know the moment W of the expectation that means I suppose now
expectation that means I suppose now here so you obviously have to couple the
here so you obviously have to couple the two equations okay so alright so
two equations okay so alright so actually the results it says here from
actually the results it says here from what amazing they look exactly the same
what amazing they look exactly the same reason as you get with expectation
reason as you get with expectation maximization
maximization the only difference is basically if you
the only difference is basically if you use the expectation of alpha all right
use the expectation of alpha all right but we got those in the trivial manner
but we got those in the trivial manner and in some sense you know it tells you
and in some sense you know it tells you that this techniques at the end of the
that this techniques at the end of the day are linked together and I remind you
day are linked together and I remind you that when the most likely that
that when the most likely that expectation maximization is a trivial
expectation maximization is a trivial stuff case of the variational method
stuff case of the variational method right so it's a simple not a surprise
right so it's a simple not a surprise that you get those results if you want
that you get those results if you want the predictive distribution we have one
the predictive distribution we have one minute to go basically that you need
minute to go basically that you need this you need to integrate a lot to be
this you need to integrate a lot to be times the posterior and here because we
times the posterior and here because we use variational method if you don't see
use variational method if you don't see the exact posterior you put the
the exact posterior you put the variational posterior and this is the
variational posterior and this is the marginalization of the two gaussians
marginalization of the two gaussians this mean here is a linear dependence
this mean here is a linear dependence from W so the solutions actually we have
from W so the solutions actually we have seen it in three times is given
seen it in three times is given analytically so basically that the mean
analytically so basically that the mean and the variance the variance right is
and the variance the variance right is and again instead of PowerPoint you get
and again instead of PowerPoint you get the expectation of if you want to
the expectation of if you want to calculate the variable
calculate the variable surprise surprise the man comes to have
surprise surprise the man comes to have a fantastic wonderful analytical form
a fantastic wonderful analytical form okay yes and if you try to apply this to
okay yes and if you try to apply this to a simple polynomial regression for
a simple polynomial regression for example you're asking what are the
example you're asking what are the polynomial M so I guess you know
polynomial M so I guess you know obviously you can use whatever maximize
obviously you can use whatever maximize the lower mountain in this case if you
the lower mountain in this case if you do this problem you can all this Python
do this problem you can all this Python code you can see m equal to three
code you can see m equal to three maximizes the lower bound okay
maximizes the lower bound okay I warned you from us who study a
I warned you from us who study a disintegration investor regression what
disintegration investor regression what she does with a single flaw but instead
she does with a single flaw but instead of flapping the low block a man will be
of flapping the low block a man will be plot the model evidence because we can
plot the model evidence because we can exactly here the assumption is yes we
exactly here the assumption is yes we can calculate the mobile leg that's
can calculate the mobile leg that's exactly but this idea of failure is very
exactly but this idea of failure is very powerful because in problems with the
powerful because in problems with the model evidence cannot be calculated you
model evidence cannot be calculated you can have many developed you okay so we
can have many developed you okay so we will continue that on Thursday and
will continue that on Thursday and continuing become this topic then do
continuing become this topic then do something with Gaussian mixture and some
something with Gaussian mixture and some other interesting aspects