all right I have not posted this lecture yet it's more than 200 pages and I
yet it's more than 200 pages and I almost have only 10 pages left you know
almost have only 10 pages left you know so let's open the mentary stop so I'm
so let's open the mentary stop so I'm going to be jumping through but I will
going to be jumping through but I will try to finish the last ten pages today
try to finish the last ten pages today and post them by the end of the day so I
and post them by the end of the day so I assume all the projects have been
assume all the projects have been submitted including from those who have
submitted including from those who have no plans to submit project all right and
no plans to submit project all right and so we have permission projects and the
so we have permission projects and the deadline was yesterday okay so we need
deadline was yesterday okay so we need project all right so we're going to do
project all right so we're going to do is I'm going to go through you know
is I'm going to go through you know notice there is another point mental
notice there is another point mental state today because I'm over a million
state today because I'm over a million things when we are trying to jump
things when we are trying to jump through the flight to be sure we cover
through the flight to be sure we cover some essential topics and depending on
some essential topics and depending on where we are we decide on Thursday if we
where we are we decide on Thursday if we continue this lecturer would jump to
continue this lecturer would jump to state-space models the slides are very
state-space models the slides are very easy so you guys can read them in detail
easy so you guys can read them in detail so I'm gonna try to to do some something
so I'm gonna try to to do some something here there so things I want to discuss
here there so things I want to discuss today hopefully we will have time to do
today hopefully we will have time to do this how do we complete parameters in
this how do we complete parameters in hmm models and in computing parameters
hmm models and in computing parameters we will see that we need to integrate
we will see that we need to integrate the algorithms for forward and backward
the algorithms for forward and backward passing message passing basically those
passing message passing basically those messages will serve as essential
messages will serve as essential statistics that will allow us to
statistics that will allow us to complete parameters given some training
complete parameters given some training data okay
data okay what number was so I'm going to be
what number was so I'm going to be jumping slide and I'm going to go we
jumping slide and I'm going to go we stopped last lecture on slide 21 so we
stopped last lecture on slide 21 so we can deal extinct
can deal extinct simple training with a Markov model okay
conservatively the the problem of learning basically mercy consists of
learning basically mercy consists of words and I'm going to introduce some
words and I'm going to introduce some probability models over a single word so
information the time is time implies sequence in a sentence okay so it's not
sequence in a sentence okay so it's not really I mean you can apply this as
really I mean you can apply this as opposed when you talk alright so this
opposed when you talk alright so this can be represented once at the given
can be represented once at the given time but right now is world within a
time but right now is world within a text question so this is what we call
text question so this is what we call the Ingram probability this is a bigram
the Ingram probability this is a bigram probability so what's the next word
probability so what's the next word going to be given the previous world and
going to be given the previous world and this is what is the next word given the
this is what is the next word given the previous two words
previous two words so we can train a model like that given
so we can train a model like that given data and do some circuit elementary
data and do some circuit elementary statistics
statistics with some prior modeling to do that this
with some prior modeling to do that this is an essential problem if you are
is an essential problem if you are interested to complete the sentence if
interested to complete the sentence if you want to compress basically text and
you want to compress basically text and also if you want to write automatically
also if you want to write automatically without you know any interference from a
without you know any interference from a human you want to write in a stay which
human you want to write in a stay which of course may not be reading anything
of course may not be reading anything but you know if you want anything
but you know if you want anything somebody will buy okay so this is
somebody will buy okay so this is textbook all right some missed an
textbook all right some missed an example of this probabilities of the
example of this probabilities of the Engram probabilities for the different
Engram probabilities for the different letters they enjoyed in the alphabet and
letters they enjoyed in the alphabet and the first letter is basically implies
the first letter is basically implies nothing unknown so as timber basically
nothing unknown so as timber basically doesn't exist within those symbols this
doesn't exist within those symbols this is the Biograph probabilities to
is the Biograph probabilities to transition from one letter to another
transition from one letter to another the biggest this white spaces the high
the biggest this white spaces the high of this probability door so this is sort
of this probability door so this is sort of like a kingdom diagram
of like a kingdom diagram so we're going to have trick to the
so we're going to have trick to the mathematical problem and we will try to
mathematical problem and we will try to explain this in the context of sentences
explain this in the context of sentences the algebra but a very sort of universal
the algebra but a very sort of universal even for hidden Markov models that he
even for hidden Markov models that he understands this we can understand a
understands this we can understand a little bit more complex pro model the
little bit more complex pro model the Markov chain is rather hidden Markov
Markov chain is rather hidden Markov model right so we have it's a next Ronix
model right so we have it's a next Ronix to our X capital T so using conditional
to our X capital T so using conditional independence relations we like this like
independence relations we like this like that this is the probability of the
that this is the probability of the initial state so this is given and this
initial state so this is given and this of the transition probabilities from
of the transition probabilities from state X want you to XT minus 1 to X T
state X want you to XT minus 1 to X T and I can run a test in a much nicer
and I can run a test in a much nicer format the way that you see on the third
format the way that you see on the third lines I want you to pay close attention
lines I want you to pay close attention because sort of the notation is very
because sort of the notation is very standard these are many other problems
standard these are many other problems for mixed models and and the like so you
for mixed models and and the like so you know this is a standard way to write the
know this is a standard way to write the joint probability distribution given the
joint probability distribution given the parameters and parameters here referring
parameters and parameters here referring to the probability the initial
to the probability the initial probabilities of being upstaged a and
probabilities of being upstaged a and the transition probabilities may carry
the transition probabilities may carry transitioning from state a to state K so
transitioning from state a to state K so look at this again does this make sense
look at this again does this make sense is this the same as what we see up there
so how do you understand can't see the probability of x1 now this is written
probability of x1 now this is written like that so what does not mean the big
like that so what does not mean the big is the indicator function right so it's
is the indicator function right so it's Rondo and the argument is school zero
Rondo and the argument is school zero otherwise
otherwise so as this don't do here addiction is on
so as this don't do here addiction is on state one right then I have a space for
state one right then I have a space for a lot of times
a lot of times so if x1 is equal to let's say is the
so if x1 is equal to let's say is the state Z so this time what will give me
state Z so this time what will give me you will give me PJ and if x1 isn't a
you will give me PJ and if x1 isn't a means x1 is not in all the other states
means x1 is not in all the other states so if this process all the attempts will
so if this process all the attempts will give me basically a power of 0 which
give me basically a power of 0 which will result to 1 okay all right so this
will result to 1 okay all right so this is the way to write P of x1 and
sentences each with length T all right so this is the one would say in tax but
so this is the one would say in tax but has okay so this is a point remove a
has okay so this is a point remove a sequence this is a beautiful in the
sequence this is a beautiful in the states of J and K and this probability
states of J and K and this probability of transitions to say JK to this
of transitions to say JK to this indicator function transitioning from J
indicator function transitioning from J of T minus 1 to K and what interested to
of T minus 1 to K and what interested to compute a JK I mean most of the things
compute a JK I mean most of the things we have done up to now we assume that
we have done up to now we assume that this parameters are known now we don't
this parameters are known now we don't know these parameters and we're going to
know these parameters and we're going to compute them from data so interesting
compute them from data so interesting here will be
here will be this one will it's a sequence of words
this one will it's a sequence of words of lengthy but now I'm going to have any
of lengthy but now I'm going to have any sequence of words each of them having
sequence of words each of them having length all right so I'm going to
length all right so I'm going to basically text of different lengths so
basically text of different lengths so x1 we have a lengthy one words executed
x1 we have a lengthy one words executed 2 etc but if you not you can take that
2 etc but if you not you can take that the length of each of this is the same
the length of each of this is the same so the is given semester of the logs i
so the is given semester of the logs i given theta and i'm making it like that
given theta and i'm making it like that so i want you to look hard from this
so i want you to look hard from this equation the third line a went to the
equation the third line a went to the nothing to it questions this make sense
to describe estimation ferrymen which is all my data sets i push it in the works
all my data sets i push it in the works okay and I left the summation so maybe
okay and I left the summation so maybe people books this progress ever becomes
people books this progress ever becomes summation right so I first destination
summation right so I first destination over the states outside and this
over the states outside and this summation over the data sets they push
summation over the data sets they push it inside should I get on this term I
it inside should I get on this term I get this all right and in this term I'm
get this all right and in this term I'm going to push the summation over n an
going to push the summation over n an estimation over the length of verse
estimation over the length of verse sentences inside and then the
sentences inside and then the estimations over the states I will leave
estimations over the states I will leave them outside and the usually not missus
them outside and the usually not missus blaze what I mean is I'm colorblind so
blaze what I mean is I'm colorblind so it's not like I'm doing it because I
it's not like I'm doing it because I enjoy a lot right so what's the reason
enjoy a lot right so what's the reason we mark them for a reason here so what
we mark them for a reason here so what you see this mr. blue colors what are
you see this mr. blue colors what are they for this nation of the parameters
they for this nation of the parameters theta Mr mouse won't know whether we
theta Mr mouse won't know whether we gonna call this
this is where the information from the data comes so in estimating this part of
data comes so in estimating this part of the speed day and alpha JK the only
the speed day and alpha JK the only information we need this to know this
information we need this to know this quantity this can be so rapidly how do
quantity this can be so rapidly how do we call them
well in principle evidence dissolve this right this is the evidence of the day
right this is the evidence of the day cow so but the very top the bank as
cow so but the very top the bank as independent entities excise a right they
independent entities excise a right they come in making the parameters theta
come in making the parameters theta inside those big summations by anything
inside those big summations by anything we need to know the individual data we
we need to know the individual data we need to know these summations so this
need to know these summations so this summation is in blue or what mister
summation is in blue or what mister patient statistics so you will need this
patient statistics so you will need this to know this blue quantities so I am
to know this blue quantities so I am going to Congress than j1 and I'm gonna
going to Congress than j1 and I'm gonna call this and JK so which words can you
call this and JK so which words can you tell me what isn't anyone so looking at
tell me what isn't anyone so looking at this body that's you know miss baptize
this body that's you know miss baptize it something and j1 because there's a J
it something and j1 because there's a J there there's no I I'm summing Ally and
there there's no I I'm summing Ally and because this refers to state 1 Americas
because this refers to state 1 Americas and J 1 so what is this in words what
and J 1 so what is this in words what sends L 1 I mean obviously mister
sends L 1 I mean obviously mister indicator function some looking at all
indicator function some looking at all the data all right and I'm accounting in
the data all right and I'm accounting in my data set so I have n of laws and
my data set so I have n of laws and sultans this arm accounting how many
sultans this arm accounting how many times what
the first segment is on the web state we should take one and I'ma counting how
should take one and I'ma counting how many times the state one is or what one
many times the state one is or what one say some particular Makati how many
say some particular Makati how many times the first and the first world in
times the first and the first world in the end documents is that particular war
the end documents is that particular war okay this is again next refers to the
okay this is again next refers to the data thirds right this is the state one
data thirds right this is the state one of each of the sentences I remind you x1
of each of the sentences I remind you x1 is a sentence of length TI all right
is a sentence of length TI all right x10 is another long sentence of words of
x10 is another long sentence of words of length T I am okay to capitulate all
length T I am okay to capitulate all right what is the symbol now what is
right what is the symbol now what is this sufficient statistic so I'm coming
this sufficient statistic so I'm coming over other data over all the words in it
over other data over all the words in it data set in each of this X 1 to X
data set in each of this X 1 to X capital N and I'm accounting work in
capital N and I'm accounting work in those sentences some accounting in all
those sentences some accounting in all my data how many times a time T I was
my data how many times a time T I was from state J and the time T plus 1 I was
from state J and the time T plus 1 I was of state K all right so we have two
of state K all right so we have two versions right how many times the pay T
versions right how many times the pay T was the what J and how many times the
was the what J and how many times the stated most one simultaneously was on
stated most one simultaneously was on state K I can the log-likelihood as
state K I can the log-likelihood as these sufficient statistic times without
these sufficient statistic times without sufficient statistic and I do alright I
sufficient statistic and I do alright I don't have time to go through the
don't have time to go through the algebra but I want you to look sort of
algebra but I want you to look sort of visual
visual we do now to find the parameters by Jay
we do now to find the parameters by Jay and DJ Kay this is sort of a generic
and DJ Kay this is sort of a generic inference problem called discrete
inference problem called discrete distributions so you should have some
distributions so you should have some good idea on how to do this so how do
good idea on how to do this so how do you compute this power that speeds Aryan
you compute this power that speeds Aryan alpha DK I give you the results are
alpha DK I give you the results are coming in my model maximizing the
coming in my model maximizing the evidence cause we're gonna take
evidence cause we're gonna take derivatives with respect to Phi J and
derivatives with respect to Phi J and alpha J carry in taking the remnants of
alpha J carry in taking the remnants of this with respect to Phi J you also have
this with respect to Phi J you also have to enhance this with something else
to enhance this with something else because the PI J's are not independent
because the PI J's are not independent of each other if you take the sum over I
of each other if you take the sum over I mean at some state so the terrified
mean at some state so the terrified zatia's to be equal to one alright so
zatia's to be equal to one alright so that we need to do is we need to send
that we need to do is we need to send additional grants multiplier to enforce
additional grants multiplier to enforce the children gonna have to add here a
the children gonna have to add here a term 1/2 times the summation of the Phi
term 1/2 times the summation of the Phi J's for take will run to K - Ronnie
J's for take will run to K - Ronnie right
and we take also vary with respect to PI J including the term you will get this
J including the term you will get this and partial derivative with respect to a
and partial derivative with respect to a JK you will get that the business will
JK you will get that the business will collapse this are central to the obvious
collapse this are central to the obvious answer so you say I do not have to do
answer so you say I do not have to do any calculations because I know what the
any calculations because I know what the answer is going to be but obviously we
answer is going to be but obviously we need this methodology for more complex
need this methodology for more complex problems so with this project
problems so with this project what was the physical meaning offends
what was the physical meaning offends anyone again
there is how many times in my data sets the step one was upwards I divide it by
the step one was upwards I divide it by how many times I was on anything on
how many times I was on anything on state one let's take one red one okay
state one let's take one red one okay and counting how many times to hit
and counting how many times to hit transitions from state day to carry
transitions from state day to carry visitors you know how many times I have
visitors you know how many times I have transitioned from as a to whatever okay
transitioned from as a to whatever okay it is really significant transitions
it is really significant transitions from the people to whatever active comm
from the people to whatever active comm transitions from stage a is this the
transitions from stage a is this the normalization factor from j2 anything
normalization factor from j2 anything else so actually to make it sort of more
else so actually to make it sort of more nice and looking at you put the K prime
nice and looking at you put the K prime there and K Prime this result okay this
there and K Prime this result okay this models are computationally very
models are computationally very difficult to work with because we
difficult to work with because we introduced this probabilities that you
introduced this probabilities that you here for improve immediately basically
here for improve immediately basically like what we did with the inference from
like what we did with the inference from with the parameter estimation problem
with the parameter estimation problem how many parameters we have just to make
how many parameters we have just to make theory each of the states it's K
the message saying that we computed how many years if this is K and K T squared
many years if this is K and K T squared all right so if you have an engine
all right so if you have an engine community this will be K to the power n
community this will be K to the power n so this is computationally very
so this is computationally very expensive and the wrong data sets and I
expensive and the wrong data sets and I was moving actually the other day so one
was moving actually the other day so one of those later says but you can download
of those later says but you can download as 30,000 words and the number of profit
as 30,000 words and the number of profit is basically to calibrate the model and
is basically to calibrate the model and this term diagram model is 2.5 billion
this term diagram model is 2.5 billion parameters actually this is not trivial
parameters actually this is not trivial because you know the model is not
because you know the model is not computationally expensive so it's not we
computationally expensive so it's not we need to go away from maximizing the
need to go away from maximizing the likelihood of the data and maybe do
likelihood of the data and maybe do something Bayesian here so this can be
something Bayesian here so this can be give me the situation where the model
give me the situation where the model that we discussed will not work so you
that we discussed will not work so you have the Italian the data with a few
have the Italian the data with a few sentences that contain a few words and
sentences that contain a few words and and you know we computed transition
and you know we computed transition probabilities you know and obviously you
probabilities you know and obviously you can do predictions you know you can and
can do predictions you know you can and I will do it actually hopefully in a few
I will do it actually hopefully in a few minutes you can predict what the next
minutes you can predict what the next word is going to be but why do we need
word is going to be but why do we need to do Bayesian rather much more likely
to do Bayesian rather much more likely if it's there in the specific mode of
if it's there in the specific mode of the language model what can go wrong
the language model what can go wrong with family
so that we would say in the training sentences which is missing would you
sentences which is missing would you ever be able to predict that work no
ever be able to predict that work no okay so obviously there are lots of
okay so obviously there are lots of tricks you can go about this all right
tricks you can go about this all right and they go with different names but I'm
and they go with different names but I'm gonna show you briefly on how we can do
gonna show you briefly on how we can do a 20 million population but let me just
a 20 million population but let me just put all of these things up here in the
put all of these things up here in the estimation you in the when we estimated
estimation you in the when we estimated this parameter say we defined basically
this parameter say we defined basically the MLE estimate as being n JK / MJ in
the MLE estimate as being n JK / MJ in science basically the transitions from J
science basically the transitions from J to anything else and when you sum the
to anything else and when you sum the mjk whole case you get we do know this
mjk whole case you get we do know this as n sorry right so a way to fix
as n sorry right so a way to fix whatever problems you have with Emily is
whatever problems you have with Emily is irrelevant
irrelevant taking the Emily estimate for a JK use
taking the Emily estimate for a JK use some weighted average of what you
some weighted average of what you completely with Emily and also the K
completely with Emily and also the K where things NK divided by L so here
where things NK divided by L so here we're interested in the transitions from
we're interested in the transitions from Zeta K but this term does what it
Zeta K but this term does what it accounts for many times I see the word
accounts for many times I see the word cake it doesn't really care about
cake it doesn't really care about transitions
transitions okay so and this is you select Atlanta
okay so and this is you select Atlanta cross validation so this is not Bayesian
cross validation so this is not Bayesian we will see how possibly we can get
we will see how possibly we can get something like that with a basin
something like that with a basin formulation okay so this is called the
formulation okay so this is called the style version is called the belt
style version is called the belt smoothing okay where anyone taking the
smoothing okay where anyone taking the MLE estimate we take a weighted average
MLE estimate we take a weighted average of the Emily estimate or diagonally
of the Emily estimate or diagonally consists and also lambda times of cake
consists and also lambda times of cake where this is the unit of frequencies
where this is the unit of frequencies which is NK / yeah all right so let's
which is NK / yeah all right so let's take how we get the measure model for
take how we get the measure model for this let me put all of this thing up
this let me put all of this thing up actually this is very simple but assumes
actually this is very simple but assumes that you know something about different
that you know something about different distributions as prior so this is the
distributions as prior so this is the situation and this is the matrix a that
situation and this is the matrix a that is being stirred by all my observations
is being stirred by all my observations so that's why you see these links like
so that's why you see these links like that and each of this is the first in
that and each of this is the first in the a matrix so if you think this will
the a matrix so if you think this will give me the probabilities to transition
give me the probabilities to transition from one to state to state one from one
from one to state to state one from one to clear from one two three one two
to clear from one two three one two three etc so the sum of these things is
three etc so the sum of these things is equal to 1 okay
equal to 1 okay so then this will give you the
so then this will give you the transition from you know the one - okay
transition from you know the one - okay and so I'm going to take the pitch of
and so I'm going to take the pitch of this Rose amethyst and then I'm going to
this Rose amethyst and then I'm going to do is I am going to put a on each of
do is I am going to put a on each of these rows okay and this one is going to
these rows okay and this one is going to be the declare distribution that looks
be the declare distribution that looks the way that you see here the distance
the way that you see here the distance basically from silty clay have been
basically from silty clay have been written in an interesting way where I
written in an interesting way where I have the time you know it's not from the
have the time you know it's not from the details but basically a 0 comes
details but basically a 0 comes everywhere then I have M 0 2 and carry
everywhere then I have M 0 2 and carry so this is if you can take the mean of
so this is if you can take the mean of this declare distribution the mean comes
this declare distribution the mean comes to the N ok and the strength of which is
to the N ok and the strength of which is defined by this coefficient of 0 okay so
defined by this coefficient of 0 okay so so
let's see what this is going to do some of these min satisfies the stomach
of these min satisfies the stomach encase has to be cooked one alright so
encase has to be cooked one alright so this is the prior and I claim that the
this is the prior and I claim that the posterior for its you know I can say and
posterior for its you know I can say and I remind you it's a healthy purge a
I remind you it's a healthy purge a contains the transition probabilities
contains the transition probabilities from J to 1 to J 2 to 20 to 3 right all
from J to 1 to J 2 to 20 to 3 right all of the things education you know this
of the things education you know this chest do you remember what time he has
chest do you remember what time he has so he can look at the analytical
so he can look at the analytical expression which a for alpha J 1 so the
expression which a for alpha J 1 so the terminal for J 1 is going to be sum
terminal for J 1 is going to be sum alpha G want some power what's the power
you guys to the computer power of youth we have a distribution of does it look
we have a distribution of does it look like you can take for distribution some
like you can take for distribution some parameters theta 1 theta 2 etc you're
parameters theta 1 theta 2 etc you're going to have people line to what power
- this - swan and mythic a it would be if they came to this power minus 1 right
if they came to this power minus 1 right can you suppress with the likelihood
can you suppress with the likelihood that had the same form that we had
that had the same form that we had before that they were the parameters to
before that they were the parameters to some power you remember the likelihood I
some power you remember the likelihood I don't want to go back 20 slides all
don't want to go back 20 slides all right
you remember
so you can see now the right to declare distribution is the appropriate
distribution is the appropriate conjugate prior alright so you multiply
conjugate prior alright so you multiply stall here with I'd say to some power
stall here with I'd say to some power and here with a educate some power and
and here with a educate some power and lower case and object this will give you
lower case and object this will give you a very clear prior base okay so the
a very clear prior base okay so the event of the day the collab liquid is
event of the day the collab liquid is declared distribution if the priors in
declared distribution if the priors in the liquor distribution the posterior
the liquor distribution the posterior will come to be a digital distribution
will come to be a digital distribution and the posterior we have the same
and the posterior we have the same promise the prior with updated
promise the prior with updated parameters and this will be the form of
parameters and this will be the form of the the operator will be the
the the operator will be the distribution with parameters of a zero
distribution with parameters of a zero times M the comes from the prior NJ not
times M the comes from the prior NJ not the scalar and Jerry NJ is the vector of
the scalar and Jerry NJ is the vector of the time to transition from TJ to state
the time to transition from TJ to state one from state a to state two and NJ to
one from state a to state two and NJ to take care okay
take care okay so the posterior distribution looks it's
so the posterior distribution looks it's not going close from the way that this
not going close from the way that this is this basically to do a better
is this basically to do a better estimation and prediction for the
estimation and prediction for the language model that's one thing and
language model that's one thing and secondly how do you actually can go and
secondly how do you actually can go and ask you something about that for 0 name
ask you something about that for 0 name okay so how do you find this parameter
okay so how do you find this parameter seen in the prior but make sure
we reduce the prestige remain a JK so each of this is that the declared
each of this is that the declared distribution we're going to use the
distribution we're going to use the posterior min and the posterior mean
posterior min and the posterior mean basically for the this distribution if
basically for the this distribution if you take each of the partitions the K
you take each of the partitions the K partition it will be M say k plus alpha
partition it will be M say k plus alpha 0 MK / MJ suppose dinner and okay so
0 MK / MJ suppose dinner and okay so into the trade is the frequency of
into the trade is the frequency of transition from J to K times n J this is
transition from J to K times n J this is what we came with family estimation plus
what we came with family estimation plus 1 plus 0 times MK and J plus alpha 0 and
1 plus 0 times MK and J plus alpha 0 and I can write this expression like this
I can write this expression like this for lambda J is alpha 0 / MJ plus alpha
for lambda J is alpha 0 / MJ plus alpha 0 so basically this approximation that
0 so basically this approximation that people introduced before it comes out to
people introduced before it comes out to be actually the posterior min when it
be actually the posterior min when it uses very clear prior on the rolls of
uses very clear prior on the rolls of the transition matrix a JK okay so the
the transition matrix a JK okay so the first evening because the 0 the
first evening because the 0 the procedure mean really is the transition
procedure mean really is the transition probability from state a to state K ok
probability from state a to state K ok so this integration it is defined
so this integration it is defined exclusively in terms of the prior
exclusively in terms of the prior strength of for 0 and also the number of
strength of for 0 and also the number of time she worked on on stage a on the
time she worked on on stage a on the word shape
okay so the question is rep all pioneers going to be okay and that is not a
going to be okay and that is not a trivial problem so I'm going to if it's
trivial problem so I'm going to if it's something that I know it somehow might
something that I know it somehow might slide in the okay it comes to be the
slide in the okay it comes to be the same thing at the end of the day the
same thing at the end of the day the likelihood alright remember the steps we
likelihood alright remember the steps we assume that each hole is independent of
assume that each hole is independent of each other so the likelihood basically
each other so the likelihood basically is the product of all the rows of this
is the product of all the rows of this interesting relationship potential
interesting relationship potential should somebody transmit from where this
should somebody transmit from where this is coming I were very happy
so remember we multiply all right we multiply and then we got a posterior
multiply and then we got a posterior that he was also at the clear
that he was also at the clear distribution and this Bank was really an
distribution and this Bank was really an j plus alpha so did this formula come
declare distribution we multiply with the dirichlet prior and then we set the
the dirichlet prior and then we set the reason the posterior is a data flow
reason the posterior is a data flow distribution as well so this I can tell
distribution as well so this I can tell you it reminds me very much the
you it reminds me very much the normalizing factor of the delay
normalizing factor of the delay distribution she wanted to have 1 over
distribution she wanted to have 1 over the Aquacade this is really the
the Aquacade this is really the normalizing question of what
normalizing question of what distributional problem remember we have
distributional problem remember we have the likelihood we assimilate a prior
the likelihood we assimilate a prior than spirit-led so for this term in the
than spirit-led so for this term in the denominator came from
that's the normalizing factor with mr. Bishop
so it's the normalizing factor of the prior right and to normalize it you have
prior right and to normalize it you have to multiply and divide by this factor so
to multiply and divide by this factor so one of our best times whatever you have
one of our best times whatever you have as a problem will give you a declared
as a problem will give you a declared posterior and this would be the
posterior and this would be the normalization factor to the power so the
normalization factor to the power so the product over J a father and also the
product over J a father and also the transition matrix of this ratio will
transition matrix of this ratio will basically give you explicitly the
basically give you explicitly the marginal likelihood and what you can do
marginal likelihood and what you can do is if you are interested to actually now
is if you are interested to actually now go and compute this parameters for
go and compute this parameters for example you know what you can do is you
example you know what you can do is you can do an optimization problem and you
can do an optimization problem and you can find the actual calculations semi
can find the actual calculations semi analytically basically this paper by
analytically basically this paper by Mincha using this expression to compute
Mincha using this expression to compute these parameters to this expression the
these parameters to this expression the posterior comes our political transition
posterior comes our political transition matrix to be declared distribution so
matrix to be declared distribution so the transition from J to K has this mean
the transition from J to K has this mean value and this mean value is the
value and this mean value is the weighted average basically of the
weighted average basically of the diagram frequencies to collide and this
diagram frequencies to collide and this template that has to do with the prior
template that has to do with the prior now I remind you but if you do this
now I remind you but if you do this empirically people will take this
empirically people will take this coefficient MK to be how many times you
coefficient MK to be how many times you have the world carrying the data search
have the world carrying the data search alright so here's X ability because NK
alright so here's X ability because NK is defined in terms of the prior so the
is defined in terms of the prior so the question is what do you take as MK so
anything what it saved look at this equation here and it makes
look at this equation here and it makes an K is proportional today such that and
an K is proportional today such that and JK greater than zero can you tell me
JK greater than zero can you tell me what this change
what this change towards take us m'kay what noticing all
towards take us m'kay what noticing all the times you see the words a what how
the times you see the words a what how many times you transition to the web K
many times you transition to the web K for many other words a okay because in
for many other words a okay because in essence this is an entropy I have and
essence this is an entropy I have and how many times you say given war okay
how many times you say given war okay and there is an example in Memphis UNC
and there is an example in Memphis UNC okay and you know this that always comes
okay and you know this that always comes after you
after you so if you need to find the transition
so if you need to find the transition probabilities basically can give the
probabilities basically can give the same thing and see something you know
same thing and see something you know genius comes up to review all right and
genius comes up to review all right and you will notice the times that you see
you will notice the times that you see appear in this model it's about the
appear in this model it's about the thing okay eleven times is the same but
thing okay eleven times is the same but utilizations language you just you could
utilizations language you just you could let you etcetera you know see you
let you etcetera you know see you whatever but in this model into account
whatever but in this model into account that this transition probability is the
that this transition probability is the weighted average of these random
weighted average of these random frequencies and how many times you
frequencies and how many times you transition to the word k okay defined by
transition to the word k okay defined by this definition does this model performs
this definition does this model performs way better found the any other sort of
way better found the any other sort of known estimate for for m'kay if I
known estimate for for m'kay if I understand is the basically non
understand is the basically non parametric model and usually this non
parametric model and usually this non parametric models use practical
parametric models use practical techniques so you can think you know
techniques so you can think you know since you are interested in model the
since you are interested in model the transition from one world to another
transition from one world to another this you can think of this this time so
this you can think of this this time so you can use ideas from sequence to
you can use ideas from sequence to Montecarlo to do that
Montecarlo to do that into service no parametric methods but I
into service no parametric methods but I know by reducing I can go back here I
know by reducing I can go back here I have I'm using the declared distribution
have I'm using the declared distribution as a prior their prior you know what it
as a prior their prior you know what it is that they reflect process and I don't
is that they reflect process and I don't know kind of you will do a profit from
know kind of you will do a profit from this what's the difference not
this what's the difference not automatically but if I go from this
automatically but if I go from this distribution to the clip process what
distribution to the clip process what you know what did the process in general
you know what did the process in general will allow me to do that this particular
will allow me to do that this particular model would not allow me anybody knows
so in this case right I have transitions from J to state 0 to K right in
from J to state 0 to K right in different postures I'm gonna be able to
different postures I'm gonna be able to have transitions to handle states
Antony okay so that way worst of you have not seen with the accountant in the
have not seen with the accountant in the private market you know because you have
private market you know because you have transitions to everything okay but I've
transitions to everything okay but I've now told it will not allow you to do
now told it will not allow you to do this so the raclette process is you know
this so the raclette process is you know that's why we call it a non parametric
that's why we call it a non parametric model because effectively you have
model because effectively you have infinite parameters to define this model
infinite parameters to define this model so if you are interested the actually
so if you are interested the actually the world of tech from Oxford basically
the world of tech from Oxford basically is the one that has produced one of the
is the one that has produced one of the best language models basically using the
best language models basically using the repair process priors from doing that
I mentioned something else here with coefficients 1 1 1 1 the you know what
coefficients 1 1 1 1 the you know what is going to happen at the end of the day
is going to happen at the end of the day on this estimate because that everybody
on this estimate because that everybody does and the girls you know it is your
does and the girls you know it is your series empirically written in a lots of
series empirically written in a lots of machine learning books so the estimate
machine learning books so the estimate AJ Clary was m JK / MJ so if my data
AJ Clary was m JK / MJ so if my data layer has coefficients 1 1 1 1 ok all
layer has coefficients 1 1 1 1 ok all was what actually this thing is going to
was what actually this thing is going to come to be what is this what will happen
come to be what is this what will happen to the mean of digital prior with
to the mean of digital prior with Kristin's want
so it will come out that this quotation here would be 1 and this would be 1
here would be 1 and this would be 1 subjectively what you will be doing in
subjectively what you will be doing in computing the posterior mean you will be
computing the posterior mean you will be adding the quantity 1 all the empirical
adding the quantity 1 all the empirical cows
cows so if one word for example doesn't exist
so if one word for example doesn't exist a term in the training data set you will
a term in the training data set you will get 1 there so the transition from J to
get 1 there so the transition from J to that one will not be 0 you're not gonna
that one will not be 0 you're not gonna get anything worth it because the
get anything worth it because the organization that prior will usually
organization that prior will usually have a transition to an award
have a transition to an award okay and this graph would let me see
okay and this graph would let me see what the name is and plus 1 or something
what the name is and plus 1 or something this is very typical
somewhere I remember well is with me okay so this is the mouthing okay so
okay so this is the mouthing okay so here we have an evolution of the space
here we have an evolution of the space the way that you see here these are my
the way that you see here these are my exist this or the observations they have
exist this or the observations they have and you know the purpose of introducing
and you know the purpose of introducing sort of this length and representations
sort of this length and representations is because it allows us to take very
is because it allows us to take very complex dependencies between the
complex dependencies between the external okay so even though given let's
external okay so even though given let's say this this observation and
say this this observation and observation are independent of each
observation are independent of each other by integrator resist how okay
other by integrator resist how okay lexis depend on each other so this is a
lexis depend on each other so this is a much more complicated model than the
much more complicated model than the Markov model even though conditioned on
Markov model even though conditioned on Z you have conditioned you know this GI
Z you have conditioned you know this GI independence relations that simplify the
independence relations that simplify the problem okay so let me just write the
problem okay so let me just write the probability distribution is going to
probability distribution is going to look like the joint of action three okay
look like the joint of action three okay is again the probability of being in
is again the probability of being in state C 1 we have the transition
state C 1 we have the transition probability exactly as in the markov
probability exactly as in the markov model and then we have the observation
model and then we have the observation probabilities so at this time the
probabilities so at this time the probability of X and given Zn sorry hmm
probability of X and given Zn sorry hmm model
model we will take the state Z to be discreet
we will take the state Z to be discreet but the observation sex can be anything
but the observation sex can be anything you want to so it can be - them can be
you want to so it can be - them can be multi no me can be any sort of
multi no me can be any sort of distribution if you make this have this
distribution if you make this have this position to be Gaussian and this to be a
position to be Gaussian and this to be a Gaussian then you get in here
Gaussian then you get in here Gaussian models basically that we will
Gaussian models basically that we will see later on and from there if you can
see later on and from there if you can get a year similar to Kalman filtering
get a year similar to Kalman filtering but right now we're going to take that
but right now we're going to take that this is a discrete distribution this can
this is a discrete distribution this can be we leave it on the earth so it can be
be we leave it on the earth so it can be anything we want we want to alright
so extremely similar to a Gaussian mixture model okay
mixture model okay the only difference so imagine that we
the only difference so imagine that we have this liquid distance right of the
have this liquid distance right of the mixture quotations that tells you when
mixture quotations that tells you when you know so let's say the parameter of
you know so let's say the parameter of XT given the state is a Gaussian all
XT given the state is a Gaussian all right and maybe in our mixture model we
right and maybe in our mixture model we have three different gaussian right so k
have three different gaussian right so k equal 1 2 or 3
equal 1 2 or 3 so if your sister is a data set that
so if your sister is a data set that comes from three different gaussian okay
comes from three different gaussian okay but incident models is a little more
but incident models is a little more complicated because z1 and z2 will again
complicated because z1 and z2 will again point to the childs Gaussian but won't
point to the childs Gaussian but won't survive with three you know what the
survive with three you know what the state trip is gonna be on this ride the
state trip is gonna be on this ride the Gaussian so you start taking samples
Gaussian so you start taking samples from this until all so why have you find
from this until all so why have you find yourself on this Gaussian so what's the
yourself on this Gaussian so what's the difference of this from a Gaussian
difference of this from a Gaussian mixture the difference is very simple
mixture the difference is very simple that the state are basically now a
that the state are basically now a Markov chain if you sample next depends
Markov chain if you sample next depends what state they were before all right so
what state they were before all right so in many ways this is very similar to a
in many ways this is very similar to a diversion mixed model behind
diversion mixed model behind without this all right I connected
without this all right I connected through the Markovian property basically
through the Markovian property basically you know the transition of the
you know the transition of the permeability of GI from given CI - Juan
permeability of GI from given CI - Juan what you see here is in constraints on
what you see here is in constraints on how we go from you know from one state
how we go from you know from one state to another
to another can you tell me if I want to generate
can you tell me if I want to generate this data given historical time for this
this data given historical time for this distribution can somebody give me an
distribution can somebody give me an idea if I want to to stop generating
idea if I want to to stop generating this picture here and it's this
this picture here and it's this observation modest is a direction with
observation modest is a direction with its own mean and variance how are you
its own mean and variance how are you going to generate the picture looking at
going to generate the picture looking at this distribution
this distribution what's restless I'm going to look like
what's restless I'm going to look like to generate data the way that you seen
to generate data the way that you seen the showing the picture so how are you
the showing the picture so how are you going to generate the observations that
going to generate the observations that we saw there from gaussians you can see
we saw there from gaussians you can see here so what do we do what's the first
here so what do we do what's the first step
from this distribution of g1 the initial State
State alright I got it what's next alright the
alright I got it what's next alright the next thing is can we sample actual right
next thing is can we sample actual right the answer is yes we can sell furniture
the answer is yes we can sell furniture on the given is d---rom from this
on the given is d---rom from this probability okay what's next
probability okay what's next we have a sample of zero and now also
we have a sample of zero and now also given the sample whatever we gonna do
given the sample whatever we gonna do samples it to now giving us the three we
samples it to now giving us the three we can sample it do etc so mister you get
can sample it do etc so mister you get this picture that you see on the left
this picture that you see on the left okay so it is a very exactly like a
okay so it is a very exactly like a Gaussian mixture the only difference is
Gaussian mixture the only difference is in a Gaussian mixture you don't have
in a Gaussian mixture you don't have this transition probability which we
this transition probability which we have here okay because we're running out
have here okay because we're running out of time if I can't pee
nope I don't see it I'm gonna have to I have to use your imagination now because
have to use your imagination now because who knows what try this now okay
it was made that I can write the initial probability of C 1 because eventually
probability of C 1 because eventually we're going to be interesting to do
we're going to be interesting to do influence of the parameters in this
influence of the parameters in this distribution I can write it like that
distribution I can write it like that so you can do something exactly what
so you can do something exactly what this equation gives me on the bottom so
this equation gives me on the bottom so I'm assuming here that the states D 1 is
I'm assuming here that the states D 1 is discrete fixed K stage so that is PI K
is the probability that that would say one I am on what state okay and where is
one I am on what state okay and where is this coming because this discrete
this coming because this discrete variable Z the aleni
so I'm gonna get okay cheer win when Z K is equal to R I mean I say the first
is equal to R I mean I say the first risk video I should not have it here but
risk video I should not have it here but oh hey the first verse 32 no actually
oh hey the first verse 32 no actually you know what
you know what this should not be an i what should this
this should not be an i what should this be right so when the state you know I'm
be right so when the state you know I'm one dataset here right when 0 C is from
one dataset here right when 0 C is from state that's a notation like this what's
state that's a notation like this what's new 1 K is equal to 1 okay so when z1 k
new 1 K is equal to 1 okay so when z1 k equal to 1 this will give me DK and all
equal to 1 this will give me DK and all the other terms we have an exponent 0 so
the other terms we have an exponent 0 so would be equal to 1 so I get basically
would be equal to 1 so I get basically the distance equal to PI K all right
the distance equal to PI K all right does this make sense
alright this exactly basically what we had for the Markov chain right so
had for the Markov chain right so there's nothing different this is the
there's nothing different this is the transition from J to K and J in k k
transition from J to K and J in k k dimensional right they can take K States
dimensional right they can take K States and on the experiences to make this
and on the experiences to make this explicit if I have GN minus 1 J this is
explicit if I have GN minus 1 J this is equal to 1 when the N minus 1 state is
equal to 1 when the N minus 1 state is on J status and this one a time step
on J status and this one a time step then I'm alakay alright so if this is
then I'm alakay alright so if this is the case the exponents equal to 1 and
the case the exponents equal to 1 and this give me a JK the rest gives me is
this give me a JK the rest gives me is doing exponent so I get a contribution
doing exponent so I get a contribution of 1 so nothing changes
of 1 so nothing changes ok so here's what we're interested we're
ok so here's what we're interested we're interested to protonate for the hidden
interested to protonate for the hidden market one of the dispositions and also
market one of the dispositions and also the history probabilities pi K potential
the history probabilities pi K potential and if you're introducing observation
and if you're introducing observation love them and this observation model we
love them and this observation model we have the chain parameters and we need to
have the chain parameters and we need to compute this as well ok and you know we
compute this as well ok and you know we can consider several different choices
can consider several different choices it's lethal for the slides but you can
it's lethal for the slides but you can imagine if you are on state K let's say
imagine if you are on state K let's say then if this coefficients can be PKA and
then if this coefficients can be PKA and this will be the chosen correspondent
this will be the chosen correspondent about k-state
about k-state sharing some mineral child by carrying
sharing some mineral child by carrying that's carrying some variants also fits
that's carrying some variants also fits all and we're going to have to compute
all and we're going to have to compute all the means and the variances of the
all the means and the variances of the observation model for each of the k
observation model for each of the k space but michigan if this is the
space but michigan if this is the discrete model can be a multi newly
discrete model can be a multi newly distribution so we have to calculate the
distribution so we have to calculate the probabilities of the different states as
probabilities of the different states as well I'm supervising this in general
well I'm supervising this in general like that ok so so tell me what do we
like that ok so so tell me what do we have here
have here so I'm looking at the emission
so I'm looking at the emission probabilities this we observe a chinois
probabilities this we observe a chinois deluxe step 10 all right and it
deluxe step 10 all right and it next scent comes from this model this
next scent comes from this model this probability papyrus ink is DNA and DNA
probability papyrus ink is DNA and DNA equal to now happens when a step and
equal to now happens when a step and almost if I would say I mean on state K
almost if I would say I mean on state K so if I'm on spent cave is equal to one
so if I'm on spent cave is equal to one so the parameters basically that define
so the parameters basically that define the observation models of the parameters
the observation models of the parameters PK and this is what we need to observe
PK and this is what we need to observe what we need to complete basically what
what we need to complete basically what we do Emily you're measuring current
[Applause]
distribution at both the observed variables and I call all of this
variables and I call all of this variable sex so from next one to X
variable sex so from next one to X capital T and G 1 2 G capital in your
capital T and G 1 2 G capital in your subscript a is the initial probability
subscript a is the initial probability of this transitions of the state and the
of this transitions of the state and the observation model 3d panel it is
observation model 3d panel it is difficult as you can see from what we
difficult as you can see from what we have seen on a Markov model here where
have seen on a Markov model here where is this a difficult problem
you can open the left hand side what is different from what we had in the market
different from what we had in the market Walden
you remember in a Markov chain we had the likelihood of the observation sex
the likelihood of the observation sex but now here I have the joint likelihood
but now here I have the joint likelihood of X and Z given the parameters and what
of X and Z given the parameters and what is different here
is different here Benghazi we don't know this tears on
Benghazi we don't know this tears on itself so basically this joint look like
itself so basically this joint look like it would it looks nice
it would it looks nice it looks exactly like an operating model
it looks exactly like an operating model but unfortunately the states they have
but unfortunately the states they have not known so we cannot go and do an
not known so we cannot go and do an Emily on this you will not work right
because it looks very this is very easy to look at and manipulate but we don't
to look at and manipulate but we don't know what saves so let's go to slide
know what saves so let's go to slide undred 70 and see on how we can compute
undred 70 and see on how we can compute all these unknown parameters hmm
all these unknown parameters hmm so that we covered in last spring and
so that we covered in last spring and I'm going to review it basically in the
I'm going to review it basically in the context of the hmm
context of the hmm is optimized maximized not the hood the
is optimized maximized not the hood the joint of likelihood of the observations
joint of likelihood of the observations of the hidden body most but the
of the hidden body most but the expectation of the joint of likelihood
expectation of the joint of likelihood with respect to the posterior
with respect to the posterior distribution of Z given live the waist
distribution of Z given live the waist of self and of course the posterior
of self and of course the posterior distribution of derivatives erections is
distribution of derivatives erections is not now because we don't know the
not now because we don't know the parameters so what we're gonna do is
parameters so what we're gonna do is we're gonna try to Eternity we update
we're gonna try to Eternity we update the parameters as follows we're going to
the parameters as follows we're going to take some previous iteration takes
take some previous iteration takes department some values and then try to
department some values and then try to compute this for strain of
compute this for strain of the necks with a barometer speaks then
the necks with a barometer speaks then compute the expectation of the join of
compute the expectation of the join of livelihood and not as this parameters
livelihood and not as this parameters here are parameters that are known and
here are parameters that are known and I'm going to update so first I'm going
I'm going to update so first I'm going to compute this expectation using this
to compute this expectation using this posterior that is approximated using
posterior that is approximated using some the previous iteration of the
some the previous iteration of the parameters and then once I compute this
parameters and then once I compute this I am going to maximize this with respect
I am going to maximize this with respect to parameters theta okay supposedly I am
to parameters theta okay supposedly I am going to abuse the complexity that has
going to abuse the complexity that has to do with the fact that I don't know Z
to do with the fact that I don't know Z by reducing the joining applied the
by reducing the joining applied the affections G but somehow transforming
affections G but somehow transforming the optimization and iterative
the optimization and iterative optimization problem who have worked
optimization problem who have worked with the expectation of the Journal of
with the expectation of the Journal of likelihood expectation with respect to
likelihood expectation with respect to this posterior and somehow it ray all
this posterior and somehow it ray all the parameters theta and at the same
the parameters theta and at the same time updating this posterior of Z makes
time updating this posterior of Z makes a little sense
a little sense so this is sort of the final
so this is sort of the final expectation-maximization algorithm to
expectation-maximization algorithm to ensure the problems we have parameters
ensure the problems we have parameters and you have some hidden variables right
but somehow I'm working directly with the journal of livelihood is a much
the journal of livelihood is a much easier proposition than working with the
easier proposition than working with the likelihood effects I mean you can
likelihood effects I mean you can imagine here if you put destinations
imagine here if you put destinations they dialect on this distribution this
they dialect on this distribution this is computationally intractable you
is computationally intractable you cannot do anything about okay you know
cannot do anything about okay you know in this field you come up with Paniagua
in this field you come up with Paniagua later but this is especially when you
later but this is especially when you take the long this is a very easy
take the long this is a very easy distribution taking the average with
distribution taking the average with respect to this posterior is going to be
respect to this posterior is going to be easy and the key thing here is compute
easy and the key thing here is compute this posterior in tentatively using an
this posterior in tentatively using an onset of the variables of these
onset of the variables of these parameters and then when you do this
parameters and then when you do this computation of this quantity Q of demise
computation of this quantity Q of demise with respect to theta then come back and
with respect to theta then come back and they dressed very compute vest take
they dressed very compute vest take another optimization with respect to
another optimization with respect to theta so this lips want us to compute
theta so this lips want us to compute this expectation that base that second
this expectation that base that second much much respect to theta and hopefully
much much respect to theta and hopefully you will achieve some convergence in a
you will achieve some convergence in a few duration we discuss you know for
few duration we discuss you know for change them and we did this with a
change them and we did this with a junction tree etc okay it comes out when
junction tree etc okay it comes out when you calculate this expectation of the
you calculate this expectation of the joint of likelihood you're gonna need
joint of likelihood you're gonna need some sufficient statistics and those
some sufficient statistics and those sufficient statistics basically will
sufficient statistics basically will abilities that we have computed from the
abilities that we have computed from the forward and backward passing masters
forward and backward passing masters algorithms so the sufficient statistics
algorithms so the sufficient statistics that we will need is this probability
that we will need is this probability okay and so it is all of the day time
okay and so it is all of the day time the train from actual text copy text
the train from actual text copy text with subscript capital T so this is the
with subscript capital T so this is the smoothing distribution that gives me the
smoothing distribution that gives me the trait if they given all my exist with a
trait if they given all my exist with a parameter space alright and I remind
parameter space alright and I remind field of symbol we use for ballistic
field of symbol we use for ballistic this is the block was running on a suit
this is the block was running on a suit not the beta masters right this is this
not the beta masters right this is this moving distribution of ZT given all the
moving distribution of ZT given all the data and the other sufficient statistics
data and the other sufficient statistics we will need is the joint probably
we will need is the joint probably distribution of of ZT minus prong n CP
distribution of of ZT minus prong n CP given to the data so this is the joints
given to the data so this is the joints moving distribution that gives me Z at t
moving distribution that gives me Z at t minus 1 jointly with GP so if you
minus 1 jointly with GP so if you support that to compute this path and do
support that to compute this path and do this ex-professional calculation you
this ex-professional calculation you will need to compute these two
will need to compute these two probabilities and that requires a
probabilities and that requires a calculation of messages and this
calculation of messages and this basically requires
basically requires with message calculation okay so
with message calculation okay so remember so yes with one of his messages
remember so yes with one of his messages are coming if you want to find the
are coming if you want to find the parameters in your model you have not
parameters in your model you have not choice in the yellow algorithm but the
choice in the yellow algorithm but the calculator is forward and backward
calculator is forward and backward passing messages and when a certain
passing messages and when a certain point of these things are coming but
point of these things are coming but rightousness
rightousness this is the big picture so let me just
this is the big picture so let me just put a plot here the Subic make visible
put a plot here the Subic make visible basically you start with some values of
basically you start with some values of the parameters you know there's lots of
the parameters you know there's lots of guidance we want to use to start with if
guidance we want to use to start with if you compute this posterior ok of
you compute this posterior ok of overstates given all the data in the
overstates given all the data in the previous parameters you calculate this
previous parameters you calculate this quantity Q which is the sexpectations
quantity Q which is the sexpectations force here of the joint log likelihood
force here of the joint log likelihood but you notice here in the log
but you notice here in the log likelihood you have no power
likelihood you have no power all right so whatever he did when I get
all right so whatever he did when I get is going to be a function of theta then
is going to be a function of theta then on the m-step you maximize with respect
on the m-step you maximize with respect to theta
to theta if you convert if you are done if not
if you convert if you are done if not you come back you update the parameters
you come back you update the parameters you compute a new posterior and you eat
you compute a new posterior and you eat a new expectation of the joint of
a new expectation of the joint of likelihood you maximize that you can do
likelihood you maximize that you can do anything you want okay I want you to
anything you want okay I want you to look at this expression and so you guys
look at this expression and so you guys can see it again alright so this is the
can see it again alright so this is the backward message is this moving
backward message is this moving posterior of c30
posterior of c30 all right and you remember city
so for example if the kids are equal to 1 you know what this is equal to is the
1 you know what this is equal to is the probability those little TJ would make
probability those little TJ would make onto our but is also the expectation of
onto our but is also the expectation of the Zeta TJ why because if a TJ can only
the Zeta TJ why because if a TJ can only take one is zero or one
let me explain this again right so this is a vector Z T right but this can take
is a vector Z T right but this can take values the CP you know why do whatever
values the CP you know why do whatever states I have I have at this time I have
states I have I have at this time I have K different states right so I can write
K different states right so I can write this in a more easier part and a steak
this in a more easier part and a steak well now obviously PJ which is the
well now obviously PJ which is the probability basically of ztj being equal
probability basically of ztj being equal to one in a claim that that is actually
to one in a claim that that is actually the expectation of z TJ because he
the expectation of z TJ because he visited J can take varnish only one and
visited J can take varnish only one and zero the profession is the same as the
zero the profession is the same as the probability West so effectively what I
probability West so effectively what I claim is that the expectation of this
claim is that the expectation of this alright is the same community simply
alright is the same community simply because he fatigues English that the
because he fatigues English that the clay has the varnish one of zero okay so
clay has the varnish one of zero okay so just and the tree which is the joints
just and the tree which is the joints moving distribution of ZT minus 1 and GT
moving distribution of ZT minus 1 and GT they are really nothing else the
they are really nothing else the posterior expectations of the z TJ
posterior expectations of the z TJ variable remember that my definition of
variable remember that my definition of gamma J right what was it the first
gamma J right what was it the first period distribution is the posterior of
period distribution is the posterior of Z that they given all my data
mr. mission social expectation of Mitchell Pacific a values because forget
Mitchell Pacific a values because forget about it so this is also the expectation
about it so this is also the expectation so can you look at this equation here
so can you look at this equation here now and tell me how from this equation
now and tell me how from this equation when I take logs and then expectation I
when I take logs and then expectation I get this equation from what did that
get this equation from what did that come from I think the assumption is and
come from I think the assumption is and this nice equation with the transition
this nice equation with the transition probabilities to a boundary right and
probabilities to a boundary right and you know we can do this the same thing
you know we can do this the same thing there but how how did I get a grammar
there but how how did I get a grammar there let's go to think of this now they
there let's go to think of this now they are giving Rama what is 0k
this is also that is the posterior expectation of the z1k so how did they
expectation of the z1k so how did they welcome this time to a gamma x level PK
remember this terminal used to be the drama still anticipate that their
the drama still anticipate that their indicator function that 0 and K is equal
indicator function that 0 and K is equal to L can give you expectation and what
to L can give you expectation and what is that the expectation is gamma Z 1 K
is that the expectation is gamma Z 1 K so similarly this in the transition from
so similarly this in the transition from t minus 1 to 3 you will get basically
t minus 1 to 3 you will get basically this quantity K which is this motoring
this quantity K which is this motoring joining posterior of z t minus 1 and t
joining posterior of z t minus 1 and t so what is this actually
so what is this actually this is expectation of what distribution
this is expectation of what distribution and in the Hollywood
this is the joint distribution of city - rondell states a and city being a speck
rondell states a and city being a speck a the proceeded expectation of that is
a the proceeded expectation of that is Vista the quantity T okay so the pension
Vista the quantity T okay so the pension is right but this van that we completed
is right but this van that we completed an exchange that we defined them as
an exchange that we defined them as posterior distributions all right this
posterior distributions all right this is how we define them okay this vectors
is how we define them okay this vectors because if he can take value 1
because if he can take value 1 you know I have different K State okay
you know I have different K State okay so when I simplify this and I'm asking
so when I simplify this and I'm asking what is grandma's GP k yes that is the
what is grandma's GP k yes that is the posterior of ZT k being equal to on but
posterior of ZT k being equal to on but is also the personal expectation of z TK
is also the personal expectation of z TK similarly when I put this Z to minus 1 3
similarly when I put this Z to minus 1 3 and c TK yes that is the probability for
and c TK yes that is the probability for stated probability of city - Ron being
stated probability of city - Ron being of say J and this being of state K but
of say J and this being of state K but is also the personal expectation of was
is also the personal expectation of was devoured and so when you take this joint
devoured and so when you take this joint of livelihood right you take the joint
of livelihood right you take the joint of likelihood you will get this
of likelihood you will get this indicator functions from the front when
indicator functions from the front when you write this any JK and on the top
you write this any JK and on the top level get the indicator function that
level get the indicator function that city - Sean J equal to 1 and Z 2 k equal
city - Sean J equal to 1 and Z 2 k equal to 1 then when you take this will come
to 1 then when you take this will come in you know expectation of that wine
in you know expectation of that wine expectations because we say that we do
expectations because we say that we do not operate with the joint of likelihood
not operate with the joint of likelihood we have to take expectations
okay we have to take expectation with respect to the posterior of Z and those
respect to the posterior of Z and those expectations give you basically the
expectations give you basically the sufficient statistics and the sufficient
sufficient statistics and the sufficient statistics come to be nothing else but
statistics come to be nothing else but this before message this gamma and this
this before message this gamma and this so this is moving distribution basically
so this is moving distribution basically and the joint posterior of ZT minus 1
and the joint posterior of ZT minus 1 and ZT and I have female think here for
and ZT and I have female think here for the observation mobile so there's
the observation mobile so there's missing energy on the first time I'm
missing energy on the first time I'm going to have k-state
going to have k-state so I'm get the summation here I'm gonna
so I'm get the summation here I'm gonna have this properly
have this properly alright this is this product and I have
alright this is this product and I have transitioned from gay personal space to
transitioned from gay personal space to carry possible states
carry possible states so here the double summation and this is
so here the double summation and this is the sufficient statistics do you get
the sufficient statistics do you get longer days okay and here if you get
longer days okay and here if you get again the scan local Christians and this
again the scan local Christians and this is the log of the observation model
is the log of the observation model considering the Vermont state flag
considering the Vermont state flag so the parameters corresponding to
so the parameters corresponding to observation model would be clear big
observation model would be clear big subscript K so I don't know if anybody
subscript K so I don't know if anybody remembers but what is the meaning we
remembers but what is the meaning we have given what is given in the
have given what is given in the literature to this posterior
literature to this posterior probabilities of z chain and we do not
probabilities of z chain and we do not write the expectation of the there was
write the expectation of the there was no z change instead of having kilogram
no z change instead of having kilogram of z1 k what did we have on the Markov
of z1 k what did we have on the Markov chain remember
remember sufficient statistics on a Markov chain just which is the time the
Markov chain just which is the time the number of times that the first let's say
number of times that the first let's say of the you know final on home state K so
of the you know final on home state K so again that was telling me how many times
here because this is a procedure quantity so this is observes the data
quantity so this is observes the data right is what is the expectation of the
right is what is the expectation of the times that I will be on on my time step
times that I will be on on my time step one on state K this is what we call the
one on state K this is what we call the what's the matter that we used what is
what's the matter that we used what is used in the literature that we use
used in the literature that we use especially for a you remember on how you
especially for a you remember on how you do the am aware if conversion mixtures
I'm looking you know whip type of things you get frequency okay I know it's a
you get frequency okay I know it's a little hard responsibility right and I'm
little hard responsibility right and I'm looking at state one in a procedure
looking at state one in a procedure setting how many times my state one is I
setting how many times my state one is I mean you know the parameter and then I'm
mean you know the parameter and then I'm gonna destroy implying the spy this
gonna destroy implying the spy this payee and this coefficients be in the
payee and this coefficients be in the observation model we wanted to work with
observation model we wanted to work with a joint likelihood because computation
a joint likelihood because computation is very easy to write this a discrete
is very easy to write this a discrete model this would say suggestions very
model this would say suggestions very nice okay what years so how can we
nice okay what years so how can we compute by what we don't know so there
compute by what we don't know so there this yes the expectation with respect to
this yes the expectation with respect to the posterior of Z right and then they
the posterior of Z right and then they stiffen the complexity but how can I do
stiffen the complexity but how can I do this well that posterior depends on the
this well that posterior depends on the parameters PI an a and C so the second
parameters PI an a and C so the second step is well start iterating on
step is well start iterating on disparities so something didn't compute
disparities so something didn't compute the expectation of this with respect to
the expectation of this with respect to the posterior given the parameters all
the posterior given the parameters all right this is what you see here then
right this is what you see here then when we have this quantity
when we have this quantity into this quantity now we didn't take
into this quantity now we didn't take derivatives with respect to Phi K alpha
derivatives with respect to Phi K alpha JK and with respect to pre-k right and
JK and with respect to pre-k right and we keep doing iteration this is actually
we keep doing iteration this is actually a first step it looks identical to what
a first step it looks identical to what we had for Markov chains there is really
we had for Markov chains there is really nothing that is different okay
nothing that is different okay so you can go in to use Lagrange
so you can go in to use Lagrange multipliers to infer that the sum of
multipliers to infer that the sum of five K's is equal to one and then take
five K's is equal to one and then take derivatives with this and I can tell you
derivatives with this and I can tell you this research on these maximization step
this research on these maximization step the suit is identical to what we did for
the suit is identical to what we did for a Markov chain but the the medium of the
a Markov chain but the the medium of the singles is very different coming to be
okay
/ this pristine responsibilities of the time Varnum in any state vary from one
time Varnum in any state vary from one to K and similarly energy H is defined
to K and similarly energy H is defined by the posterior transition
by the posterior transition probabilities that so this patient a JK
probabilities that so this patient a JK so but at time t minus one among set
so but at time t minus one among set among state J and then I transitional
among state J and then I transitional time T to state k so this is exactly
time T to state k so this is exactly what we had before the only difference
what we had before the only difference is that this gene gamma our posterior
is that this gene gamma our posterior probabilities and there's nothing
probabilities and there's nothing probabilities because here to calculate
probabilities because here to calculate gamma and your current flow the data
gamma and your current flow the data from time let's say 1 or 0 all the way
from time let's say 1 or 0 all the way to capital T okay
to capital T okay so this one's smoking probabilities not
so this one's smoking probabilities not predictive probability stress not
predictive probability stress not something you know you can stay up here
something you know you can stay up here and estimate what this is okay series
and estimate what this is okay series alright and then you say now can you
alright and then you say now can you tell me what the expectation when the
tell me what the expectation when the probability of z1 K being equal to 1 and
probability of z1 K being equal to 1 and is given by this entity so that will
is given by this entity so that will give you PI K etcetera etcetera
give you PI K etcetera etcetera and insanity enclosures because he's run
and insanity enclosures because he's run for the calendars and how do you
for the calendars and how do you calculate
so this is a possibility because I am counting all of the data right in my
counting all of the data right in my stickers and I'm waiting them with these
stickers and I'm waiting them with these probabilities which are the posterior
probabilities which are the posterior probabilities and similarly for the
probabilities and similarly for the variance basically it is like you know
variance basically it is like you know you're estimating a Gaussian alright you
you're estimating a Gaussian alright you are using all the data okay
are using all the data okay this is with respect to this mean by the
this is with respect to this mean by the way all right
way all right this is very important and again your
this is very important and again your wafers with respect to the
wafers with respect to the responsibilities that the data time T
responsibilities that the data time T belongs to theta you can extend this to
belongs to theta you can extend this to actually to the distribution so if you
actually to the distribution so if you have a multinomial or Bernoulli
have a multinomial or Bernoulli distribution many other things work you
distribution many other things work you can work the algebra by the way is I'm
can work the algebra by the way is I'm going to go back and bring it to the
going to go back and bring it to the need basically so completing the smoking
need basically so completing the smoking distributions so you people think is
distributions so you people think is working distributions
working distributions sort of
sort of then you know who wants to use all the
then you know who wants to use all the data we are interested in online
data we are interested in online estimation right but you can see when if
estimation right but you can see when if you do the expectation-maximization
you do the expectation-maximization algorithm you really need to have this
algorithm you really need to have this posterior responsibilities and disjoint
posterior responsibilities and disjoint expectations and those required that you
expectations and those required that you use all the data so there's nothing
use all the data so there's nothing distributions so we'll discuss on how
distributions so we'll discuss on how with message-passing we can compute them
with message-passing we can compute them I'm going to practice like the best when
I'm going to practice like the best when I look at them to acquire the things
I look at them to acquire the things looking they're very complicated but I
looking they're very complicated but I think in many ways the hmm model is the
think in many ways the hmm model is the simplest okay so you should invest some
simplest okay so you should invest some time to understand