all right this 1232 so let's part I am sure the rain is a
so let's part I am sure the rain is a factor on some not coming on time so
factor on some not coming on time so behind these lectures I thought that
behind these lectures I thought that hidden Markov models will work them in
hidden Markov models will work them in the past but based on at least questions
the past but based on at least questions I have from two of you I don't know why
I have from two of you I don't know why some kind of having picked up lots of
some kind of having picked up lots of the ideas because we already cover the
the ideas because we already cover the loss of the algorithms with hmm but
loss of the algorithms with hmm but maybe you only pick up ideas after the
maybe you only pick up ideas after the homework shall I assume you know you
homework shall I assume you know you have to work on the homework and then
have to work on the homework and then things are clear so anyways so I have to
things are clear so anyways so I have to spend maybe 10 mins to repeat some of
spend maybe 10 mins to repeat some of the things we discussed on the previous
the things we discussed on the previous lecture even though they were not very
lecture even though they were not very essential I mean not very difficulties
essential I mean not very difficulties so let me go back to 166 hopefully you
so let me go back to 166 hopefully you all got the slide so Vicki made
all got the slide so Vicki made everybody so when we discuss on
everybody so when we discuss on estimating the parameters of a hidden
estimating the parameters of a hidden Markov model from observations on the
Markov model from observations on the variables X so effectively we have to
variables X so effectively we have to compete with other parameter star on
compete with other parameter star on this initial distribution P of Z one of
this initial distribution P of Z one of these transition matrix in this
these transition matrix in this probability city given ZT minus 1 and
probability city given ZT minus 1 and whatever unknowns we have on the
whatever unknowns we have on the observation what oh I'm sorry on the
observation what oh I'm sorry on the yeah on the on the you know on the
yeah on the on the you know on the measurement distribution the the things
measurement distribution the the things that I basically covered on the last
that I basically covered on the last lecture are really independent of what
lecture are really independent of what type of distribution we assume for the
type of distribution we assume for the probability of XT given the hidden state
probability of XT given the hidden state so you can have a Gaussian and a multi
so you can have a Gaussian and a multi newly distribution you can they have
newly distribution you can they have whatever this sort of is generic and
whatever this sort of is generic and then you have to do something special
then you have to do something special about
about raising the parameters of the last term
raising the parameters of the last term okay simple statement serious you cannot
okay simple statement serious you cannot really go and integrate Z out because
really go and integrate Z out because that will require a massive calculation
that will require a massive calculation so what you need to do is you need to be
so what you need to do is you need to be able to estimate the parameters with the
able to estimate the parameters with the maximum likelihood sort of an estimate
maximum likelihood sort of an estimate you need to work with their expectation
you need to work with their expectation maximization algorithm and I you know I
maximization algorithm and I you know I provided the specifics for the case of
provided the specifics for the case of hmm but really fist the same home where
hmm but really fist the same home where in in many other areas of machine
in in many other areas of machine learning so next repeat with the Albert
learning so next repeat with the Albert looks like extra mass transfer next one
looks like extra mass transfer next one let's say to X capital T Z are they
let's say to X capital T Z are they affiliated latent variables we don't
affiliated latent variables we don't know what they are people of the
know what they are people of the parameters all right so whether it is
parameters all right so whether it is weak form this is the joint likelihood
weak form this is the joint likelihood usually the recipient of observations
usually the recipient of observations right so obviously Z is not observed but
right so obviously Z is not observed but this is the this distribution is written
this is the this distribution is written as a function and the posted information
as a function and the posted information variable Z it's also function of
variable Z it's also function of parameter so what we do is to create an
update this on the previous values this is the expectation of the joint of life
is the expectation of the joint of life it will be respect to this posterior and
it will be respect to this posterior and the expectation step is basically to
the expectation step is basically to compute this whole term Q all right do
compute this whole term Q all right do the calculations and then the
the calculations and then the maximization is once we compute it
maximization is once we compute it optimize it with respect to theta and
optimize it with respect to theta and once we do that then you come back to
once we do that then you come back to the first step to complete this with
the first step to complete this with theta being taking now that all the
theta being taking now that all the fifth power all and again updating theta
fifth power all and again updating theta etcetera etcetera okay hmm in other
etcetera etcetera okay hmm in other place you will get different sufficient
place you will get different sufficient statistics the sufficient statistics
statistics the sufficient statistics that they were coming up where
that they were coming up where effectively this is moving distribution
effectively this is moving distribution gamma this is gamma of G T which is the
gamma this is gamma of G T which is the probability of Z little T given all the
probability of Z little T given all the data and again compute at the old
data and again compute at the old parameters so this is a smoking
parameters so this is a smoking distribution because we are estimating Z
distribution because we are estimating Z at some time T given day the way past
at some time T given day the way past three by this our data from time 0 to
three by this our data from time 0 to time capital T and then we also needed
time capital T and then we also needed the joint smoking distribution of Z t
the joint smoking distribution of Z t minus 1 DT okay and I'm going to remind
minus 1 DT okay and I'm going to remind you today and we have seen these
you today and we have seen these calculations from 12 is are coming so
calculations from 12 is are coming so this is the Joint Distribution of CT
this is the Joint Distribution of CT minus 1 and city now ZT is let's say we
minus 1 and city now ZT is let's say we have K States all right so this is a
have K States all right so this is a vector at this time of vector of
vector at this time of vector of dimension K and this symmetric state by
dimension K and this symmetric state by K okay in this recipe in this problem
K okay in this recipe in this problem this time the sufficient statistics that
this time the sufficient statistics that you need to compute the joint of
you need to compute the joint of likelihood in essence all the
likelihood in essence all the information you need to extract from the
information you need to extract from the data is list and that ok now this you
data is list and that ok now this you know I already have you know discussed
know I already have you know discussed this before we're going to basically
this before we're going to basically need to do that for words mark wants
need to do that for words mark wants messed is fasting okay because basically
messed is fasting okay because basically this gamma is the product of alpha and
this gamma is the product of alpha and beta messages but you know you can do a
beta messages but you know you can do a llama decryption and we already have
llama decryption and we already have seen that as well and
seen that as well and first I'll show you know will become if
first I'll show you know will become if you do it for good the backward passing
you do it for good the backward passing you can calculate this on the fly as
you can calculate this on the fly as well alright so we don't need this let
well alright so we don't need this let me just go to review very fast I two
me just go to review very fast I two days ago so when I sum we have to
days ago so when I sum we have to calculate one of Z T right zippy can
calculate one of Z T right zippy can take K values so we actually take them
take K values so we actually take them escape analysis to calculate one of ZT k
escape analysis to calculate one of ZT k so can you tell me this is mystically so
so can you tell me this is mystically so when I shall teach and a time indicator
when I shall teach and a time indicator care is a straight indicator so what is
care is a straight indicator so what is very much city K so we know that we're
very much city K so we know that we're talking about the same things the
talking about the same things the probability is that
so the system probability right Caesar is a fastidious moving distribution
is a fastidious moving distribution doesn't credit accounts so it what is
doesn't credit accounts so it what is gamma opposite decay and I remind you
gamma opposite decay and I remind you again I kept no one to keep going back
again I kept no one to keep going back to takes ten minutes to do so this is
to takes ten minutes to do so this is the definition of the veteran CT gamma Z
the definition of the veteran CT gamma Z T it's the post a diversity given all
T it's the post a diversity given all the data from time one to time capital T
the data from time one to time capital T so what this gram of ZT k when I put the
so what this gram of ZT k when I put the index there explicitly so this is a
index there explicitly so this is a number is not a vector right so what is
number is not a vector right so what is gamma of Z DK is the probability of
we sent it so basically this agency decay Spanish missions to them and this
decay Spanish missions to them and this is the posterior probability that they
is the posterior probability that they will take the value up okay and if the
will take the value up okay and if the values are 1 and 0 obviously this is the
values are 1 and 0 obviously this is the same is the expectation of ztk right
same is the expectation of ztk right because the expectation is the value at
because the expectation is the value at x1 times the probability times the other
x1 times the probability times the other value 0 times the probability so it's
value 0 times the probability so it's really equal to the probability that
really equal to the probability that typically is equal to 1 what's the
typically is equal to 1 what's the posterior probability and certainly you
posterior probability and certainly you can think this as this joint expectation
can think this as this joint expectation in a very similar fashion from time that
in a very similar fashion from time that they wanted capital T all right so this
they wanted capital T all right so this is my capital X and we're going to
is my capital X and we're going to calculate this Q and when you remember
calculate this Q and when you remember Danny is the expectation of the joint of
Danny is the expectation of the joint of likelihood this is y so actually just
likelihood this is y so actually just remind me again how did this gamma come
remind me again how did this gamma come here at how the tea came the other let's
here at how the tea came the other let's look at this theory when did this second
look at this theory when did this second from this term there
kazumi office in temperature probably discussed writing in the likely return
discussed writing in the likely return this was let's say this was the
this was let's say this was the probability of transitioning from J to K
probability of transitioning from J to K which is from J to K so this would be a
which is from J to K so this would be a JK - what ^ indicator function that this
JK - what ^ indicator function that this term here is the K term of that is equal
term here is the K term of that is equal to 1 and that the I'm sorry that the
to 1 and that the I'm sorry that the j-turn or that's equal to 1 and that the
j-turn or that's equal to 1 and that the later about is equal to 1 right and the
later about is equal to 1 right and the function when you take the expectations
function when you take the expectations with respect to the posterior what do
with respect to the posterior what do you get you get that all right
you get you get that all right and similarly from this you get this and
and similarly from this you get this and here I'm assuming that the observation
here I'm assuming that the observation model there is one observation model for
model there is one observation model for each state K so for the state K
each state K so for the state K basically observation what it would be P
basically observation what it would be P of XT given 3 K 4 PK of the parameters
of XT given 3 K 4 PK of the parameters involved in this expectation model so to
involved in this expectation model so to be able to do the expectation step on
be able to do the expectation step on the EM algorithm you have to compute
the EM algorithm you have to compute this gamma you have to compute XT and
this gamma you have to compute XT and and of course you know these two terms
and of course you know these two terms here required and in this term requires
here required and in this term requires 4 with but with message passing at the
4 with but with message passing at the same thing with itself there is step is
same thing with itself there is step is to basically take derivatives of these
to basically take derivatives of these things with respect to PK and their
things with respect to PK and their units with respect to H say K so it's
units with respect to H say K so it's simple calculus okay the only thing is
simple calculus okay the only thing is when you take the unit's with respect to
when you take the unit's with respect to B K you have to put in advance
B K you have to put in advance multiplier because the time for the P
multiplier because the time for the P K's
K's over the capital K States is equal to 1
over the capital K States is equal to 1 very very differentiated take the units
very very differentiated take the units equal to 0 you get basically
equal to 0 you get basically PK to be equal dot and a JK equal to 1
PK to be equal dot and a JK equal to 1 okay and then the British action is
okay and then the British action is exactly what you will expect as an
exactly what you will expect as an answer right range a K the
answer right range a K the the Emily estimate is the number of
the Emily estimate is the number of times that you transition from state say
times that you transition from state say to carry over have different time
to carry over have different time instants ISTE right and divide it by the
instants ISTE right and divide it by the time square developed state J and the
time square developed state J and the transition to anything given by the
transition to anything given by the label level L equal 1 to capital K make
label level L equal 1 to capital K make some sense okay
no calculation for the observation model if the answers you gave of course depend
if the answers you gave of course depend on what observation model you have so
on what observation model you have so let's say if the observation volunteers
let's say if the observation volunteers that contain small as a Gaussian and the
that contain small as a Gaussian and the unknowns for each state k is me to the
unknowns for each state k is me to the mean and the covariance basically then
mean and the covariance basically then taking derivatives of the last time I
taking derivatives of the last time I mean Q basically leaving this is the
mean Q basically leaving this is the only place where this coefficients come
only place where this coefficients come so really you won't get any effect from
so really you won't get any effect from there so if you take the log of the
there so if you take the log of the Gaussian and you differentiate you
Gaussian and you differentiate you effectively get forties did you get the
effectively get forties did you get the UK is the weighted average of all the
UK is the weighted average of all the observations X 3 but this rate is with
observations X 3 but this rate is with respect to this procedure
respect to this procedure responsibilities comma right actually
responsibilities comma right actually that is the reason we call gamma to be
that is the reason we call gamma to be the posterior responsibilities and
the posterior responsibilities and similarly you get 4 Sigma K the same
similarly you get 4 Sigma K the same thing this is like the sample covariance
thing this is like the sample covariance but now it's you notice is weighted by
but now it's you notice is weighted by the posterior possibilities this is
the posterior possibilities this is identical effectively with estimating
identical effectively with estimating the coefficients in a Gaussian mixture
the coefficients in a Gaussian mixture all right because as we know the you
all right because as we know the you know the hmm model but this in the
know the hmm model but this in the context of wearing the parameters is not
context of wearing the parameters is not very much different from the estimated
very much different from the estimated parameters in the Gaussian mixture maybe
parameters in the Gaussian mixture maybe should be wants to give you some
should be wants to give you some homework some calculating those things
homework some calculating those things ok they each of them is like 5 lines but
ok they each of them is like 5 lines but in Ephesus to will force you to do the
in Ephesus to will force you to do the algebra and figure out for example here
algebra and figure out for example here that Bernoulli observation model or a
that Bernoulli observation model or a multi unit you know to do this
multi unit you know to do this calculations correct and not sure to
calculations correct and not sure to understand what this meaning side
understand what this meaning side because if you have a little bit small
because if you have a little bit small beware maybe a very small bill all right
beware maybe a very small bill all right so you know you ever have to give us a
so you know you ever have to give us a multi annuity distribution so this
multi annuity distribution so this calculation stuff basically
calculation stuff basically straightforward with just a few lines of
straightforward with just a few lines of calculations okay
calculations okay I remember I'm left with this but let me
I remember I'm left with this but let me just say the the following which
just say the the following which sometimes when you try to to learn the
sometimes when you try to to learn the parameters with one dataset from the
parameters with one dataset from the take time you want the time capital T so
take time you want the time capital T so you live data basically on one pass over
you live data basically on one pass over the train maybe the data is not an
the train maybe the data is not an obstacle to making the parameters
obstacle to making the parameters because if you think that you have an
because if you think that you have an XML mangled up is from a satellite so
XML mangled up is from a satellite so you can go backwards so once we move
you can go backwards so once we move speak to you never go back to say - so
speak to you never go back to say - so you won't have enough information to say
you won't have enough information to say to cut made the transition from due to
to cut made the transition from due to slightly you only have one equation
slightly you only have one equation information to help you to do that so in
information to help you to do that so in that case what it helps is to repeat
that case what it helps is to repeat this not for one data set all right each
this not for one data set all right each of them being a sequence of data from
of them being a sequence of data from time wanna take the time Ti so basically
time wanna take the time Ti so basically we would have done in this slide and I'm
we would have done in this slide and I'm not going to go through all of the
not going to go through all of the calculations are exactly the same
calculations are exactly the same results that I had before the only thing
results that I had before the only thing that I have changed this in the
that I have changed this in the sufficient statistics by the summation
of course you know the duration of the train if you like that each of them we
train if you like that each of them we have a different duration from let's say
have a different duration from let's say time 1 2 TI right to be the same but can
time 1 2 TI right to be the same but can be different but so the only thing I
be different but so the only thing I have is different from before varies
have is different from before varies estimation capital n capital n is how
estimation capital n capital n is how many knots you know how many capital
many knots you know how many capital extra stuff I had before I have provided
extra stuff I had before I have provided you because capital X was data from time
you because capital X was data from time wanted to T now I give you n approach
wanted to T now I give you n approach okay so about the only thing that
okay so about the only thing that changes the rest remains basically
changes the rest remains basically in veins the tape let me go fastest if
in veins the tape let me go fastest if there is anything interesting
and then we would get out of this in case you have not seen it for example
case you have not seen it for example when I knew this is the yep alright what
when I knew this is the yep alright what you can do is you can enhance your
you can do is you can enhance your business best friend anomaly estimate
business best friend anomaly estimate right so you can put something in the
right so you can put something in the parameters and immediately transform of
parameters and immediately transform of this to an office and that's the trivial
this to an office and that's the trivial calculation so if you look at maybe
calculation so if you look at maybe books or even people give this as a call
books or even people give this as a call mark maybe
mark maybe Subic wants to give you this as a
Subic wants to give you this as a homework you can put some prior on 5k
homework you can put some prior on 5k some fire on a JK and base you can
some fire on a JK and base you can before if you remember what we did is we
before if you remember what we did is we started me crazy the likelihood model
started me crazy the likelihood model like that so now that you will base you
like that so now that you will base you have the likelihood modern times the
have the likelihood modern times the probability law the parameters and then
probability law the parameters and then be exactly the same calculation you will
be exactly the same calculation you will just give contribution from the much of
just give contribution from the much of the priors but eventually when you do
the priors but eventually when you do that I am aware that you will give you
that I am aware that you will give you my estimates for the parameters and that
my estimates for the parameters and that standard okay
standard okay to get you know good results especially
to get you know good results especially when we have limited data okay
when we have limited data okay there is there are other ways actually
there is there are other ways actually that you know instead of getting the map
that you know instead of getting the map estimate somebody may be interested to
estimate somebody may be interested to get samples of actions II instead and I
get samples of actions II instead and I think if I have time I'm going to come
think if I have time I'm going to come back to that because has implications in
back to that because has implications in the lots of applications in robotics and
the lots of applications in robotics and animation things that use particle
animation things that use particle filter specially to operate with okay
right so today I have been given a circus clown Olympic review or the
circus clown Olympic review or the message passing without using actually
message passing without using actually the propagation it is science physical
the propagation it is science physical science is you know prediction of
science is you know prediction of whether climate whatever this is have
whether climate whatever this is have problems that you need on each of them
problems that you need on each of them so I need to interstate so this is
so I need to interstate so this is what's called the filtering distribution
what's called the filtering distribution so the anticipate that the filtering
so the anticipate that the filtering distribution would be noisy you won't be
distribution would be noisy you won't be able estimated precisely because somehow
able estimated precisely because somehow you just got some measurements on the
you just got some measurements on the case ago you know you're not going to
case ago you know you're not going to give the best estimates for this G of T
give the best estimates for this G of T so expect this filtering distribution to
so expect this filtering distribution to be noise the smoothing distribution
be noise the smoothing distribution which we actually gives it to define
which we actually gives it to define this gamma messages okay is the
this gamma messages okay is the condition to compute the little T given
condition to compute the little T given all the data back to capital T this is
all the data back to capital T this is the smoothing distribution so
the smoothing distribution so effectively you use future data to do
effectively you use future data to do estimation at earlier times so you know
estimation at earlier times so you know this is an effective organization if you
this is an effective organization if you like on the on on this destination so
like on the on on this destination so you expect this distribution to be where
you expect this distribution to be where is mother than this distribution now
is mother than this distribution now this
and have the luxury to do and give estimation as anytime you want to first
estimation as anytime you want to first you say yes to me now so that's the best
you say yes to me now so that's the best you can do okay so this is very much
you can do okay so this is very much related sort of if you are going to do
related sort of if you are going to do an inverse problem maybe this is more
an inverse problem maybe this is more related but if you do online estimation
related but if you do online estimation you want to know where to navigate about
you want to know where to navigate about let you know you need to know the faith
let you know you need to know the faith Testament all the time so this is the
Testament all the time so this is the distribution interplay with obviously
distribution interplay with obviously you know you can do some smoothing not
you know you can do some smoothing not that the state feedback of say P minus L
that the state feedback of say P minus L so this is the fixed large more thing if
so this is the fixed large more thing if you pixel so maybe at this time you can
you pixel so maybe at this time you can have the nutrient the previous estimates
have the nutrient the previous estimates all right this is this fixed large house
all right this is this fixed large house nothing you can do predictions of what
nothing you can do predictions of what the state is going to be next
the state is going to be next all right so this is and here the simple
all right so this is and here the simple calculation on how using the time of the
calculation on how using the time of the time P to actually go further than
time P to actually go further than calculate the speed T steps ahead and
calculate the speed T steps ahead and now this is actually the only thing that
now this is actually the only thing that you need to know to do this calculation
you need to know to do this calculation is to know this filtering distribution
is to know this filtering distribution which we will compute okay that's the
which we will compute okay that's the filtering distribution and using basic
filtering distribution and using basic laws of probability the two additional
laws of probability the two additional things that are coming is the
things that are coming is the transitions from T to T plus 1 and Tim
transitions from T to T plus 1 and Tim plus 1 to T plus 2 you can actually set
plus 1 to T plus 2 you can actually set the algebra
the algebra ok the risk you know there is really
ok the risk you know there is really nothing here so it's basically this
nothing here so it's basically this calculation for dimensionalize with
calculation for dimensionalize with respect to DT and DT plus 1 so you can
respect to DT and DT plus 1 so you can Nestle the future right but you do not
Nestle the future right but you do not need to now again with the filtering
need to now again with the filtering distribution at time T
right and something that actually you don't see what's in books but it is
don't see what's in books but it is essential as you collect date and time
essential as you collect date and time you may want to ask yourself okay a
you may want to ask yourself okay a collected date of the time T what is the
collected date of the time T what is the probability of observing some need a
probability of observing some need a part time T plus eight all right so you
part time T plus eight all right so you can figure this rental car as a right
can figure this rental car as a right but based on the knowledge that you have
but based on the knowledge that you have up to time T it tells you the
up to time T it tells you the probability of observing beta X at time
probability of observing beta X at time T plus h so this is what is called a
T plus h so this is what is called a posterior predictive dance that they are
posterior predictive dance that they are right and the difference basically from
right and the difference basically from what we did here is here we are
what we did here is here we are predicting the state attacked here were
predicting the state attacked here were predicting the observations have these
predicting the observations have these distributions you see here of this
distributions you see here of this picture there is very fundamental I mean
picture there is very fundamental I mean if that's why I'm trying to do this as
if that's why I'm trying to do this as elementary as possible because if you
elementary as possible because if you work on anything that has to do with
work on anything that has to do with mental and dynamics which is it it
mental and dynamics which is it it doesn't matter what the technique is if
doesn't matter what the technique is if it's an hmm if it is a mechanic's
it's an hmm if it is a mechanic's probabilities of the universe of the
probabilities of the universe of the whole or something whatever was in
whole or something whatever was in unused today this is it okay
unused today this is it okay so you need to know this idea now that's
so you need to know this idea now that's not the problems and the elevation
not the problems and the elevation problems that they're a little more
problems that they're a little more complicated to do work where some we
complicated to do work where some we have discussed right when I give you say
have discussed right when I give you say well an introduction to the Viterbi
well an introduction to the Viterbi algorithm what does the Viterbi
algorithm what does the Viterbi algorithm
what was that we tell the algorithm
you know we spent half an hour on it and you guys forgot about
and I'm sure somebody listens the vision sees some believable systems don't
sees some believable systems don't remember what was the Viterbi algorithm
remember what was the Viterbi algorithm what is not so what was a bit hurt you
so it was the most effective part right
given some of the resistance exhaust it is that what he said the most likely saw
is that what he said the most likely saw this many this is the path from Z of Z
this many this is the path from Z of Z from 1 to capital T given the
from 1 to capital T given the observation of x1 city ok so the basic
observation of x1 city ok so the basic infinite especially if the states of
infinite especially if the states of every time is the bigger number alright
every time is the bigger number alright so this says we're maximizing basically
so this says we're maximizing basically the posterior but in the be turbulent if
the posterior but in the be turbulent if we were really interested define this is
we were really interested define this is not what the maximum joint distribution
not what the maximum joint distribution all those this was but to find what our
all those this was but to find what our resist what is the path that maximizes
resist what is the path that maximizes this force field distribution now you
this force field distribution now you know again it's the true thick to give
know again it's the true thick to give you a homework on this to drive you not
you a homework on this to drive you not so you can learn something but the idea
so you can learn something but the idea here is this is not a very robust
here is this is not a very robust calculation and sometimes if you want
calculation and sometimes if you want this you may be happy if you actually go
this you may be happy if you actually go from the posterior or something taking
from the posterior or something taking you may want to estimate strong force
you may want to estimate strong force all right so it's a very substantial
all right so it's a very substantial problem and we covered this idea with
problem and we covered this idea with using sequence some of the cargo methods
using sequence some of the cargo methods in the course in in the fall so if
in the course in in the fall so if anybody wants to read more details on
anybody wants to read more details on this type of problems using sequential
this type of problems using sequential Montecarlo used to look up then this is
Montecarlo used to look up then this is not I emphasize this is not particular
not I emphasize this is not particular to this fast if you do any problem where
to this fast if you do any problem where you have data coming in right these are
you have data coming in right these are fundamental problems there is no way you
fundamental problems there is no way you can escape from this ok it's in our any
can escape from this ok it's in our any character in computer science and
character in computer science and physics in chemistry in engineering this
physics in chemistry in engineering this is a very sensitive problem to be able
is a very sensitive problem to be able sample from the posterior ok this
sample from the posterior ok this all right you need to play from the
all right you need to play from the evidence to maximize the evidence with
evidence to maximize the evidence with respect to the parameters this is how at
respect to the parameters this is how at the end of the day even the EMR which
the end of the day even the EMR which works but this calculation is not what
works but this calculation is not what you need to do and we would still what
you need to do and we would still what if you do message passing actually you
if you do message passing actually you can calculate this always with linear
can calculate this always with linear cost on the length of the chain in a
cost on the length of the chain in a very trivial fashion using forward and
very trivial fashion using forward and backward messaging all right so this is
backward messaging all right so this is a picture showing the different problems
a picture showing the different problems alright are you sure we did and this is
alright are you sure we did and this is an example again it's in the notes to
an example again it's in the notes to tell you how the different resolution
tell you how the different resolution I'm not gonna go through that so let me
I'm not gonna go through that so let me keep going and going all right right I
keep going and going all right right I have the message parsing algorithms that
have the message parsing algorithms that you need in the context of the e/m
you need in the context of the e/m algorithm to have better relations
algorithm to have better relations without using after the propagation none
without using after the propagation none of the above because we have done all of
of the above because we have done all of this i'd always using the simple rules
this i'd always using the simple rules of probability and i want to
there's nothing new the compressions are so you mentally you don't need to
so you mentally you don't need to complicate them for this problem to get
complicate them for this problem to get this results you can get them with a lot
this results you can get them with a lot of ability and you may ask me then why
of ability and you may ask me then why did belief propagation and all of these
did belief propagation and all of these things on junction 3 well because not
things on junction 3 well because not everything is it didn't lock up more
everything is it didn't lock up more than in life well the pumps are much
than in life well the pumps are much more complicated right you know can be
more complicated right you know can be anything and you know that is not a tree
anything and you know that is not a tree you won't be able to use this recursive
you won't be able to use this recursive techniques you have to use belief
techniques you have to use belief propagation Junction tree however it's
propagation Junction tree however it's as we discussed okay but the end that
as we discussed okay but the end that like the state space water we covered
like the state space water we covered next week I'll sort of the essential
next week I'll sort of the essential element of them and I want to be sure
element of them and I want to be sure that can work to actually notice it okay
that can work to actually notice it okay so lots of calculations basically to
so lots of calculations basically to convey to themselves that they
convey to themselves that they understand what's going on using
understand what's going on using absolutely nothing else but dissipation
absolutely nothing else but dissipation and independence for the hidden Markov
and independence for the hidden Markov model okay so what you want is I want to
model okay so what you want is I want to complete with anime means this the
complete with anime means this the problem intensity given the data time T
problem intensity given the data time T and we call this the filtering
and we call this the filtering distribution okay so in two steps
distribution okay so in two steps okay so we're going to assume that this
okay so we're going to assume that this is going to be recursive calculation is
is going to be recursive calculation is going to be a forward calculation which
going to be a forward calculation which means I am going to assume that somehow
means I am going to assume that somehow I know this content distribution of time
I know this content distribution of time t minus one okay so this distribution
t minus one okay so this distribution that we see here
anyway so the plan is to compute on and we're leaving two steps so the first
we're leaving two steps so the first step is I am going to calculate the
step is I am going to calculate the predictive distribution of Z P which is
predictive distribution of Z P which is one step ahead give it back up to ten
one step ahead give it back up to ten minus one
minus one I mean this is you can enter this
I mean this is you can enter this equation and you're not gonna tell me
equation and you're not gonna tell me you don't understand from 40k right so I
you don't understand from 40k right so I need to calculate this city equal to j
need to calculate this city equal to j given extra 1 to t minus 1 and I have
given extra 1 to t minus 1 and I have that I do this as the probability of
that I do this as the probability of city - one being I given the date up to
city - one being I given the date up to t minus 1 and then the probability of CP
t minus 1 and then the probability of CP given 60 minus 1 the shipping for a
given 60 minus 1 the shipping for a Baptist ridiculous I introduced ZT minus
Baptist ridiculous I introduced ZT minus 1 inside there so I perform a city minus
1 inside there so I perform a city minus 1 and minus J okay okay
1 and minus J okay okay you need some country no okay all right
you need some country no okay all right so that's one okay so we we assume we
so that's one okay so we we assume we know things up to two minus one we know
know things up to two minus one we know this so we can go one step ahead in time
this so we can go one step ahead in time T and find city I'm going to compute
T and find city I'm going to compute risk and I'm exploring the different
risk and I'm exploring the different notations in the literature basically
notations in the literature basically don't get confused they all give you the
don't get confused they all give you the same answers at the end of the day so we
same answers at the end of the day so we want to compute this and this is this is
want to compute this and this is this is what we have used it exactly like this
what we have used it exactly like this in with some difference based on this
in with some difference based on this normalization factor the probability of
normalization factor the probability of the data okay this distribution to be my
the data okay this distribution to be my optimistic I'll give it a name J okay so
optimistic I'll give it a name J okay so I 1/2 T is X 1 to t minus 1 and XT all
I 1/2 T is X 1 to t minus 1 and XT all right and I say this looks ball should
right and I say this looks ball should not be bored okay all right unless X of
not be bored okay all right unless X of course is a multi-variant volleyball
course is a multi-variant volleyball there okay
there okay so what you write down from here to
so what you write down from here to there so basically when I have done by
there so basically when I have done by using a factory sent obey this rule if
using a factory sent obey this rule if you like or the probabilities I remember
you like or the probabilities I remember sixth eighth to the left and I move a
sixth eighth to the left and I move a normalization
communities but conditions still investing with you know toxic this is is
investing with you know toxic this is is you know because what distribution is
you know because what distribution is this is the distribution we computed and
this is the distribution we computed and what distribution is risk
what distribution is risk you never does XP the based on the
you never does XP the based on the previous measurements if I know the
previous measurements if I know the strength of time T dissipation is you
strength of time T dissipation is you know the state the kind of patient I'm
know the state the kind of patient I'm tips okay so the other message which is
tips okay so the other message which is this is written as observation value
this is written as observation value which we know okay and the normalization
which we know okay and the normalization factor that we live here is that there
factor that we live here is that there are media effects they given X 1 2 3
are media effects they given X 1 2 3 minus 1 and this way the normalization
minus 1 and this way the normalization factor is if you take all of this
factor is if you take all of this alright and you sign for the possible
alright and you sign for the possible values of Z so basically if you take
values of Z so basically if you take this distribution there and you
this distribution there and you normalize it with respect to Z you get
normalize it with respect to Z you get the GT and it looks shelter for useless
the GT and it looks shelter for useless calculation this DT virtuosity would be
calculation this DT virtuosity would be essential because you will give us a
essential because you will give us a rapid calculation of the evidence but is
rapid calculation of the evidence but is used everywhere in Mesilla okay message
used everywhere in Mesilla okay message and this is the way that roughly defines
and this is the way that roughly defines it as the poster of city given date up
it as the poster of city given date up to 20 so sentences but can know their
to 20 so sentences but can know their papers and many other offers they
papers and many other offers they defined the Alpha masses not as the
defined the Alpha masses not as the posterior of ZT given this data but
posterior of ZT given this data but isn't joint
isn't joint and papers inside my notes if not
and papers inside my notes if not indicate this one as the posterior okay
x1 to XP and ending on stage but this is the first video to have the state equal
the first video to have the state equal to J given all the observations there
to J given all the observations there faster the same thing okay
faster the same thing okay but again is when you do calculations to
but again is when you do calculations to define it very distant and and so we
define it very distant and and so we don't have any mistakes what I chose
don't have any mistakes what I chose sorry
sorry the line senescence defined as this
the line senescence defined as this filtering posterior distribution is the
filtering posterior distribution is the product of the observation model times
product of the observation model times this predictive one step ahead
this predictive one step ahead distribution where this one step ahead
distribution where this one step ahead the tradition was written like that and
the tradition was written like that and I can tell you that it's there if you
I can tell you that it's there if you want to provision this
want to provision this it's a one-line calculation so a music
it's a one-line calculation so a music notation from at this book to divide he
notation from at this book to divide he divides me the transition matrix notice
divides me the transition matrix notice a capital sigh and the observation model
a capital sigh and the observation model of the state text a XD Givens DJ is DT
of the state text a XD Givens DJ is DT equal to J as little sigh of J appointee
equal to J as little sigh of J appointee and
okay so when I do this combination is a matrix times a vector for each of the
matrix times a vector for each of the stage I guess I get this vector and what
stage I guess I get this vector and what is this
okay which means you need to be done okay
the normalization right in the derivation here is the probability given
derivation here is the probability given all the previous data this is nice you
all the previous data this is nice you know why because of this normalization
know why because of this normalization factor from time 1 to capital P it will
factor from time 1 to capital P it will give you actually the evidence from 1 to
give you actually the evidence from 1 to capital T so the evidence basically is
capital T so the evidence basically is the summation of all of the normal is
the summation of all of the normal is the launch of the organization factors
the launch of the organization factors that you will get when you normalize
that you will get when you normalize this outlet is probability okay so so
this outlet is probability okay so so the other one is basically you know
the other one is basically you know obviously you have to start the
obviously you have to start the algorithm units that formula
algorithm units that formula message-passing you have to calculate
message-passing you have to calculate the Alpha measures and the normalization
the Alpha measures and the normalization factor step one and then basically you
factor step one and then basically you do this multiplication this kind of our
do this multiplication this kind of our product you normalize to get the
product you normalize to get the normalization GT and the message alpha T
normalization GT and the message alpha T and if you want find the evidence
and if you want find the evidence basically you take the sum of all the
basically you take the sum of all the logs of cities and as the evidence and
logs of cities and as the evidence and results am
definition of family it doesn't make a difference because it's so personal you
difference because it's so personal you know going to sound to our answer if
know going to sound to our answer if this can normalize them and so if you
this can normalize them and so if you only think you're fine definition versus
only think you're fine definition versus the other
the other either the normalization factor will
either the normalization factor will come to be on everyone and you
come to be on everyone and you contradict okay so you don't have to
contradict okay so you don't have to worry about the patient's years because
worry about the patient's years because they're at the end of the day equivalent
if I can give in in explicit form it's a calculation right for sure to complete
calculation right for sure to complete the message a 12-time think you need to
the message a 12-time think you need to know the matter of x t minus 1 and
know the matter of x t minus 1 and effectively obviously you need to
effectively obviously you need to advance this with the transition
advance this with the transition probability plus the observation model
probability plus the observation model and so so it's a parable ms despacio
and so so it's a parable ms despacio now there's masses past week and even
now there's masses past week and even when we did the junction tree
when we did the junction tree implementation for the hmm I told you
implementation for the hmm I told you that they're discussing is more
that they're discussing is more important than the message passing so
important than the message passing so I'm gonna start with an ominous is
I'm gonna start with an ominous is fasting but I'll be trying to make the
fasting but I'll be trying to make the posterior of City given what type of
posterior of City given what type of distribution then is this is this a
distribution then is this is this a filtering distribution what is this is a
filtering distribution what is this is a smoothing distribution so the nominal
smoothing distribution so the nominal mast is now because the ability know
mast is now because the ability know what reduces
I am going to what's going out there so I am going to so I have P of x1 the
I am going to so I have P of x1 the capital T given the different sphere of
capital T given the different sphere of CT and now a righty I am using the
CT and now a righty I am using the observations T plus 1 to capital
this is independence
it doesn't matter so this is the alchemist isn't it remember messages the
alchemist isn't it remember messages the provision of you
provision of you occupy and um given state at time T
occupy and um given state at time T right so that's the Alpha message and
right so that's the Alpha message and what is this this is what we call known
what is this this is what we call known ago the bitter message is knowing that I
ago the bitter message is knowing that I start at twenty P equal to J let's say
start at twenty P equal to J let's say what's the preferred video that will
what's the preferred video that will observe Dave XT plus 1 to X T okay
observe Dave XT plus 1 to X T okay that's the bigger message so you can see
that's the bigger message so you can see that there are now a system where anyone
that there are now a system where anyone interested is the product of the I'll
interested is the product of the I'll convey the message normalized okay again
and then use this formula to compute the realm of ZT you know an average of eight
realm of ZT you know an average of eight GT is the most easy thing to complete
GT is the most easy thing to complete because at the end of the day in the my
because at the end of the day in the my well at least you care about the gamma
well at least you care about the gamma messages we don't care about the bigger
messages we don't care about the bigger messages but you know one way or another
messages but you know one way or another the computation approach will be similar
the computation approach will be similar violence so when you complete this
violence so when you complete this different marketing take the profits of
different marketing take the profits of each thing to get this or if you come up
each thing to get this or if you come up with regulation for gamma city updates
with regulation for gamma city updates so to calculate the beta messages at t
so to calculate the beta messages at t minus one is basically the bigger
minus one is basically the bigger message supplying P times the transition
message supplying P times the transition matrix provide the G times the
matrix provide the G times the observation model at time T and you
observation model at time T and you stand for all stage J right and this
stand for all stage J right and this this is the
this is the the point is t minus one and the
the point is t minus one and the delicious actually
delicious actually trivial and if you want to program the
trivial and if you want to program the bigger message literally what you notice
bigger message literally what you notice you never have enough product between
you never have enough product between the observer and model and the message
the observer and model and the message beta time T and then once you've found
beta time T and then once you've found that vector we multiply the proposition
that vector we multiply the proposition letters I without new vector and you get
letters I without new vector and you get the message because P minus 1 and again
the message because P minus 1 and again you say if you define the bit of essence
you say if you define the bit of essence or the Alpha masters in a different way
or the Alpha masters in a different way this may come to make reference right
this may come to make reference right but the normalization factor you can
but the normalization factor you can beat afterwards that's why I put a
beat afterwards that's why I put a proportionality condition there so that
proportionality condition there so that this is applicable to whatever
this is applicable to whatever definitions used for the outcome
definitions used for the outcome measures okay so so he doesn't make
measures okay so so he doesn't make alright if you do this update then at
alright if you do this update then at this time when you finish going all the
this time when you finish going all the way backwards you can multiply the often
way backwards you can multiply the often bigger message that it's time T and this
bigger message that it's time T and this will give me the gamma masters this is
will give me the gamma masters this is the initial condition we started with a
the initial condition we started with a bit of Masters of Terror at the end
bit of Masters of Terror at the end basically equal to 1 let me see if I
basically equal to 1 let me see if I have a date for gamma
what is my gamma
you see rammasun Clerk
okay so it's I'm pointing to sly so I'm going to keep clicking all right but at
going to keep clicking all right but at least we got one way we got one way to
least we got one way we got one way to compute these gamma messes by
compute these gamma messes by multiplying the Alpha and the beta
multiplying the Alpha and the beta messages okay and if you want to find
messages okay and if you want to find that away with the alpha beta resistant
that away with the alpha beta resistant we did this really well as well look at
we did this really well as well look at this equation right
this equation right if this purple images have normalized
if this purple images have normalized and and the definition that I have here
and and the definition that I have here are normalized and you sum for personal
are normalized and you sum for personal values of this to GT this posterior
values of this to GT this posterior probabilities will sum to 1 so actually
probabilities will sum to 1 so actually from this equation at any node P you can
from this equation at any node P you can calculate the evidence by standing on
calculate the evidence by standing on possible values of the city by
possible values of the city by multiplying the master day alpha and
multiplying the master day alpha and beta okay
beta okay and in actually this formula can even
and in actually this formula can even look more trivial if you select there's
look more trivial if you select there's no P to be the capital you know T you
no P to be the capital you know T you know why how is this a question going to
know why how is this a question going to be simplified if we apply to this is for
be simplified if we apply to this is for a multi to be total time taken to
a multi to be total time taken to capital T what the dissipation will be
capital T what the dissipation will be politically applied for T equal to
politically applied for T equal to capital T you remember somewhere I
capital T you remember somewhere I mentioned something here
when you initialize the migga messages like starting from them the messages of
like starting from them the messages of yourself is equal to one so effectively
yourself is equal to one so effectively it can occupy played this in an even
it can occupy played this in an even simpler way out there is no good day
simpler way out there is no good day will it look like we do the summation of
will it look like we do the summation of the MS is too long again that's it okay
sighs there must be a basic available essences potential you remember we had
essences potential you remember we had to complete this joint distribution of z
to complete this joint distribution of z PM z p plus 1 the procedure given
PM z p plus 1 the procedure given observation choice there's nothing joint
observation choice there's nothing joint distribution so we needed remembering
distribution so we needed remembering the sufficient statistics that were
the sufficient statistics that were coming X - Alki J the transition matrix
coming X - Alki J the transition matrix we need to find how many times will
we need to find how many times will state I and the transition say and that
state I and the transition say and that came out to be equal to this sufficient
came out to be equal to this sufficient statistic so the actual independence it
statistic so the actual independence it comes out that the completeness the
comes out that the completeness the transition from i to j at t minus 1 t
transition from i to j at t minus 1 t what you need to do is the following
what you need to do is the following take the offer message computed i take
take the offer message computed i take the business is at P plus 1 computed J
the business is at P plus 1 computed J multiplied with the observation more
multiplied with the observation more than P plus 1 computed a and multiplying
than P plus 1 computed a and multiplying with the position let fix I'd say and
with the position let fix I'd say and actually if you remember with mastered
actually if you remember with mastered passing right when we wanted to find the
passing right when we wanted to find the Joint Distribution between two two
Joint Distribution between two two nights you know what we did is we took
nights you know what we did is we took that connects the two nights which is
that connects the two nights which is this times the evidenced and then we
this times the evidenced and then we took the message coming one more than
took the message coming one more than the rest come to the other note first
the rest come to the other note first unless is counting authority on one
unless is counting authority on one direction the message is coming at time
direction the message is coming at time T so actually lists exactly the same
T so actually lists exactly the same equations when we did the propagation ok
equations when we did the propagation ok so there's nothing it's just what is
so there's nothing it's just what is know is that the variation is down in
know is that the variation is down in this rise with an elementary caution
this rise with an elementary caution without knowing very much about the
without knowing very much about the liberal foundation but all these a list
liberal foundation but all these a list of dates are only applicable to change
of dates are only applicable to change and in this case the hidden Markov
and in this case the hidden Markov models so
models so so if you want to complete this this
so if you want to complete this this clothes moving joint for studio and then
clothes moving joint for studio and then you have to form a matrix between this
you have to form a matrix between this tab and doctor alright so basically you
tab and doctor alright so basically you know this is shorten shortage of
know this is shorten shortage of business let's say here in beta what's
business let's say here in beta what's the vector okay metrics and then
the vector okay metrics and then basically okay so all of these things
basically okay so all of these things are ready to go if you guys want to
are ready to go if you guys want to program this and again you know you
program this and again you know you don't like this and then whatever you
don't like this and then whatever you have a nice level ization routine and
have a nice level ization routine and you say now normalize so if you means
you say now normalize so if you means you know it miss this evidence from the
you know it miss this evidence from the bottom and it's better not have to
bottom and it's better not have to bother right keeping this track all the
bother right keeping this track all the time so you miss it you just come and be
time so you miss it you just come and be normal eyes and actually that will give
normal eyes and actually that will give you immediately what that value of the
you immediately what that value of the evidence all right
evidence all right so basically we use this to compute the
so basically we use this to compute the the sufficient statistics in in when we
the sufficient statistics in in when we did the you know the EMR growth since I
did the you know the EMR growth since I mentioned the Viterbi problem so let me
mentioned the Viterbi problem so let me go back to you
there is nothing new on what I'm going to say I'm gonna rewrite your question
to say I'm gonna rewrite your question again sure you guys can remember what we
again sure you guys can remember what we were touching so we're interested to
were touching so we're interested to find the maximum of the posterior focus
find the maximum of the posterior focus if Adam was given all the data but in
if Adam was given all the data but in particularly in the View tab you see
particularly in the View tab you see which one is to find the observed or
which one is to find the observed or gives me that much
gives me that much all right and this takes up its time or
all right and this takes up its time or many you know so this table is huge this
many you know so this table is huge this can you cannot go and say give me over
can you cannot go and say give me over stage and I would select one that much
stage and I would select one that much mice the posterior
mice the posterior so now you need to find disease for
so now you need to find disease for which so that's the argument right there
which so that's the argument right there aren't much problem he'll find the
aren't much problem he'll find the system maximize this posterior and we
system maximize this posterior and we resent that
resent that maximizing reagent is I think it will
maximizing reagent is I think it will not give you a right answer so we need
not give you a right answer so we need to maximize the given time step all
to maximize the given time step all right now edge weights
using the mission trip abused observationally and the transition will
observationally and the transition will be made this and especially much demise
be made this and especially much demise we must my stuff okay this is the
we must my stuff okay this is the stamping this is the probability of
stamping this is the probability of being on you know a particular state one
being on you know a particular state one this is the observation model of state
this is the observation model of state one this is the transition probability
one this is the transition probability between two time steps and this is the
between two time steps and this is the observation of time T and then this is
observation of time T and then this is you move from here to there and then you
you move from here to there and then you say what is the minimal way the populism
say what is the minimal way the populism in one maximal way basically and after
in one maximal way basically and after the Derby part the algorithm is simple
the Derby part the algorithm is simple dynamic programming algorithm gonna go
dynamic programming algorithm gonna go directly which is actually the same
directly which is actually the same equation we have seen in this book
equation we have seen in this book shalini divination hopefully things will
shalini divination hopefully things will click and you remember whether the
click and you remember whether the algorithms and tell me what that is
[Music]
- reflexive relation looking at that definition and tell me what this we have
definition and tell me what this we have a question says good
memories don't it because then you will not understand okay so we took my square
not understand okay so we took my square ended in 2-1
you know the taste and basically that give me the optimal
are we going to be able to count the correct answer at any stage don't
correct answer at any stage don't contaminate the other bills and then
contaminate the other bills and then work backwards figure out what is the
work backwards figure out what is the path that led to God
I'm disgusted
so she was very urbanized they're just old little different
mystical optimizes Thanks versus note
maybe this makes another nice homework by the way ok I see lots of nice chrome
by the way ok I see lots of nice chrome work ok something today
work ok something today ok so actually you know and then minus
ok so actually you know and then minus one and then again city minus one I can
one and then again city minus one I can one find the optimal SAT minus 2 until I
one find the optimal SAT minus 2 until I find all the way back to step 1 ok so
find all the way back to step 1 ok so actively what you need to do is you need
actively what you need to do is you need you know for anybody of like a 50 plus
you know for anybody of like a 50 plus one you need to know what is the optimal
one you need to know what is the optimal value at the previous step
the states because the Chinese optimized but the optimal are the tape across run
but the optimal are the tape across run you will be able to go straight to that
you will be able to go straight to that and then he will continue so the
and then he will continue so the previous step and the previous step on
previous step and the previous step on tigress have one and then you are done
and in many primitive elements is you know is used in hundreds of different
know is used in hundreds of different applications right you may have heard
applications right you may have heard the term is a real person that we tell
the term is a real person that we tell the College of Engineering at the UST
the College of Engineering at the UST you know so so this is a real person
you know so so this is a real person with a real algorithm it has made lots
with a real algorithm it has made lots of impact in in computer science enjoy
the list there is an example basic of the absolutely and you may not you know
the absolutely and you may not you know maybe so it will give you another
maybe so it will give you another example similar to this let me see
example similar to this let me see whether it's just a schematic I can
whether it's just a schematic I can guide myself so here we have three
guide myself so here we have three states all right and this is the
states all right and this is the transition probabilities for the three
transition probabilities for the three states so if you know this state your
states so if you know this state your point three probability to remain this
point three probability to remain this page 0.7 to go to state two etc etc and
page 0.7 to go to state two etc etc and this time the observation probability so
this time the observation probability so if you know state 1 with probability
if you know state 1 with probability point 5 you can observe see one with
point 5 you can observe see one with probability point two three two and with
probability point two three two and with probability 2/3 etc etc so you know the
probability 2/3 etc etc so you know the problem is asked you know if you know
problem is asked you know if you know that you start in state 3 1 right we
that you start in state 3 1 right we start from there and we have
start from there and we have observations because before everything
observations because before everything is a posterior probability so our
is a posterior probability so our observations have to answer presupposes
observations have to answer presupposes tricks in first steps
tricks in first steps it is fidelity so we have observations
it is fidelity so we have observations have G 1 2 3 4 6 6 we know the start
have G 1 2 3 4 6 6 we know the start from state 1 we know the transition
from state 1 we know the transition probabilities we know the observation
probabilities we know the observation probabilities and tells you when to go
probabilities and tells you when to go out the party let's actually on
out the party let's actually on extracting from a variable a lie that
extracting from a variable a lie that you can know everything actually has
you can know everything actually has education on probabilistic that they are
education on probabilistic that they are very nicely written story recommend but
very nicely written story recommend but when you have time and you have nothing
when you have time and you have nothing else to do
[Applause]
this is
right so you can see and eventually basically you can optimize when you
basically you can optimize when you reach the entered a website figure out
reach the entered a website figure out what is the optimal product in this case
what is the optimal product in this case comes to be you know one to two and
comes to be you know one to two and three I mean obviously this is a trivial
three I mean obviously this is a trivial problem but you can appreciate trying to
problem but you can appreciate trying to do this and much more complex scenario
do this and much more complex scenario so there's a very interesting sort of
so there's a very interesting sort of diving problem tomorrow
diving problem tomorrow so the main hesitation so I you know any
so the main hesitation so I you know any questions again usually the time to
questions again usually the time to customize
customize the available most of the days accepting
the available most of the days accepting today ministers from relatives prepare
today ministers from relatives prepare today but ok but tomorrow you can see me
today but ok but tomorrow you can see me show you how to clear if not it will
show you how to clear if not it will work right so I'll see you Paisley