but I was not waiting for anybody else to show up we need to start this bill 51
to show up we need to start this bill 51 so I'm gonna try to finish state-space
so I'm gonna try to finish state-space models today there will be more things
models today there will be more things in where they are then unbelievers as
in where they are then unbelievers as they say and more okay so where I was
they say and more okay so where I was gonna say what we are trying to finish
gonna say what we are trying to finish states based on those but there is lots
states based on those but there is lots of stuff in the notes that I don't think
of stuff in the notes that I don't think I will cover so that you don't get a
I will cover so that you don't get a headache and also we can discuss more
headache and also we can discuss more topics so what I want to do today is
topics so what I want to do today is something sort of elementary and some
something sort of elementary and some ways implied in in the things we have
ways implied in in the things we have seen before I you know so last lecture
seen before I you know so last lecture we derived the turn of history questions
we derived the turn of history questions for linear dynamical systems from
for linear dynamical systems from scratch basically we looked at the
scratch basically we looked at the questions we said this this independence
questions we said this this independence relations and playing with probability
relations and playing with probability laws we derived the the color pintura
laws we derived the the color pintura question so what I want to do is I want
question so what I want to do is I want to show you that in essence everything
to show you that in essence everything we learn about rest is passing when we
we learn about rest is passing when we apply that to the other amical systems
apply that to the other amical systems actually will give us directly the the
actually will give us directly the the the color of military questions and can
the color of military questions and can be generalized as well so I'm going to
be generalized as well so I'm going to do this highlight basically some of the
do this highlight basically some of the derivation the way they go they are not
derivation the way they go they are not trivial so so in some sense you're doing
trivial so so in some sense you're doing extra airport using masters passing but
extra airport using masters passing but at the expense basically of having an
at the expense basically of having an algorithm of this very general okay in
algorithm of this very general okay in considering the district or some
considering the district or some probabilistic graphical models what we
probabilistic graphical models what we have to do I will suggest actually that
have to do I will suggest actually that you guys'
you guys' the homework 5 maybe you do some of the
the homework 5 maybe you do some of the analytical calculations that we
analytical calculations that we discussed today because there is much to
discussed today because there is much to learn and they are not very difficult
learn and they are not very difficult but in essence if you do them you have a
but in essence if you do them you have a good sense of both masters passing but
good sense of both masters passing but also of you know dealing with the carbon
also of you know dealing with the carbon of in two types of equations all right
of in two types of equations all right so let me review for you the factor
so let me review for you the factor graph that corresponds to the state
graph that corresponds to the state space model of interest the only thing
space model of interest the only thing that is different here that I want to
that is different here that I want to remind you is that the way that we
remind you is that the way that we define the structure nodes we
define the structure nodes we incorporated both the transition model P
incorporated both the transition model P of Z enthusiam from Zn minus 1 to the N
of Z enthusiam from Zn minus 1 to the N but also the observation model so keep
but also the observation model so keep that in mind so it looks like a same
that in mind so it looks like a same thing but in reality we have accounted
thing but in reality we have accounted for what probability non-factor in
for what probability non-factor in similarly for the first part of her age
similarly for the first part of her age is the probability of the initial state
is the probability of the initial state in the observation model in the initial
in the observation model in the initial State
State alright so the message passing and you
alright so the message passing and you don't have to remember any questions
don't have to remember any questions because really it is graphical so let's
because really it is graphical so let's concentrate on this equation we only
concentrate on this equation we only look at messages that factors past the
look at messages that factors past the node all right the nose can actually do
node all right the nose can actually do anything in this draft so the message
anything in this draft so the message from FN to Zn is the factor itself all
from FN to Zn is the factor itself all right which connects the bottom of Zn
right which connects the bottom of Zn minus 1 is G n times the message that
minus 1 is G n times the message that the factor of Zn minus 1 that is some
the factor of Zn minus 1 that is some curved air passes to note the N minus 1
curved air passes to note the N minus 1 well it makes sense whatever comes st.
well it makes sense whatever comes st. plus the factor then you integrate the N
plus the factor then you integrate the N minus 1 out and you get the earth now if
minus 1 out and you get the earth now if this the variables are continuous would
this the variables are continuous would be in our problem
be in our problem that summation would be an integral okay
that summation would be an integral okay the first equation basically says that
the first equation basically says that the message that the notes positive
the message that the notes positive factor is the same as the message the
factor is the same as the message the previous from the bus is known so in
previous from the bus is known so in essence it emphasizes that we are just
essence it emphasizes that we are just happy enough to only work with messages
happy enough to only work with messages from factors to know you don't need to
from factors to know you don't need to bother progressing for multiparty all
bother progressing for multiparty all right so this is the common message
right so this is the common message passing and we call this the alpha
passing and we call this the alpha message okay and we discuss sort of two
message okay and we discuss sort of two different notations you know one that
different notations you know one that the message corresponding to this it was
the message corresponding to this it was the posterior of Zn given all the data
the posterior of Zn given all the data at the time and and I think another
at the time and and I think another notation was a nun normalized posterior
notation was a nun normalized posterior effectively so if you don't want to get
effectively so if you don't want to get confused with the notation effectively
confused with the notation effectively you can write that this is proportional
you can write that this is proportional to what you see on the right-hand side
to what you see on the right-hand side so when you compute the right-hand side
so when you compute the right-hand side then you normalize it and you get a
then you normalize it and you get a distribution so one way or another
distribution so one way or another it doesn't really matter if you see
it doesn't really matter if you see different notations okay so this is the
different notations okay so this is the forward messages and I also want to show
forward messages and I also want to show you the same schematic basically the
you the same schematic basically the backward messages from the root to no
backward messages from the root to no dates to the left so the message the
dates to the left so the message the message passing is basically identical
message passing is basically identical to before the things but it goes
to before the things but it goes backwards so the message from the
backwards so the message from the factory and the little the masters from
factory and the little the masters from at n plus one to note the end alright so
at n plus one to note the end alright so again we are making a messages from
again we are making a messages from practice to notes so this message here
practice to notes so this message here okay
okay is this factor
is this factor why is the message without the factor of
why is the message without the factor of ten plus two cents to note ZL plus one
ten plus two cents to note ZL plus one which is this and obviously this message
which is this and obviously this message the same as that business right so again
the same as that business right so again this message is this factor times this
this message is this factor times this message where we integrate out to the n
message where we integrate out to the n plus one and obviously you can see that
plus one and obviously you can see that this process is backwards because we
this process is backwards because we require this message to the right to
require this message to the right to compute the rest to the left and the
compute the rest to the left and the integration is to the variables to the
integration is to the variables to the right which is in this case Zn plus 1
right which is in this case Zn plus 1 and we call this the mega message okay
and we call this the mega message okay so the bigger message go backwards the
so the bigger message go backwards the Alpha message is to go forward so what
Alpha message is to go forward so what I'm gonna do is I'm going to play with
I'm gonna do is I'm going to play with its equations and device for you they
its equations and device for you they come up in three questions and it looks
come up in three questions and it looks sort of a massive algebraic calculation
sort of a massive algebraic calculation but I recommend that you do it because
but I recommend that you do it because not only you'll be happy that you
not only you'll be happy that you discover the Kalman filter equations
discover the Kalman filter equations from a completely different way from the
from a completely different way from the way carbon driver which is actually
way carbon driver which is actually different from the one we already have
different from the one we already have done in the earlier lecture but there is
done in the earlier lecture but there is much to learn both from Esther's passing
much to learn both from Esther's passing and playing with a gaussians
and playing with a gaussians conditionals partial answers to things
conditionals partial answers to things like that okay so I am going to use
like that okay so I am going to use first the form of the question that
first the form of the question that defines the Alpha messages so and again
defines the Alpha messages so and again as I told you if you don't you know want
as I told you if you don't you know want to worry what the normalization constant
to worry what the normalization constant here is or without fires you don't need
here is or without fires you don't need to bother okay you just say this is
to bother okay you just say this is proportional throughout and you
proportional throughout and you normalize and with every good luck to be
normalize and with every good luck to be the Alpha messages but fear I'm writing
the Alpha messages but fear I'm writing it in a precise for okay where this
it in a precise for okay where this message is the posterior of Zn given
message is the posterior of Zn given all the the date of the observations of
all the the date of the observations of Japan man okay
Japan man okay and this quotation is GL Scylla is
and this quotation is GL Scylla is basically the probability of friction
basically the probability of friction given X 1 to X n minus 1 okay again
given X 1 to X n minus 1 okay again if you like this rather than having this
if you like this rather than having this filtering distribution we have the joint
filtering distribution we have the joint distribution of Zn relaxed one to excel
distribution of Zn relaxed one to excel you're not going to get that TN okay but
you're not going to get that TN okay but more or less the question of sort of the
more or less the question of sort of the same alright so if you look at these
same alright so if you look at these equations right and obviously we're
equations right and obviously we're gonna make that summation and integral
gonna make that summation and integral and we want to get a methodology to make
and we want to get a methodology to make derive an inference algorithm that is
derive an inference algorithm that is linearly the length of the chain
linearly the length of the chain we need sort of to take advantage of the
we need sort of to take advantage of the structure of this equation in a way that
structure of this equation in a way that when we plug in here whatever
when we plug in here whatever distribution this alpha lessons is we
distribution this alpha lessons is we would like to get the same sort of
would like to get the same sort of distribution for the masses out partying
distribution for the masses out partying and in some sense if this belongs to
and in some sense if this belongs to some family of distributions we would
some family of distributions we would like the only thing to have to do when
like the only thing to have to do when we apply this equation to update the
we apply this equation to update the parameters of this distribution to get
parameters of this distribution to get the distribution of GA right so this is
the distribution of GA right so this is a Gaussian for example right it would be
a Gaussian for example right it would be great if somehow this is also a Gaussian
great if somehow this is also a Gaussian and the only thing we have to do is
and the only thing we have to do is update the mean and the variance of the
update the mean and the variance of the previous distribution okay now this was
previous distribution okay now this was doing gaussians right and this you know
doing gaussians right and this you know will fit perfectly with any distribution
will fit perfectly with any distribution from the exponential family but today we
from the exponential family but today we will discuss basically this the Gaussian
will discuss basically this the Gaussian distribution okay
now if so we're gonna take another Miss Landow in state space model where
Landow in state space model where basically what the probability of Zn
basically what the probability of Zn given CN - trauma and the probability of
given CN - trauma and the probability of Excel given Zn are Gaussian and then at
Excel given Zn are Gaussian and then at the end of the day basically all the
the end of the day basically all the distributions were going to get will be
distributions were going to get will be gaussians so the Joint Distribution of
gaussians so the Joint Distribution of correlated volumes to be a multivariate
correlated volumes to be a multivariate Gaussian and we have seen actually this
Gaussian and we have seen actually this problem letting you have done it you
problem letting you have done it you sort of done a homework problem with
sort of done a homework problem with this but we will see a different
this but we will see a different perspective here so let me give you the
perspective here so let me give you the result summary of the results if you
result summary of the results if you apply for a Gaussian linear system the
apply for a Gaussian linear system the forward fasting message equations did
forward fasting message equations did you get the identical equations
you get the identical equations corresponding to the color filter okay
corresponding to the color filter okay if you apply the support three questions
if you apply the support three questions so you know this is the bigger message
so you know this is the bigger message you get the comments motor equations
you get the comments motor equations that I think if I remember we didn't
that I think if I remember we didn't have time to cover in last lecture I may
have time to cover in last lecture I may be wrong but you stop there but you can
be wrong but you stop there but you can imagine that similar to the beta message
imagine that similar to the beta message right this government's motion equations
right this government's motion equations basically will give us the posterior of
basically will give us the posterior of specific variables given all the data
specific variables given all the data from 1 to capital T okay that's why this
from 1 to capital T okay that's why this equations are quote is moving a
equations are quote is moving a questions so this is nice right
questions so this is nice right phone that gives me the Kalman filter
phone that gives me the Kalman filter bar forgives with it's moving equations
bar forgives with it's moving equations and actually if you do the forward on
and actually if you do the forward on the back of the questions you can get
the back of the questions you can get the sufficient statistics from the
the sufficient statistics from the hidden variables that are needed to
hidden variables that are needed to compute the parameters view expectation
compute the parameters view expectation maximization you know ever that when we
maximization you know ever that when we did the hmm so we will actually turn to
did the hmm so we will actually turn to our crystals highlight for you the
our crystals highlight for you the questions if you don't need to
questions if you don't need to the parameters and they're fixed right
the parameters and they're fixed right depending on what your interest is if
depending on what your interest is if you want the predicted distributions the
you want the predicted distributions the floor where the questions will do is if
floor where the questions will do is if you want this more thing the backward
you want this more thing the backward will do it if you're gonna do the amount
will do it if you're gonna do the amount we have to basically do more how can be
we have to basically do more how can be the lesson I'm gonna use the notation
the lesson I'm gonna use the notation from Bishop's book actually to simplify
from Bishop's book actually to simplify the notation for the you variables that
the notation for the you variables that we had but the fact we there were
we had but the fact we there were nothing else but a constant term in the
nothing else but a constant term in the the mean of these distributions I
the mean of these distributions I omitted here but actually if you can
omitted here but actually if you can solve you can take the final results in
solve you can take the final results in with a trivial trick you can discover
with a trivial trick you can discover the you know the modify the question
the you know the modify the question when there is an extra term of the means
when there is an extra term of the means here but right now concentrate on the
here but right now concentrate on the greatest or questioners look like right
greatest or questioners look like right so a an Rama will decline the transition
so a an Rama will decline the transition model for the states and this is the
model for the states and this is the observation model with metrics it here
observation model with metrics it here Sigma and C n Sigma remember this
Sigma and C n Sigma remember this because I will forget the and we will be
because I will forget the and we will be lost to the algebra okay so a and gamma
lost to the algebra okay so a and gamma C and Sigma we supposed to from some
C and Sigma we supposed to from some initial state and so the initial state
initial state and so the initial state is going to be given also as a Gaussian
is going to be given also as a Gaussian I mean we you can see actually later on
I mean we you can see actually later on maybe in the slide if we have time and
maybe in the slide if we have time and remember I will let you know if this is
remember I will let you know if this is somehow not a Gaussian Gaussian mixture
somehow not a Gaussian Gaussian mixture then you don't get you get the different
then you don't get you get the different equations and kind of filtering right so
equations and kind of filtering right so this is not a job basically in to start
this is not a job basically in to start with a Gaussian otherwise you may get in
with a Gaussian otherwise you may get in trouble so mister questions basically if
trouble so mister questions basically if you don't want them in written in terms
you don't want them in written in terms of distributions you know this is how
of distributions you know this is how the questions look like they are all
the questions look like they are all linear right big asked why we call this
linear right big asked why we call this a linear dynamical
a linear dynamical so later on we will actually if I don't
so later on we will actually if I don't have time you would have to read it
have time you would have to read it right but we can expect this where for
right but we can expect this where for example here rather than having
example here rather than having something a function of Z n minus 1
something a function of Z n minus 1 maybe we can put some function f of Z n
maybe we can put some function f of Z n minus 1 or here some function G of Z ok
minus 1 or here some function G of Z ok but right now everything is in here and
but right now everything is in here and everything is gone
everything is gone so a lot of parameters right so from the
so a lot of parameters right so from the dynamics basically we have a and gamma
dynamics basically we have a and gamma from the observation we have C and Sigma
from the observation we have C and Sigma and from the initial model you have mu 0
and from the initial model you have mu 0 and B 0 so really if you want to
and B 0 so really if you want to complete the problem and do expectation
complete the problem and do expectation maximization you need to basically
maximization you need to basically calculate all these parameters from
calculate all these parameters from observations okay and in some sense this
observations okay and in some sense this is something at least in engineering
is something at least in engineering books you will ever see you know nobody
books you will ever see you know nobody bothers to tell you how to compute these
bothers to tell you how to compute these parameters but really the algorithm here
parameters but really the algorithm here is just a simple application of e/m the
is just a simple application of e/m the same way we work with hidden Markov
same way we work with hidden Markov model ok derive the forward equations
model ok derive the forward equations for this alpha messages and somehow
for this alpha messages and somehow let's discover that mr. questions are
let's discover that mr. questions are really the Kalman filter equations so
really the Kalman filter equations so we're going to do is since this is a
we're going to do is since this is a part with algorithm I'm going to denote
part with algorithm I'm going to denote so everything's a Gaussian so I am going
so everything's a Gaussian so I am going to denote these for the Alpha message
to denote these for the Alpha message you know corresponding to state G n I'm
you know corresponding to state G n I'm going to denote the mean and the
going to denote the mean and the variance is mu N and VN and the idea
variance is mu N and VN and the idea would be that I am going to start with a
would be that I am going to start with a master DN minus 1 so I'm going to know
master DN minus 1 so I'm going to know this mu n minus 1 and VN
this mu n minus 1 and VN one and then somehow using this for
one and then somehow using this for growth message-passing equation I should
growth message-passing equation I should be able to update new n minus 1 and DN
be able to update new n minus 1 and DN minus 1 the UN and via ok
minus 1 the UN and via ok nothing major so basically what I have
nothing major so basically what I have done is I took this equation and I
done is I took this equation and I expanded it by plugging in all the terms
expanded it by plugging in all the terms still CN remember again is really not
still CN remember again is really not necessary sometimes confusing but to
necessary sometimes confusing but to make this an equal sign you need that so
make this an equal sign you need that so this is the mr. x this Gaussian okay the
this is the mr. x this Gaussian okay the observation model is clear the message
observation model is clear the message at n minus 1 is there so we suppose we
at n minus 1 is there so we suppose we know this and this is the transition
know this and this is the transition model looks like that ends the N minus 1
model looks like that ends the N minus 1 is integrated off ok so again the
is integrated off ok so again the problem is given this because we will do
problem is given this because we will do it this as we go forward
it this as we go forward we want to compute that okay
and a sponson in the process if we want to have these equations properly
to have these equations properly normalized we will need to update these
normalized we will need to update these coefficients here as well all right I am
coefficients here as well all right I am going to take highlight as much as I can
going to take highlight as much as I can all right the rest i really suggest that
all right the rest i really suggest that you do it as a homework okay put in
you do it as a homework okay put in elevation arteries on the slides in the
elevation arteries on the slides in the slides but I want you to just copy this
slides but I want you to just copy this formula is actually going to either
formula is actually going to either because you learned about manipulative
because you learned about manipulative gaussians about the Woodbury identity
gaussians about the Woodbury identity marginalization conditionals Vegas rule
marginalization conditionals Vegas rule everything is there
everything is there how can you go wrong okay so so when we
how can you go wrong okay so so when we are this first I'm going to look at this
are this first I'm going to look at this list
list this ain't a grow is this integral in
this ain't a grow is this integral in the ocean and why the whole integral and
the ocean and why the whole integral and it is a Gaussian from kinds of magical
it is a Gaussian from kinds of magical are coming to be Gaussian white set out
are coming to be Gaussian white set out listing the glow when we are here on
listing the glow when we are here on this integral
I have the product of two gaussians but the min of one of them right is linear
so it's very very heaviest is like having a probability of Y given X all
having a probability of Y given X all right but this linear in X times the
right but this linear in X times the probability of X and what I'm asking is
probability of X and what I'm asking is to find the probability of Y when I
to find the probability of Y when I integrate X out right because I won't
integrate X out right because I won't see n minus 1 out right so basically
see n minus 1 out right so basically this is like having the Joint
this is like having the Joint Distribution of two versions then you
Distribution of two versions then you want to multi-role lies
want to multi-role lies okay so the idea is this is the formula
okay so the idea is this is the formula that I cut and paste it not everywhere
that I cut and paste it not everywhere but you guys will do the algebra and you
but you guys will do the algebra and you will learn it better than me so here is
will learn it better than me so here is like having Congress to distribution px
like having Congress to distribution px all right this is given this is given
all right this is given this is given all right hold this P of Y given X all
all right hold this P of Y given X all right and you notice the mean is linear
right and you notice the mean is linear in X which is the N minus 1 you see that
in X which is the N minus 1 you see that there's not be here in the Sigma Y of
there's not be here in the Sigma Y of course is this gamma so from my
course is this gamma so from my information of this for in a Gaussian
information of this for in a Gaussian models P of Y comes to be this nice
models P of Y comes to be this nice distribution that just mean that you
distribution that just mean that you securely has variance that we've set up
securely has variance that we've set up the service you don't need to prove them
the service you don't need to prove them you pull the mouse égalité and and you
you pull the mouse égalité and and you work with them okay be sure when you see
work with them okay be sure when you see them the first time in a textbook we
them the first time in a textbook we derive them because a little mistake in
derive them because a little mistake in the textbook we mess up the rest of your
the textbook we mess up the rest of your lives and I can easily see that because
lives and I can easily see that because I've seen those mistakes in textbooks
I've seen those mistakes in textbooks all right in the most common formula so
all right in the most common formula so so why is given like that right so this
so why is given like that right so this integral I can write it as a Gaussian
integral I can write it as a Gaussian that looks like that and he comes
that looks like that and he comes that the mean is a times mu n minus 1
that the mean is a times mu n minus 1 and the variance is P n minus 1 where
and the variance is P n minus 1 where the variance is written by this is
the variance is written by this is coming up from this nice form
coming up from this nice form okay you don't have to believe me
okay you don't have to believe me because this is the variance you plug it
because this is the variance you plug it in and that's what you get okay
in and that's what you get okay all right so obviously I'm putting n
all right so obviously I'm putting n minus 1 here everything because you know
minus 1 here everything because you know you know this whole divided was fairly
you know this whole divided was fairly for the time and minus 1 so we call this
for the time and minus 1 so we call this intermediate mathematics PN minus 1 okay
so this integral it comes out to be a decision in Z so this tentacle is an
decision in Z so this tentacle is an arginine shell and what is this thing
arginine shell and what is this thing today is a Gaussian in extent that has
today is a Gaussian in extent that has immense linear function of Z so what can
immense linear function of Z so what can we do we need to do two things right we
we do we need to do two things right we need basically to complete the posterior
need basically to complete the posterior of this so here is not marginalization
of this so here is not marginalization what we need to do is sort of from P of
what we need to do is sort of from P of X given Y go to P of Y given X all right
X given Y go to P of Y given X all right and this proficiency well is really feel
and this proficiency well is really feel fractious the normalization factor okay
fractious the normalization factor okay so so what when so tell us what you need
so so what when so tell us what you need you know you know perfect I'm using this
you know you know perfect I'm using this generic notation and P of Y effects and
generic notation and P of Y effects and we need to invert this and we need to
we need to invert this and we need to compute P of X given Y and that is given
compute P of X given Y and that is given by this nice formal of this mean and
by this nice formal of this mean and this variance right and
and actually there is as I've written down they don't use these variances you
down they don't use these variances you see here all right what the use is they
see here all right what the use is they gives the Woodbury identity where if you
gives the Woodbury identity where if you complete this all right you can simplify
complete this all right you can simplify to actually PN minus 1 minus J n times T
to actually PN minus 1 minus J n times T P and minus 1 for Tyrion comes to this
P and minus 1 for Tyrion comes to this and I know you forgot but this KN it is
and I know you forgot but this KN it is identical to what we derived in the last
identical to what we derived in the last lecture which is the column J gain
lecture which is the column J gain matrix okay so in this coefficient Sigma
matrix okay so in this coefficient Sigma n okay
n okay which is basically least marginal
which is basically least marginal effects and it's also a Gaussian that
effects and it's also a Gaussian that comes later okay
comes later okay again one less interested on Sigma n but
again one less interested on Sigma n but if we want to make that equation to be
if we want to make that equation to be to have an equal sign right it has to
to have an equal sign right it has to look like that this the normalization
look like that this the normalization factor and so look at this equation so
factor and so look at this equation so let me just remind you what we compute
let me just remind you what we compute it right what we computed is the mean
it right what we computed is the mean and variance of the alpha methods and
and variance of the alpha methods and the optimises is the filtering
the optimises is the filtering distribution of Z F and the president
distribution of Z F and the president distribution is the probability of Zn
distribution is the probability of Zn given the data x1 to X label that okay
so this is the mean alright this is the mean for this filtering distribution can
mean for this filtering distribution can you put this term physical meaning to
you put this term physical meaning to Vista question so that if we have some
Vista question so that if we have some physical meaning then you can write the
physical meaning then you can write the equation from intuition rather than
equation from intuition rather than algebra so what is a times nu n minus 1
so you take basically the printing distribution of 10-1
distribution of 10-1 and you push fun with the mean with the
and you push fun with the mean with the transition matrix a you sit up okay
transition matrix a you sit up okay so that's what it is and now we have
so that's what it is and now we have this gain matrix times some error and
this gain matrix times some error and that error is the observation that you
that error is the observation that you saw suddenly you see data that's your
saw suddenly you see data that's your observational time n right and what is C
observational time n right and what is C a mule and - you just told me that
a mule and - you just told me that a mu n minus 1 is this transy is pushing
a mu n minus 1 is this transy is pushing forward the previous mean with the
forward the previous mean with the transition matrix a so what is G times a
transition matrix a so what is G times a new n minus 1 it's got no observation on
new n minus 1 it's got no observation on that you will have and this is really
that you will have and this is really the other what to do and effectively
the other what to do and effectively before you have a landing matrix which
before you have a landing matrix which is this common gain matrix right so k
is this common gain matrix right so k times this error plus the first pair
times this error plus the first pair gives you the new updated mean and
gives you the new updated mean and that's right out okay first you know
that's right out okay first you know this is easy to remember but you do not
this is easy to remember but you do not remember that actually the exact
remember that actually the exact learning matrix this gain matrix is
learning matrix this gain matrix is given by anything like that but you know
given by anything like that but you know what at the end of the days we know for
what at the end of the days we know for stochastic optimization it doesn't
stochastic optimization it doesn't really matter in other ways if you put
really matter in other ways if you put something else and you start iterating
something else and you start iterating you will give the right answer straining
you will give the right answer straining waste okay but if we want to do things
waste okay but if we want to do things exactly and this is how the name looks
exactly and this is how the name looks of the variance and house here you need
of the variance and house here you need to start the algorithm and swiftly take
to start the algorithm and swiftly take the rest is passing on the first step
the rest is passing on the first step the first message basically requires the
the first message basically requires the initial state to the probability of Z 1
initial state to the probability of Z 1 times the first measurement that you do
times the first measurement that you do so this is our first P of Z 1 this is
so this is our first P of Z 1 this is the emission
the emission of x1 okay so if you plug in actually
of x1 okay so if you plug in actually following the same ones are blessed or
following the same ones are blessed or messes passing its to through to the
messes passing its to through to the algebra because you don't have any
algebra because you don't have any integral anything like that here is muon
integral anything like that here is muon and here is v1 and the constants to our
and here is v1 and the constants to our scanner like that okay so you have a way
scanner like that okay so you have a way to start the algorithm and and then if
to start the algorithm and and then if you use the update formulas and that's
you use the update formulas and that's the come up into the questions and done
the come up into the questions and done okay in you know in a few minutes we
okay in you know in a few minutes we basically finished with a color filter
basically finished with a color filter questions using ideas of masters party
just a mini are sort of a graphical representation of the way that you
representation of the way that you compute this printing distributions so I
compute this printing distributions so I think and I think this is how we derive
think and I think this is how we derive these things last week so this is the
these things last week so this is the printing distribution of n minus 1 then
printing distribution of n minus 1 then you use the transition model basically
you use the transition model basically defined by this probability of Zn given
defined by this probability of Zn given Zn minus 1 so you update basically
Zn minus 1 so you update basically interstate is the end still using the
interstate is the end still using the measurements from x1 to xn minus 1 so
measurements from x1 to xn minus 1 so this is like an accretion model and the
this is like an accretion model and the values of this dictates basically a
values of this dictates basically a distribution that has is much wider in
distribution that has is much wider in support from the splintering stage at n
support from the splintering stage at n minus 1 and then effectively what to get
minus 1 and then effectively what to get the filtering state at time n you
the filtering state at time n you basically have to multiply with the
basically have to multiply with the observation model ok that looks like
observation model ok that looks like this and eventually this very broad
this and eventually this very broad push forward apply for one step
push forward apply for one step predicting this position now is modified
predicting this position now is modified to give you to give you this good
to give you to give you this good distribution that is the
distribution that is the take the time that so basically again
take the time that so basically again one-step prediction you know ahead and
one-step prediction you know ahead and then you collect the measurement accent
then you collect the measurement accent and you update with this model for a
and you update with this model for a minute efficiency it gives you and you
minute efficiency it gives you and you get the right to talk alright so now we
get the right to talk alright so now we have to discuss the backward message
have to discuss the backward message passing I wanna do this fast because
passing I wanna do this fast because basically the question is look the same
basically the question is look the same okay you will only be interested from
okay you will only be interested from this backward passing for getting this
this backward passing for getting this smoothing equations but I don't think I
smoothing equations but I don't think I cover or maybe it was in last two
cover or maybe it was in last two seconds from the previous lecture so we
seconds from the previous lecture so we need to get the smoothing distributions
need to get the smoothing distributions potential I remind you that we have
potential I remind you that we have defined as gamma messages okay as the
defined as gamma messages okay as the product of the message is coming at each
product of the message is coming at each node so the product of alpha and beta
node so the product of alpha and beta and this gamma messages define the
and this gamma messages define the sufficient statistics that we need of
sufficient statistics that we need of the EM algorithm
the EM algorithm okay and we were breaking discussed me
okay and we were breaking discussed me in one word
in one word well today all right so the debate looks
well today all right so the debate looks like that we basically have to go
like that we basically have to go backward we'd have to start to the last
backward we'd have to start to the last so ten plus one to complete the master
so ten plus one to complete the master then I have defined exactly the message
then I have defined exactly the message here so that this is equality including
here so that this is equality including the closeness of the heft and again you
the closeness of the heft and again you can look back on the previous lecture
can look back on the previous lecture but I had this equation that we
but I had this equation that we normalize our normalized form okay this
normalize our normalized form okay this is is precisely God so and again what's
is is precisely God so and again what's the meaning of the bigger message is the
the meaning of the bigger message is the probability of sending observations to
probability of sending observations to xn plus 1 to x cup the length given that
xn plus 1 to x cup the length given that I started third Zn at some value okay so
I started third Zn at some value okay so that's the bit America
I remember I give you the answer blog but basically what you need to do is
but basically what you need to do is take the since everything is a Gaussian
take the since everything is a Gaussian let me see we're going to assume that
let me see we're going to assume that this bigger message this is a given
this bigger message this is a given anywhere
all right so we have this okay we know that we have that we know that we know
that we have that we know that we know the update from the alpha messengers we
the update from the alpha messengers we know the skin obviously where I have
know the skin obviously where I have this rather than giving you the little
this rather than giving you the little essence it and actually if it is not in
essence it and actually if it is not in the slides maybe that's an external
the slides maybe that's an external hormone to the idea of explicitly the
hormone to the idea of explicitly the bit of assistance or the bus was moving
bit of assistance or the bus was moving color filtering equations okay so this
color filtering equations okay so this peg will I have is the combined message
peg will I have is the combined message Department beta in the derivation but if
Department beta in the derivation but if you only use this to compute this beta
you only use this to compute this beta messages thank you good you get this the
messages thank you good you get this the smoothing distributions so what I have
smoothing distributions so what I have here is I defined the gamma to be a
here is I defined the gamma to be a Gaussian with mean this new and Hart and
Gaussian with mean this new and Hart and V and Hart and you can show by you know
V and Hart and you can show by you know if actually what you need to do is
if actually what you need to do is multiply this with an R for instance all
multiply this with an R for instance all right so you can get the Rommel essence
right so you can get the Rommel essence of the left and then plug in everything
of the left and then plug in everything you know on the right everything is a
you know on the right everything is a Gaussian and here is the final answer
Gaussian and here is the final answer the mean and the variance for the gamma
the mean and the variance for the gamma resist is the mean and the variance that
resist is the mean and the variance that we computed for the Alpha messages times
we computed for the Alpha messages times this are the mean and the variance one
this are the mean and the variance one step ahead right because these are
step ahead right because these are backwards equations minus alpha nu n
backwards equations minus alpha nu n minus P n but we derive it in this
minus P n but we derive it in this matrix J and here is given V n times a
matrix J and here is given V n times a transpose B n minus
transpose B n minus okay so a very nice equation and I think
okay so a very nice equation and I think bits of the equations actually for the
bits of the equations actually for the carbons moving algorithm if you see in
carbons moving algorithm if you see in the notes basically you will immediately
the notes basically you will immediately recognize what the questions you need to
recognize what the questions you need to so coming out of this alright
so coming out of this alright to apply this equations or give you the
to apply this equations or give you the gamma Leicester's obviously you have
gamma Leicester's obviously you have first to run the power of addresses
first to run the power of addresses passing together nu + V and then go
passing together nu + V and then go backwards to calculate gamma okay
backwards to calculate gamma okay alright so you have to blossom in
alright so you have to blossom in sequence now there is one more
sequence now there is one more distribution that you need to get on the
distribution that you need to get on the air Margaret remember that remember this
air Margaret remember that remember this weird distribution the joint
weird distribution the joint distribution of Zn minus 1 CL that comes
distribution of Zn minus 1 CL that comes with the first one we did it apply the
with the first one we did it apply the hidden order
hidden order am L going from the hmm order okay so we
am L going from the hmm order okay so we will need to compute this joint
will need to compute this joint distribution for staining of Zn -
distribution for staining of Zn - Rollins yeah all right and there are
Rollins yeah all right and there are multiple ways of doing it you know and
multiple ways of doing it you know and here obviously the most trivial way to
here obviously the most trivial way to do it is to take the masters to derive
do it is to take the masters to derive so no than minus 1 and alpha message
so no than minus 1 and alpha message that the message that I should not beat
that the message that I should not beat up from right and then multiply with the
up from right and then multiply with the transition model and the observation
transition model and the observation model and that will give you this
model and that will give you this distribution so when you plug in all the
distribution so when you plug in all the distributions where it comes out is but
distributions where it comes out is but the joint distribution of Zn minus n CN
the joint distribution of Zn minus n CN is nu n minus 1 mu n I remind you these
is nu n minus 1 mu n I remind you these are the means for the gamma messages
are the means for the gamma messages okay and the core audience is J n minus
okay and the core audience is J n minus 1 times these variants of the gamma
1 times these variants of the gamma methods and
methods and the J metrics some priority is given by
the J metrics some priority is given by this okay so let me understand that
this okay so let me understand that equations are easy right but you know if
equations are easy right but you know if you think of writing a computer program
you think of writing a computer program that implements this it's basically once
that implements this it's basically once you put their analytical expressions the
you put their analytical expressions the whole algorithm is basically ten lines
whole algorithm is basically ten lines and literally Spain I mean if you search
and literally Spain I mean if you search on the web and you download the color
on the web and you download the color filter algorithm it's ten lights because
filter algorithm it's ten lights because every do you know the MATLAB knows how
every do you know the MATLAB knows how to manipulate gaussians and you don't
to manipulate gaussians and you don't have to do much you give the exact
have to do much you give the exact expressions and the rest is history
expressions and the rest is history okay I mean they become how we're going
okay I mean they become how we're going to get all these parameters now that we
to get all these parameters now that we got the sufficient statistics for you
got the sufficient statistics for you know with other sufficient statistics
know with other sufficient statistics for this from this gamma messages so I
for this from this gamma messages so I remind you what we need to do and let
remind you what we need to do and let somebody remind me so what we supposed
somebody remind me so what we supposed to do yes whether we will we take so the
to do yes whether we will we take so the expectation of what
the joint log-likelihood so we will take basically there's only like if result
basically there's only like if result observations and hidden variables
observations and hidden variables because what's a very easy distribution
because what's a very easy distribution right Gaussian basically easy to write
right Gaussian basically easy to write down especially the long and because we
down especially the long and because we don't know z we will take the
don't know z we will take the expectation of that with respect to the
expectation of that with respect to the posterior of the Samadhi
posterior of the Samadhi so rather than a step to do that
so rather than a step to do that computation with all the parameters
computation with all the parameters fixed are variously to all and then once
fixed are variously to all and then once we compute out so that we prepare to be
we compute out so that we prepare to be sufficient statistics because that
sufficient statistics because that expectation with respect to the
expectation with respect to the posterior of Z right will acquire the
posterior of Z right will acquire the mean of Z and you know the C variables
mean of Z and you know the C variables that we saw before so that's part of the
that we saw before so that's part of the step and in the m-step basically we are
step and in the m-step basically we are going to take derivatives with respect
going to take derivatives with respect to the theta parameters and will provide
to the theta parameters and will provide update and the three parameters here are
update and the three parameters here are sort of elastic because we have one two
sort of elastic because we have one two three four five matrices in one vector
three four five matrices in one vector okay the next thing is you will see that
okay the next thing is you will see that the equations actually decouple and in
the equations actually decouple and in almost in a trivial way they look like
almost in a trivial way they look like I'm making a lot of these matrices like
I'm making a lot of these matrices like the covariances like you know gamma and
the covariances like you know gamma and Sigma you will see that it looks almost
Sigma you will see that it looks almost like working with estimating the mean
like working with estimating the mean and the variance of a multivariate
and the variance of a multivariate Gaussian so basically doing Emily
Gaussian so basically doing Emily estimate for the multivariate Gaussian
estimate for the multivariate Gaussian and as you know what you do Emily you
and as you know what you do Emily you basically get the sample mean of the
basically get the sample mean of the sample variance okay so this is the
sample variance okay so this is the sufficient statistic that we need right
sufficient statistic that we need right the expectation of Zn
the expectation of Zn we already completed it
we need the this remember this joint thinks you know
this remember this joint thinks you know we need the expectation of Z and Z and
we need the expectation of Z and Z and minus one post post so you can since you
minus one post post so you can since you know the distribution of the joint the
know the distribution of the joint the joint distribution of z LZ at minus 1
joint distribution of z LZ at minus 1 this will be the body also that this
this will be the body also that this relation
relation - unit responds and then of course you
- unit responds and then of course you will need the expectation of TN z and
will need the expectation of TN z and transpose that is given like that and
transpose that is given like that and all of these parties we just computed
all of these parties we just computed all right so this will be can be sort of
all right so this will be can be sort of that in the aesthetic
that in the aesthetic so the not like equal to it's a trivial
so the not like equal to it's a trivial because you know you have the initial
because you know you have the initial observation model I mean the initial
observation model I mean the initial state model and then the transition and
state model and then the transition and the measurement and these are gaussians
the measurement and these are gaussians so we'll take long substring just
so we'll take long substring just simplify the trivial matter
simplify the trivial matter so this is what we need to compute need
so this is what we need to compute need to take the joint of likelihood and take
to take the joint of likelihood and take the expectation with respect to
the expectation with respect to parameters are showing the expectation
parameters are showing the expectation with respect to the z variables keeping
with respect to the z variables keeping the parameters fixed so let's do sort of
the parameters fixed so let's do sort of a trivial application of this to
a trivial application of this to computing new 0 and p 0 i remind you
computing new 0 and p 0 i remind you those are the mean and variance for the
those are the mean and variance for the initial state okay so basically in that
initial state okay so basically in that preparation of the joint of likelihood
preparation of the joint of likelihood only this term will give the
only this term will give the contribution for the involved in here 0
contribution for the involved in here 0 0 and really I mean estimating easier to
0 and really I mean estimating easier to 0 is like an Emily for multivariate
0 is like an Emily for multivariate Gaussian right I mean it's identical
Gaussian right I mean it's identical okay so when you write you expand this
okay so when you write you expand this this is what you get right
this is what you get right the only difference from doing Emily of
the only difference from doing Emily of multi-value Gaussian here is an
multi-value Gaussian here is an expectation with respect to the Z
expectation with respect to the Z variables so you notice the expectation
variables so you notice the expectation with involved
with involved you know z1 transposing one in also
you know z1 transposing one in also expectation of Z 1 verse of the
expectation of Z 1 verse of the sufficient statistic that I saw before
sufficient statistic that I saw before so z1 expectation of Z 1 and Z ones you
so z1 expectation of Z 1 and Z ones you want to expose so you have altered and
want to expose so you have altered and so when so these are the statistics you
so when so these are the statistics you need to compute okay and in the end step
need to compute okay and in the end step four is the maximization with respect to
four is the maximization with respect to the 0 and p 0 which the same thing as
the 0 and p 0 which the same thing as have antiviral gaussian and basically
have antiviral gaussian and basically these are the results that you get
these are the results that you get okay so the the updates of the main and
okay so the the updates of the main and the valiant are given basically actually
the valiant are given basically actually in terms of the sufficient statistics
in terms of the sufficient statistics because I mean this destructive expected
because I mean this destructive expected result here ok these are again like the
result here ok these are again like the sample mean right and this is like the
sample mean right and this is like the sample body right the expectations them
sample body right the expectations them so far of something okay
so far of something okay very fast you know if you want to
very fast you know if you want to calculate for example a and gamma okay
calculate for example a and gamma okay you need to expand this term so to
you need to expand this term so to expand it you can get something like
expand it you can get something like this
this alright and you complete your sufficient
alright and you complete your sufficient statistics then we take derivatives with
statistics then we take derivatives with respect to a and gamma the game it looks
respect to a and gamma the game it looks identical to multivariate Gaussian you
identical to multivariate Gaussian you know and be obtained of a and gamma in
know and be obtained of a and gamma in the m-step look like this really the
the m-step look like this really the only thing you need to compute again is
only thing you need to compute again is the sufficient statistics okay
the sufficient statistics okay and the sufficient statistics for a and
and the sufficient statistics for a and gamma obviously they involve all the
gamma obviously they involve all the sufficient statistics overall little
sufficient statistics overall little left right so you don't have you know in
left right so you don't have you know in this case all right well as suppose in
this case all right well as suppose in the previous case for the initial state
the previous case for the initial state you didn't have this
you didn't have this relations but here basically without the
relations but here basically without the summations that you need to make this to
summations that you need to make this to go in similarly for this calculation of
go in similarly for this calculation of Sigma of Z and Sigma that they come in
Sigma of Z and Sigma that they come in the observation model again mr. Fisher's
the observation model again mr. Fisher's for distinct look like this okay and
actually you can see immediately why we had caused the end to be sort of to be
what's the name we gave to the N I forgot remind me
say the word but for that I'm tired you know I am justified you know with the
know I am justified you know with the world that's nice amenity responsibility
world that's nice amenity responsibility okay
okay similarly the concept of the
similarly the concept of the responsibility because you know you
responsibility because you know you completing C and if you take all the day
completing C and if you take all the day all the observations but you sign a
all the observations but you sign a posterior probability to each of them
posterior probability to each of them right you know estimate basically the
right you know estimate basically the only thing you need to do is when you're
only thing you need to do is when you're going and finish the equation when
going and finish the equation when you're going to compute this expectation
you're going to compute this expectation the joint of likelihood the only thing
the joint of likelihood the only thing you have to do is write one put some log
you have to do is write one put some log of the prior probability there as well
of the prior probability there as well and the rest is service it will change
and the rest is service it will change any between in the derivative to get
any between in the derivative to get some extra terms the doctors regular
some extra terms the doctors regular license basically but getting the map
license basically but getting the map estimate is sort of trivial now again
estimate is sort of trivial now again this thinks they look like comma type of
this thinks they look like comma type of problems but you know as you can see you
problems but you know as you can see you know former promised you know there were
know former promised you know there were lots of progress on the spending habits
lots of progress on the spending habits how would this work you know they were
how would this work you know they were things done in the last 15-20 years so
things done in the last 15-20 years so this a nice reference that contains this
this a nice reference that contains this sort of calculation
okay I'm losing my audience what's happening today it's like I'm telling
happening today it's like I'm telling that back for two minutes and then
that back for two minutes and then everybody's gone if you try to play with
everybody's gone if you try to play with this message passing and and references
this message passing and and references I don't have them here but deny if you
I don't have them here but deny if you search you will find ways of doing this
search you will find ways of doing this but let's say that somehow you're not
but let's say that somehow you're not happy with messages that are gaussians
happy with messages that are gaussians right I mean I can you know maybe you're
right I mean I can you know maybe you're nice model is not Gaussian maybe your
nice model is not Gaussian maybe your initials trade is non Gaussian so how do
initials trade is non Gaussian so how do you use this equation let's say well
you use this equation let's say well this is a Gaussian mixture okay now if
this is a Gaussian mixture okay now if business a Gaussian makes the right and
business a Gaussian makes the right and there's the time put here okay xn given
there's the time put here okay xn given Zn so you start with say with the
Zn so you start with say with the methods of a z1 that is a Gaussian
methods of a z1 that is a Gaussian mixture then a of z2 will be also mixed
mixture then a of z2 will be also mixed with K square components basically it
with K square components basically it would be a Gaussian mixed with K cubed
would be a Gaussian mixed with K cubed components so basically you know
components so basically you know identical dilatory explosion in
identical dilatory explosion in components of these messages so the only
components of these messages so the only way that you can pursue sort of a non
way that you can pursue sort of a non Gaussian representation gives an extra
Gaussian representation gives an extra sphere would be to actually take
sphere would be to actually take different listeners with this mixtures
different listeners with this mixtures but before you update and you go to the
but before you update and you go to the next clip projecting back to K
next clip projecting back to K components so your new combinations of K
components so your new combinations of K square components but then you know
square components but then you know perhaps made this again with case J
perhaps made this again with case J component and
the wristwatch remember out of the group at MIT that had done this type of
at MIT that had done this type of calculations many 10 years course oh so
calculations many 10 years course oh so basically yes gaussians make this update
basically yes gaussians make this update progress analytical but you know if you
progress analytical but you know if you want to use anything that's long
want to use anything that's long Gaussian ignoring new territories and
Gaussian ignoring new territories and you have to be very careful how you do
you have to be very careful how you do okay
okay it doesn't mean you cannot be done what
it doesn't mean you cannot be done what he means is not going to be easy to
he means is not going to be easy to compute this topic is related with this
compute this topic is related with this type of exchange extensions when the
type of exchange extensions when the messages are non Gaussian how do you
messages are non Gaussian how do you actually okay is there are other any
actually okay is there are other any other methods okay
other methods okay and one of the methods that allows you
and one of the methods that allows you to do messages that they are non
to do messages that they are non Gaussian is to use a particle
Gaussian is to use a particle representation of the of the vestiges so
representation of the of the vestiges so you can figure out basically having the
you can figure out basically having the messages represented in terms of top box
messages represented in terms of top box alright and I know in the cola gave at
alright and I know in the cola gave at least three or four lectures of the
least three or four lectures of the topics are not quite sure how much you
topics are not quite sure how much you will be for us to discuss a lot of
will be for us to discuss a lot of details right somewhere try to spend
details right somewhere try to spend maybe 10 minutes okay because this maps
maybe 10 minutes okay because this maps are extremely powerful like for example
are extremely powerful like for example in robotics in tackling everything is
in robotics in tackling everything is using particle methods because those
using particle methods because those emissions long work gaussians are the
emissions long work gaussians are the wrong approach equation so the only way
wrong approach equation so the only way out is time approximation method or
out is time approximation method or using this part of things okay
using this part of things okay now I know about the 10th of the class -
now I know about the 10th of the class - good luck with my you know attending my
good luck with my you know attending my lectures in the hole
lectures in the hole but I also test that the remember
but I also test that the remember nothing okay
nothing okay right you sick they remember absolutely
right you sick they remember absolutely nothing so let me so I'm not going to
nothing so let me so I'm not going to let me jump okay
let me jump okay sorry I'm not going to tell you
sorry I'm not going to tell you everything
alright so me discuss sort of this prediction and update of the state that
prediction and update of the state that we use basically for the Kalman filter
we use basically for the Kalman filter equations of the previous lectures and
equations of the previous lectures and when I show here is rather than of
when I show here is rather than of making one state at the time they think
making one state at the time they think so in this case from the Stefan versus
so in this case from the Stefan versus prediction I have data from 1 to n minus
prediction I have data from 1 to n minus 1 all right
1 all right and I'm updating all the states
and I'm updating all the states including our state n and the addition
including our state n and the addition of the prediction step is the end of
of the prediction step is the end of this distribution at the joint of Z's
this distribution at the joint of Z's from 1 to N minus 1 given X 1 n minus 1
from 1 to N minus 1 given X 1 n minus 1 so this prediction one step ahead only
so this prediction one step ahead only involves lives of these dynamics the
involves lives of these dynamics the probability of Zn given Zn minus 1 okay
probability of Zn given Zn minus 1 okay right so again in for the filtering a
right so again in for the filtering a question the prediction step involving
question the prediction step involving the variables here here just because I
the variables here here just because I company's equations for much more
company's equations for much more general sort of type of calculations I
general sort of type of calculations I demonstrate this when we keep the
demonstrate this when we keep the posterior of all of these variables ok
posterior of all of these variables ok so this is the prediction for one step
so this is the prediction for one step ahead that we have seen and and as we
ahead that we have seen and and as we discussed even today if you want now if
discussed even today if you want now if you observe want you
you observe want you the point xn and you want to update the
the point xn and you want to update the prospero of all the Z's up to n then
prospero of all the Z's up to n then definitely what you need to do is take
definitely what you need to do is take this distribution multiplied with the
this distribution multiplied with the observation model xn given Zn so in a
observation model xn given Zn so in a particle that metals so if you you know
particle that metals so if you you know make all of this delusion then you get
make all of this delusion then you get that these filter equations ok because
that these filter equations ok because here I don't have all my observations on
here I don't have all my observations on each sub to help ok so you get the color
each sub to help ok so you get the color of entry questions for this so the idea
of entry questions for this so the idea of this particle levels are asking
of this particle levels are asking informant in time to represent these
informant in time to represent these distributions with samples without
distributions with samples without detection
detection ok and somehow another one understanding
ok and somehow another one understanding the distributions as you go from one
the distributions as you go from one step to another are provide basically
step to another are provide basically the the waves of this Delta functions as
the the waves of this Delta functions as you go from n minus 1 to n right
you go from n minus 1 to n right so the idea here is that you have Delta
so the idea here is that you have Delta functions but in shall we do class some
functions but in shall we do class some of the Cardinal the weight is the same
of the Cardinal the weight is the same so we're going to have weighted samples
so we're going to have weighted samples to express these distributions and if
to express these distributions and if your I these distributions in terms of
your I these distributions in terms of samples you can actually in principle
samples you can actually in principle represent any sort of distributions can
represent any sort of distributions can be anything all right
be anything all right anything that the distribution is very
anything that the distribution is very complex you will need more samples but
complex you will need more samples but this ideas here it comes out that if you
this ideas here it comes out that if you take the samples and somehow you update
take the samples and somehow you update are ways to one step to another the
are ways to one step to another the algoriphagus the complexity that depends
algoriphagus the complexity that depends the area or the number of the samples
the area or the number of the samples not on the little n so in principle you
not on the little n so in principle you can keep doing this forever you can
can keep doing this forever you can control us
control us distribution from time while 2 to
distribution from time while 2 to infinity even though there would be the
infinity even though there would be the generous issues and all the things that
generous issues and all the things that we have no time to discuss ok give you
we have no time to discuss ok give you basically I'm actually I'm going to go
basically I'm actually I'm going to go directly on the picture okay since we
directly on the picture okay since we Vista so so we have here is the mountain
Vista so so we have here is the mountain the define them and we know the temple
the define them and we know the temple in distribution and I write the specter
in distribution and I write the specter in distribution in terms of this
in distribution in terms of this particle service event the functions
particle service event the functions that are you know sentient basically on
that are you know sentient basically on this part it was capital of Z n okay and
this part it was capital of Z n okay and this are wage okay in the way it's
this are wage okay in the way it's actually when I represent this are the
actually when I represent this are the particles a different location and to
particles a different location and to indicate which way it's a bigger
indicate which way it's a bigger basically it's a bigger okay so to be
basically it's a bigger okay so to be able to move forward this particles and
able to move forward this particles and compute the filtering distribution time
compute the filtering distribution time n plus 1 you remember I need to do two
n plus 1 you remember I need to do two things first I need to move most fair
things first I need to move most fair which with this dynamical model and then
which with this dynamical model and then I need to apply the observation the
I need to apply the observation the emission probabilities P of X given Z so
emission probabilities P of X given Z so the variability is assuming that you
the variability is assuming that you have this particle distribution if you
have this particle distribution if you take this update equations other hands
take this update equations other hands before alright and if you apply the
before alright and if you apply the levity update equation somewhere I have
levity update equation somewhere I have an update equation what is it here this
an update equation what is it here this is the prediction for one step ahead the
is the prediction for one step ahead the only thing you have to do is take rest
only thing you have to do is take rest approach in terms of particles and then
approach in terms of particles and then multiply this with the dynamical model
multiply this with the dynamical model of P of Z L given Zn minus 1 so
of P of Z L given Zn minus 1 so basically this is what I have done here
basically this is what I have done here all right I compute
all right I compute the posterior of CN plus one still given
the posterior of CN plus one still given heaven with only the date of the time
heaven with only the date of the time man
man so this one required this posterior of
so this one required this posterior of CN plus 1 given at the end and then
CN plus 1 given at the end and then because you have these Delta functions
because you have these Delta functions this posterior we have to be calculated
this posterior we have to be calculated given its particle I don't know if you
given its particle I don't know if you can see what you actually get through
can see what you actually get through there is terms of a Gaussian mixture
right you get the Gaussian x2 distribution okay and because we don't
distribution okay and because we don't like thousand extras what you can do is
like thousand extras what you can do is you can understand all this all right
you can understand all this all right you can example this and if your sample
you can example this and if your sample is show that all the new samples
is show that all the new samples basically have equal weight the way you
basically have equal weight the way you do with Monte Carlo and this little
do with Monte Carlo and this little squares here little circles for equal
squares here little circles for equal radius base period of the new samples
radius base period of the new samples that give you this one step ahead
that give you this one step ahead predicted distribution okay so then I
predicted distribution okay so then I took my filtering distribution at time N
took my filtering distribution at time N and I now do one step ahead prediction
and I now do one step ahead prediction with recently and I get this little star
with recently and I get this little star post ok and what remains is to actually
post ok and what remains is to actually multiply this distribution with the
multiply this distribution with the observation model which is P of X given
observation model which is P of X given Z and if you do that because you have
Z and if you do that because you have this Delta functions the new
this Delta functions the new distribution will be basically the
distribution will be basically the effects given each of these particles
effects given each of these particles times this Delta function but you
times this Delta function but you compute it there so you can see the new
compute it there so you can see the new filter in this position the location of
filter in this position the location of the part of this hasn't changed but the
the part of this hasn't changed but the waste have changed because the weights
waste have changed because the weights now are dictated by the observational
now are dictated by the observational model of P of X given C
I know there is too much there to get but I need to tell you about this
but I need to tell you about this because some of these methods are the
because some of these methods are the methods that are used in practice
methods that are used in practice this is how we're gonna implement the
this is how we're gonna implement the trainer
trainer Gaussian models maybe even a linear
Gaussian models maybe even a linear models or unity of non Gaussian noise
models or unity of non Gaussian noise you know this meant was work and they
you know this meant was work and they are sort of the standard methods for
are sort of the standard methods for implementing lists of data questions in
implementing lists of data questions in many areas all right
many areas all right many are okay I'm actually with the bad
many are okay I'm actually with the bad reasons I have committed to give I don't
reasons I have committed to give I don't know how many lectures this summer in
know how many lectures this summer in another university on the top of this
another university on the top of this type of metals so if you are interested
type of metals so if you are interested I will try to sort of prepare specific
I will try to sort of prepare specific notes from scotts basically for this
notes from scotts basically for this part of into methods maybe by by
part of into methods maybe by by mid-june or so okay so what a wise you
mid-june or so okay so what a wise you can look at the notes from the course
can look at the notes from the course last semester that contains more
last semester that contains more information any questions to this at
information any questions to this at least in spirit what they are I mean the
least in spirit what they are I mean the whole idea is I represent the
whole idea is I represent the distributions the splintering
distributions the splintering distributions in terms of samples right
distributions in terms of samples right and a distribution in terms of samples
and a distribution in terms of samples is a bunch of Delta functions all right
is a bunch of Delta functions all right if you just need these are depending how
if you just need these are depending how we do the sampling to know if the
we do the sampling to know if the weights are equal or they are different
weights are equal or they are different okay and so in this case you start with
okay and so in this case you start with so when we see some of the start with
so when we see some of the start with bigger than others the weights different
bigger than others the weights different but if you sample from this you notice
but if you sample from this you notice like this sample that has degrade as you
like this sample that has degrade as you sample it gives you two children by just
sample it gives you two children by just the idea because there's no worry okay
the idea because there's no worry okay but it's not the new samples all of them
but it's not the new samples all of them have now equal way okay and then this is
have now equal way okay and then this is your observation model so obviously
your observation model so obviously these samples for example here when we
these samples for example here when we passed and prove this observation model
passed and prove this observation model we have bigger weight and again here we
we have bigger weight and again here we have bigger weights of they're small and
have bigger weights of they're small and so this is sort of a very powerful way
so this is sort of a very powerful way to do something to do small thing to
to do something to do small thing to there are lots of different type of
there are lots of different type of things and then the standard levels as I
things and then the standard levels as I said in robotics in in any sort of
said in robotics in in any sort of dynamical problems not on your body
dynamical problems not on your body touching anything all right
touching anything all right we have a few minutes left so let me
we have a few minutes left so let me Pacific how show you can finish this
Pacific how show you can finish this topic how you extend this ideas when the
topic how you extend this ideas when the model is not linear all right so so we
model is not linear all right so so we had two linear models right both the
had two linear models right both the dynamics it was for the Z you know
dynamics it was for the Z you know remember Z n equal a Z n minus 1 plus
remember Z n equal a Z n minus 1 plus noise let's say that the relation is not
noise let's say that the relation is not linear then we basically have the N
linear then we basically have the N minus 1 goes to some linear function f
minus 1 goes to some linear function f of X to give me to give me Z n okay you
of X to give me to give me Z n okay you can do this you know in in instead of
can do this you know in in instead of the matrix a or you can have something
the matrix a or you can have something like that to represent noise okay but
like that to represent noise okay but the bottom line is the relation we have
the bottom line is the relation we have between variables at n minus 1 and n all
between variables at n minus 1 and n all between the state and the observations
between the state and the observations in the given time they're coupled to
in the given time they're coupled to some nonlinear function and so we need
some nonlinear function and so we need to find some way to deal with it
in terms of particles you know that's not an issue right so well when I say we
not an issue right so well when I say we need to find some way to deal with this
need to find some way to deal with this can we actually want to try the carbon
can we actually want to try the carbon filter equations to do that okay and the
filter equations to do that okay and the answer of course is yes you can
answer of course is yes you can so yes then this is the trivial model so
so yes then this is the trivial model so let's say the the dynamics are given by
let's say the the dynamics are given by this function G okay and the observation
this function G okay and the observation model by another nonlinear function
model by another nonlinear function eight okay so the phonology is called
eight okay so the phonology is called the extended Kalman filter and it's
the extended Kalman filter and it's nothing else but linearization of GNH
nothing else but linearization of GNH and among the previous state estimates
and among the previous state estimates using basically a Taylor series
using basically a Taylor series expansion
expansion okay and actually there are versions of
okay and actually there are versions of this form you can use first on the
this form you can use first on the Taylor expansion and also a second of
Taylor expansion and also a second of the Pedro expansion you can do anything
the Pedro expansion you can do anything you want to the against once you
you want to the against once you approximate this and you you know if you
approximate this and you you know if you use the Taylor series expansion will
use the Taylor series expansion will give you sort of a linear term is a 3-1
give you sort of a linear term is a 3-1 or a near term intensity and so would
or a near term intensity and so would you sort of a derivative times 90 minus
you sort of a derivative times 90 minus 1 and if you approximate the derivative
1 and if you approximate the derivative of the previous state then the common
of the previous state then the common equation so really it's super fancy bra
equation so really it's super fancy bra there is really nothing there I think
there is really nothing there I think the equations are sort of in your eyes
the equations are sort of in your eyes and then cut and paste from the only
and then cut and paste from the only questions from the new questions but let
questions from the new questions but let me show you graphically what the idea
me show you graphically what the idea here is so remember we have
here is so remember we have as some function some running a function
as some function some running a function G of X all right so if X is a Gaussian
G of X all right so if X is a Gaussian the idea is when you compute let's say
the idea is when you compute let's say which Montecarlo y equals G of X you
which Montecarlo y equals G of X you don't get a Gaussian you get a real
don't get a Gaussian you get a real distribution of usage here so this
distribution of usage here so this bimodal distribution okay so the
bimodal distribution okay so the question is not really neat to do when
question is not really neat to do when we take a Gaussian and we apply this
we take a Gaussian and we apply this mapping to effects to get the Gaussian
mapping to effects to get the Gaussian right and so the idea for this extended
right and so the idea for this extended color filter is to do linearization in
color filter is to do linearization in the mode of X ok and then basically
the mode of X ok and then basically alright so this is the approximation we
alright so this is the approximation we do all right and then we pass the
do all right and then we pass the probability we passed this line through
probability we passed this line through the probability of P of X and that will
the probability of P of X and that will give me this dotted Gaussian which is
give me this dotted Gaussian which is the expanding our field of Gaussian that
the expanding our field of Gaussian that has a mean basically that is given by
has a mean basically that is given by this value here okay so how does the
this value here okay so how does the linearization look like so for example
linearization look like so for example this is the observation order your
this is the observation order your interest first on the table since the
interest first on the table since the question this is the value so we had H
question this is the value so we had H here right so we is the value is
here right so we is the value is computed at the previous mean okay if
computed at the previous mean okay if you remember this notation which is near
you remember this notation which is near 50 minus 1 is the main of what
50 minus 1 is the main of what distribution then this is the
distribution then this is the observationally right so what is mere TT
observationally right so what is mere TT minus 1
how many data have collected through this after 3-1 so this is the main of
this after 3-1 so this is the main of the one step ahead prolific distribution
the one step ahead prolific distribution okay some approximating age using the
okay some approximating age using the mean plus the derivative at the same
mean plus the derivative at the same location times the error of this one
location times the error of this one have I had in prediction the other if
have I had in prediction the other if you look from the observation Y key okay
you look from the observation Y key okay I don't know why it is white you know
I don't know why it is white you know text but anyways coming forward from
text but anyways coming forward from here of their give us different
here of their give us different equations so so basically they tell us
equations so so basically they tell us this expansion here around the mean of
this expansion here around the mean of the one hand one step ahead predictive
the one hand one step ahead predictive distribution okay another place there's
distribution okay another place there's absolutely nothing different from what
absolutely nothing different from what we had before if you remember the linear
we had before if you remember the linear model for coming up integration she goes
model for coming up integration she goes the Gaussian of YT given let's say what
the Gaussian of YT given let's say what was the metrics that we have here you
was the metrics that we have here you see sometimes right p plus some constant
see sometimes right p plus some constant so the constant is this minus this times
so the constant is this minus this times that okay and of course here I'm
that okay and of course here I'm thinking that the noisiest Gaussian okay
thinking that the noisiest Gaussian okay if the noisiest Gaussian is not Gaussian
if the noisiest Gaussian is not Gaussian basically you have to incorporate things
basically you have to incorporate things in a slightly different form okay
in a slightly different form okay and you know same thing for the
and you know same thing for the evolution of the of the dynamics let's
evolution of the of the dynamics let's not bother about you all right students
not bother about you all right students really move it on the previous slide so
really move it on the previous slide so basically you take linear Taylor series
basically you take linear Taylor series expansion around these the previous
expansion around these the previous night the main of the three stage which
night the main of the three stage which is near t minus one and this is the
is near t minus one and this is the error again times this Jacobian there
error again times this Jacobian there but there's a gradient position Z with
but there's a gradient position Z with respect to Z I mean you know once you do
respect to Z I mean you know once you do this if you look at your genetic type of
this if you look at your genetic type of simple equations did you cut and paste
simple equations did you cut and paste on solvers
on solvers updating that this is your matrix x y
updating that this is your matrix x y this is the constant and the rest is
this is the constant and the rest is very useful okay and if anyone you know
very useful okay and if anyone you know of notation basically you know if you do
of notation basically you know if you do this linearization you can get various
this linearization you can get various different versions of this extended
different versions of this extended Kalman filter including what's called
Kalman filter including what's called its innovative dkf if anybody is
its innovative dkf if anybody is interested I can give you to read a very
interested I can give you to read a very nice book by a stonker that I promise
nice book by a stonker that I promise you you can read it in less than three
you you can read it in less than three hours okay and he has a computer program
hours okay and he has a computer program that comes with it has nothing in the
that comes with it has nothing in the conditional probability graphical models
conditional probability graphical models but is everything from zero including
but is everything from zero including applications to the most complex sort of
applications to the most complex sort of way for doing some sort of essence of
way for doing some sort of essence of karma filter if you'll read the book in
karma filter if you'll read the book in three hours and a minute
three hours and a minute so if anybody's interested I think it's
so if anybody's interested I think it's online that okay and if you know access
online that okay and if you know access but you can actually reach this Christus
but you can actually reach this Christus that is two or three years before this
that is two or three years before this book okay
book okay so you can look at those things just six
so you can look at those things just six minutes finis right another algorithm is
minutes finis right another algorithm is the uncertainty column of the table to
the uncertainty column of the table to do TRAI and the idea here is that it is
do TRAI and the idea here is that it is easier to approximate the Gaussian run
easier to approximate the Gaussian run the log to approximate the function
the log to approximate the function so actually one to linear paste the
so actually one to linear paste the function you tried actually to
function you tried actually to approximate some data to fit the
approximate some data to fit the Gaussian so basically don't manipulate
Gaussian so basically don't manipulate the function trying to make data to fit
the function trying to make data to fit in some Gaussian point okay and how do
in some Gaussian point okay and how do you do this
you do this so here's the idea if the ocean all
so here's the idea if the ocean all right this is this is the unscented
right this is this is the unscented transport basically that you have to use
transport basically that you have to use if you have some distribution that fits
if you have some distribution that fits in the Gaussian and you want to pass
in the Gaussian and you want to pass this to a mapping of the form y equal f
this to a mapping of the form y equal f of X right F is a nonlinear function
of X right F is a nonlinear function which you need to do is you need to
which you need to do is you need to compute what is called Sigma points and
compute what is called Sigma points and these are constants basically that you
these are constants basically that you can optimize all right these are the
can optimize all right these are the columns of the Sigma matrix this is the
columns of the Sigma matrix this is the mean of this G of X so you calculate the
mean of this G of X so you calculate the Sigma forest and never can do this
Sigma forest and never can do this you Paskus this Sigma points through the
you Paskus this Sigma points through the function f and then you fit this data
function f and then you fit this data wise to now sir that's all
wise to now sir that's all so again money relating this function f
so again money relating this function f to give you a linear equation that will
to give you a linear equation that will lead to a Gaussian with the dress you
lead to a Gaussian with the dress you introduced this Sigma points okay
introduced this Sigma points okay and in this case they have to D plus 1
and in this case they have to D plus 1 points you pass this through the
points you pass this through the function f and then in through the
function f and then in through the Gaussian so obviously in our case we
Gaussian so obviously in our case we have to do this twice you have to do
have to do this twice you have to do this for the the dynamical model and we
this for the the dynamical model and we have to do this for the observational
have to do this for the observational model and effectively if so if you pass
model and effectively if so if you pass this through the function and you want
this through the function and you want to compute the mean and the variance
to compute the mean and the variance this the general response okay this
this the general response okay this looks very much like sample mean the
looks very much like sample mean the sample variance the only difference here
sample variance the only difference here is because these points were selected in
is because these points were selected in the some optimal way their weights would
the some optimal way their weights would not be equal so you know the weights
not be equal so you know the weights they have to be calculated depending on
they have to be calculated depending on the parameters that you use in the
the parameters that you use in the uncertain transport if you try to do
uncertain transport if you try to do this in one day in case you get inspired
this in one day in case you get inspired that this reminds you anything the three
that this reminds you anything the three points for example that you're going to
points for example that you're going to use is given Gaussian in one deal with
use is given Gaussian in one deal with mu nu minus square root of 3 times Sigma
mu nu minus square root of 3 times Sigma and mu plus square root of 3 times Sigma
and mu plus square root of 3 times Sigma and the algorithm is again sort of the
and the algorithm is again sort of the first step is we need to predict the one
first step is we need to predict the one hand of step so to compute the filtering
hand of step so to compute the filtering distribution again right you first have
distribution again right you first have to go one step ahead with observations
to go one step ahead with observations only after t minus 1 okay so to do this
only after t minus 1 okay so to do this what we have to do is pass the previous
what we have to do is pass the previous Gaussian distribution the Gaussian
Gaussian distribution the Gaussian approximation we had for the filter and
approximation we had for the filter and distribution of CP minus 1 so what you
distribution of CP minus 1 so what you need to this first this through the
need to this first this through the function G that defines the kinematic
function G that defines the kinematic model right the dynamical model G so
model right the dynamical model G so basically start with this decline the
basically start with this decline the Sigma points and then pass them to G and
Sigma points and then pass them to G and then to compute the mean of the variance
then to compute the mean of the variance of that you weight them appropriately
of that you weight them appropriately using the standard formulas from the
using the standard formulas from the insensitive small and you get the mean
insensitive small and you get the mean of the volatility like that and
of the volatility like that and eventually to genetic impedance of this
eventually to genetic impedance of this observation model but is nonlinear okay
observation model but is nonlinear okay so so what you need to miss you need to
so so what you need to miss you need to pass the power of Sigma T that we
pass the power of Sigma T that we completed the previous step there is the
completed the previous step there is the observation London okay so this is what
observation London okay so this is what you get okay and then eventually you are
you get okay and then eventually you are going to have this is sort of a
going to have this is sort of a likelihood and this is sort of like a
likelihood and this is sort of like a primer so you're going to need to do the
primer so you're going to need to do the 2013 distribution you will need to use
2013 distribution you will need to use Bayes rule and compute the probability
Bayes rule and compute the probability of Z given Y so if you have nice and and
of Z given Y so if you have nice and and if you have P of Z they're basically
if you have P of Z they're basically just Vegas truth directly it can give
just Vegas truth directly it can give you the filtering distribution so this
you the filtering distribution so this is just from the formulas for Gaussian
is just from the formulas for Gaussian linear models by noting specific this
linear models by noting specific this once alpha qkf algorithm is basically
once alpha qkf algorithm is basically clever another kind of reasoning is the
clever another kind of reasoning is the desirable algorithm because have much
desirable algorithm because have much higher accuracy than the linearization
higher accuracy than the linearization that we discussed before okay and the
that we discussed before okay and the objection is you have optimized this
objection is you have optimized this various points don't may be the function
various points don't may be the function and you know it's very nice
and you know it's very nice extermination to program you don't have
extermination to program you don't have to program so you didn't give them any
to program so you didn't give them any hormones to program this right but
hormones to program this right but things maybe you should give them
things maybe you should give them something worth a download maybe one of
something worth a download maybe one of the algorithms and the play with a
the algorithms and the play with a tortoise you can plot to see how the
tortoise you can plot to see how the Pinto
Pinto looks like you know how this malting
looks like you know how this malting distribution looks like and and and the
distribution looks like and and and the like just to finish the 125 right
like just to finish the 125 right obviously this nebula sound a small part
obviously this nebula sound a small part of this whole area of data stimulation
of this whole area of data stimulation right so cue work with dynamical data
right so cue work with dynamical data you need to know all of the specifics up
you need to know all of the specifics up and down every single detail because
and down every single detail because playing with data in time requires that
playing with data in time requires that you do prediction you do small things of
you do prediction you do small things of filtering all right all of the above
filtering all right all of the above okay there are lots of power of new
okay there are lots of power of new books that are coming out on data
books that are coming out on data stimulation dressed up with a little bit
stimulation dressed up with a little bit of mathematics they don't contain
of mathematics they don't contain anything new because this ideas have
anything new because this ideas have been out there for 20 years
been out there for 20 years okay but people who want right I mean if
okay but people who want right I mean if you want to write a book you know you
you want to write a book you know you can do something on Kalman filtering six
can do something on Kalman filtering six months okay
months okay and then someone can read it you know
and then someone can read it you know how many also to the three hours okay
how many also to the three hours okay and and always there's something to make
and and always there's something to make it different
it different okay but in the end you the formulas are
okay but in the end you the formulas are in the books already in papers and you
in the books already in papers and you can read them and so on Thursday we're
can read them and so on Thursday we're going to change subject and move the
going to change subject and move the body to variational approximate method
body to variational approximate method okay and where we need to spend at least
okay and where we need to spend at least three or four lectures discuss polyester
three or four lectures discuss polyester on that okay
on that okay a lot of stuff to read I'm going to post
a lot of stuff to read I'm going to post this lectures today so you guys can take
this lectures today so you guys can take a look and and take it from there all
a look and and take it from there all right