all right I hope you survive the last two lectures and I'm assuming the topics
two lectures and I'm assuming the topics that needed to be covered were covered
that needed to be covered were covered so I'm not you know I have not received
so I'm not you know I have not received any note contrary to God so we have
any note contrary to God so we have accuracy dual lectures some of them are
accuracy dual lectures some of them are they may sound a little review but
they may sound a little review but hopefully we will do some new things in
hopefully we will do some new things in between and today I want to just go back
between and today I want to just go back to a directly graphical models because
to a directly graphical models because basically they are the graphical models
basically they are the graphical models of more importance for scientific
of more importance for scientific applications okay so we need to to cover
applications okay so we need to to cover a few things in details reminder not
a few things in details reminder not next week next next week all the
next week next next week all the presentations in the class are going to
presentations in the class are going to start and I'm gonna be randomly picking
start and I'm gonna be randomly picking names and we're saying you you and you
names and we're saying you you and you today you you tomorrow
today you you tomorrow okay so don't send me in the quest and
okay so don't send me in the quest and say please can I speak the last can I do
say please can I speak the last can I do this can I do that you know and I think
this can I do that you know and I think your presentations it will be useful if
your presentations it will be useful if you a day before you actually speak the
you a day before you actually speak the the papers we can make them to be view
the papers we can make them to be view basically at the end of the semester so
basically at the end of the semester so that's where you have a few more weeks
that's where you have a few more weeks to write the actual six pages okay but
to write the actual six pages okay but there's no point of giving a
there's no point of giving a presentation then say please see revise
presentation then say please see revise presentation of course if the
presentation of course if the presentation and the paper don't agree
presentation and the paper don't agree in content we're in trouble
in content we're in trouble okay so don't bother basically
okay so don't bother basically submitting them if they are not on the
submitting them if they are not on the same on the same frequency
now next week is the scientific meeting I am NOT going to be here I have an idea
I am NOT going to be here I have an idea it's avec is going to be here so we may
it's avec is going to be here so we may have a lecture on Friday if I make it on
have a lecture on Friday if I make it on time but for sure I'm not here Tuesday
time but for sure I'm not here Tuesday and Thursday okay
so actually for this would be most probably more than one lecture I don't
probably more than one lecture I don't know how much we're going to cover today
know how much we're going to cover today the price for three lectures but the
the price for three lectures but the thing I don't have that luxury strong a
thing I don't have that luxury strong a maximum of two lectures this palace
maximum of two lectures this palace it's after nineteen from reqtest book
it's after nineteen from reqtest book and also taught the spelling seven from
and also taught the spelling seven from colors and Friedman PGM book okay so
colors and Friedman PGM book okay so they're both excellent reached all right
they're both excellent reached all right and as I said for those in who work in
and as I said for those in who work in science and engineering this is a very
science and engineering this is a very relevant topic so we may give you
relevant topic so we may give you basically minders and we'll try to to
basically minders and we'll try to to revisit a few concepts so what you see
revisit a few concepts so what you see on the top is an example of a directed
on the top is an example of a directed graph right and on the bottom we see an
graph right and on the bottom we see an undirected version of this where you
undirected version of this where you notice we have done what with the
notice we have done what with the buzzword what it is
buzzword what it is modernization so we have moralized the
modernization so we have moralized the parlance so for example seven has three
parlance so for example seven has three parents right and you notice four five
parents right and you notice four five and six
and six basically we linked them similarly five
basically we linked them similarly five has two parents two and three and we
has two parents two and three and we made them now we will say that when you
made them now we will say that when you mobilize it doesn't by any way imply
mobilize it doesn't by any way imply that whatever conditioning dependence
that whatever conditioning dependence relationship for the graph on the top
relationship for the graph on the top you are going to have the same relations
you are going to have the same relations on the graph on the bottom and this can
on the graph on the bottom and this can be an issue I mean it's easier to work
be an issue I mean it's easier to work with this model right and today we're
with this model right and today we're actually going to be talking about
actually going to be talking about undirected graphs okay so there is a
undirected graphs okay so there is a merit to do this but you need to be
merit to do this but you need to be aware but the conditional relations here
aware but the conditional relations here they are not the same as the ops on the
they are not the same as the ops on the bottom not always all right so why do we
bottom not always all right so why do we need to understand undirected graphical
need to understand undirected graphical models there is just example
models there is just example think
think about the the knowledge the longer
about the the knowledge the longer variables in your graph let's say the
variables in your graph let's say the pixel bodies in an image it doesn't make
pixel bodies in an image it doesn't make a sense to actually put directions with
a sense to actually put directions with us the elections being an image right
us the elections being an image right the this pixel effects is the parent of
the this pixel effects is the parent of that pixel and that is the size of our
that pixel and that is the size of our picture what does that mean it doesn't
picture what does that mean it doesn't mean anything so we only there's no
mean anything so we only there's no meaning to actually use a direct
meaning to actually use a direct graphical model it's a in the context of
graphical model it's a in the context of famous analysis and more importantly
famous analysis and more importantly it's not relevant to use it in this huge
it's not relevant to use it in this huge field of special statistics okay you
field of special statistics okay you have to be try to model correlations in
have to be try to model correlations in a special domain so I'll give you an
a special domain so I'll give you an example and to indicate basically how
example and to indicate basically how different things can be between
different things can be between directed graphical models and undirected
directed graphical models and undirected graphical model so let's go sit right on
graphical model so let's go sit right on no date okay so this is you can think of
no date okay so this is you can think of this as an image and this have the pixel
this as an image and this have the pixel values right which we take them to be
values right which we take them to be rondo and let's say we put some arrows
rondo and let's say we put some arrows the way that you secure all this grade
the way that you secure all this grade okay so we look on node X a can you tell
okay so we look on node X a can you tell me just looking at this graft all of
me just looking at this graft all of this other knowledge that you see there
this other knowledge that you see there all together what are they what do can
all together what are they what do can we assign them a name in the context of
we assign them a name in the context of the node X a and Y so it's very
the node X a and Y so it's very carefully all of this knows by the sound
carefully all of this knows by the sound excited except of course Mira can see
excited except of course Mira can see here x2 right it isn't an all together
here x2 right it isn't an all together what are they in the context of x8
the make a blanket okay so the market includes the parents includes the
includes the parents includes the children and what our x12 and explore
children and what our x12 and explore the corporates okay
the corporates okay obviously is not included right so the
obviously is not included right so the idea obviously of the Markov blanket is
idea obviously of the Markov blanket is that we know the values of the Markov
that we know the values of the Markov blanket of this Novak's a then extract
blanket of this Novak's a then extract is conditionally independent of anything
is conditionally independent of anything else in the ground okay so obviously we
else in the ground okay so obviously we have to look very carefully on all this
have to look very carefully on all this grid here to say yes this is the Markov
grid here to say yes this is the Markov blanket but x2 is not included the x14
blanket but x2 is not included the x14 is not included okay so let's look now
is not included okay so let's look now the undirected graph the Markov blanket
the undirected graph the Markov blanket is only those four nodes the neighbors
is only those four nodes the neighbors because you remember conditional
because you remember conditional independence basically in an undirected
independence basically in an undirected graph is defined by the neighbor so if
graph is defined by the neighbor so if you describe the values of these
you describe the values of these neighbors right x8 is independent
neighbors right x8 is independent anything else because if you look this
anything else because if you look this if you think of this operation the graph
if you think of this operation the graph from excited to any other node you have
from excited to any other node you have to go through this neighbors this Markov
to go through this neighbors this Markov blanket and and and if this are observed
blanket and and and if this are observed got blocked okay so point is this
got blocked okay so point is this condition independence relations in the
condition independence relations in the context of undirected graphs are very
context of undirected graphs are very simpler than what you see with a
simpler than what you see with a directed graph so obviously there is a
directed graph so obviously there is a merit to actually work with undirected
merit to actually work with undirected graphs so if you want SQ advantages and
graphs so if you want SQ advantages and disadvantages so the undirected graphs
disadvantages so the undirected graphs have symmetric you noticed when you look
have symmetric you noticed when you look for example for the neighbors is not
for example for the neighbors is not like this is the father
like this is the father there is norian tation this is the kids
there is norian tation this is the kids we start the comparison you don't have
we start the comparison you don't have anything like that
anything like that everything allowed to know the symmetric
everything allowed to know the symmetric alright so in the context of special
alright so in the context of special statistics is very relevant we will say
statistics is very relevant we will say it not today on Thursday that when you
it not today on Thursday that when you discuss this cumulative analysis so when
discuss this cumulative analysis so when you try to produce models P of Y given X
you try to produce models P of Y given X and this we will do this in the context
and this we will do this in the context of conditional random fields you know
of conditional random fields you know the you know undirected graphical models
the you know undirected graphical models are very appropriate this is very
are very appropriate this is very difficult to do with directly graphical
difficult to do with directly graphical models we have disadvantages in memory
models we have disadvantages in memory we will revisit this today the
we will revisit this today the privatization of the joint probability
privatization of the joint probability distribution in a direct graphic of
distribution in a direct graphic of Morgan's in terms of tricks right
Morgan's in terms of tricks right there's no physical meaning they're not
there's no physical meaning they're not make probabilities you know so you
make probabilities you know so you cannot really interpret things as easy
cannot really interpret things as easy as you do with directed graphical models
as you do with directed graphical models and the parameters that are involved in
and the parameters that are involved in the clinics are very difficult to
the clinics are very difficult to compute so the others are little bit
compute so the others are little bit more complicated even and again we may
more complicated even and again we may see this today or on our first day when
see this today or on our first day when you work with direct graphical models
you work with direct graphical models and naturally local probabilities like
and naturally local probabilities like the parameters are not given spotters
the parameters are not given spotters are normalized this is not the case from
are normalized this is not the case from direct graphical models so the
direct graphical models so the normalization requires actually to work
normalization requires actually to work with all the clicks everywhere and that
with all the clicks everywhere and that is a very computationally difficult
is a very computationally difficult problem ok actually most of the
problem ok actually most of the algorithms have difficulties just
algorithms have difficulties just because of computing properly the
because of computing properly the normalization factor
so in an undirected graphs the only conditional relation that we basically
conditional relation that we basically have played with is what you see here
have played with is what you see here defined with the separation so X a is
defined with the separation so X a is independent of X B given X C right when
independent of X B given X C right when any power from x-a to x-b has to go
any power from x-a to x-b has to go through XC okay and this is what we call
through XC okay and this is what we call a normal market property right so for
a normal market property right so for example if you look at nodes 1 &amp; 2 &amp; 6 &amp;
example if you look at nodes 1 &amp; 2 &amp; 6 &amp; 7
7 they're conditionally independent from I
they're conditionally independent from I mean 1 2 &amp; 6 7 or addition independent
mean 1 2 &amp; 6 7 or addition independent given 3 4 &amp; 5
given 3 4 &amp; 5 because to go from one or two to six or
because to go from one or two to six or seven you every part has to grow through
seven you every part has to grow through 3 5 &amp; 4 so that's the global Markov
3 5 &amp; 4 so that's the global Markov property the these geometrical property
property the these geometrical property is basically defined in terms of the
is basically defined in terms of the immediate neighbors of a node so if you
immediate neighbors of a node so if you fix their immediate neighbors that's the
fix their immediate neighbors that's the Markov blanket basically this node
Markov blanket basically this node becomes separated from where the other
becomes separated from where the other nodes okay so this is the local property
nodes okay so this is the local property so you just look at the nodes of of the
so you just look at the nodes of of the neighbors of the node and then there is
neighbors of the node and then there is ok so here's one example one is so
ok so here's one example one is so different or three one is independent of
different or three one is independent of the other node all right
the other node all right because again 23 are the neighbors of
because again 23 are the neighbors of fun once you block them there is no path
fun once you block them there is no path to go from 1 to any corrupt and and then
to go from 1 to any corrupt and and then you have this paralyzed Markov property
you have this paralyzed Markov property all right
all right so if so if yes again your neighbors so
so if so if yes again your neighbors so financial condition independent given
financial condition independent given the rest if there is not direct edge
the rest if there is not direct edge between them okay
between them okay notes are conditionally dependent given
notes are conditionally dependent given the rest right if there's no s between
the rest right if there's no s between them can you sit up I mean if the amount
them can you sit up I mean if the amount of dissipation is so let's say I'm
of dissipation is so let's say I'm looking at the note 6 8 and X 9 and all
looking at the note 6 8 and X 9 and all the other notes of things all right
the other notes of things all right obviously there is a path from X 8 X 9
obviously there is a path from X 8 X 9 on this plot all right so the only way
on this plot all right so the only way you can make this independent if there
you can make this independent if there is no link and that's why this is called
is no link and that's why this is called a pairwise markov property so for
a pairwise markov property so for example is X 7 X 13th independent given
example is X 7 X 13th independent given everything else is X 7 and X 13
everything else is X 7 and X 13 independent given all of the other no
yes or no yes okay so and the proof is given in the big Bible on Modest by :
given in the big Bible on Modest by : the serpent is the global properties
the serpent is the global properties these pairwise and the local property
these pairwise and the local property they're all equivalent so if you start
they're all equivalent so if you start on you can saw the other two it's not an
on you can saw the other two it's not an honest theorem and the blue-faced is not
honest theorem and the blue-faced is not very tricky but you know not well I
very tricky but you know not well I believe actually talk very well that it
believe actually talk very well that it was never formally published anywhere
was never formally published anywhere but is given in the book that you can
but is given in the book that you can read you know nationally beginning that
read you know nationally beginning that conditional independence relations
conditional independence relations between you know when you memorize the
between you know when you memorize the graph basically if you don't maintain
graph basically if you don't maintain the same condition independent relations
the same condition independent relations between the director of directed graph
between the director of directed graph and they take example is a directed
and they take example is a directed graph that looks like this okay you
graph that looks like this okay you remember this for example the explaining
remember this for example the explaining away and the undirected version that
away and the undirected version that looks like that okay so so for example
looks like that okay so so for example on this graph right with this separation
on this graph right with this separation which depicts be there's no path from A
which depicts be there's no path from A to C sorry a and C are independent here
to C sorry a and C are independent here if you fix B a and C B come
if you fix B a and C B come conditionally independent you remember
conditionally independent you remember so if you do not be a in still
so if you do not be a in still independent but if you know be alright
independent but if you know be alright and in C complete to explain be okay and
and in C complete to explain be okay and that's what the dependence comes so
that's what the dependence comes so immediately you can see that this
immediately you can see that this condition and dependence relations are
condition and dependence relations are not the same between the directed and
not the same between the directed and sort of the equivalent directed god so
sort of the equivalent directed god so visualization and I'm going to show you
visualization and I'm going to show you the maximum organization does not
the maximum organization does not maintaining the conditional independent
maintaining the conditional independent properties of the directed graph so
properties of the directed graph so let's briefly see this this directed
let's briefly see this this directed graph and the corresponding mobilized
graph and the corresponding mobilized undirected block so will be a blueish we
undirected block so will be a blueish we have given to what is still given 2005
have given to what is still given 2005 alright given two four and five are
alright given two four and five are conditioned independent right okay so
conditioned independent right okay so let's look here given to two and five
let's look here given to two and five not conditioned independent was not
because you can actually go to 5 through 6
6 remember conditional independence
remember conditional independence relationships all of directed graphs is
relationships all of directed graphs is is this I call this this what was there
is this I call this this what was there was more experiment right so you can
was more experiment right so you can actually if you were to 5 through 6
actually if you were to 5 through 6 right nothing is blocked so Claire is
right nothing is blocked so Claire is not independent of heart so we can
not independent of heart so we can actually fix this and make circle for
actually fix this and make circle for this bar to have sort of similar
this bar to have sort of similar conditional independence relationships
conditional independence relationships with an undirected version and the
with an undirected version and the answer is yes so let's look at this
answer is yes so let's look at this example with a little bit more detail
example with a little bit more detail here right so it says give you two turns
here right so it says give you two turns out they are not independent
out they are not independent okay now is in this diagram that makes
okay now is in this diagram that makes this relation to be destroyed can you
this relation to be destroyed can you look shorter form tell be working in
look shorter form tell be working in that undirected graph is responsible for
that undirected graph is responsible for violating this independence relation in
violating this independence relation in other ways work between more
other ways work between more but somehow resulted on five not being
but somehow resulted on five not being independent of five given for not being
independent of five given for not being independent five given to which link is
independent five given to which link is there but creating the problems
the pants of seven arginine 26 there's let's make them in this condition in the
penalizing four and six and then this conditional independence relationship
conditional independence relationship that we have on the Left will also be a
that we have on the Left will also be a block so here's what you need to do if
block so here's what you need to do if you want to prove a conditional
you want to prove a conditional independence if you say now pay and B
independence if you say now pay and B given C you only kid so you started off
given C you only kid so you started off the pony has denotes a B and C that we
the pony has denotes a B and C that we have okay all right and then you can
have okay all right and then you can search on you know particular case
certainly six and seven is not there so there's no need to actually you know to
there's no need to actually you know to put six and seven in the picture at all
put six and seven in the picture at all alright so we don't have any six and
alright so we don't have any six and seven so so if you can see that if you
seven so so if you can see that if you analyze this all right this relation is
analyze this all right this relation is actually true it's not the case given to
actually true it's not the case given to be exploring the pen defied all right so
be exploring the pen defied all right so so again if you restrain yourself on the
so again if you restrain yourself on the ancestral graph alright in this case
ancestral graph alright in this case this beginning of a B and C you can
this beginning of a B and C you can maintain the conditional dependence
maintain the conditional dependence relations from the directed and
relations from the directed and undirected
lectures will define basically it won't be an amicable distribution if the
be an amicable distribution if the independence relations implied by the
independence relations implied by the graph for subsets of the independent
graph for subsets of the independent elections implied by the distribution
elections implied by the distribution and we also define a perfect map so
and we also define a perfect map so Jason Patric monopoly distribution if I
Jason Patric monopoly distribution if I have J equal to I of P the message here
have J equal to I of P the message here is that the directed and undirected
is that the directed and undirected graphs are perfect Maps basically four
graphs are perfect Maps basically four different sets of distributions okay so
different sets of distributions okay so in this sense they are powerful but
in this sense they are powerful but basically they're pretty mental of each
basically they're pretty mental of each other or I continentally of each other
other or I continentally of each other so let me give you an example I think it
so let me give you an example I think it was this was in an early election but we
was this was in an early election but we make an effort to avoid discussion of
make an effort to avoid discussion of the details so let's consider this
the details so let's consider this undirected graph all right and can you
undirected graph all right and can you give me some independent statements on
give me some independent statements on this graph simply by looking at this
this graph simply by looking at this operation
so what it is independent the condition independent said given what they'll be
independent said given what they'll be because every math is blocked by DMV and
because every math is blocked by DMV and similarly there'd be our condition
similarly there'd be our condition dependent given agency so the position
dependent given agency so the position that someone may ask is this many basic
that someone may ask is this many basic to go that in quotes exactly the same
to go that in quotes exactly the same independence relation says this endeavor
independence relation says this endeavor the answer is you can't all right the
the answer is you can't all right the answer is no and when I demonstrate here
answer is no and when I demonstrate here is two examples you can try as many as
is two examples you can try as many as you want
you want design this directed graph so this we
design this directed graph so this we can say that a and C are independent
can say that a and C are independent given baby that's nice
given baby that's nice you should not okay so the energy
you should not okay so the energy independent given B and D which is the
independent given B and D which is the same as thought but let's look at the
same as thought but let's look at the northern relation of actually is implied
northern relation of actually is implied by this graph given a B and D are
by this graph given a B and D are conditionally independent you see that
conditionally independent you see that so it is being independent given air is
so it is being independent given air is being the independent knowing right
being the independent knowing right because there is about to be from B to C
because there is about to be from B to C okay
okay so business of work let's look at this
so business of work let's look at this graph we satisfy given baby and you see
graph we satisfy given baby and you see an independent alright so this is the
an independent alright so this is the same relation as there so let's
same relation as there so let's concentrate on this independent relation
concentrate on this independent relation that say but do you think this
that say but do you think this independent of B why is that
that's obvious isn't it
so this is independent of me I mean there's no such a thing being dependent
there's no such a thing being dependent of liver okay you can tell other cases
of liver okay you can tell other cases right you can convince yourself that
right you can convince yourself that there are a few graphical models
there are a few graphical models basically have the same independence
basically have the same independence relations and the majority basis
relations and the majority basis basically are coming from the fact of
basically are coming from the fact of this explaining away scenario but we
this explaining away scenario but we have seen earlier in the course so
have seen earlier in the course so basically what is a conclusion if you
basically what is a conclusion if you take the whole subset of probabilistic
take the whole subset of probabilistic graphical models okay this is the direct
graphical models okay this is the direct a graphical models right with their
a graphical models right with their condition independence relations to the
condition independence relations to the undirected graphical models and there is
undirected graphical models and there is a subset of dialectical director that
a subset of dialectical director that they're
they're graphical models but basically say the
graphical models but basically say the same conditional independence relations
same conditional independence relations models you get the same way Treehugger
models you get the same way Treehugger alright so there is a relation there
alright so there is a relation there that's why the junction tree algorithm
that's why the junction tree algorithm is successful so the half is a graph
is successful so the half is a graph where if you collapse the matter will
where if you collapse the matter will see needs click together
see needs click together megohm elements what you get is you get
megohm elements what you get is you get a tree okay so apart from that there is
a tree okay so apart from that there is a whole subset basically of conditional
a whole subset basically of conditional dependence relations you can get with
dependence relations you can get with the red gloves but you never get with on
the red gloves but you never get with on the left so as I discussed about the
the left so as I discussed about the parameterization so the parameterization
parameterization so the parameterization we discuss it has to be internship for
we discuss it has to be internship for potentials defined over the clicks so
potentials defined over the clicks so this potential system is finalized with
this potential system is finalized with a set of parameters theta C so this is
a set of parameters theta C so this is potential on click see this potential
potential on click see this potential sculptural basically locally dependence
sculptural basically locally dependence between
between but they're not probabilities okay so
but they're not probabilities okay so you cannot really say maximal working
you cannot really say maximal working alone of this potential
alone of this potential you cannot basically do inference
you cannot basically do inference because you do inference you will need
because you do inference you will need to put the whole Janie distribution with
to put the whole Janie distribution with all the potential terms together so the
all the potential terms together so the this is the most famous theorem actually
this is the most famous theorem actually there harmlessly playful theorem that
there harmlessly playful theorem that says that the Joint Distribution of all
says that the Joint Distribution of all this viable swine and undirected graphs
this viable swine and undirected graphs is the product of potentials definable
is the product of potentials definable maximal cliques divided by an
maximal cliques divided by an organization cost of this partition
organization cost of this partition function taken of the parameters defined
function taken of the parameters defined over its click okay this the composition
over its click okay this the composition is not unique and so for example if you
is not unique and so for example if you have potentials here that their
have potentials here that their potentials and you have so carefully
potentials and you have so carefully these potentials which note you can
these potentials which note you can learn them together to power potentials
learn them together to power potentials so this the composition is not unique
so this the composition is not unique as a matter when the algorithms you may
as a matter when the algorithms you may want to make this decomposition as any
want to make this decomposition as any way that the thing is going to simplify
way that the thing is going to simplify your type of calculations now the
your type of calculations now the difficult thing here and if I have time
difficult thing here and if I have time we will discuss you today all the way
we will discuss you today all the way from Thursday's completing this
from Thursday's completing this parameters theta and you notice
parameters theta and you notice unfortunately you will not be able to do
unfortunately you will not be able to do influence locally in general you would
influence locally in general you would have to this this term here this
have to this this term here this partition function is that brings
partition function is that brings everything together and is going to
everything together and is going to complicate it so here is an example of
complicate it so here is an example of one partition in multiple clicks a clip
one partition in multiple clicks a clip 1 2 3 2 3 4 &amp; 3 5 so writers in terms of
1 2 3 2 3 4 &amp; 3 5 so writers in terms of this potential
I mention a lot of these things are very much related with physics but this
much related with physics but this particular statistical physics so this
particular statistical physics so this distribution the most normal way to do
distribution the most normal way to do this is write it in terms of families is
this is write it in terms of families is affiliated with its peak we really have
affiliated with its peak we really have seen this before so
seen this before so so here basically children potentials is
so here basically children potentials is written to what sport e to the minus C
written to what sport e to the minus C where is an energy defined over that
where is an energy defined over that particular clickin because the product
particular clickin because the product basically you get the gives distribution
basically you get the gives distribution where the energy of the system is the
where the energy of the system is the sum of the energy so for maximal cliques
sum of the energy so for maximal cliques okay so this is the potential defined
okay so this is the potential defined over over its belief now this comes with
over over its belief now this comes with different names right as we receive in
different names right as we receive in some books they say mister maximum
some books they say mister maximum entropy Tydfil for distribution in
entropy Tydfil for distribution in machine learning they call this energy
machine learning they call this energy models at the end of the den of the day
models at the end of the den of the day you can even think of this as a pig
you can even think of this as a pig right well there is no energy or
right well there is no energy or something like that but you have these
something like that but you have these potentials e to the minus exponential
potentials e to the minus exponential because that way you can see that you
because that way you can see that you will get a positive product that is
will get a positive product that is relative to have the factor piston
relative to have the factor piston distribution right so I think it
distribution right so I think it probably does if the minus energy it
probably does if the minus energy it doesn't have to be motivated by twisting
doesn't have to be motivated by twisting all right so this is a parametrization
all right so this is a parametrization that only accounts for pairwise
potentials all right when we say but this is not maximal cliques right so I
this is not maximal cliques right so I can see here potential want to 1 3 2 3
can see here potential want to 1 3 2 3 so as I said you can actually do
so as I said you can actually do anything you want here because this
anything you want here because this factorization is not unique
factorization is not unique so she reviews pairwise potentials okay
so she reviews pairwise potentials okay so she the bins are a way of analyzing
so she the bins are a way of analyzing this potentials from their cliques and
this potentials from their cliques and this is what is called a linear model so
this is what is called a linear model so it's potential directed as potential to
it's potential directed as potential to be a some basis functions defined over
be a some basis functions defined over the features YC so these are the
the features YC so these are the variables in the clique product with set
variables in the clique product with set of parameters theta C alright so this is
of parameters theta C alright so this is a noble right in statistics of the main
a noble right in statistics of the main potential is expressed here selenium or
you may have to ask yourself whether this future functions here P okay so and
this future functions here P okay so and sometimes you just fistic aliyou assume
sometimes you just fistic aliyou assume something all right
something all right you know the title for mobiles and for
you know the title for mobiles and for example language models you don't have
example language models you don't have to learn this future constants well you
to learn this future constants well you can you know you can envision throwing
can you know you can envision throwing and lots of this function so letting the
and lots of this function so letting the data figure out which ones are needed
data figure out which ones are needed and the second problem would be to
and the second problem would be to calculate those parameters theta C and
calculate those parameters theta C and we will say that's where the concept of
we will say that's where the concept of stochastic optimization will come in in
stochastic optimization will come in in in the various parameters are computed
in the various parameters are computed so potential over the maximal clique all
so potential over the maximal clique all right so the potential is to this linear
right so the potential is to this linear term here the distribution so this
term here the distribution so this distribution is the product of all the
distribution is the product of all the potentials so the
potentials so the information of all of his limbs so I'm
information of all of his limbs so I'm going to have the summation of all of
going to have the summation of all of this it's a function of times theta C
this it's a function of times theta C decline over leads click - the
decline over leads click - the normalization factor Z of people ok and
normalization factor Z of people ok and again you see that this animal kills if
again you see that this animal kills if theta is going to be coming in all the
theta is going to be coming in all the time and it's going to be a should they
time and it's going to be a should they because it's not like okay this is
because it's not like okay this is proportional to Y we don't need to this
proportional to Y we don't need to this so unfortunately if you're going to
so unfortunately if you're going to estimate these parameters respond that
estimate these parameters respond that those are powerful through this
those are powerful through this normalization term okay so for example
normalization term okay so for example when we try to delete a maximum
when we try to delete a maximum likelihood estimation or map estimation
likelihood estimation or map estimation where you can envision if you like this
where you can envision if you like this can try to maximize this right and if
can try to maximize this right and if you do MLA this term is going to be
you do MLA this term is going to be difficult to compute because you will
difficult to compute because you will require integration basically on YC or
require integration basically on YC or the product of the potential so that
the product of the potential so that would be very difficult time to operate
would be very difficult time to operate all right so it was an example if this
all right so it was an example if this future functions are if so we paralyze
future functions are if so we paralyze market on the field I forgot to mention
market on the field I forgot to mention that the field is basically the
that the field is basically the alternative world that goes for this
alternative world that goes for this undirected graphical models so we only
undirected graphical models so we only think they paralyze potentials and we
think they paralyze potentials and we assume that each of the body which can
assume that each of the body which can take K values and so this future
take K values and so this future functions are basically indicator
functions are basically indicator function so in this case this particular
function so in this case this particular indicator function takes the value 1
indicator function takes the value 1 when the variable Y else is day and the
when the variable Y else is day and the value of YT is equal to K ok so and so
value of YT is equal to K ok so and so effectively you can think of this you
effectively you can think of this you know F is a vector of length K squared
know F is a vector of length K squared because you have K times K variables
because you have K times K variables okay so the petition basically can be
okay so the petition basically can be written as a table because if you try to
written as a table because if you try to calculate the potential for values of y
calculate the potential for values of y es and YT equals a and Kelly so
es and YT equals a and Kelly so effectively what you need to do is you
effectively what you need to do is you can see that this is the exponential of
can see that this is the exponential of the JK parameter theta s T okay so in
the JK parameter theta s T okay so in some sense there is a similarity between
some sense there is a similarity between for this discrete model using tables and
for this discrete model using tables and using this function okay so for example
using this function okay so for example based you know can be any indicator
based you know can be any indicator function of a few minutes
function of a few minutes these are indexed in the text okay
these are indexed in the text okay typically of the corresponding
typically of the corresponding parameters all right so this function is
parameters all right so this function is a binary function can take the value 0
a binary function can take the value 0 over 1 so this way you can identify
over 1 so this way you can identify certain words so if you have for example
certain words so if you have for example this is for triplet so if you have a
this is for triplet so if you have a world I and G or you know or something
world I and G or you know or something similar where the problem is if you try
similar where the problem is if you try to do this for a real text right and you
to do this for a real text right and you take you know 26 letters in the alphabet
take you know 26 letters in the alphabet so this will result basically to 26:58
so this will result basically to 26:58 parameters theta so will be
parameters theta so will be computationally a very difficult thing
computationally a very difficult thing to do alright so it's not like you're
to do alright so it's not like you're going to populate tables with millions
going to populate tables with millions of parameters and you're going to do
of parameters and you're going to do sort of MLE to computer so this will not
sort of MLE to computer so this will not work very well
work very well okay so now I went to the back to and
okay so now I went to the back to and slowly to the Ising model and revisited
slowly to the Ising model and revisited basically some of the ideas with this
basically some of the ideas with this person and see how we can train this
person and see how we can train this model which the hostak optimization the
model which the hostak optimization the Ising model we're looking on a good in
Ising model we're looking on a good in two dimensions or three dimensions we're
two dimensions or three dimensions we're basically trying to mimic the behavior
basically trying to mimic the behavior of magnets so these animals of binary
of magnets so these animals of binary variables plus minus one you can think
variables plus minus one you can think of this spin up spin down type of things
of this spin up spin down type of things when neighboring spins particularly in
when neighboring spins particularly in the same direction you get what's called
the same direction you get what's called ferromagnets when they try to align in
ferromagnets when they try to align in opposite direction you get
opposite direction you get antiferromagnets sometimes you get to be
antiferromagnets sometimes you get to be behaving this way how to behave that way
behaving this way how to behave that way and then in some sense you have a phase
and then in some sense you have a phase transition okay you may think this is a
transition okay you may think this is a toy problem it's a very biblical problem
toy problem it's a very biblical problem and some of the references of I posted
and some of the references of I posted actually not surprising they're like
actually not surprising they're like from the last five years okay because if
from the last five years okay because if you can do this problem properly with
you can do this problem properly with millions of applications in in in many
millions of applications in in in many different areas and of course you must
different areas and of course you must similarity hello okay so the position
similarity hello okay so the position from the model so the potential is not
from the model so the potential is not like this so we're looking here at the
like this so we're looking here at the pairwise potential obviously each of
pairwise potential obviously each of these variables can be spin up or spin
these variables can be spin up or spin down so plus minus one all right so it's
down so plus minus one all right so it's on our table each of those values we're
on our table each of those values we're gonna write it as a to W and E minus W
gonna write it as a to W and E minus W who use the same value basically to
who use the same value basically to describe what this probabilities and the
describe what this probabilities and the story is going to be on
story is going to be on - somehow we we have to computer or
- somehow we we have to computer or askew you remember the independence of
askew you remember the independence of the energies that we used before right
the energies that we used before right what's the local energy here from the
what's the local energy here from the system
system remember you have to learn with the
remember you have to learn with the potentials to be at work for I mean the
potentials to be at work for I mean the potential in this cable to the energy
potential in this cable to the energy here okay no energy means high
here okay no energy means high probability so so can you tell me from
probability so so can you tell me from all of this looking at the stable which
all of this looking at the stable which situation will give you that the low
situation will give you that the low energy so that the W is positive and
energy so that the W is positive and determine the Arabs is minus W so gamma
determine the Arabs is minus W so gamma is positive which configurations are
is positive which configurations are going to give you low energy if gamma is
going to give you low energy if gamma is positive
remember this is the configuration one plus 1 this is 4 minus 1 this is plus
plus 1 this is 4 minus 1 this is plus minus 1 plus minus 1 so which
minus 1 plus minus 1 so which configurations will give you will give
configurations will give you will give you the longest tendency of the highest
you the longest tendency of the highest probability if the energy is minus W
remember means minus a hundred is whatever - a 50 or zero or 10
whatever - a 50 or zero or 10 so which configurations are going to be
so which configurations are going to be over it in both case which means either
over it in both case which means either the left or on speed up or they're both
the left or on speed up or they're both down spin down so basically the system
down spin down so basically the system will try to give you the same
will try to give you the same arrangements of the spins throughout the
arrangements of the spins throughout the lattice ok and and of course you get the
lattice ok and and of course you get the opposite effect when the W is negative
opposite effect when the W is negative okay so in in the trivial sense if you
okay so in in the trivial sense if you want if you make WS stay constant okay
want if you make WS stay constant okay you can get sort of a simple the most
you can get sort of a simple the most obvious version of 12 of this Ising
obvious version of 12 of this Ising model
model alright so we discuss all of this
alright so we discuss all of this because I mentioned that the
because I mentioned that the normalization constant for this you know
normalization constant for this you know market on the princes is there today
market on the princes is there today so in general to compute a normalization
so in general to compute a normalization term living from the Ising model is
term living from the Ising model is np-hard
np-hard ok and actually
ok and actually you know I was looking at it this
you know I was looking at it this morning you can look at if you pay a
morning you can look at if you pay a distance I am yes
distance I am yes you know 10 15 years ago that basically
you know 10 15 years ago that basically gives Apple and how difficult is the
gives Apple and how difficult is the computer normalization in a simple
computer normalization in a simple two-dimensional Ising model okay so now
two-dimensional Ising model okay so now I see one that is five by five you can
I see one that is five by five you can do it by hand 10 by 10 you can do it by
do it by hand 10 by 10 you can do it by can try to do it in a million by Amelia
can try to do it in a million by Amelia but okay that's a very difficult
but okay that's a very difficult complicated things there is a relation
complicated things there is a relation between the Ising model and the asian
between the Ising model and the asian graphical models we actually if you may
graphical models we actually if you may be for that but somehow some of the
be for that but somehow some of the examples we we use this ideas so if I'd
examples we we use this ideas so if I'd taken the Ising model paralyzed
taken the Ising model paralyzed potentials alright so I can write this
potentials alright so I can write this as this alright so the line of my
as this alright so the line of my distribution is minus the summation of
distribution is minus the summation of this terms remember because we had the
this terms remember because we had the original - lab menu I still have the
original - lab menu I still have the same thing because this Y value must
same thing because this Y value must replace minus 1 okay all right so
replace minus 1 okay all right so basically this is like selling one of
basically this is like selling one of the energies on this time somewhere over
the energies on this time somewhere over the pair's and if you want to write this
the pair's and if you want to write this in a matrix form
in a matrix form alright you will put on a half so when
alright you will put on a half so when because this is another directed graph
because this is another directed graph you don't account the interactions that
you don't account the interactions that say from outside and say twice okay so
say from outside and say twice okay so so maybe you can see that this looks
so maybe you can see that this looks like a Gaussian Marco I mean those in
like a Gaussian Marco I mean those in graphical model alright
graphical model alright but obviously you will need something to
but obviously you will need something to mimic the minterm and the way you do
mimic the minterm and the way you do this is by introducing an external field
this is by introducing an external field in the energy function that looks like
in the energy function that looks like this okay
this okay you can think physically if you in this
you can think physically if you in this magnet model right you want to control
magnet model right you want to control the obvious magnetization of the system
the obvious magnetization of the system okay if this is a composition of a
okay if this is a composition of a material system and al-ahli
material system and al-ahli you can control maybe the average
you can control maybe the average composition you know
composition you know this can be related to an external
this can be related to an external magnetic field or something like that so
magnetic field or something like that so in the context of what we do is we
in the context of what we do is we basically enhance the energy with this
basically enhance the energy with this term beta transpose Y and immediately
term beta transpose Y and immediately you can save to plug things together and
you can save to plug things together and you complete the square
you complete the square you basically you can tell us this you
you basically you can tell us this you know it's in mobile as a graphical
know it's in mobile as a graphical browser graphical model
browser graphical model all right the relation between variables
all right the relation between variables is basically direct so the precision for
is basically direct so the precision for the Gaussian model is basically the
the Gaussian model is basically the strength of these links that you know in
a Gaussian position actually is very easy because the nomination for Gaussian
easy because the nomination for Gaussian is is the determinant of 2 Pi Sigma then
is is the determinant of 2 Pi Sigma then you can do this in the dimensions with a
you can do this in the dimensions with a cost that goes to they came when I'm
cost that goes to they came when I'm constantly in immersive mode the right
constantly in immersive mode the right if you have de the pixels and insulin
if you have de the pixels and insulin can be as minus 1 we will have to sound
can be as minus 1 we will have to sound to find an organization over to the
to find an organization over to the power
you know one of those - okay and this is where I mentioned that this is np-hard
where I mentioned that this is np-hard okay so those initial to normalize the
okay so those initial to normalize the Ising model not very easy to normalize
Ising model not very easy to normalize very much
very much and of course in many ways you will
and of course in many ways you will think of the Ising model being trivial
think of the Ising model being trivial but the Gaussian is much more rich model
but the Gaussian is much more rich model but we can see there is a complexity
but we can see there is a complexity there in a signal you can generalize
there in a signal you can generalize actually if you have a fully connected
actually if you have a fully connected Ising model all right so all the entries
Ising model all right so all the entries in the W no despair potentials but you
in the W no despair potentials but you have all the answers W you get with the
have all the answers W you get with the squirrel have to network and I think
squirrel have to network and I think this was one of the many applications of
this was one of the many applications of probabilistic graphical models back in
probabilistic graphical models back in the seventies or eighties all right and
the seventies or eighties all right and the I'm gonna give you only an example
the I'm gonna give you only an example of web business so in this little
of web business so in this little networks basically with this you provide
networks basically with this you provide the rest of time in images all right and
the rest of time in images all right and system system was missing and I said
system system was missing and I said what is his name you know who is that
what is his name you know who is that person right because my bank cannot take
person right because my bank cannot take all the pixels and process them so the
all the pixels and process them so the idea here is to give this training
idea here is to give this training images with lots of black pixels missing
images with lots of black pixels missing all right and then this social network
all right and then this social network is trying to figure out to what it
is trying to figure out to what it corresponds and you can see this of the
corresponds and you can see this of the recovery images in some interactive
recovery images in some interactive kostik optimization so per version of
kostik optimization so per version of this algorithms and we will revisit we
this algorithms and we will revisit we will visit in today or on Thursday this
will visit in today or on Thursday this algorithm okay so
so this is sort of the imputation problem in in this imaging and that's
problem in in this imaging and that's why it's called associative memory is
why it's called associative memory is like you know you have memorize things
like you know you have memorize things but you know you want to be able to make
but you know you want to be able to make decisions using incomplete version of
decisions using incomplete version of this images and figure out what they are
this images and figure out what they are okay this actually give you a lot of
okay this actually give you a lot of details of this because we will do
details of this because we will do gradient methods to address these
gradient methods to address these problems the method that in I indicated
problems the method that in I indicated here their information specifically
this is plus one then has to be plus one something like that so in some sense
something like that so in some sense this is what this does
this is what this does okay so there is an analytical solution
okay so there is an analytical solution to that problem of course this have to
to that problem of course this have to be weighted with the strength of the
be weighted with the strength of the interactions of the pixel s with the
interactions of the pixel s with the other pixel thing okay there is a
other pixel thing okay there is a mathematical solution as I said but that
mathematical solution as I said but that we will discuss with the gradient
we will discuss with the gradient methods this also goes you know it's
methods this also goes you know it's very much related to what's called we
very much related to what's called we can you
can you it works as mama sins are basically
it works as mama sins are basically extensions of this hostile models where
extensions of this hostile models where you simply introduce him and animals in
you simply introduce him and animals in addition to what we saw up to now okay
addition to what we saw up to now okay so I'm going to say much more and
so I'm going to say much more and alright so and limit pennies on this
another name that is very popular in in six and it's that's Bobby Luanne a it's
six and it's that's Bobby Luanne a it's like the Ising model but here you are
like the Ising model but here you are looking for multiple discrete states
looking for multiple discrete states so I increased three discrete states and
so I increased three discrete states and the same strength of the bonds basically
the same strength of the bonds basically say the table form of these potentials
say the table form of these potentials looks like this okay I can turn back if
looks like this okay I can turn back if you ask me I can recognize different
you ask me I can recognize different problems that I came across using the
problems that I came across using the first model when I was a graduate
first model when I was a graduate student so this is a very important
student so this is a very important model in multiple areas okay so I'm
model in multiple areas okay so I'm certain if you sell some good parts
certain if you sell some good parts model you will come with a million
model you will come with a million basically hits okay because there's a
basically hits okay because there's a lots of crazy ones so to me Sam
so an application of the hosting of the Pat's model basically and I think you
Pat's model basically and I think you guys worked on a homework on this kind
guys worked on a homework on this kind of beyond the shakiest strength all
of beyond the shakiest strength all right and trying to find this very
right and trying to find this very mountain estimate or the lowest energy
mountain estimate or the lowest energy of the system and you notice when J is
of the system and you notice when J is very big if you get clusters but they're
very big if you get clusters but they're spin up when J is very low you have very
spin up when J is very low you have very small clusters actually if you want to
small clusters actually if you want to you know
you know now remember one of the main application
now remember one of the main application supports models if you want to get
supports models if you want to get samples of crystal micro structures this
samples of crystal micro structures this is how you do it
is how you do it alright so those things can basically in
alright so those things can basically in nice particles but you can figure out
nice particles but you can figure out how you say here's one claim there's
how you say here's one claim there's another grain and another grain stuff
another grain and another grain stuff this is something that can mimic a
this is something that can mimic a nucleation processing and will give you
nucleation processing and will give you if you're going to get it again if we
if you're going to get it again if we give you definitions of a pretty crystal
give you definitions of a pretty crystal microstructure okay some point between
microstructure okay some point between for jelly you have a phase transition
for jelly you have a phase transition right and this is a very important area
right and this is a very important area of research trying to compute actually
of research trying to compute actually when the phase transition takes place
when the phase transition takes place not an easy problem maybe some colors
not an easy problem maybe some colors because this supports more the lights
because this supports more the lights were there they density of the color
were there they density of the color stays what state you are so you don't
stays what state you are so you don't just black and white but different
just black and white but different colors I think if you click this little
colors I think if you click this little library from Kevin left this to looks
library from Kevin left this to looks you will see what's the corresponding K
you will see what's the corresponding K for this discussing some sort of
for this discussing some sort of complexity of this model so here the
complexity of this model so here the actual pixel values is this actually
actual pixel values is this actually what I have in here
what I have in here all right this particles okay and they
all right this particles okay and they are defined about a grid so a mid way to
are defined about a grid so a mid way to more than just Y variables is an
more than just Y variables is an underactive module okay but I should
underactive module okay but I should observe variations of this nodes and a
observe variations of this nodes and a very good way to describe the
very good way to describe the subservience is to redirect it model so
subservience is to redirect it model so really what you have is you have a
really what you have is you have a mixture and on the Left model to
mixture and on the Left model to describe basically the correlations on a
describe basically the correlations on a grid of the Y variables and then to
grid of the Y variables and then to describe the observations you have a
describe the observations you have a direct okay
direct okay so if you plan to hide the giant
so if you plan to hide the giant revisionist admission basically and
revisionist admission basically and already have seen this you're going to
already have seen this you're going to capture these dependencies between the
capture these dependencies between the variables by factorizing this piston
variables by factorizing this piston vesicle distribution of Y as a market
vesicle distribution of Y as a market I'll go through it
I'll go through it okay this had potential trouble exits
okay this had potential trouble exits and then of course we are going to hear
and then of course we are going to hear these observations but I've defined
these observations but I've defined through a directive okay so very much to
through a directive okay so very much to emphasize that this is sort of an
emphasize that this is sort of an interesting new type of a graph because
interesting new type of a graph because obviously you're not going to capture
obviously you're not going to capture the correlations in Y with a directed
the correlations in Y with a directed graph because it makes no sense in the
graph because it makes no sense in the limits right so you're going to capture
limits right so you're going to capture them with an undirected graph but this
them with an undirected graph but this really you know it is directed model as
really you know it is directed model as you see here Y is the parent of white is
you see here Y is the parent of white is the parent of X so this is the
the parent of X so this is the probability of observing XP assuming
probability of observing XP assuming that the true state of the picture
that the true state of the picture escaped if you actually want to avoid
escaped if you actually want to avoid complex this you know what you can do is
complex this you know what you can do is you can take this down here and lamp it
you can take this down here and lamp it is try this connect potentials and then
is try this connect potentials and then actually work with an undirected graph
actually work with an undirected graph and never bother with and remember we
and never bother with and remember we were doing this when we have this
were doing this when we have this evidence potentials we will lumping them
evidence potentials we will lumping them on these terms all right so we can
on these terms all right so we can watching this to think and so you avoid
watching this to think and so you avoid having to say that you have an
having to say that you have an undirected graph and then you know a
undirected graph and then you know a direct proportion of
all right so this graph actually in the literature when you have left a mixture
literature when you have left a mixture of on the left and the left is called
of on the left and the left is called the Chandra I think somewhere I may have
the Chandra I think somewhere I may have mentioned this in passing in in an
mentioned this in passing in in an earlier lecture
earlier lecture demand is really the hidden Markov model
demand is really the hidden Markov model okay and it's such a problem as you
okay and it's such a problem as you observed markup on the field okay
observed markup on the field okay it's faster you observe because you
it's faster you observe because you don't know the rise but you know the
don't know the rise but you know the extras all right so an influence is is a
extras all right so an influence is is a difficult problem so we need to discuss
difficult problem so we need to discuss on how to do this okay
on how to do this okay this mention this right and maybe
this mention this right and maybe there's an example of two in the slides
there's an example of two in the slides we take this model and your objective is
we take this model and your objective is the use of the integration constant so
the use of the integration constant so you know you give an X and you try to
you know you give an X and you try to compute Y so this first layer it's in
compute Y so this first layer it's in that soil is basically this all right
that soil is basically this all right this is a markup random field it's very
this is a markup random field it's very popular on supervised problem is in an
popular on supervised problem is in an unsupervised context this can work
unsupervised context this can work completely because for example you can
completely because for example you can think this emphasis must nurses you pass
think this emphasis must nurses you pass from one picture to another but there
from one picture to another but there are 15 images you can have discontinuity
are 15 images you can have discontinuity somewhere from black to delight 70 right
somewhere from black to delight 70 right so in an unsupervised problem this file
so in an unsupervised problem this file will not work
will not work all right so it's okay to use it here or
all right so it's okay to use it here or the supervised problem but it doesn't
the supervised problem but it doesn't work for supervised problems
these so let me just finish on this with discussing about this Gaussian mark of
discussing about this Gaussian mark of didn't specifically written intentional
didn't specifically written intentional from precision metrics is known for
from precision metrics is known for volumes Memphis's so again I have paper
volumes Memphis's so again I have paper pencils here and the sentence
pencils here and the sentence pretentious if you like and you can
pretentious if you like and you can parameterize them like this or like that
parameterize them like this or like that so immediately you can see if you
so immediately you can see if you privatization is given like this you
privatization is given like this you will get a decision basically but this
will get a decision basically but this Gaussian is going to be on an
Gaussian is going to be on an information form because it's with in
information form because it's with in terms of Precision's and this why I
terms of Precision's and this why I delete all of them to mean all right and
this models were written in terms of precision matrices and particularly
precision matrices and particularly because this precision met reserves past
because this precision met reserves past we have sparse precision matrices versus
we have sparse precision matrices versus spots the various matrices can remember
spots the various matrices can remember way that we used in this course a
way that we used in this course a Gaussian representation of a random
Gaussian representation of a random field when we had is passed to the
field when we had is passed to the audience methods and we did some where
audience methods and we did some where it should ask you the composition and I
it should ask you the composition and I believe he did to see a formal like
believe he did to see a formal like maybe homework one or two
we went to some kind of you should to give you a homework corner on the
give you a homework corner on the Gaussian random field it seems I know
Gaussian random field it seems I know for sure right but what's happening is
for sure right but what's happening is metrics not the precision metrics and
metrics not the precision metrics and especially trans metrics is not the same
especially trans metrics is not the same as the space precision metrics okay
as the space precision metrics okay right so this this measurement around
right so this this measurement around the fields need to Espace precision
the fields need to Espace precision metrics okay the numbers we worked every
metrics okay the numbers we worked every into the course they were leading to
into the course they were leading to sparse covariance matrix again you may
sparse covariance matrix again you may want to look on on on the notes so
want to look on on on the notes so obviously you don't even know the
obviously you don't even know the specialty of this lambda so here we use
specialty of this lambda so here we use pairwise for pencils
pairwise for pencils so in essence in essence here if this
so in essence in essence here if this term is data or not it implements if
term is data or not it implements if there is link between two notes or not
there is link between two notes or not so in essence learning the values of
so in essence learning the values of lambda is the same problem as learning a
lambda is the same problem as learning a structure of the graphical model okay so
structure of the graphical model okay so you can pass this as an optimization
you can pass this as an optimization problem for you learn the structure of
problem for you learn the structure of the problem on the clock right
so I'm going to give you an extension we discussed on this you know you know
discussed on this you know you know Pat's model where the microphone that
Pat's model where the microphone that feels for y all right and and and then
feels for y all right and and and then we had an observation longer but can do
we had an observation longer but can do anything basically can be a Gaussian or
anything basically can be a Gaussian or something like that so I mean I'm going
something like that so I mean I'm going to give you a picture and I want you to
to give you a picture and I want you to look at this picture and they'll be so
look at this picture and they'll be so this is all right and things are
this is all right and things are basically
basically latane spaced so I want you to tell me
latane spaced so I want you to tell me what exactly you see when it comes to
what exactly you see when it comes to the context of the links on this on the
the context of the links on this on the same as the change in time
same as the change in time okay so look let's say at a given time
okay so look let's say at a given time is the past
so we are looking here it depends on who - view but also depends on 2-3 right
looks like this alright the permeability of YT specifically given YT minus 1 YT
of YT specifically given YT minus 1 YT minus 2 and so this mattress is that you
minus 2 and so this mattress is that you see here define the sparsity of the
see here define the sparsity of the connections in time okay now now if you
connections in time okay now now if you notice I shall and again this is so
notice I shall and again this is so forth in one day but you can clean of
forth in one day but you can clean of this body was being on a good the
this body was being on a good the dependence at the given time between the
dependence at the given time between the Y variables what do you think how do you
Y variables what do you think how do you think they're being done if this was and
think they're being done if this was and if the name of the training video right
if the name of the training video right and this were instances of the videos of
and this were instances of the videos of different times so the pixels are the
different times so the pixels are the given time the coordinator obviously in
given time the coordinator obviously in time you can see all right how's it
time you can see all right how's it going to protonate the pixels to the
going to protonate the pixels to the given time okay the sparsity the
given time okay the sparsity the evolution of wash in time
evolution of wash in time okay this Sigma is it depend how you do
okay this Sigma is it depend how you do this around okay
this around okay they're going to define the oscillations
they're going to define the oscillations at the given time inspect okay
at the given time inspect okay so velocity in the dynamics but very
so velocity in the dynamics but very sparsely basically in capturing the
sparsely basically in capturing the correlations in
correlations in for a given time alright so there is
for a given time alright so there is this dynamic probabilistic graphical
this dynamic probabilistic graphical models actions very how the area of
models actions very how the area of research and the disorganization book if
research and the disorganization book if anyone is interested to look it's a you
anyone is interested to look it's a you know it's in Palace but I have a
know it's in Palace but I have a complicated you know for review so if
complicated you know for review so if anybody's interested you can let me know
anybody's interested you can let me know to make seven hundred pages of very new
to make seven hundred pages of very new algorithms for doing this type of
algorithms for doing this type of problems but don't need this okay and
problems but don't need this okay and I'd have to go now to slide 65 so we can
I'd have to go now to slide 65 so we can do maybe some of the training all right
do maybe some of the training all right all right
so let's go back to this at least we can start to discuss you this so we write
start to discuss you this so we write this probability of y given theta if you
this probability of y given theta if you remember in village potentials is it to
remember in village potentials is it to the paper burns for some future
the paper burns for some future functions to the point of where the
functions to the point of where the clickstream so the type of distillations
clickstream so the type of distillations with maximum likelihood estimation and I
with maximum likelihood estimation and I think once you know how to Emily to do
think once you know how to Emily to do basically a map estimation is nothing
basically a map estimation is nothing but to put the power out there and do
but to put the power out there and do the same sort of calculation okay so n
the same sort of calculation okay so n data points so this not my observations
data points so this not my observations weii okay and i'm i put this powerful
weii okay and i'm i put this powerful man over in there because it's going to
man over in there because it's going to simplify the calculations i want to do
looks like to show this against alright so we're gonna take the folks you're
so we're gonna take the folks you're gonna give a list notation function here
gonna give a list notation function here all right and then the exponential will
all right and then the exponential will disappear if you can get the summation
disappear if you can get the summation of this and then summation over all the
of this and then summation over all the data point right the formulas equation
data point right the formulas equation the way it is a very general it appears
the way it is a very general it appears in intimate settings in in machine
in intimate settings in in machine learning but here the difficult thing is
learning but here the difficult thing is you have there's no parameters and you
you have there's no parameters and you can envision language for your various
can envision language for your various parameters locally but unfortunately
parameters locally but unfortunately this time it's basically messes you are
this time it's basically messes you are because it released all of the
because it released all of the parameters since this time to complete
parameters since this time to complete this partition functions a
this partition functions a you have to serve as we would say an
you have to serve as we would say an infinite problem you have to compute we
infinite problem you have to compute we have to link basically everything
have to link basically everything together okay so this is not good
together okay so this is not good all right so we need to find some way to
all right so we need to find some way to handle this problem okay so let's see
handle this problem okay so let's see what is going to lead into this
what is going to lead into this distribution form it looks like an
distribution form it looks like an exponential function type of
exponential function type of distribution so if we haven't proved it
distribution so if we haven't proved it on this semester it's in the notes from
on this semester it's in the notes from the Christmas semester so you can look
the Christmas semester so you can look at it basically the likelihood is a
at it basically the likelihood is a convex function of the parameters so it
convex function of the parameters so it has a unique maximum so that's good news
has a unique maximum so that's good news so this is a solution if we want to do
so this is a solution if we want to do an MLA I mean this is of concern
an MLA I mean this is of concern obviously because if you have some
obviously because if you have some partition functions yes what happens
partition functions yes what happens right there's no I don't think that it
right there's no I don't think that it will give you a convex function but
will give you a convex function but because of this exponential poly
because of this exponential poly distributions you get a convex function
on the parameters the potentional click on click see so let's again when you
on click see so let's again when you take those who aspire to stay the same
you get the person functions plain to see see right I think's wrong I okay
see see right I think's wrong I okay alright so this is what you get and then
alright so this is what you get and then from the second term human hand
from the second term human hand basically 2/3 relevance with respect to
basically 2/3 relevance with respect to fit the story of the of Z okay right so
fit the story of the of Z okay right so if you can exercise you can function
if you can exercise you can function with respect to the promise of click see
with respect to the promise of click see it is nothing else but the expectation
it is nothing else but the expectation of the person function space see with
of the person function space see with respect to the underlying probability of
respect to the underlying probability of P of Y this is no approximation or
P of Y this is no approximation or anything you know if you think you know
anything you know if you think you know the distribution being the path of this
the distribution being the path of this potential to have nerves so you get
potential to have nerves so you get summation which of the stems and all of
summation which of the stems and all of these things will actually give you the
these things will actually give you the parameters theta C so fact in the end of
parameters theta C so fact in the end of the day it is the expectation of the
the day it is the expectation of the future function P see remember is this
future function P see remember is this function PC that's affiliated with it as
function PC that's affiliated with it as T all right so you need expectation with
T all right so you need expectation with respect to the underlying distribution
respect to the underlying distribution show you know the scale there's no
show you know the scale there's no evidence right dispose why i given theta
evidence right dispose why i given theta and it's a beautiful calculation right
and it's a beautiful calculation right you have to you have to find this
you have to you have to find this expectation and to make it worse you
expectation and to make it worse you have to find this expectation it's step
have to find this expectation it's step in the gradient descent on good so it's
in the gradient descent on good so it's not like they're gonna be advanced and
not like they're gonna be advanced and you have done because this involves the
you have done because this involves the parameters theta and that's what we're
parameters theta and that's what we're interested concrete so you're going to
interested concrete so you're going to have to do iterations for that okay so
have to do iterations for that okay so let's see something extremely
let's see something extremely interesting that comes out of this okay
interesting that comes out of this okay so if you passed me that this is the
so if you passed me that this is the expectation of the treacherous functions
expectation of the treacherous functions we see with a step to the flow
we see with a step to the flow distribution P of Y right surviving this
distribution P of Y right surviving this anotation of expectation and the first
anotation of expectation and the first term all right okay hopefully I don't
term all right okay hopefully I don't think I have missed it one of rank you
think I have missed it one of rank you so I don't know if they won over them
so I don't know if they won over them disappeared there okay and this is
disappeared there okay and this is outside the parentheses or you guys
outside the parentheses or you guys second for me so this is one over N
second for me so this is one over N times the summation of the future
times the summation of the future functions PC compute the fixed rate the
functions PC compute the fixed rate the for y I so this is what you get from the
for y I so this is what you get from the first step so look at this and tell me
first step so look at this and tell me in a more compact notation what is that
so many of the end times so you have a data set endpoints and you
so you have a data set endpoints and you compute this crucial function C of all
compute this crucial function C of all the data ports so what is that it is an
the data ports so what is that it is an expectation of this chain right with
expectation of this chain right with respect investment web distribution
nope
our samples they'll kill her from this distribution
they'll kill her from this distribution so when I ran the samples the
so when I ran the samples the approximation of distribution having a
approximation of distribution having a corner distribution with other functions
corner distribution with other functions it's not the camera type thing
you know expectation with respect to the empirical distribution okay so basically
empirical distribution okay so basically the dissonant with respect to the
the dissonant with respect to the parameters to the say is the expectation
parameters to the say is the expectation of this XI with respect to the empirical
of this XI with respect to the empirical distribution - the expectation of
distribution - the expectation of receiver respect to the exact
receiver respect to the exact distribution so basically if you set
distribution so basically if you set this you say in this case you set this
this you say in this case you set this equal to zero and basically we have a
equal to zero and basically we have a problem that we were discussing in the
problem that we were discussing in the last three or four lectures and that
last three or four lectures and that problem is not it's made no marching you
problem is not it's made no marching you see that so expectations of each
see that so expectations of each respective functions for each case needs
respective functions for each case needs too much
too much that was funny expectations under the
that was funny expectations under the empirical distribution some please away
empirical distribution some please away to implement actually rest okay so
to implement actually rest okay so actively you have to set this equal to
actively you have to set this equal to this moment
this moment defined for the under the empirical
defined for the under the empirical distribution okay
you can say that we call the maze that actually we so it's not going to find
actually we so it's not going to find the pinnacle distribution of okay okay
the pinnacle distribution of okay okay you will need to integrate gates Bibles
looks very similar conceptually and automatically like computing the
automatically like computing the partition function will be integrated in
partition function will be integrated in Y so effectively this terms that you get
Y so effectively this terms that you get the look like partition functions
the look like partition functions completed not arbitrary where they are
completed not arbitrary where they are integrating over Y takes an integrating
integrating over Y takes an integrating knowledge but they are still partition
knowledge but they are still partition functions and I'm going to give you the
functions and I'm going to give you the answer and then we'll come back to it at
answer and then we'll come back to it at the end of the day so the answer comes
basically that the building of the state of the parameters theta C is there is a
of the parameters theta C is there is a summation in the hidden value
summation in the hidden value integrate those out and basically is the
integrate those out and basically is the difference of two expectations one of
difference of two expectations one of them is the distribution of expectation
them is the distribution of expectation a beta distribution of Y and the other
a beta distribution of Y and the other one is actually the actual moment so
one is actually the actual moment so this moment marching here with its
this moment marching here with its integrated out okay in one of the
integrated out okay in one of the moments Y is basically integrated out in
moments Y is basically integrated out in the other a moment Y is fixed
the other a moment Y is fixed okay Y space and this has a magical
okay Y space and this has a magical total firm implementations based on
total firm implementations based on expectation maximization actually what
expectation maximization actually what is great with the name generalized
is great with the name generalized expectation maximization so we don't
expectation maximization so we don't have to waste some on Thursday and then
have to waste some on Thursday and then we will give the stability and
we will give the stability and dissentient of approximation for this
dissentient of approximation for this type of problems