Pancho's comfort sciences engineering and that's our project is the father of
and that's our project is the father of I scale it allows realization
what with this content and Babylon
our oxygens are collocated physically
and they were happy
it's mostly we go to the sender and Senate in 2014
we go to the sender and Senate in 2014 and we go stock unit director for my
and we go stock unit director for my because many different still salvation
because many different still salvation so only one feel alive today and so
so only one feel alive today and so there is no countries or implementation
there is no countries or implementation in 2014 but a remarkable achievements
in 2014 but a remarkable achievements can be provided in international
can be provided in international measures where there are enormous
measures where there are enormous efforts both from industry and
efforts both from industry and they invested to this field so a lot of
they invested to this field so a lot of learnings and else you're gonna answer
learnings and else you're gonna answer on experience
on experience oh really
oh really so my whole thing to follow him he'll
so my whole thing to follow him he'll understand
with
[Music]
they also procedure
the resident incentive
adventures it's actually been trying to make some
it's actually been trying to make some sort of internship
just emoticon sentences can be described in this block and these pauses between
in this block and these pauses between world
[Music]
and
the son of two halibut you only knew they wanted to
Oh
there's a high single formula up here
[Music]
lost function
and finally
[Music]
and
there are some occasions
[Music]
in today's top five we were too complicated model simple very hot and we
complicated model simple very hot and we can
[Music]
the intuitive is equal to is still simple
too much
no or
and using the form of my
[Music]
one apparently
and
[Music] they'll want to ignore
they'll want to ignore oh please for geography
oh please for geography Oh
electric never wear em because they like to come by
if you'll edit my size
in fact a buffalo in film Fantasia extra
so with all those
and four different color
but if there's no only feel like a people like Bill told the dream home
people like Bill told the dream home life's real castle
his life can be beautiful maybe for other guests
it's been exciting to interact with other common sense
everything
are you all common
because when the bill was right there
and eat natural color of waffle work all over the stage that
over the stage that [Music]
[Music] unlike most all of it
unlike most all of it [Music]
[Music] Oh
with ocean alignment
hi
Oh
in my face this is a crazy scientist or teacher telling without question so much
teacher telling without question so much all those tickets are a year of conquer
all those tickets are a year of conquer Europe this fortune different features
Europe this fortune different features and opportunity of all penalties amazing
and opportunity of all penalties amazing creatures
creatures all the clothing falling in touch with
all the clothing falling in touch with both Amy and
and those kids are along on 25,000 college of dentistry there
college of dentistry there that's slightly on faceted and the very
that's slightly on faceted and the very people that are provided by this box
people that are provided by this box it's also a binary package equivalent
it's also a binary package equivalent test only like Oh 100 samples and the
test only like Oh 100 samples and the relative truth of 1810 was 14
and the yeah stance against it and the incidental constants of 619
and the incidental constants of 619 position we completed the first one you
position we completed the first one you have my sin
Oh
over people
without fulfilling to image size and
we kept our accessories with the iterator and
iterator and it's the most function value and this is
it's the most function value and this is only one religion and
and
so the accumulation and spinning and
with all the gold
[Music]
here
and this Apple
[Music]
we have fun disabilities that's disgusting
for example
[Music]
we love
the opinion of my knowledge through your basic thinking
yeah
didn't see
we can see the times of my children go through
1:44 Oh
Oh to
and if you like a little like you're investigating their family huh because
investigating their family huh because every
and yeah feels like
[Music]
listen to these more elaboration
think about choice agent standard within the assignment over the freaking place
exactly we learn more [Music]
the solution is smaller and
is the exact problem
[Music] a lot of artists
beautiful or
Oh
almost
[Applause]
Oh agency yeah I suppose me feel fancy because you're ever
because you're ever the beginning stage of commotion on a
the beginning stage of commotion on a real I resisted by the leaders for
real I resisted by the leaders for passive occasions like some conflicts
passive occasions like some conflicts attracted each other today my image mesh
attracted each other today my image mesh also attracted by
in my example to classify a trip there are typically a lot of South America
are typically a lot of South America have different features of action and
have different features of action and the tendencies to talk about whether
the tendencies to talk about whether this is good or not
all right hello everyone says I'm Nick Geneva and I want to presenting on
Geneva and I want to presenting on comprising graphical models with my
comprising graphical models with my original title was neural networks but
original title was neural networks but we're going to generalize it to machine
we're going to generalize it to machine learning for structural representation
all right so originally this I guess this presentation is kind of a story of
this presentation is kind of a story of how I was originally going to focus on
how I was originally going to focus on this paper up here this 2016 there's
this paper up here this 2016 there's paper then basically got lost in one of
paper then basically got lost in one of the references which actually ended up
the references which actually ended up proposing that did I found kind of
proposing that did I found kind of interesting and hard to understand
interesting and hard to understand because it motivated a lot of what kind
because it motivated a lot of what kind of ideas that are happening up in this
of ideas that are happening up in this one so yeah all right starting off when
one so yeah all right starting off when we're building a model where the model
we're building a model where the model to represent data a model to generate
to represent data a model to generate day of whatever you want generally you
day of whatever you want generally you may have two different goals you may
may have two different goals you may want to have a flexible approach so
want to have a flexible approach so let's say you have some non parametric
let's say you have some non parametric representation of some complex high
representation of some complex high dimensional data or you may want to
dimensional data or you may want to structure our approach and this may be
structure our approach and this may be to find a structure representation of
to find a structure representation of data that can then be generalized
data that can then be generalized perhaps so in terms of platform model
perhaps so in terms of platform model that's when I say flexible models I mean
that's when I say flexible models I mean like I said I'm talking about these
like I said I'm talking about these black box methods so machine learning
black box methods so machine learning you're looking for buzzword like neural
you're looking for buzzword like neural networks convolutional Network
networks convolutional Network autoencoders Gans support vector
autoencoders Gans support vector machines aa website structure model
machines aa website structure model course PGM class so it's all about
course PGM class so it's all about probabilistic graphical models stuff
probabilistic graphical models stuff where we actually have values that means
where we actually have values that means something rather than just random
something rather than just random weights and stuff that they're just kind
weights and stuff that they're just kind matching up a function so the question
matching up a function so the question is what do we want what happens if we
is what do we want what happens if we want both A's flexible yet also
want both A's flexible yet also structured approach so this means
structured approach so this means essentially like if I want like let's
essentially like if I want like let's say like I have some high dimensional
say like I have some high dimensional data that I need to map or something
data that I need to map or something with some flexible method but I also
with some flexible method but I also want some sort of values I can then
want some sort of values I can then relate to maybe physical dynamics
relate to maybe physical dynamics there's something about the actual prom
there's something about the actual prom because of that price so just the
because of that price so just the problem to kind of motivate this as an
problem to kind of motivate this as an example so let's suppose that we have
example so let's suppose that we have this mountain that's inside of this
this mountain that's inside of this spherical container moving around and
spherical container moving around and our input data is going to be some
our input data is going to be some height so basically our input is this
height so basically our input is this image and from that when our output
image and from that when our output debase be the interest in trouble
debase be the interest in trouble structure of essentially the mouse's
structure of essentially the mouse's actual behavior so these may be the
actual behavior so these may be the current of dance edits in or movement no
current of dance edits in or movement no I'm not so as they clearly have this
I'm not so as they clearly have this high dimensional image coming in so we
high dimensional image coming in so we kind of want a flexible model to learn
kind of want a flexible model to learn that but then our output we want to have
that but then our output we want to have some sort of probabilistic inference on
some sort of probabilistic inference on what's probably of the mouse's actions
what's probably of the mouse's actions sitting up on its hind legs or if it's
sitting up on its hind legs or if it's scratching its ear and stuff like that
scratching its ear and stuff like that those are very structured output on so
those are very structured output on so basically one kind of a combination and
basically one kind of a combination and that's kind of a whole main idea of this
that's kind of a whole main idea of this paper and kind of cold I think growing
paper and kind of cold I think growing field is essentially can we combine
field is essentially can we combine these to build stronger modeling tools
these to build stronger modeling tools that can really get the best of both
that can really get the best of both worlds is essentially it so for this we
worlds is essentially it so for this we won't be looking at might we be looking
won't be looking at might we be looking at something a little bit more dull
at something a little bit more dull which is a natural clustering frog so
which is a natural clustering frog so these are just an example it's a really
these are just an example it's a really great toy problem on one we'll be
great toy problem on one we'll be looking at is spiral problems maybe in a
looking at is spiral problems maybe in a spiral and the reason for that is one
spiral and the reason for that is one it's great they're both within two
it's great they're both within two also it's these clusters are very
also it's these clusters are very discrete clusters that we want to you
discrete clusters that we want to you know categorize though each one of these
know categorize though each one of these you want to just find is a different
you want to just find is a different class however they are still there
class however they are still there non-college so there and this is
non-college so there and this is unsupervised learning problem so they
unsupervised learning problem so they sleep you don't have any labels so
sleep you don't have any labels so before we get into the actual paper room
before we get into the actual paper room visit our old friend Gaussian mixture
visit our old friend Gaussian mixture models to go over so this is the
models to go over so this is the non-bayesian formulation I find this and
non-bayesian formulation I find this and Bishop just to review if you're like me
Bishop just to review if you're like me and have a memory of a goldfish we tend
and have a memory of a goldfish we tend to forget this stuff however the idea of
to forget this stuff however the idea of Ecology mixture model is that we have a
Ecology mixture model is that we have a latent variable Z which is binary
latent variable Z which is binary variable which represents which class of
variable which represents which class of which cause mixture we're pulling from
which cause mixture we're pulling from and we have for each causing make sure
and we have for each causing make sure we have respective mean and it also
we have respective mean and it also precision we can increase complexity a
precision we can increase complexity a little bit and make it kind of more
little bit and make it kind of more Bayesian correlation by introducing some
Bayesian correlation by introducing some priors onto our precision and all
priors onto our precision and all certainty which is T nope here these are
certainty which is T nope here these are our high performers that we're
our high performers that we're introducing so this is just some
introducing so this is just some reminders again if you want to know more
reminders again if you want to know more much rating so just refresh your memory
much rating so just refresh your memory so again our joint distribution it's
so again our joint distribution it's going to be a the multiplication of
going to be a the multiplication of essentially like including our priors or
essentially like including our priors or not the likelihood takes the form of
not the likelihood takes the form of course our cause in C is binary
yeah just mixing coefficients we're just gonna go kind of fast through this - I
gonna go kind of fast through this - I have greens on afterwards
have greens on afterwards yet only used a anything here alright so
yet only used a anything here alright so just to refresh your memory for actually
just to refresh your memory for actually on conducting for tuning this problem
on conducting for tuning this problem are legit
are legit in France and whatnot it's day like
in France and whatnot it's day like someone to enum algorithms with this
someone to enum algorithms with this Bayesian that they've yet to take kind
Bayesian that they've yet to take kind of a variational approach which involves
of a variational approach which involves maximizing lower bound we all know that
maximizing lower bound we all know that and it's an alternative estimate we came
and it's an alternative estimate we came Kong back and forth between essential
Kong back and forth between essential updating responsibilities computing the
updating responsibilities computing the relevant statistics related to those
relevant statistics related to those responsibilities and also updating the
responsibilities and also updating the hyper parameters space you have to jump
hyper parameters space you have to jump back and forth between these two then
back and forth between these two then converge the actual solution in
converge the actual solution in particular mission we don't know now the
particular mission we don't know now the problem with this problem of interest is
problem with this problem of interest is basically we can't actually describe
basically we can't actually describe these regions very efficiently and like
these regions very efficiently and like a hint said that before we chose us prom
a hint said that before we chose us prom specifically because these are indeed
specifically because these are indeed there they don't really fit college so
there they don't really fit college so essentially even though we're able to
essentially even though we're able to fit the data through mixture we don't
fit the data through mixture we don't really get the five discrete classes
really get the five discrete classes that we actually originally wanted so
that we actually originally wanted so let's look at something completely
let's look at something completely different now let's say all right so
different now let's say all right so this was the structured result so now
this was the structured result so now let's go to entirely flexible is all an
let's go to entirely flexible is all an idea here is that now instead of
idea here is that now instead of essentially having you know this mixture
essentially having you know this mixture guardians were going to basically be
guardians were going to basically be using a narrow network since you predict
using a narrow network since you predict to predict a mean and also a procedure
so this is now our likelihood and you see that our our actual mean and also
see that our our actual mean and also our precision is now so wait biases of
our precision is now so wait biases of the neural network now this is actually
the neural network now this is actually a function that's basically being
a function that's basically being produced here now of course the issue
produced here now of course the issue with this is obvious
with this is obvious we've lost all the sort of categorizing
we've lost all the sort of categorizing is essentially it sure we can fit this
is essentially it sure we can fit this very nicely we get very nice densities
very nicely we get very nice densities where the actual data is but in the way
where the actual data is but in the way of classifying the different actual
of classifying the different actual clusters Bravo
clusters Bravo alright so now about which papers to
alright so now about which papers to this later paper back in 2012 and I'm
this later paper back in 2012 and I'm talking about a method which is kind of
talking about a method which is kind of general approach car rat the mixture
general approach car rat the mixture models and the core idea is essentially
models and the core idea is essentially in its name so we're going to take a
in its name so we're going to take a mixture model so on the left and
mixture model so on the left and basically wrap it and some sort of
basically wrap it and some sort of function that transforms basically the
function that transforms basically the the latent variable was returned
the latent variable was returned determined for the mixture model into a
determined for the mixture model into a non Gaussian and spacing on garden
non Gaussian and spacing on garden animals essentially so the idea is that
animals essentially so the idea is that instead of using them as the direct
instead of using them as the direct output along map it through some sort of
output along map it through some sort of function do they get a much more complex
function do they get a much more complex output yet will also retain the
output yet will also retain the structured representation
so here's what we're looking at on here so basically everything most of it has
so basically everything most of it has remained the same I'll talk about this
remained the same I'll talk about this and break down more detail but only if
and break down more detail but only if now at this arbitrary function over here
now at this arbitrary function over here and for this and the paper we're gonna
and for this and the paper we're gonna be following it it's gonna be a Gaussian
be following it it's gonna be a Gaussian process so Reagan is down on the left
process so Reagan is down on the left this is actually precisely the Bayesian
this is actually precisely the Bayesian on Gaussian mixture model that we had
on Gaussian mixture model that we had before
before exactly actually except the key
exactly actually except the key difference is that now the outputs are
difference is that now the outputs are not the actual observations they're not
not the actual observations they're not a set of latent variables so these don't
a set of latent variables so these don't actually have really true meaning
actually have really true meaning they're not what we're seeing isn't it's
they're not what we're seeing isn't it's not what our actual data I also want to
not what our actual data I also want to note here that I personally I predefined
note here that I personally I predefined a set of mixture components k however
a set of mixture components k however you can indeed have a infinite set which
you can indeed have a infinite set which is what they do in the paper through a
is what they do in the paper through a Derrick wave process and give sampling
Derrick wave process and give sampling of that
now on the right side basically this is now going to be our Gaussian process
now going to be our Gaussian process here so basically it's going to be
here so basically it's going to be mapping these latent variables here to a
mapping these latent variables here to a non ecology manifold is the idea and I
non ecology manifold is the idea and I stay here that this is a Gaussian
stay here that this is a Gaussian process however on this is not actually
process however on this is not actually inclusive so you can extend this idea to
inclusive so you can extend this idea to others or a methods however you want
others or a methods however you want actually one of the map how you wanted
actually one of the map how you wanted to find this function um it's just what
to find this function um it's just what we launched we're doing this particular
we launched we're doing this particular paper um I do know here that they're
paper um I do know here that they're basically so this right here we have
basically so this right here we have inputs our latent variables on that the
inputs our latent variables on that the in mm process and this is precisely a
in mm process and this is precisely a Gaussian process lake imperative model
Gaussian process lake imperative model in fact if we ignore this closed section
in fact if we ignore this closed section out here and we just take these guys as
out here and we just take these guys as basically fixed it's precisely a gauntly
basically fixed it's precisely a gauntly so in essence you can view this as a
so in essence you can view this as a more generalized version of GPL so if
more generalized version of GPL so if you like me and you're not too well
you like me and you're not too well first on gauzy and upon latent variable
first on gauzy and upon latent variable models we're gonna go over it so the
models we're gonna go over it so the idea the the key principle is that
idea the the key principle is that instead of having circle represent your
instead of having circle represent your likelihood through a German Gaussian and
likelihood through a German Gaussian and your actual covariance matrix is going
your actual covariance matrix is going to be defined through a kernel function
to be defined through a kernel function down here now the key thing that makes
down here now the key thing that makes this innovation very models is that this
this innovation very models is that this kernel function is governed through
kernel function is governed through latent variables so these variables are
latent variables so these variables are related to your actually do get related
related to your actually do get related but there's been leading variables
but there's been leading variables basically it now of course we need to
basically it now of course we need to optimize these latent variables so we
optimize these latent variables so we needed to tune this model so you can get
needed to tune this model so you can get desired result on that is done basically
desired result on that is done basically if ingredient based operations
if ingredient based operations optimization and yeah so I just quickly
optimization and yeah so I just quickly list some gradients here you can see
list some gradients here you can see that basically we want a cost function
that basically we want a cost function or you know what I like over here like a
or you know what I like over here like a note of observation is getting laid
note of observation is getting laid variables and also the data is gonna
variables and also the data is gonna represent our parameters and the GPM and
represent our parameters and the GPM and essentially this using chain rule you
essentially this using chain rule you can see that basically this combined
can see that basically this combined with this will give you the derivative
with this will give you the derivative of the of your cost function so your
of the of your cost function so your wall of your likelihood with respect to
wall of your likelihood with respect to your actual latent variable be consumed
alright so now moving into the actual paper now so we're gonna break this down
paper now so we're gonna break this down and look into three parts of this actual
and look into three parts of this actual of this rap mixture model I want to talk
of this rap mixture model I want to talk about a generation this is a generative
about a generation this is a generative model I don't talk about the training of
model I don't talk about the training of it they don't talk about on briefly
it they don't talk about on briefly prediction so it's thermal energy ppl
prediction so it's thermal energy ppl Fiona song
Fiona song essentially this is a generative model
essentially this is a generative model so we can generate realizations from
so we can generate realizations from this PGM basic generator instead of
this PGM basic generator instead of latent variables and feed it through our
latent variables and feed it through our Gaussian process on to non Gaussian
Gaussian process on to non Gaussian manifolds idea so the idea is I surmise
manifolds idea so the idea is I surmise it's in three steps though for each
it's in three steps though for each component for volume to I remember going
component for volume to I remember going back to our PGM here so the first step
back to our PGM here so the first step is that we want to draw precision and it
is that we want to draw precision and it also mean for each component right from
also mean for each component right from our priors who's here
our priors who's here somewhere as we always define though
somewhere as we always define though there's a Wishart distribution and the
there's a Wishart distribution and the social pathology and distribution here
social pathology and distribution here we can then draw a function so this is
we can then draw a function so this is basically if you have priors over your
basically if you have priors over your actual parameters and you're calling
actual parameters and you're calling processed me I should draw those
processed me I should draw those parameters for your GP and that foreign
parameters for your GP and that foreign lady here function that's a long map
lady here function that's a long map user space and for for each desired
user space and for for each desired observation that you want you can then
observation that you want you can then draw a assignment so you just choose
draw a assignment so you just choose which class you want and from that draw
which class you want and from that draw a set of latent variables from your T
a set of latent variables from your T GM's this is from their cause in and you
GM's this is from their cause in and you seek those X's through your dogs and
seek those X's through your dogs and possible generator why
possible generator why now that's nice but we still have to
now that's nice but we still have to worry about how do we actually get this
worry about how do we actually get this model to mark how do we trade it so we
model to mark how do we trade it so we have two systems on or over further than
have two systems on or over further than two systems in this you have the PGM and
two systems in this you have the PGM and also the GP and we're going to be
also the GP and we're going to be optimizing those simultaneously and
optimizing those simultaneously and basically what you want to maximize are
basically what you want to maximize are displayed here like there's a billion
displayed here like there's a billion variables so this is different
variables so this is different originally than our GP procedure but
originally than our GP procedure but however if we expand it out we see that
however if we expand it out we see that actually his and this is a kind of core
actually his and this is a kind of core idea here is that essentially we have we
idea here is that essentially we have we break it apart yes you have a loop
break it apart yes you have a loop electrically that was from our Gaussian
electrically that was from our Gaussian process but then we have essentially
process but then we have essentially this you can consider it like a prior is
this you can consider it like a prior is basically it so we have this complex
basically it so we have this complex prior that's getting tagged on to our
prior that's getting tagged on to our loss function which is then going to
loss function which is then going to improve its performance and this is
improve its performance and this is basically this idea right here is the
basically this idea right here is the same concept that is used actually also
same concept that is used actually also in the 2000 sticking paper that I was
in the 2000 sticking paper that I was supposed to really focus on but it's the
supposed to really focus on but it's the same with the same idea essentially
same with the same idea essentially they're tacking on a more complex more
they're tacking on a more complex more descriptive prior on to their loss
descriptive prior on to their loss function
function which basically allows them to do a lot
which basically allows them to do a lot who were stuff
yes so to kind of evolve this on in this
so to kind of evolve this on in this paper they use a hybrid Monte Carlo or
paper they use a hybrid Monte Carlo or Hamiltonian Monte Carlo debate please
Hamiltonian Monte Carlo debate please sample I say kind of move because I need
sample I say kind of move because I need coming from a background in terms of
coming from a background in terms of research I think gradient but it's
research I think gradient but it's sampling so one sample a set of
sampling so one sample a set of particles from basically this posterior
particles from basically this posterior here so the idea there is essentially
here so the idea there is essentially we're going to have an additional set of
we're going to have an additional set of latent variables if you recall HMC
latent variables if you recall HMC basically we're then going to propagate
basically we're then going to propagate those using hamiltonian dynamics so to
those using hamiltonian dynamics so to do that you meet the gradient the
do that you meet the gradient the gradient here is actually so if we take
gradient here is actually so if we take the log of the rights the logs put it
the log of the rights the logs put it across then you have this sum of these
across then you have this sum of these so we call that the gradient here is
so we call that the gradient here is exactly comes from our GP so that's we
exactly comes from our GP so that's we already have these here and then the
already have these here and then the derivative of our prior is analytical
derivative of our prior is analytical because it's a PGM and we can control we
because it's a PGM and we can control we can say that
can say that nice distributions here that allows us
nice distributions here that allows us you know find this attractable
you know find this attractable actual long solution
so yeah so base B once once the particles are sampled with HMC so
particles are sampled with HMC so essentially we have a set then propagate
essentially we have a set then propagate a little bit through his set amounts to
a little bit through his set amounts to that so like 25 or whatever we then
that so like 25 or whatever we then update the PCM so basically this new set
update the PCM so basically this new set of particles within which are latent
of particles within which are latent variables act as observations for the
variables act as observations for the PGM and in a sense she then we take over
PGM and in a sense she then we take over and we do the standard mixture of
and we do the standard mixture of garbage in optimization process you know
garbage in optimization process you know the variational approach or if you're
the variational approach or if you're not so in the Bayesian and DM approach
not so in the Bayesian and DM approach at an optimized peak and then you go
at an optimized peak and then you go back you return to the document process
back you return to the document process you optimize and basically on you repeat
you optimize and basically on you repeat you jump back and forth so in summary
you jump back and forth so in summary essentially we have a set of training
essentially we have a set of training observations Y we have an initial set of
observations Y we have an initial set of latent variable is packed however
latent variable is packed however looking for each training parameters
looking for each training parameters here so theta again is our Gaussian
here so theta again is our Gaussian process parameters so length scales or
process parameters so length scales or whatever some additional noise terms and
whatever some additional noise terms and then these are all part of our actual
then these are all part of our actual PDF so the first step is that we're
PDF so the first step is that we're going to calculate the gradient of our
going to calculate the gradient of our potential here we're then little conduct
potential here we're then little conduct agency so essentially we're going to
agency so essentially we're going to take every single particle or I'll move
take every single particle or I'll move it a little bit a little bit a little
it a little bit a little bit a little bit toward the posterior and then that
bit toward the posterior and then that sample right there after stead amount of
sample right there after stead amount of steps will then act as a new set of
steps will then act as a new set of waiting observations for the
waiting observations for the probabilistic graphical models from here
probabilistic graphical models from here we then conduct the inference on the PGM
we then conduct the inference on the PGM we iterate back and forth between
we iterate back and forth between computing the responsibilities and
computing the responsibilities and actual parameters the hyper parameters
actual parameters the hyper parameters and we update them and then down here I
and we update them and then down here I did not mention this but essentially the
did not mention this but essentially the the parameters and the Guardian process
the parameters and the Guardian process are also updated through agency also so
are also updated through agency also so basically they sample length scales and
basically they sample length scales and noise terms and slowly propagate those
noise terms and slowly propagate those as well and basically this entire
as well and basically this entire process and then it looped over and over
process and then it looped over and over and over until you team convergent or
and over until you team convergent or your epoch has been reached
your epoch has been reached alright yes this is a quick on
alright yes this is a quick on discussion regarding the predictive
discussion regarding the predictive distribution so this is a little bit
distribution so this is a little bit it's a little bit involved essentially
it's a little bit involved essentially we have to do a Monte Carlo
we have to do a Monte Carlo approximation unfortunately last and
approximation unfortunately last and unfortunately but yeah and the main
unfortunately but yeah and the main reason behind that is because we're
reason behind that is because we're using monstro it's actually sampled
using monstro it's actually sampled easily in variables and optimize it but
easily in variables and optimize it but I will say here that on so breaking
I will say here that on so breaking apart actual predictive distribution
apart actual predictive distribution where Y stars weren't guaranteed
where Y stars weren't guaranteed observation that were interested in and
observation that were interested in and X star is going to be so if we kind of
X star is going to be so if we kind of split this up and separate it we can see
split this up and separate it we can see that this guy here this is actually done
that this guy here this is actually done through agency so this is it done three
through agency so this is it done three agencies this is also so this is
agencies this is also so this is basically done by sampling we
basically done by sampling we marginalized yeah so we compute this by
marginalized yeah so we compute this by essentially and playing a bunch of new
essentially and playing a bunch of new flaking variables from our PGM and
flaking variables from our PGM and feeding them forward through the network
feeding them forward through the network and this right here is actually the GP
and this right here is actually the GP predictive distribution which there's
predictive distribution which there's actually playing analytical for because
actually playing analytical for because it's just bizarre
all right
still angry work I don't know which
I have no internet
okay all right well anyway I'll just I'll just kind of illustrate this here
I'll just kind of illustrate this here so essentially this if you look on the
so essentially this if you look on the slides basically this is a movie that
slides basically this is a movie that illustrates this whole process so the
illustrates this whole process so the idea is that on on the right we have a
idea is that on on the right we have a set of observations and a spiral
set of observations and a spiral basically these we through the GP on
basically these we through the GP on these are translated to variables that
these are translated to variables that we then propagate through HMC the PGM
we then propagate through HMC the PGM then tries to map instead of mixtures
then tries to map instead of mixtures onto that and then over here we then
onto that and then over here we then basically sample a bunch from these and
basically sample a bunch from these and then this represents the standpoint by
then this represents the standpoint by the colors and there's also shows in the
the colors and there's also shows in the paper of how
and also our breakfast any question
[Applause]
good afternoon everyone I'll be talking about the paper that has been recently
about the paper that has been recently published in 2017 that is a learning in
published in 2017 that is a learning in network structure of heterogeneous data
network structure of heterogeneous data by your pairwise exponential macro
by your pairwise exponential macro random field and in this we can observe
random field and in this we can observe there are three main important keywords
there are three main important keywords one is the learning the network
one is the learning the network structure second one is a word data
structure second one is a word data it's a heterogeneous in nature and the
it's a heterogeneous in nature and the third one is what model we are going to
third one is what model we are going to want to pair with exponential Markov
want to pair with exponential Markov random field and this is the outline of
random field and this is the outline of my this thing I mean talk to me first
my this thing I mean talk to me first I'll be giving an introduction of water
I'll be giving an introduction of water test next but the motivation of its of
test next but the motivation of its of the work and then later the column
the work and then later the column definition and then I'll be talking very
definition and then I'll be talking very in detail about pmrs and later since
in detail about pmrs and later since there is one term that is the partition
there is one term that is the partition function which is not tractable so
function which is not tractable so computationally so we go for
computationally so we go for approximated or maximum like here
approximated or maximum like here instead of going for exact maximum
instead of going for exact maximum likelihood and then later I'll be
likelihood and then later I'll be discussing about optimization technique
discussing about optimization technique called or a DMM that is alternating
called or a DMM that is alternating direction or method of power multiplex
direction or method of power multiplex and then I will show a bleep result of
and then I will show a bleep result of what is obtained and then the conclusion
what is obtained and then the conclusion so what does and Markov random feel like
so what does and Markov random feel like its importance of macro random field is
its importance of macro random field is like its importance is fundamental tool
like its importance is fundamental tool to many applications in machine learning
to many applications in machine learning and also it is necessary for the samara
and also it is necessary for the samara from all this a matter for heterogeneous
from all this a matter for heterogeneous entities so if for example you have a
entities so if for example you have a medical database and nature so that is
medical database and nature so that is it has between the categorical and
it has between the categorical and continuous variables so for example the
continuous variables so for example the age gender the medical history of the
age gender the medical history of the patient and the other interesting area
patient and the other interesting area where it can be used for analyzing the
where it can be used for analyzing the protein interaction
there is one major major field which implements this and that is in
implements this and that is in computational biology which is the being
computational biology which is the being unable to task for this is to
unable to task for this is to infrastructure and what is happening we
infrastructure and what is happening we now people and people who sees the
now people and people who sees the Gaussian graphical models but in
Gaussian graphical models but in nowadays with new technologies of this
nowadays with new technologies of this DNA sequencing we can which produces the
DNA sequencing we can which produces the data with or with nitrogen is activation
data with or with nitrogen is activation and this growth gaussian graphical
and this growth gaussian graphical models will not be able to extract
models will not be able to extract generate the structure for this
generate the structure for this heterogenous domain so because of this
heterogenous domain so because of this we are going to outline the entire now
we are going to outline the entire now in the sport questions we are going to
in the sport questions we are going to see what there's a PMRF and then second
see what there's a PMRF and then second we are going to of approximate the
we are going to of approximate the [Applause]
[Applause] formula to approximate in maximum
formula to approximate in maximum likelihood problem and then develop
likelihood problem and then develop Avant and then on the partition function
Avant and then on the partition function in the later a scalable or a DML
in the later a scalable or a DML optimization algorithm with the closed
optimization algorithm with the closed form update and then you'll also know
form update and then you'll also know that if then our estimator is a Faustian
that if then our estimator is a Faustian so what is PMS going to diffuse of EMR
so what is PMS going to diffuse of EMR so there are some definitions that we
so there are some definitions that we are going to consider first we'll
are going to consider first we'll consider that data is like an
consider that data is like an independent multiband observation and
independent multiband observation and then later these samples are iid from an
then later these samples are iid from an exponential family of institution it's P
exponential family of institution it's P of X comma theta and then later with
of X comma theta and then later with represented by P no graphical model with
represented by P no graphical model with the natural parameter theta and and we
the natural parameter theta and and we use these samples to estimate the
use these samples to estimate the underling distribution and this is the
underling distribution and this is the in general like we have London PGM where
in general like we have London PGM where V is my Nora vertices and E is my edge
V is my Nora vertices and E is my edge and the length of this is P and also the
and the length of this is P and also the structure is encoded with this
structure is encoded with this exponential family parameter theta so
exponential family parameter theta so PMRF pms is a subclass of multivariate
PMRF pms is a subclass of multivariate exponent
or exponential family that can explain explicitly relieve the marker structure
explicitly relieve the marker structure across heterogeneous variables and here
across heterogeneous variables and here this these are the few notations that we
this these are the few notations that we will follow in this light falling slice
will follow in this light falling slice the inner product is given by this
the inner product is given by this trailer of a B and also the obvious upma
trailer of a B and also the obvious upma contaminate the set of very effectors in
contaminate the set of very effectors in this form okay so let's consider a
this form okay so let's consider a random vector with X X 1 to X B and then
random vector with X X 1 to X B and then later which are retro genus and within
later which are retro genus and within this domain or extras a chronicle
this domain or extras a chronicle product of just variables so what is it
product of just variables so what is it if you have a matrix a which is a 1 a 2
if you have a matrix a which is a 1 a 2 a 3 a 4 and B so we multiply each
a 3 a 4 and B so we multiply each element of this a1 through this matrix B
element of this a1 through this matrix B and a to this PHP so that's the
and a to this PHP so that's the chronicle product here and then later or
chronicle product here and then later or suppose we the conditional distribution
suppose we the conditional distribution of each variable is X are given all my
of each variable is X are given all my previous PP minus 1 variables are
previous PP minus 1 variables are unknown to be the exponential
unknown to be the exponential distribution in this domain is the sy
distribution in this domain is the sy are Thea ok so yeah and then later the
are Thea ok so yeah and then later the distribution is also specified with this
distribution is also specified with this M R dimensional or potential with BR and
M R dimensional or potential with BR and s BR into X Appa and my scale based
s BR into X Appa and my scale based parameters TR into extra part and then
parameters TR into extra part and then my let the K this is the way this is the
my let the K this is the way this is the main Joint Distribution for this the
main Joint Distribution for this the condition is that my X is 1 to XP you
condition is that my X is 1 to XP you should follow this joint distribution
should follow this joint distribution where a of theta is my partition
where a of theta is my partition function and theta is my the no
function and theta is my the no parameter sorry this X parameter and the
parameter sorry this X parameter and the sweetest monitor is my parameter so yeah
sweetest monitor is my parameter so yeah theta 1 to theta P so we're maldita is
theta 1 to theta P so we're maldita is the node parameter and the big theta is
the node parameter and the big theta is my order Kappa theta is my H parameter
my order Kappa theta is my H parameter and your Peter make a lock partition
and your Peter make a lock partition function which is expressed in this
function which is expressed in this equation ok
equation ok so now this is a small brief like like
so now this is a small brief like like we're going to say we're going to define
we're going to say we're going to define this P of X in terms of this exponential
this P of X in terms of this exponential family expression so where B of X is
family expression so where B of X is nothing but when sufficient statistic
nothing but when sufficient statistic this is my base parameter and a of theta
this is my base parameter and a of theta is my partition function and this inner
is my partition function and this inner product I define it in this fashion okay
so the next important thing is what happens at one node so one a conditional
happens at one node so one a conditional distribution what happens so a node
distribution what happens so a node condition distribution given node X are
condition distribution given node X are given all my known condition on may all
given all my known condition on may all only previous notes that V of you'll
only previous notes that V of you'll know that it's an exponential
know that it's an exponential exponential family is given by this
exponential family is given by this expression and I don't have a of beta
expression and I don't have a of beta because I have given up proportional
because I have given up proportional sign here where my sufficient statistics
sign here where my sufficient statistics is just our these variables and these
is just our these variables and these values and base parameter of these
values and base parameter of these values okay the reason why because we
values okay the reason why because we are both we are doing node by node or
are both we are doing node by node or basis because of that I defined that the
basis because of that I defined that the road condition institution okay next the
road condition institution okay next the PMRF model can is the populace tribution
PMRF model can is the populace tribution which which can ranging from a
which which can ranging from a homogeneous to or mixed one and then
homogeneous to or mixed one and then later from a node conditional
later from a node conditional distribution in previous equation we can
distribution in previous equation we can that we can design up
that we can design up PMR for a node by node distance by
PMR for a node by node distance by choosing a decide of my base parameter
choosing a decide of my base parameter and my official status in the VR and see
and my official status in the VR and see oh yeah putting still BR and my based
oh yeah putting still BR and my based measure TR and note that this is a joint
measure TR and note that this is a joint this is valid if I am able to obtain a
this is valid if I am able to obtain a value for y of theta but my L theta is
value for y of theta but my L theta is computationally intractable so the
computationally intractable so the reason why we go for approximate log
reason why we go for approximate log likelihood okay so for example I don't
likelihood okay so for example I don't give an example of a universal
give an example of a universal distribution where are my
distribution where are my Sigma into the - and what happens if my
Sigma into the - and what happens if my lambda is in a structured graph so and
lambda is in a structured graph so and again in this we use a penalty so this
again in this we use a penalty so this one have taken it from the mouse we book
one have taken it from the mouse we book chapter 23 I believe so this is an
chapter 23 I believe so this is an example so my lambda is very high so it
example so my lambda is very high so it is very sparse in nature and for this my
is very sparse in nature and for this my lambda is equal to 0 so it is very dense
lambda is equal to 0 so it is very dense in nature so my lambda gives me a very
in nature so my lambda gives me a very big spectrum of my specificity okay so
big spectrum of my specificity okay so next a parent thing is the approximate
next a parent thing is the approximate maximum like you know make you so we go
maximum like you know make you so we go for a profit because a of theta as high
for a profit because a of theta as high dimensional integral and it's typically
dimensional integral and it's typically intractable and in order to do this we
intractable and in order to do this we replace your theta with intractable or
replace your theta with intractable or convex upper value of theta or for my
convex upper value of theta or for my problem for proceeding for me to obtain
problem for proceeding for me to obtain our value for U of T Tauri of theta so
our value for U of T Tauri of theta so we need we need to recall all
we need we need to recall all patience because from the I mean a
patience because from the I mean a different paper so in order to have a
different paper so in order to have a compact notation
compact notation I just recall everything again so theta
I just recall everything again so theta is my natural parameter and be your
is my natural parameter and be your purchase my sufficient statistics and
purchase my sufficient statistics and it's in this domain and also my inner
it's in this domain and also my inner product is expressed in this fashion
product is expressed in this fashion which we all remember few slides back
which we all remember few slides back and also here the new thing is we're
and also here the new thing is we're going to define the mean parameters in
going to define the mean parameters in this fashion and this is for my for my
this fashion and this is for my for my edge so main one is for my edge and my
edge so main one is for my edge and my expectation of the VR of X is nothing
expectation of the VR of X is nothing but my mu R and for the similarly for
but my mu R and for the similarly for the S parameter and also one more
the S parameter and also one more important thing is you are going to
important thing is you are going to express it and the Google map the for
express it and the Google map the for the node and the X parameter with the in
the node and the X parameter with the in this matrix okay the reason I mentioned
this matrix okay the reason I mentioned it because in this book and the
it because in this book and the surrealist paper
surrealist paper Jordan paper he gives an expression for
Jordan paper he gives an expression for the upper bound the lock partition
the upper bound the lock partition function of theta has the following
function of theta has the following upper bound and here the same notations
upper bound and here the same notations what a different report is used here in
what a different report is used here in this paper and this is just a brief
this paper and this is just a brief explanation of how he has obtained this
explanation of how he has obtained this one so in particularly we obtain the
one so in particularly we obtain the upper bound relationship between the
upper bound relationship between the entropy H of X and the entropy of the
entropy H of X and the entropy of the node potential given by this in addition
node potential given by this in addition to the different choices of L R where R
to the different choices of L R where R because I have in my Pino does this
because I have in my Pino does this thing so it's goes from R 1 to P 4 or
thing so it's goes from R 1 to P 4 or heterogeneous domains so I have this
heterogeneous domains so I have this expression for a of theta now is by
expression for a of theta now is by taking the dedication of this dual you
taking the dedication of this dual you can convert this high dimension problem
can convert this high dimension problem from the above theorem and that is
from the above theorem and that is orderable mention equation to the
orderable mention equation to the calling or tractable form so that the
calling or tractable form so that the same expression we can write in this
same expression we can write in this where F of 2 is expressed in the
where F of 2 is expressed in the equation here later we are going to plug
equation here later we are going to plug in this a of theta into the main
in this a of theta into the main equation here
into the main equation here and then later simplifying it we obtain this
later simplifying it we obtain this optimization problem available to
optimization problem available to minimize this and where this is my
minimize this and where this is my different matrix we have a theta belongs
different matrix we have a theta belongs to and this this expression is nothing
to and this this expression is nothing but the expression that we had observed
but the expression that we had observed when Cody Baker explained that yesterday
when Cody Baker explained that yesterday yesterday afternoon so when he explained
yesterday afternoon so when he explained this group graphical so yesterday so
this group graphical so yesterday so this is something similar to that so to
this is something similar to that so to make it group so what we do is we for a
make it group so what we do is we for a zero-mean graph a Gaussian amara with
zero-mean graph a Gaussian amara with additional constraint that is
conditionally independent then what we do is we study to 0 and in that case
do is we study to 0 and in that case profit is equal to the graphical Rezo
profit is equal to the graphical Rezo but there's one difference in the
but there's one difference in the optimization procedure what he or what
optimization procedure what he or what he has followed and what is followed
he has followed and what is followed here in that the graphical ticket
here in that the graphical ticket optimizes you with respect to the
optimizes you with respect to the empirical covariance matrix but in our
empirical covariance matrix but in our case or what we do is we optimize with
case or what we do is we optimize with respect to using the sample average of
respect to using the sample average of the sufficient statistics of the EMRs
the sufficient statistics of the EMRs those things we are talking about the
those things we are talking about the optimization procedure we are going to
optimization procedure we are going to this alternating direction or method of
this alternating direction or method of multipliers and I just give you a brief
multipliers and I just give you a brief explanation of what DMMs and then and
explanation of what DMMs and then and then explain again like how the being
then explain again like how the being implemented so this is just a small
implemented so this is just a small explanation and algorithm which also
explanation and algorithm which also complex optimization problem by breaking
complex optimization problem by breaking into smaller pieces each other which can
into smaller pieces each other which can easily then be handled example it is
easily then be handled example it is considered this would be objective
considered this would be objective function we have to minimize this
function we have to minimize this objective function f of X plus G of Z
objective function f of X plus G of Z and we have to design variables
and we have to design variables X and Z which is subjected to a
X and Z which is subjected to a constraint that is our 8 plus B Z equals
constraint that is our 8 plus B Z equals T and now we define an argument a
T and now we define an argument a Lagrangian with the three parameter Rho
Lagrangian with the three parameter Rho or just greater than zero and we say
or just greater than zero and we say that is nothing but the objective
that is nothing but the objective function plus u u transpose of this
function plus u u transpose of this constraint here plus my LP parameter to
constraint here plus my LP parameter to the norm and what we do we update X for
the norm and what we do we update X for updating X we take the value of Z of the
updating X we take the value of Z of the previous clip and you of the previous
previous clip and you of the previous clip and then later or we update Z when
clip and then later or we update Z when we updating Z we take the updated value
we updating Z we take the updated value of x and then we update we update the D
of x and then we update we update the D but we we do not have the update develop
but we we do not have the update develop view so we are using the previous
view so we are using the previous updated value here and later we get the
updated value here and later we get the closed form or solution with with with
closed form or solution with with with this expression here and that is reason
this expression here and that is reason why it is known as alternating direction
why it is known as alternating direction because we do it for X then we do it for
because we do it for X then we do it for Z and then we do it again at last for
Z and then we do it again at last for closed form solution for UK I mean so we
closed form solution for UK I mean so we do it until the stop criterion is
do it until the stop criterion is mentioned so this is in general so
mentioned so this is in general so basically we have to update these three
basically we have to update these three parameters coming back to this problem
parameters coming back to this problem here we dated again saying that we have
here we dated again saying that we have to minimize this and again you say that
to minimize this and again you say that we have to update three things theta big
we have to update three things theta big and you it is the same thing but for
and you it is the same thing but for this problem we prom late top-40 to
this problem we prom late top-40 to update this is the formulation where eta
update this is the formulation where eta is nothing but Rho by n and this is
is nothing but Rho by n and this is nothing but Q this my decomposition and
nothing but Q this my decomposition and later for Z update again this is the
later for Z update again this is the expression which we have already seen
expression which we have already seen and also this is from a you updated cell
and also this is from a you updated cell phone solution so I'll be able to get an
phone solution so I'll be able to get an optimum value okay I mean it is used for
optimum value okay I mean it is used for to visualize the wafer to inspect the
to visualize the wafer to inspect the performance of classification and in
performance of classification and in this we have two x axis and y axis which
this we have two x axis and y axis which is to positive and false positive and
is to positive and false positive and my book club is part of my corner then
my book club is part of my corner then the system is accurate its operating the
the system is accurate its operating the venue and since the area under this
venue and since the area under this curve gives me the appreciation okay I
curve gives me the appreciation okay I took a small toy problem because I did
took a small toy problem because I did not get the data set what the paper has
not get the data set what the paper has implemented so in this in this forum
implemented so in this in this forum I've taken eight Bernoulli eight gamma
I've taken eight Bernoulli eight gamma eight Gaussian and made a distillate
eight Gaussian and made a distillate with K is equal to 3 and there are two
with K is equal to 3 and there are two cases one has power he other is the
cases one has power he other is the dense case was fast case taken or the
dense case was fast case taken or the 10% of the potential that exists and the
10% of the potential that exists and the for dense case have taken the 50% of the
for dense case have taken the 50% of the potential edge exists and then these are
potential edge exists and then these are the results that have obtained this is
the results that have obtained this is for highly structure and this world
for highly structure and this world knows fast structure and we can observe
knows fast structure and we can observe that the the that they illustrate the de
that the the that they illustrate the de Graaff with the high degree of sparsity
Graaff with the high degree of sparsity to recover few samples it is much
to recover few samples it is much possible so that is this is much better
possible so that is this is much better that is the illustrate just and ok again
that is the illustrate just and ok again this is the same I'm going to conclude
this is the same I'm going to conclude to conclude this so in this work we have
to conclude this so in this work we have discussed the method for learning the
discussed the method for learning the Markov networks that is from
Markov networks that is from observational data and then this PMRF is
observational data and then this PMRF is a multivariate genius data which is much
a multivariate genius data which is much required for example you take our
required for example you take our medical database or something like that
medical database or something like that and then we have not used the exact use
and then we have not used the exact use approximate maximum likelihood for this
approximate maximum likelihood for this problem and you also developed our a DMM
problem and you also developed our a DMM algorithm which can reduce me a
algorithm which can reduce me a closed-form updates and these are the
closed-form updates and these are the references and from this paper or taken
references and from this paper or taken the like the main people that have
the like the main people that have effort and further to obtain a of theta
effort and further to obtain a of theta I hope that theta the upper bound refers
I hope that theta the upper bound refers for this paper and this paper gives a
for this paper and this paper gives a brief explanation of early how do we go
brief explanation of early how do we go about of using the approximately
Oh
so hi I am a wishing that from the physics department the generation of the
physics department the generation of the handwritten like image using variational
handwritten like image using variational auto encoder it has been trained on the
auto encoder it has been trained on the eminence to dataset the outline is that
eminence to dataset the outline is that introduction a little bit about
introduction a little bit about missionaries which are like standard we
missionaries which are like standard we start with scanner auto encoder we
start with scanner auto encoder we introduced variation on experience
introduced variation on experience variational outside color -
variational outside color - normalization and the resultant clock so
normalization and the resultant clock so I'll be talking about a little bit in
I'll be talking about a little bit in little about this machineries because I
little about this machineries because I learned about them while starting after
learned about them while starting after starting working on this project itself
so an autoencoder network is a pair of true connected networks
the encoder component makes and gains the representation of the original data
the representation of the original data Angele la or grid of pixels and then we
Angele la or grid of pixels and then we call that n color information and the
call that n color information and the decoder part decodes it back to the
decoder part decodes it back to the original dimension usually higher than
original dimension usually higher than the dimensional representation like this
the dimensional representation like this this is the description
so in general the output of the decoder network would not match with the input
network would not match with the input using the input data point like new data
using the input data point like new data points then it tells because it won't
points then it tells because it won't it can only give must output replicating
it can only give must output replicating the denser representation of our
the denser representation of our original input so it cannot create new
original input so it cannot create new things so it's that's that's where
things so it's that's that's where standard auto encoder slack so these are
standard auto encoder slack so these are kind of an example of the representation
kind of an example of the representation of the MST data state where we have like
of the MST data state where we have like twenty eighteen to twenty eighth
twenty eighteen to twenty eighth dimension we have converted it to the
dimension we have converted it to the two dimension so their distribution and
two dimension so their distribution and it's kind of get rich there is no
it's kind of get rich there is no continuity from one the representation
continuity from one the representation data point of one visit to the other so
data point of one visit to the other so we won't want that because where it's
we won't want that because where it's difficult to general
difficult to general models while the distribution is like
models while the distribution is like that in generative models we would not
that in generative models we would not want to replicate data that we used it
want to replicate data that we used it to train in the first place but also we
to train in the first place but also we want to sample data points from the
want to sample data points from the distribution the latent space and decode
distribution the latent space and decode them to form Chancellor's and the higher
them to form Chancellor's and the higher data points so suppose we we have a lot
data points so suppose we we have a lot of data points of the handwritten digits
of data points of the handwritten digits and we want to create a model to get the
and we want to create a model to get the probability distribution of life of
probability distribution of life of those data points now these images are
those data points now these images are 28 by trend age so to get a maximum
28 by trend age so to get a maximum likelihood would have to get a min of 28
likelihood would have to get a min of 28 into 28 dimension and and the covariance
into 28 dimension and and the covariance matrix of the similar dimensions those
matrix of the similar dimensions those are very computationally intractable
are very computationally intractable that's why the idea of auto-encoders
that's why the idea of auto-encoders comes into play in the first place to
comes into play in the first place to get a more compressed representation so
get a more compressed representation so from the probabilistic graphical models
from the probabilistic graphical models from what we can say
[Music]
in the denominator itself is very difficult to compute very expensive
difficult to compute very expensive that's why we use variation insurance to
that's why we use variation insurance to approximate the posterior with a family
approximate the posterior with a family of distribution which represents the
of distribution which represents the parameters of the distributions we are
parameters of the distributions we are trying to fit for example a cube or a
trying to fit for example a cube or a normal distribution it will mean the new
normal distribution it will mean the new X I and Sigma X we will use KL
X I and Sigma X we will use KL divergence which should quantify the
divergence which should quantify the information lost we try to replace the
information lost we try to replace the primary distribution P with lambda
for that yeah kill divergences define as the expected expectation value of the
the expected expectation value of the log of Q lambda over P and we can
log of Q lambda over P and we can express in there the subtractive swarm
express in there the subtractive swarm and using Bayes theorem we can express
and using Bayes theorem we can express it in the like a form of equation two
like here the approximate for optimal posture is clear I swore to get
posture is clear I swore to get approximate optimal posture we minimize
approximate optimal posture we minimize KL divergence with respect to lambda to
KL divergence with respect to lambda to get the optimized Q lambda but the
get the optimized Q lambda but the intractable term log of px till lost
intractable term log of px till lost within the expression of the KL
within the expression of the KL divergence like this is equal to that
divergence like this is equal to that and that term is very computationally
and that term is very computationally expensive so we want to remove that
expensive so we want to remove that that's why we just flip side and Express
that's why we just flip side and Express as this subtractive form of to
as this subtractive form of to expectation values plus KL divergence
expectation values plus KL divergence now we know that KL divergence is always
now we know that KL divergence is always non-negative so it's I'm sorry so its
non-negative so it's I'm sorry so its minimum value is 0 so to maximize this
minimum value is 0 so to maximize this we want to minimize this and maximum
we want to minimize this and maximum discharge so now this becomes a bit
discharge so now this becomes a bit tractable to compute
and informational insurance we use union vo checking Forrester into the Thomas
vo checking Forrester into the Thomas Trump's dependent only upon the single
Trump's dependent only upon the single data points this allows for the use of
data points this allows for the use of stochastic gradient descent with respect
stochastic gradient descent with respect to the variation of parameters lambda
to the variation of parameters lambda for a given data point X right the LPO
for a given data point X right the LPO are defined on this so long T exceeds
expectation of log of P of a given Z minus Q lambda Disney different extend
minus Q lambda Disney different extend teasing minus KL divergence of Q lambda
teasing minus KL divergence of Q lambda Z given X and P Z given X so we want to
Z given X and P Z given X so we want to optimize log tapes by trying to find a
optimize log tapes by trying to find a lower bound of the quantity inside the
lower bound of the quantity inside the curly bracket computationally
curly bracket computationally intractable maximizing this is a sample
intractable maximizing this is a sample PC is really in the latent space also we
PC is really in the latent space also we can add an advantage of obtaining closed
can add an advantage of obtaining closed formulation of the KL divergence which
formulation of the KL divergence which will see Z and Q lambda Z given X we
will see Z and Q lambda Z given X we check easy to the standard normal
check easy to the standard normal distribution with mean 0 and standard
distribution with mean 0 and standard deviation is 1 and 2 lambda Z given X to
deviation is 1 and 2 lambda Z given X to be
be like this also another normal
like this also another normal distribution here this is the covariance
distribution here this is the covariance matrices constraint to the diagonal
matrices constraint to the diagonal matrix to keep computation easy but
matrix to keep computation easy but final the final expression is easy if
final the final expression is easy if the closed form expression that we get
the closed form expression that we get by some algebraic manipulation is the
by some algebraic manipulation is the normalization which is a very useful
normalization which is a very useful technique introduced to improve the
technique introduced to improve the performance of GAE and in general vision
normalization output of f3 hidden layer is standardized over every single mini
is standardized over every single mini batch path in the training session it
batch path in the training session it will be clear suppose we have a
will be clear suppose we have a classifier and we want the classifier to
classifier and we want the classifier to classify between some images which
classify between some images which contents cat and which doesn't have a
contents cat and which doesn't have a cat in the image so our training data
cat in the image so our training data contents on the black cat and all other
contents on the black cat and all other non cat images and then will be after
non cat images and then will be after training we introduced cat images which
training we introduced cat images which are colorful cat in general and non cat
are colorful cat in general and non cat or transfer won't be trouble too far
or transfer won't be trouble too far from that good as it did for the
from that good as it did for the training dataset this is called this is
training dataset this is called this is a very fancy term called covariate shift
a very fancy term called covariate shift which means the a shift in the data
which means the a shift in the data point in its distribution
situation model
so suppose the the data parts of black cats - like this very thing the data
cats - like this very thing the data points and the non cats are like this
points and the non cats are like this black crosses so usually this poor each
black crosses so usually this poor each we don't use vaginal normalization our
we don't use vaginal normalization our model would likely learn straight line
model would likely learn straight line difference we should separate these data
difference we should separate these data points like this straight line when we
points like this straight line when we introduced these colorful cats these
introduced these colorful cats these data points of this colorful cat lines
data points of this colorful cat lines here which our model won't be able to
here which our model won't be able to classify it correctly because now they
classify it correctly because now they have only joined a straight line which
have only joined a straight line which clearly don't classify them accurately
clearly don't classify them accurately that so that's why we want to we want to
that so that's why we want to we want to use batch normalization so that even if
use batch normalization so that even if our data points to vary by some amount
our data points to vary by some amount if normalizes it back and our our model
if normalizes it back and our our model learns faster learns more reliable
learns faster learns more reliable denser representation
these are some advantages of using that's normalization which makes our
that's normalization which makes our model to launch faster makes it converge
model to launch faster makes it converge better in a better value and in a faster
better in a better value and in a faster manner while each training iteration
manner while each training iteration will become somewhat skewer because the
will become somewhat skewer because the externalization calculations in the
externalization calculations in the forward path but eventually it would
forward path but eventually it would converge quickly to overall combination
converge quickly to overall combination because pockets these are the I used for
because pockets these are the I used for layer deep fully connected Network as
layer deep fully connected Network as both encoder and decoder salsa eminence
both encoder and decoder salsa eminence together set I take one more minute this
together set I take one more minute this is the
yeah so this is the convergence of lost function without using rationalization
function without using rationalization and this is the generated data set
and this is the generated data set without rationalization next I am used
without rationalization next I am used batch normalization and the it converges
batch normalization and the it converges to a better value which is a bit more
to a better value which is a bit more cleaner
these are using the four four dimensions for the Latin twist instead of two with
for the Latin twist instead of two with without BN this is again it using BM so
without BN this is again it using BM so you can see that the loss function
visitor references
[Applause]