okay okay I become the first person to give presentation today hello everyone
give presentation today hello everyone my name is Tina I'm the first year
my name is Tina I'm the first year graduate student in the department
graduate student in the department working with environmental combustion
working with environmental combustion yes destroyed I'm experimental people
yes destroyed I'm experimental people and majority of my previous research and
and majority of my previous research and ongoing job are related to experiment
ongoing job are related to experiment instead of computation so this causes
instead of computation so this causes the most challenging class I've ever
the most challenging class I've ever taken but do I have to do I'm very
taken but do I have to do I'm very interested in that and we definitely
interested in that and we definitely know a lot although sometimes we are
know a lot although sometimes we are they take pressure and for my present
they take pressure and for my present for my future I just like a candle is
for my future I just like a candle is the topic which I want to try if you
the topic which I want to try if you want to apply what we've learned class
want to apply what we've learned class to a real world case which is using the
to a real world case which is using the Bayesian network approaches to predict
Bayesian network approaches to predict the well fire consequence
the well fire consequence well fire we generate some some damage
well fire we generate some some damage and you lead to some cost if you are
and you lead to some cost if you are person working maybe government
person working maybe government department when there is a well fire you
department when there is a well fire you will be probably surrounded by a lot of
will be probably surrounded by a lot of people from different media keep asking
people from different media keep asking you unknowing questions about the
you unknowing questions about the consequence of the well fire do you want
consequence of the well fire do you want to be complete - good job you have to
to be complete - good job you have to keep them down raise doubt the the
keep them down raise doubt the the consequence of the world fire however a
consequence of the world fire however a true value is accountant of the welfare
true value is accountant of the welfare it's kind of hard job because it's
it's kind of hard job because it's information from many different areas
information from many different areas for example you have to think about the
for example you have to think about the type of your city and you the road
type of your city and you the road density and your type of your
density and your type of your construction it's a kind of knowledge
construction it's a kind of knowledge from stable engineering and the
from stable engineering and the landscape environment something related
landscape environment something related to geology or biology and the value of
to geology or biology and the value of your building
your building finish their job of Business School so
finish their job of Business School so your word complex and hard and it keeps
your word complex and hard and it keeps the nightmares who the traditional
the nightmares who the traditional myself to calculate the counts quest
myself to calculate the counts quest however the Bayesian network or hurdle
however the Bayesian network or hurdle can depend on the information from
can depend on the information from different area very well as same time
different area very well as same time and there are many researchers using
and there are many researchers using Bayesian network to do some work on
Bayesian network to do some work on different areas for example the biology
different areas for example the biology system and you know well fire and this
system and you know well fire and this person whose name is I don't know his
person whose name is I don't know his name the correct pronunciation he
name the correct pronunciation he develop up internet work and the user to
develop up internet work and the user to access the suicide the building damage
access the suicide the building damage called the cost to buy well fire in
called the cost to buy well fire in tableau and in his work he just used use
tableau and in his work he just used use the software commercial software named
the software commercial software named fusion mister very strong software you
fusion mister very strong software you can't or actually tore your Bayesian
can't or actually tore your Bayesian network and that's the input your CPT
network and that's the input your CPT and click run and you will get your
and click run and you will get your result not very simple but he might I'm
result not very simple but he might I'm worried the interest in his job and want
worried the interest in his job and want to want to reproduce his work to a
to want to reproduce his work to a similar work but I don't want to use
similar work but I don't want to use commercial software and I want to use
commercial software and I want to use that want to view so busy a network in
that want to view so busy a network in MATLAB and to select several inference
MATLAB and to select several inference engines and try to see what I can get to
engines and try to see what I can get to decide or a silent
decide or a silent limit theory and see and is very large
limit theory and see and is very large and the wire here for you to study the
and the wire here for you to study the whole island I spend time and to as
whole island I spend time and to as is also similar in my work we just
is also similar in my work we just separate this island into several into
separate this island into several into thousands of a hotel and so each time we
thousands of a hotel and so each time we just the focus on one wire cells which
just the focus on one wire cells which is represented by the right square in
is represented by the right square in the in the matter and it has blood has
the in the matter and it has blood has the area of one of one kilometer square
the area of one of one kilometer square now we decided our aim just tells the
now we decided our aim just tells the next step we try to figure out one way
next step we try to figure out one way to quantify all the consequences of well
to quantify all the consequences of well fire several researchers has established
fire several researchers has established this constants which indicate that the a
this constants which indicate that the a good way to formular the expected value
good way to formular the expected value of the of the well fire is this function
of the of the well fire is this function and this one lifetime size expected
and this one lifetime size expected value may be the little value and leave
value may be the little value and leave the function of probability of hazard
the function of probability of hazard and the probability of damage
and the probability of damage conditional hazard and here and fiercely
conditional hazard and here and fiercely cost function and so last weekend we
cost function and so last weekend we know this formula we've got some hint to
know this formula we've got some hint to to think to consider the indicator to to
to think to consider the indicator to to consider the the way to comic-con
consider the the way to comic-con calculates are a consequence the next
calculates are a consequence the next that we tried to find indicator
that we tried to find indicator represent either the damage etc let's
represent either the damage etc let's come back to the little cells again and
come back to the little cells again and no judge nor no no are now uncle in job
no judge nor no no are now uncle in job is to find the indicators even if in the
is to find the indicators even if in the little cell they are still a lot of
little cell they are still a lot of indicator you have to think about for
indicator you have to think about for example we assume that the Hatters to be
example we assume that the Hatters to be the burn area and fire intensity and
the burn area and fire intensity and zero several and the earth
zero several and the earth something influenced your damage maybe
something influenced your damage maybe for example your your building type if
for example your your building type if it is the apartment or it's a single
it is the apartment or it's a single building and the how many building in
building and the how many building in this location the building density and
this location the building density and at same times your distance to the fire
at same times your distance to the fire station and the road surround you
station and the road surround you maybe maybe also maybe play a role in
maybe maybe also maybe play a role in strife because love did not decide that
strife because love did not decide that your chance to get help from fire
your chance to get help from fire department if you have a better chance
department if you have a better chance to find a chance to control the wealth
to find a chance to control the wealth but also fire not will definitely reduce
but also fire not will definitely reduce your cost
your cost so this speaker just gave me something
so this speaker just gave me something give us some hint about how to fuse the
give us some hint about how to fuse the classic model so what watch the
classic model so what watch the indicator we want to study we can create
indicator we want to study we can create these weak raises to act involve graphic
these weak raises to act involve graphic model like this and to be honest the
model like this and to be honest the several indicator has been already
several indicator has been already ignored sense we only want to study
ignored sense we only want to study something we are really really
something we are really really interested and it's very hard for you to
interested and it's very hard for you to study piracy in the to build everything
study piracy in the to build everything in a bottle and on the top the while
in a bottle and on the top the while each node represents the the hazard
each node represents the the hazard which is the burn area and fire
which is the burn area and fire intensity so little at least a light
intensity so little at least a light green nodes representing the item at at
green nodes representing the item at at the item at risk with this list we call
the item at risk with this list we call it Explorer this knows where you cost
it Explorer this knows where you cost your damage after your building and you
your damage after your building and you their major cost so unless we get to our
their major cost so unless we get to our model the next stop is to connect up to
model the next stop is to connect up to find the conditional probability
find the conditional probability distribution and and here we do another
distribution and and here we do another another assumption that we assume each
another assumption that we assume each node has finite state and and we assume
node has finite state and and we assume I also assume that the North follows of
I also assume that the North follows of discrete distributed instead of causing
discrete distributed instead of causing distributor also just get this value as
distributor also just get this value as this probability distribution value from
this probability distribution value from some literature research government
some literature research government report or historical record just like
report or historical record just like it's a mic so chose I chose here however
it's a mic so chose I chose here however unfortunately those data I know it's
unfortunately those data I know it's very important but this data is now
very important but this data is now we're not given in the paper that gave
we're not given in the paper that gave me an admirer to compete to do to
me an admirer to compete to do to continue so and forced us to do some
continue so and forced us to do some simplification and do some assumptions
simplification and do some assumptions and try to take this hope
here here let's come back to the graphic model again and and now we have to
model again and and now we have to everything ourselves first I want to do
everything ourselves first I want to do some simplification for this graphical
some simplification for this graphical model if you example when you when you
model if you example when you when you see when you're deciding and we will
see when you're deciding and we will decide that is prefigured probability or
decide that is prefigured probability or for the building damage you can see that
for the building damage you can see that it has swore parent 1 2 3 4 which I'm
it has swore parent 1 2 3 4 which I'm the each parent has different state
the each parent has different state which means that that if you want to
which means that that if you want to create a table that will be a really
create a table that will be a really huge large table you have to input a lot
huge large table you have to input a lot of data and you are you are under high
of data and you are you are under high risk to make mistake and actually I made
risk to make mistake and actually I made that and but interesting you go to his
that and but interesting you go to his paper and check that the beauty talk and
paper and check that the beauty talk and the contraction has almost similar
the contraction has almost similar similar meanings so for simple to
similar meanings so for simple to simplify this this model I just combine
simplify this this model I just combine them together combined together and then
them together combined together and then assume that the the Firewise know I'll
assume that the the Firewise know I'll have three states inside and the yellow
have three states inside and the yellow node has toothpaste inside so that's
node has toothpaste inside so that's fair enough but and not gave me a
fair enough but and not gave me a nightmare to defy the cpt and also the
nightmare to defy the cpt and also the earth and independence assumption to
earth and independence assumption to simplify or chair or so okay like that
simplify or chair or so okay like that KB here's a very example is a very
KB here's a very example is a very simple example for one for CPT for the
simple example for one for CPT for the positional
positional this is a fire suppression and it has
this is a fire suppression and it has three parents and fire intensity this by
three parents and fire intensity this by real health I define it as three states
real health I define it as three states and this too has has to stay inside so
and this too has has to stay inside so you
buuuut this table you can sleep on the consider different states of different
consider different states of different parents and each island each elements in
parents and each island each elements in the table I just gave our reasonable
the table I just gave our reasonable reasonable cats for the probability the
reasonable cats for the probability the the meaning of reasonable is that for
the meaning of reasonable is that for example if you have a really low fire
example if you have a really low fire intensity and your building is wearing
intensity and your building is wearing the buildings very close to the fire
the buildings very close to the fire station and you are surrounded by really
station and you are surrounded by really at once the vault system which means to
at once the vault system which means to the role density is very high you will
the role density is very high you will fight you will get better care better
fight you will get better care better health from the fire department which
health from the fire department which means that the fire control could be
means that the fire control could be successful or medium instead of poor so
successful or medium instead of poor so for example this case I just gave the
for example this case I just gave the poor poor can the four states has a
poor poor can the four states has a really low I give him a really low
really low I give him a really low probability and gave the medians control
probability and gave the medians control and successful control a really high
and successful control a really high probability so now we built our or
probability so now we built our or graphic model and also also have our
graphic model and also also have our probability distribution table for each
probability distribution table for each note the next stop Ahmet life is to make
note the next stop Ahmet life is to make all the inference engine here in this
all the inference engine here in this problem which 408 y31 see the first line
problem which 408 y31 see the first line is the junction tree an inference engine
is the junction tree an inference engine and neither one has to be belief
and neither one has to be belief propagation engine we have talked a lot
propagation engine we have talked a lot in the class and the tribe test allows
in the class and the tribe test allows in the homework so I won't discuss this
in the homework so I won't discuss this too much there and there is another
too much there and there is another little bit detention to use to use
little bit detention to use to use sampling engine called likelihood
sampling engine called likelihood waiting standpoint hinging
waiting standpoint hinging so it's a kind of temporal inking the
so it's a kind of temporal inking the basic idea of sample engines are you
basic idea of sample engines are you just the cheapest and whole handle turns
just the cheapest and whole handle turns they're from your from your Bayesian
they're from your from your Bayesian network and to compute the probability
network and to compute the probability of this temple computer ancient temple
of this temple computer ancient temple Allah keeps temple in now if you get
Allah keeps temple in now if you get enough sample the final distribution of
enough sample the final distribution of your sampling would be close to the true
your sampling would be close to the true distribution that's a basic idea of
distribution that's a basic idea of sampling and likelihood likelihood
sampling and likelihood likelihood waiting sampling is done it will be
waiting sampling is done it will be updated sampling work it's just we have
updated sampling work it's just we have the evidence and it takes to have this
the evidence and it takes to have this variable and only sample the one above
variable and only sample the one above is a wearable variables not related to
is a wearable variables not related to the average not only samples and man
the average not only samples and man evidence variables and for each sample
evidence variables and for each sample we just multiply it by the weight which
we just multiply it by the weight which is fine I've used a lot of literature's
is fine I've used a lot of literature's talk about the likelihood waiting
talk about the likelihood waiting waiting waiting waiting inference and
waiting waiting waiting inference and the sums up term are very complicated
the sums up term are very complicated and contain a lot of information here I
and contain a lot of information here I adjust the last day introduced by using
adjust the last day introduced by using a simple simple example let's come back
a simple simple example let's come back our cream-coloured sprinkler model we
our cream-coloured sprinkler model we are which we are worried familiar waste
are which we are worried familiar waste so and assume that we are required to
so and assume that we are required to compute the probability of R of R which
compute the probability of R of R which is ring given as is true that cream
is ring given as is true that cream color is 2 and the white grass is true
color is 2 and the white grass is true and let's start or simply first wish you
and let's start or simply first wish you the simple see the quality there is no
the simple see the quality there is no country and say we just assume that we
country and say we just assume that we can call it as true which please
can call it as true which please what which is plastic
what which is plastic and the sense this wife's decide when we
and the sense this wife's decide when we will next with simple the simple sighs
will next with simple the simple sighs so since whiskey style we have we can
so since whiskey style we have we can only offer to like our eyes from this
only offer to like our eyes from this right back however the ice is thick by
right back however the ice is thick by the evidence which is true so we can
the evidence which is true so we can only strike the wider of point one then
only strike the wider of point one then because our first weight of point one
because our first weight of point one and then come to our instance tastes
and then come to our instance tastes simple which is part so we can only like
simple which is part so we can only like our values from this bar right box and
our values from this bar right box and and there is no constraint on heart
and there is no constraint on heart which means that we can send off
which means that we can send off whatever we want
whatever we want let's assume that with simple art is
let's assume that with simple art is true are true and then we move to
true are true and then we move to example the table and says the our eyes
example the table and says the our eyes way is for that to be true
way is for that to be true our is sample to be true and come back
our is sample to be true and come back to the evidence we record W to be true
to the evidence we record W to be true so because the table can be only only it
so because the table can be only only it can be only in 9.99
can be only in 9.99 and we caught another way finally our
and we caught another way finally our total weight is 0.1 multiplied 199 which
total weight is 0.1 multiplied 199 which is 0.09 tonight and we just just
is 0.09 tonight and we just just multiplied and just multiply our sample
multiplied and just multiply our sample with this is our sample by this weight
with this is our sample by this weight and then to a lot of iterations to trim
and then to a lot of iterations to trim your job and finally the cat's a result
your job and finally the cat's a result of the final of probability and catch
of the final of probability and catch this one there is some problem of
this one there is some problem of likelihood waiting for example if you
likelihood waiting for example if you are required to compute probability of T
are required to compute probability of T given I signed the are you are what
given I signed the are you are what you're worried you can maybe sometimes
you're worried you can maybe sometimes thousands thousands go well with
thousands thousands go well with evidence
evidence sans use the the U star U star sample
sans use the the U star U star sample its sample to see here you don't need to
its sample to see here you don't need to think about the as your evidence which
think about the as your evidence which is a silent awfully oh yeah there's some
is a silent awfully oh yeah there's some opted for the sampling for under some
opted for the sampling for under some some other sampling changings to fix it
some other sampling changings to fix it problem which I won't talk here here's
problem which I won't talk here here's the result I got from the my life and
the result I got from the my life and this this part on the left-hand side I
this this part on the left-hand side I just the picture burn I rare to be zero
just the picture burn I rare to be zero point zero two zero point zero one
point zero two zero point zero one kilometer square and the changing the
kilometer square and the changing the fire intensity the actual painting
fire intensity the actual painting change for the cost or the cost that's
change for the cost or the cost that's because I assume last things as a higher
because I assume last things as a higher in fire intensity has a really really
in fire intensity has a really really low very low probabilities and this part
low very low probabilities and this part on the right hand side I just fix the
on the right hand side I just fix the fire intensity to be this one and the
fire intensity to be this one and the changing the upper area artist showed
changing the upper area artist showed generally those increasing trend as a
generally those increasing trend as a function of burn area that makes the
function of burn area that makes the instance if you have a fire intensity
instance if you have a fire intensity and have a larger burn area your result
and have a larger burn area your result would be a little your cost will be a
would be a little your cost will be a little bit large and this poll also
little bit large and this poll also showed the photos do something for
showed the photos do something for different inference engines that we know
different inference engines that we know the junction Creek and of accurate
the junction Creek and of accurate changing and the PD publication and
changing and the PD publication and likely who waiting proximate engines you
likely who waiting proximate engines you can see that for this case the chance to
can see that for this case the chance to be worthwhile where we always compared
be worthwhile where we always compared to the junction you know the belief
to the junction you know the belief complication works very well and there's
complication works very well and there's some
some different but between the likely who to
different but between the likely who to the junction tree and this one belief
the junction tree and this one belief propagation works also worried well but
propagation works also worried well but except here okay
except here okay the beautiful tools to the similar work
the beautiful tools to the similar work Prada but all the thousands of cells in
Prada but all the thousands of cells in on the island you can end up with this
on the island you can end up with this damaged custom at might even to learn in
damaged custom at might even to learn in the project they also just separates
the project they also just separates this island to nine thousand little
this island to nine thousand little cells though I don't have enough time to
cells though I don't have enough time to do Irish to do Irish a for the whole
do Irish to do Irish a for the whole island so this one just give you our
island so this one just give you our hints about the final result which and
hints about the final result which and there are some other thing we can talk
there are some other thing we can talk and the quality of trembling as a
and the quality of trembling as a function of number of your sample so you
function of number of your sample so you can see that the likelihood luckily
can see that the likelihood luckily who's awaiting awaiting inference
who's awaiting awaiting inference engines results come close to the
engines results come close to the junction sweet results the difference
junction sweet results the difference please the petite the appropriate a
please the petite the appropriate a difference that means the difference
difference that means the difference between junction tree and likelihood
between junction tree and likelihood reading so if you increase your number
reading so if you increase your number of sampling you will reduce the
of sampling you will reduce the difference which means the likelihood
difference which means the likelihood close to the close to the junction tree
close to the close to the junction tree however there is no freelance and if you
however there is no freelance and if you increase your number of increase your
increase your number of increase your time okay okay
time okay okay future world some future work definitely
future world some future work definitely for the work of this welfare study you
for the work of this welfare study you can definitely add more information more
can definitely add more information more cost more nodes and each note you can
cost more nodes and each note you can separate into more space that will
separate into more space that will definitely increase your accuracy of
definitely increase your accuracy of your approximation and I also think
your approximation and I also think about think about the for my own
about think about the for my own research also think about one way I can
research also think about one way I can maybe who I can I can apply what I've
maybe who I can I can apply what I've learned in this cost in my research
learned in this cost in my research to do some more uncertainty vacation for
to do some more uncertainty vacation for my experiments that would be interesting
my experiments that would be interesting to conclude today's presentation first
to conclude today's presentation first inquiry simple project is a single topic
inquiry simple project is a single topic compared to you guys may be busy Network
compared to you guys may be busy Network definitely really strong for in which
definitely really strong for in which you can use to you to evaluate the fire
you can use to you to evaluate the fire well fire consequence and I'm also think
well fire consequence and I'm also think about one way to apply it to my own
about one way to apply it to my own research and the advantage of busy and
research and the advantage of busy and network is is ability to power
network is is ability to power information from different area parties
information from different area parties to worry computational expense if you
to worry computational expense if you build a really large piece their network
build a really large piece their network and create you have also you need to do
and create you have also you need to do a lot of work to find the apt and since
a lot of work to find the apt and since the separatists are known for this for
the separatists are known for this for the other didn't give me in the paper we
the other didn't give me in the paper we can now compute our result with the with
can now compute our result with the with the authors cave without and and another
the authors cave without and and another two chances I act exact approximation
two chances I act exact approximation this exact approach and another to
this exact approach and another to proximate approaches and
[Applause]
yeah yeah
[Music]
Oh
so he asked me where's the most the computation who explains the part for
computation who explains the part for the junction tree to compute I think
the junction tree to compute I think that the I don't know no score exactly I
that the I don't know no score exactly I think if my answer is salad maybe in the
think if my answer is salad maybe in the junction tree you have to we run the
junction tree you have to we run the code you have to find the optimize the
code you have to find the optimize the biased junction tree for the birthday
biased junction tree for the birthday for your model so maybe that will be
for your model so maybe that will be called sometime or it is computationally
called sometime or it is computationally expensive
I didn't I didn't do that deeply here
I'm a second year student in galactic convenience I'm in possession and today
convenience I'm in possession and today my turn project linear time algorithm in
my turn project linear time algorithm in Bayesian email engine based on Gaussian
Deltora is animating noisy I really have two steps first is the hopper parameter
two steps first is the hopper parameter estimation by yeah matters
expectation maximization and second that will be the image restoration by an AP
will be the image restoration by an AP maximize a posterior metric and in this
those things change that requires inverse of environment variance matrix
inverse of environment variance matrix the computation under order of natives
the computation under order of natives order of Ernie blogging I need this
order of Ernie blogging I need this people achieve
the reason why is because virtually having related to what we can learn
having related to what we can learn about the past like GM adoption my
about the past like GM adoption my father and intimidation laughter and
father and intimidation laughter and second reason is that it's highly
second reason is that it's highly related to what i'm doing here i'm doing
related to what i'm doing here i'm doing the noted image alignment and the melty
the noted image alignment and the melty image development it is the best way to
image development it is the best way to show my my algorithm itself so I'm
show my my algorithm itself so I'm really interested to choose excellent
really interested to choose excellent clarity in both insurance caps and the
clarity in both insurance caps and the parameter settings it's very clear for
parameter settings it's very clear for me to follow each step so I will not go
me to follow each step so I will not go into a loop or I don't know what's going
into a loop or I don't know what's going on
this report our first introduced the framers hoste them in 18 only and second
framers hoste them in 18 only and second how are you to introduce you their
how are you to introduce you their linear time algorithm second I add a
linear time algorithm second I add a comparison other rhythm to do this paper
comparison other rhythm to do this paper increase in previous paper the only
increase in previous paper the only averaging everything else which is just
averaging everything else which is just as units together and divide to the
as units together and divide to the remember a free print so I think too
remember a free print so I think too simple I thought to show more features
simple I thought to show more features of this outer limits them so I added the
of this outer limits them so I added the matter called Libyan 3d the original is
matter called Libyan 3d the original is very long it's a video Facebook noising
very long it's a video Facebook noising bye-bye passage history being truthful
bye-bye passage history being truthful it's very longer recorded vivianne 3d
it's very longer recorded vivianne 3d and this method should there be result
and this method should there be result in any papers so I want to show the
in any papers so I want to show the comparison between the people other
comparison between the people other algorithm in this paper and Libyan 3d
algorithm in this paper and Libyan 3d last I will show you the massage and we
last I will show you the massage and we can discuss the results
can discuss the results given given an original image composed
given given an original image composed of we buy the kid for a depleted image
of we buy the kid for a depleted image of the same size of the original one is
of the same size of the original one is generated by adding additive white
generated by adding additive white Gaussian noise awgn to the original one
Gaussian noise awgn to the original one suppose we independently of team K
suppose we independently of team K degrade image and he is bigger than one
degrade image and he is bigger than one we denoted the original image by the
we denoted the original image by the water so it is actually imagined you
water so it is actually imagined you just vectorized into a vector to
just vectorized into a vector to simplify the computation and it has n
simplify the computation and it has n pick stars
pick stars [Music]
[Music] skin roll a burrito you know to the case
skin roll a burrito you know to the case degraded image by the rector next I will
degraded image by the rector next I will introduce the definition of prior
introduce the definition of prior distribution for v5 a square grid graph
distribution for v5 a square grid graph TV in the refuge's of arrivals you know
TV in the refuge's of arrivals you know it in Ezra and E is the edge so the
it in Ezra and E is the edge so the prior distribution is defined as
on July 2 the broth it's represented by the movement of
it's represented by the movement of energy functions
as I as I swear
the parameter team Yaya and alpha is the we want to act
we want to act the contract is
this is because well it was people try the matter and the waves and complete
the matter and the waves and complete routine to the inverse of this
routine to the inverse of this crustacean a success in doing by natural
crustacean a success in doing by natural decomposition
in the model of the Moodle office
the awgn now we are ready to find the posterior distribution
and
we can do
ladies position that means the profit margin lambda
since we're already having our prior distribution and
the lavenders by EMS search
Pacific that will be there to function we find a connection with to Maxine
we find a connection with to Maxine is illustrate the use of all production
is illustrate the use of all production posterior distribution are we join the
posterior distribution are we join the group
group and what special abilities we define as
and what special abilities we define as the production
we will compute for each requires the inverse of the covariance magic makes
inverse of the covariance magic makes the computation time is thank you
for the image restoration
time is and thank you
really like the immunity approximation validation they lead to a scene
what do we actually do is
Saavik type of ranchers and old and the old on the mutation time a
what to me the whole algorithm what we need to do is the partial
what we need to do is the partial derivatives in another energy the energy
derivatives in another energy the energy of the fire
as for the Flyers for the triumph energy
no Allison Stockport this device but I is Alice
we know the gravity it can be written as
similarly the for the area
for the determinants of decision matrix absolutely
really the derivative
actually very hey it converged please like them 13
hey it converged please like them 13 iterations and the here
iterations and the here I will first assure you it's the patch
I will first assure you it's the patch faced the baby and three
but in total we have up to
ladies to live in that we keep the one of the decree the Prince as the rapper
in the first part is just for the average of all the projects
average of all the projects and the second part is actually is to
and the second part is actually is to attenuate the frequency for positions
attenuate the frequency for positions that do not match the record and it is
Cynthia is constant this fix the constant actually is
constant actually is where is the noise variance would
where is the noise variance would activate in the footage function we
activate in the footage function we believe is the difference between the
believe is the difference between the touch of the rapper's
and here is the result for the number of the gradient noise you make is 3 and the
the gradient noise you make is 3 and the include noise variance is their tape
include noise variance is their tape image size is 2 to 5 6 by 2 pi
I show their results by it he asked I speak tonight racial and asked to have
I speak tonight racial and asked to have dr. Shri Mataji
the Boosters ts the time as I am the feeder of the Badgers so if you remember
feeder of the Badgers so if you remember the largely work to the wrong tree
[Music]
is the result for bigger image size Oh 5 to 5
let me show you the even bigger image
yes
swing by the doctor twice
also consider the English team leader I I just popped the remark from the
I just popped the remark from the teenage member from zero enough
the otherwise
all our three matches between that
that forever after leaving my village
forever after leaving my village immediately
immediately fifty
fool on the linear record out of two points
points these more amazing wonders
these more amazing wonders yeah they are very close to each other
according to Authority benamber may be expiated
expiated I also tie the image type the previous
I also tie the image type the previous month like five five runs to buy I
month like five five runs to buy I wanted things they happen maybe the
wanted things they happen maybe the right life the vision actually is good
right life the vision actually is good in the bean bag is not inclusive that
in the bean bag is not inclusive that price and opportunity so it's
price and opportunity so it's preventively welcome
this linear time neither can you resolve a nice image most successfully than
a nice image most successfully than aberration answered all the time in all
aberration answered all the time in all cases for lasher's tries on the small
cases for lasher's tries on the small amount of teammates read the amps medium
amount of teammates read the amps medium 3d is the little battery tender linear
3d is the little battery tender linear time but for the larger amount of image
time but for the larger amount of image linear matters profound
maybe the owl earlier the selenium Athens rather than amazing of countries
Athens rather than amazing of countries in my legs
so your posture is why the number of minutes notice
let's play of equation two
if you have a distribution or even for the options and the big hominoid
the options and the big hominoid be affected by the tsunami the marries
be affected by the tsunami the marries of noise won't be pleased Sigma square
of noise won't be pleased Sigma square well if you crease the into Sigma square
well if you crease the into Sigma square a you're in it so the more the more you
a you're in it so the more the more you makes you get Latino is very you have so
makes you get Latino is very you have so is something like they'd like to add
is something like they'd like to add them together and the the the noise
them together and the the the noise variance
would you mean a cookie
if it's difference between the 932 NASA wonder for all of the matter the
wonder for all of the matter the computation time will increase
computation time will increase the number of units for the aboriginal
the number of units for the aboriginal it's very small always lifestyle website
it's very small always lifestyle website because you didn't do that keep
because you didn't do that keep syntactic it has to actually add them
syntactic it has to actually add them together but for the other matter it
together but for the other matter it really depends depends on the speech of
really depends depends on the speech of matter
I find it
with more image members the living their master has less computation time than we
master has less computation time than we do you have
oh hello everyone my name is Lucy same way I'm from the aerospace and
way I'm from the aerospace and mechanical engineering taking this
mechanical engineering taking this course it's kind of cold but a great
course it's kind of cold but a great challenge for me and it's my pleasure to
challenge for me and it's my pleasure to do my presentation about delivering
do my presentation about delivering using the things I learned in the car I
using the things I learned in the car I do this because of its very interesting
do this because of its very interesting project on the website so when we
project on the website so when we thought should be laboring we can find a
thought should be laboring we can find a lot of examples we can the most famous
lot of examples we can the most famous woman is a Caltech 1:01 the labels
woman is a Caltech 1:01 the labels airplanes or other object tools in our
airplanes or other object tools in our daily lives like a chair or table or
daily lives like a chair or table or whatever you can say of recently there's
whatever you can say of recently there's another image love love they label these
another image love love they label these birds and they can characterize about
birds and they can characterize about either and this is also the reason why
either and this is also the reason why we do this labeling before because if
we do this labeling before because if you want to know what this is you first
you want to know what this is you first have to label yet you have a big picture
have to label yet you have a big picture then we have to say where is the object
then we have to say where is the object this is a primary step
this is a primary step when we search on Google who can render
when we search on Google who can render some papers they talk about this project
some papers they talk about this project please kind of true product it is a
please kind of true product it is a customer Redmond field and we have great
customer Redmond field and we have great observations and the hidden value about
observations and the hidden value about the hand observe reservations image and
the hand observe reservations image and popular methods are iterative
popular methods are iterative conditional mode this Laster we have a
conditional mode this Laster we have a homework in human to when you do this
homework in human to when you do this this is the beginning of this project
this is the beginning of this project then based on these at the end we can do
then based on these at the end we can do a graphic art and god Carter actually it
a graphic art and god Carter actually it can be applied not only on this idea we
can be applied not only on this idea we can also applied on Vicki and thousand
can also applied on Vicki and thousand methods because the growth current
methods because the growth current basically it can kill a lot of cool
basically it can kill a lot of cool pixels not only one pixels and then
pixels not only one pixels and then distill method I will talk about is the
distill method I will talk about is the loop he believes to propagation
poster staffer to catch the master depositing metal and an advanced master
depositing metal and an advanced master that would be sequential train waited
that would be sequential train waited message conference which is based on
message conference which is based on Avicii and when I talk about this method
Avicii and when I talk about this method I hope you can tell me where I'm wrong
I hope you can tell me where I'm wrong because we can say this equation in our
because we can say this equation in our work part is observed by the total
work part is observed by the total energy the Sun from the observation and
energy the Sun from the observation and the neighbor neighbor the most important
the neighbor neighbor the most important part is
part is actually both important under this label
actually both important under this label will be actual consume the states naval
will be actual consume the states naval reserve information we came out to
reserve information we came out to change because it is what would help and
change because it is what would help and by some summarizes these two parts to
by some summarizes these two parts to have a total energy and whether accept
have a total energy and whether accept or not attractive is the picked
or not attractive is the picked alternative decided by the energy
alternative decided by the energy whether it's decrease or increase in the
whether it's decrease or increase in the Angela will have lowest damages when we
Angela will have lowest damages when we turn all the pixels and we do a lot of
images and also the weighting factors work from the preservation of bronze
work from the preservation of bronze neighbor we can till this part we
neighbor we can till this part we increase or under the division the image
increase or under the division the image will be different and then I will talk
will be different and then I will talk about the graph card both parties are
about the graph card both parties are for this part we tune with those colors
for this part we tune with those colors it's like a freezer we cut through these
it's like a freezer we cut through these parts and was an account or not it's
parts and was an account or not it's also described by the energy if Y
also described by the energy if Y invalid in brought carton 2000 army just
invalid in brought carton 2000 army just calculate the energy again but it will
calculate the energy again but it will be more computational cost because the
be more computational cost because the number of neighbors is enlarged the one
number of neighbors is enlarged the one I do this record and if I increase the
I do this record and if I increase the say the size or the D if I want to throw
say the size or the D if I want to throw up a lot of pixels and tram will be very
up a lot of pixels and tram will be very maybe not very good for some complicated
maybe not very good for some complicated applications but it's very effective
in my study I didn't surprises not broadcasting to the party it's
minimization actually there are a lot of ways to recount all the messages this is
ways to recount all the messages this is actually in my case I did it similar to
actually in my case I did it similar to the sequential trade I needed to decide
the sequential trade I needed to decide how to accept all of the messages and I
how to accept all of the messages and I needed to actually decide the formation
needed to actually decide the formation of the trade inside of this mark and in
of the trade inside of this mark and in my case I just do love to write the top
my case I just do love to write the top bottom and my last part again when I
bottom and my last part again when I can't do a color of the pixel I needed
can't do a color of the pixel I needed to maximize this message and in
to maximize this message and in calculation I do also make them because
calculation I do also make them because these two are all written in turn we
these two are all written in turn we won't find the maximized
and what we want is to have a larger be under simulate society and I have a
under simulate society and I have a weighting factors order from other
weighting factors order from other messages from the reservation and from
messages from the reservation and from some neighbors for neighbors in this
some neighbors for neighbors in this case the respect eyes
I mean the contrary to the message passing is the singular is the munster
passing is the singular is the munster of believe the publication this case the
of believe the publication this case the way how I we have a complicated not here
way how I we have a complicated not here it's maybe more complicated than range
it's maybe more complicated than range but we can the composite into a lot of
but we can the composite into a lot of groups very simple tree then we
groups very simple tree then we summarize the messages from each of
summarize the messages from each of trainees we get a total messages and
trainees we get a total messages and this works well well and there are a lot
this works well well and there are a lot of things we can design here first is
of things we can design here first is how weighted the composer the traced and
how weighted the composer the traced and how a way to infiltrate this will be
how a way to infiltrate this will be very interesting and in this case in my
very interesting and in this case in my coding I got to this left to right and
with I want to images from the quality library and
library and and the way I needed to close to turn
and the way I needed to close to turn these to a color RPG into a black white
these to a color RPG into a black white I just to use my bathroom like to try
I just to use my bathroom like to try the at which the range it should be
the at which the range it should be black this is after I am and which is
black this is after I am and which is still the black inside is a white
still the black inside is a white surrounded by the whites then I energy
surrounded by the whites then I energy is decreasing is no way to sit down the
is decreasing is no way to sit down the later I used here I can actually use
later I used here I can actually use different
this is the using I send along the board and this is mix good
drop cards here and here the culture is not very good and this is the
not very good and this is the propagation to believe to be I this is
propagation to believe to be I this is the eyes to try summarize to all the be
the eyes to try summarize to all the be other images actually long as you stab
other images actually long as you stab it just convert this is the message
it just convert this is the message accounting I to make a trade
because of my coding is only doing this to images then I I just gotta spell this
to images then I I just gotta spell this - he looks - fine then I I can also
- he looks - fine then I I can also chill before well how do they do
suppose this tasty I said if I pick another image
this leads to labels or suppose it's looked also very good for ITN
this was true
wonderful Oh
in this case I am Prince multi-ball a good because socially big marzyong
good because socially big marzyong remove this part we we don't like the
remove this part we we don't like the sustain those heart believes to
sustain those heart believes to constrain
- much better than Medicaid
and also mr. Messer the sequence to the trailer which is not a department is too
trailer which is not a department is too flexible
flexible masterda assume look at those parameters
masterda assume look at those parameters wait until the weight of each of three I
wait until the weight of each of three I have two here and also the way to strong
have two here and also the way to strong evidence and the weight from neighbors
evidence and the weight from neighbors we can tune those and the if I kill me
we can tune those and the if I kill me too
and in one way of
this could be
I don't know whether this is bad enough but listen can lead to us all those that
but listen can lead to us all those that we can select a path parameter this
we can select a path parameter this become a higher quality of photos to the
become a higher quality of photos to the picture mechanizations
because if we make it too far along
you know this is the truth our ultra spot please the whole part is to
spot please the whole part is to becoming the boat because i propagate
becoming the boat because i propagate left to right I think after tandem
left to right I think after tandem dominant this trilogy is the final a
dominant this trilogy is the final a code of throne that love a house I think
code of throne that love a house I think they did a very good coding
of
thank you for your attention
[Applause]
yeah
I don't know