welcome to another class on Republican graphical models so we were summarizing
graphical models so we were summarizing basically an example of reduction three
basically an example of reduction three algorithms so before I discussed the
algorithms so before I discussed the example once more I wanted to remind you
example once more I wanted to remind you the message passing that is applied by
the message passing that is applied by the junction tree algorithm and there is
the junction tree algorithm and there is no unfortunately schematic here I may
no unfortunately schematic here I may need to add the schematic but basically
need to add the schematic but basically what we have is we have a situation
what we have is we have a situation where I have one you know one maximal
where I have one you know one maximal clique that we call it V to the left and
clique that we call it V to the left and another W to the right in between them
another W to the right in between them we have the separator s so the idea was
we have the separator s so the idea was passing messages from V to W in a
passing messages from V to W in a forward manner this equation on the top
forward manner this equation on the top and then on reversed passing messages
and then on reversed passing messages from W back to me through the separator
from W back to me through the separator so I want to review with you the
so I want to review with you the question so then we will try to see this
question so then we will try to see this in a very specific example on what
in a very specific example on what exactly we tried to do so if you
exactly we tried to do so if you remember the separator involves the
remember the separator involves the variables that they are common to both V
variables that they are common to both V and W so obviously to show me initially
and W so obviously to show me initially initialize the separator potentials to 1
initialize the separator potentials to 1 ok so obviously to update the separator
ok so obviously to update the separator potentials we have to integrate out all
potentials we have to integrate out all the volume Wilson V except the very much
the volume Wilson V except the very much in the separator right so Ross V minor
in the separator right so Ross V minor says they are not relevant information
says they are not relevant information for W so we have to integrate them out
for W so we have to integrate them out so this is pissed R subscript s means
so this is pissed R subscript s means the potential of the separator is this
the potential of the separator is this then we go to W and we update the
then we go to W and we update the potential of the maximal clique W by
potential of the maximal clique W by multiplying by this factor of the
multiplying by this factor of the updated separator potential divided by
updated separator potential divided by the original separator potential and
the original separator potential and obviously when you start the algorithm
obviously when you start the algorithm first is equal to one in the process
first is equal to one in the process we've been tax really great
we've been tax really great so the objective just to be consistent
so the objective just to be consistent because everything has one star the
because everything has one star the updated cyber cyber star is equal to
updated cyber cyber star is equal to original the type II that we started
original the type II that we started with right now in the propagation of
with right now in the propagation of messages from W back to V so we are
messages from W back to V so we are going to update the separator potential
going to update the separator potential by starting with the potential of W and
by starting with the potential of W and you've never lost the ability potential
you've never lost the ability potential that we computed here and we're gonna
that we computed here and we're gonna integrate you have pretty valuable
integrate you have pretty valuable except desktop then we're going to go to
except desktop then we're going to go to the potential of the click V and take
the potential of the click V and take the previous value which is this and
the previous value which is this and update it began by multiplying with this
update it began by multiplying with this three double star divided by pitstop
three double star divided by pitstop alright so this is the new value of the
alright so this is the new value of the separator divided by the old value the
separator divided by the old value the new value is this the old values what we
new value is this the old values what we computed on the previous step as we go
computed on the previous step as we go from V to W and a mystic process again W
from V to W and a mystic process again W doesn't change the equations look weird
doesn't change the equations look weird but what is interesting is when we do
but what is interesting is when we do this update the the calculations are
this update the the calculations are consistent consistent in the sense that
consistent consistent in the sense that if you calculate the separation
if you calculate the separation potential by starting with this click
potential by starting with this click for W and you integrate average
for W and you integrate average everything out except s1 if you start
everything out except s1 if you start with a click of V and you integrate
with a click of V and you integrate everything out except s this is equal to
everything out except s this is equal to rot so result
rot so result consistent secure at the end of the day
consistent secure at the end of the day the separator potential is calculated
the separator potential is calculated uniquely there's no double star shared
uniquely there's no double star shared because you remember side double star
because you remember side double star maybe I should put it to look nicer side
maybe I should put it to look nicer side double star W is equal to PI star of
double star W is equal to PI star of that be okay and another thing that we
that be okay and another thing that we mentioned was that both in the forward
mentioned was that both in the forward and the backward swept the joint
and the backward swept the joint probability distribution of both the
probability distribution of both the variables in the junction tree remains
variables in the junction tree remains invariant physically okay and I have I
invariant physically okay and I have I don't think we missed a premium example
don't think we missed a premium example right click will say be here another
right click will say be here another colleague would be ste so actually you
colleague would be ste so actually you can take this as a simple example of the
can take this as a simple example of the previous case that I held so before we
previous case that I held so before we have BMW so this here is a and B WS b n3
have BMW so this here is a and B WS b n3 and the separator is b so that i am
and the separator is b so that i am showing you here with a very simple
showing you here with a very simple calculation is that each step in the
calculation is that each step in the process all effects basically remains
process all effects basically remains the same
the same alright so we're not really playing with
alright so we're not really playing with the joint distribution and a simple
the joint distribution and a simple proof in the forward step is the
proof in the forward step is the following if you calculate size style of
following if you calculate size style of V times y star of W divided by the
V times y star of W divided by the separator potential star but the way I
separator potential star but the way I remind you in a junction tree because
remind you in a junction tree because originally we started with the stability
originally we started with the stability potential equal to 1 we hide the Joint
potential equal to 1 we hide the Joint Distribution as the product of the
Distribution as the product of the potentials of all the cliques in the
potentials of all the cliques in the numerator divided by the product of the
numerator divided by the product of the potentials of all the separators so we
potentials of all the separators so we don't double count effectively for the
don't double count effectively for the separator right because
separator right because we have two potentials that say V and W
we have two potentials that say V and W right and they serve the separator
right and they serve the separator potential so we divide by that of course
potential so we divide by that of course initially this is equal to answer it's
initially this is equal to answer it's not an issue but I wanted to show you
not an issue but I wanted to show you that this remaining sequel to the
that this remaining sequel to the original joint probability distribution
original joint probability distribution at every step and we can see it here in
at every step and we can see it here in the forward step so if I calculate this
the forward step so if I calculate this quantity here and I stopped you beside
quantity here and I stopped you beside this table I remind you besides star
this table I remind you besides star doesn't change on the forward step so
doesn't change on the forward step so it's I've a the update of side W is the
it's I've a the update of side W is the website W times the sub J factor with
website W times the sub J factor with the new separator potential divided by
the new separator potential divided by the old times try W so in T star and P R
the old times try W so in T star and P R star cancel out and basically what you
star cancel out and basically what you get is you get the joint probability
get is you get the joint probability distribution that we started with so
distribution that we started with so effectively the do manipulations of the
effectively the do manipulations of the potentials for the maximal cliques and
potentials for the maximal cliques and the separators but in the process fire
the separators but in the process fire effects remain the same so we will see
effects remain the same so we will see an example what exactly form this
an example what exactly form this potential take with a very simple case
potential take with a very simple case but I think I started discussing this
but I think I started discussing this one on Tuesday so the example we talking
one on Tuesday so the example we talking about hidden models today surrounding
about hidden models today surrounding maybe spend two or three lectures so we
maybe spend two or three lectures so we do this sort of in some detail but I
do this sort of in some detail but I won't give you an application of the
won't give you an application of the junction tree algorithm on a hidden
junction tree algorithm on a hidden Markov model so then this is front of
Markov model so then this is front of the most on the mental model for
the most on the mental model for dynamics okay and
dynamics okay and the idea here is we have some
the idea here is we have some observations y0 y1 YT y capital
observations y0 y1 YT y capital traversal in time I mean I'm
traversal in time I mean I'm interpreting here it's time since we
interpreting here it's time since we talked about dynamics but to be any
talked about dynamics but to be any sequence to really and this are some
sequence to really and this are some hidden state okay
hidden state okay and but we don't know what they are and
and but we don't know what they are and so what we do is we have a dynamical
so what we do is we have a dynamical model in this case a Markovian model
model in this case a Markovian model that tells me how I move from the state
that tells me how I move from the state a time that say one to the time 2 and
a time that say one to the time 2 and then I have an observation model that
then I have an observation model that tells me as which state what's the
tells me as which state what's the probability of observing let's say y1
probability of observing let's say y1 given Q 1 so effectively I have a joint
given Q 1 so effectively I have a joint distribution that looks like this again
distribution that looks like this again we're going to give you a risk
we're going to give you a risk interpretation on what this model is
interpretation on what this model is good right in starting today basically
good right in starting today basically maybe the excuse that we reach this
maybe the excuse that we reach this point but the for now the Joint
point but the for now the Joint Distribution is basically this is a
Distribution is basically this is a directed graph is where you start right
directed graph is where you start right and the probability of the initial state
and the probability of the initial state and then you have the probability of for
and then you have the probability of for reservation loaders given the state
reservation loaders given the state which we take them to be independent
which we take them to be independent okay so given Q these wives are
okay so given Q these wives are independent and the independence comes
independent and the independence comes from this separation you can see that y
from this separation you can see that y 0 to the end of y 1 given this state
0 to the end of y 1 given this state because if you go this way it is and
because if you go this way it is and this is given the path is blocked here
this is given the path is blocked here all right but again not very important
all right but again not very important for this lecture and then we have the
for this lecture and then we have the product of these transition
product of these transition probabilities but basically give me how
probabilities but basically give me how from the state PT I go through T plus 1
from the state PT I go through T plus 1 I mean I have a graphical model that has
I mean I have a graphical model that has a joint distribution that looks like
a joint distribution that looks like this and I would like somehow to go and
this and I would like somehow to go and and apply the junction tree algorithm
and apply the junction tree algorithm and see if it sort of makes that now
and see if it sort of makes that now this looks like it's saying right even
this looks like it's saying right even though we do have observations so you
though we do have observations so you remember for change we derive the
remember for change we derive the coordinate message this alpha we derive
coordinate message this alpha we derive the backward messages beta and I'm going
the backward messages beta and I'm going to give you the recursive equations
to give you the recursive equations again and we will see that of this about
again and we will see that of this about what the Rama message just as well so
what the Rama message just as well so the idea is now the junction tree was
the idea is now the junction tree was going to give us something distant some
going to give us something distant some shape of the Americans were somehow able
shape of the Americans were somehow able love for this trivial problem we give us
love for this trivial problem we give us things but plate they look very familiar
things but plate they look very familiar interesting actually writes a realized
interesting actually writes a realized application to see what we get from this
application to see what we get from this model so the joint probability
model so the joint probability distribution again I am not gonna bother
distribution again I am not gonna bother actually relations we're going to see
actually relations we're going to see this in in next week so with the
this in in next week so with the junction tree I believe right if we do
junction tree I believe right if we do things correctly given some evidence so
things correctly given some evidence so given the measurements would say at
given the measurements would say at different times you may be interested at
different times you may be interested at this time T to calculate the posterior
this time T to calculate the posterior of the state TP this is called the
of the state TP this is called the filtering problem maybe if we given some
filtering problem maybe if we given some instruments of the time s we want to
instruments of the time s we want to predict ahead the stage but prediction
predict ahead the stage but prediction problem and those movie problem is if we
problem and those movie problem is if we are using lots of data a past time T can
are using lots of data a past time T can we come back and calculate an estimate
we come back and calculate an estimate of the state together this better more
of the state together this better more smooth from these filtering posterior
smooth from these filtering posterior distribution so this is the smoking
distribution so this is the smoking problem this are one of the reasons I
problem this are one of the reasons I want to do this hidden Markov models and
want to do this hidden Markov models and state-space models in a little bit more
state-space models in a little bit more detail right is
performance even though they I am discussing them therefore it's a men
discussing them therefore it's a men there are sort of very fundamental
there are sort of very fundamental problems in the context of data
problems in the context of data simulation so any of you who works on
simulation so any of you who works on any sort of dynamical problems from
any sort of dynamical problems from fluid mechanics to weather prediction to
fluid mechanics to weather prediction to earthquakes to whatever the vibrations
earthquakes to whatever the vibrations you know this are the problems that you
you know this are the problems that you need to know how to address the emergent
need to know how to address the emergent of academic problems they have practical
of academic problems they have practical problems at least three you need to know
problems at least three you need to know if somebody asked you what is filtering
if somebody asked you what is filtering what's prediction with this moving and
what's prediction with this moving and this topic is self-contained in a way
this topic is self-contained in a way that they have been three years many
that they have been three years many individuals have written which one after
individuals have written which one after the other rediscovering things and
the other rediscovering things and dressing them up with nice algebra
dressing them up with nice algebra things that they were known in the
things that they were known in the forties and fifties okay but lots of us
forties and fifties okay but lots of us are in discovering this with new
are in discovering this with new techniques so there hasn't been any
techniques so there hasn't been any major developments for 40 years or
major developments for 40 years or Cassini whoops don't expect to see
Cassini whoops don't expect to see something new it's just the same things
something new it's just the same things presently different okay like today I'm
presently different okay like today I'm going to present this with the junction
going to present this with the junction 3 algorithm I don't think in any of
3 algorithm I don't think in any of these books they actually bring the
these books they actually bring the junction tree algorithm because that is
junction tree algorithm because that is too complicated for people who do data
too complicated for people who do data stimulation ok so what I want to do so
stimulation ok so what I want to do so viscous the amazement we need a graph
viscous the amazement we need a graph theoretic approach right if for example
theoretic approach right if for example if you want to be simplest of these
if you want to be simplest of these problems that I mentioned before are
problems that I mentioned before are very complicated and unless you somehow
very complicated and unless you somehow use conditional independence relations
use conditional independence relations implied by the graph and an easy way to
implied by the graph and an easy way to see how complicated calculations would
see how complicated calculations would be look at the calculating for example
be look at the calculating for example the marginal likelihood so if you want
the marginal likelihood so if you want to try to to complete parameters in the
to try to to complete parameters in the model like parameters see that if
model like parameters see that if they're in the state transition model or
they're in the state transition model or in the observation model effectively we
in the observation model effectively we have to do some sort of car
have to do some sort of car model evidence by playing with you know
model evidence by playing with you know maximizing this likelihood and that is
maximizing this likelihood and that is this life is within involves integration
this life is within involves integration over all possible values of all the
over all possible values of all the states at all times so if you have you
states at all times so if you have you know we have capital T steps here and
know we have capital T steps here and each page will take and take M values
each page will take and take M values mr. problem M to power T excuse me I
mr. problem M to power T excuse me I mean if P is 4 million and M is 100 you
mean if P is 4 million and M is 100 you know then just good luck
know then just good luck cannot do it but with dysgraphia lytic
cannot do it but with dysgraphia lytic approaches you can actually do this
approaches you can actually do this problem on your little PC okay and and
problem on your little PC okay and and we hope that you will do this you see as
we hope that you will do this you see as a former problem as well okay in in
a former problem as well okay in in details next well Tuesday I wanted to
details next well Tuesday I wanted to remind you in the context of what we're
remind you in the context of what we're gonna do with Junction three algorithms
gonna do with Junction three algorithms on how the conditional dependence
on how the conditional dependence relations and the definitions of the
relations and the definitions of the various interest points of interest you
various interest points of interest you can calculate for example basis given
can calculate for example basis given all of the data Y right this is this
all of the data Y right this is this nothing distribution gives you the
nothing distribution gives you the probability of P P so what I say
probability of P P so what I say assistance is right from time 0 to time
assistance is right from time 0 to time capital T so if you can travel all right
capital T so if you can travel all right if you know I'm too nice calculations
if you know I'm too nice calculations that you guys can follow but it comes
that you guys can follow but it comes out this is making distribution is the
out this is making distribution is the product of this joint distribution and
product of this joint distribution and the product of this conditional
the product of this conditional distribution divided by the marginal of
distribution divided by the marginal of Y so this tradition is is the
Y so this tradition is is the probability of observing y0 y1 wealthy a
probability of observing y0 y1 wealthy a number of safety 3 right and what is
number of safety 3 right and what is nice
nice this is holding a pee-pee observing when
this is holding a pee-pee observing when I pick this one away people are still
I pick this one away people are still like fidelity okay in the note that I'm
like fidelity okay in the note that I'm concerned I have not finished them yet
concerned I have not finished them yet though for its immense that meant them
though for its immense that meant them 200 something pages in in some groups
200 something pages in in some groups this service is called at least today
this service is called at least today when the Condors the Alpha mastered and
when the Condors the Alpha mastered and this world economy domestics and you
this world economy domestics and you will see why I call it out from it
will see why I call it out from it alphas we call it on for change the
alphas we call it on for change the forward message right and bit enough
forward message right and bit enough with message from Bella convinced you
with message from Bella convinced you that this is really requires a forward
that this is really requires a forward calculation or update as we move forward
calculation or update as we move forward in India hmm and this required backward
in India hmm and this required backward calculations so anyways when I wanted to
calculations so anyways when I wanted to say the definition of alpha in other
say the definition of alpha in other books rather than being given by this
books rather than being given by this Joint Distribution is really the
Joint Distribution is really the posterior of QT given y 0 to Y T so
posterior of QT given y 0 to Y T so silly the tutoring distribution it
silly the tutoring distribution it doesn't really at the end of the day you
doesn't really at the end of the day you will notice any book reviews or any
will notice any book reviews or any papers you refer when they complete this
papers you refer when they complete this a lot of times necessary not equal they
a lot of times necessary not equal they seek proportional right so whatever the
seek proportional right so whatever the clinician you use for this if it is
clinician you use for this if it is equal to i4 proportional to alpha you
equal to i4 proportional to alpha you get the same equation so that should not
get the same equation so that should not be an issue so let me give you let me
be an issue so let me give you let me give you B a question that we will
give you B a question that we will probably sort of see next week when we
probably sort of see next week when we discuss about hidden Markov models this
discuss about hidden Markov models this is the plate for this - quantity ok the
is the plate for this - quantity ok the Alpha message so the calculator time T
Alpha message so the calculator time T plus 1 alpha you require to know Alfred
plus 1 alpha you require to know Alfred time QT and so you know this is
time QT and so you know this is basically a forward recursive
basically a forward recursive calculation so you start from time 0 you
calculation so you start from time 0 you can calculate the master time t1 and
can calculate the master time t1 and and you can keep going so this is
and you can keep going so this is exactly like we have seen for change the
exactly like we have seen for change the difference of postulate for change we
difference of postulate for change we didn't have an observation model we only
didn't have an observation model we only had a transition model but you know what
had a transition model but you know what if you actually take this and you don't
if you actually take this and you don't be together with this in principle you
be together with this in principle you get the same equation as for change and
get the same equation as for change and some words actually we don't want to
some words actually we don't want to treat this as a new problem they merge
treat this as a new problem they merge the evolution equations the dynamics to
the evolution equations the dynamics to the observation model so they can
the observation model so they can recycle the questions that use for
recycle the questions that use for checks but sort of here it's nicely
checks but sort of here it's nicely written okay because you explicitly see
written okay because you explicitly see the the observation model and and also
the the observation model and and also of this transition probabilities from
of this transition probabilities from state T to T plus 1 okay so this is the
state T to T plus 1 okay so this is the forward recursive equation for finding
forward recursive equation for finding alpha this is now the beta messes it
alpha this is now the beta messes it comes to look like that and you notice
comes to look like that and you notice the calculated because QT we need not be
the calculated because QT we need not be the QT plus one so this is a bad word
the QT plus one so this is a bad word equation and when you have made often
equation and when you have made often bit at a given time by using that both
bit at a given time by using that both forward and backward messages
forward and backward messages effectively you can calculate this
effectively you can calculate this moving distribution of QT given all the
moving distribution of QT given all the data from y 0 to Y T by multiplying the
data from y 0 to Y T by multiplying the messages that arrived from left and
messages that arrived from left and right at up to know the time T the
right at up to know the time T the aluminum we did message-passing having a
aluminum we did message-passing having a 5 marginal right you take the messages
5 marginal right you take the messages that arrive in unknown and you multiply
that arrive in unknown and you multiply them so it's not surprising that shear
them so it's not surprising that shear so we get the same relation so this you
so we get the same relation so this you know there is no Junction Ravens no
know there is no Junction Ravens no nothing you can derive this you know
nothing you can derive this you know using conditional dependence relation so
using conditional dependence relation so everything you just can deriving the
everything you just can deriving the pantograph
pantograph so next week we will formally derive
so next week we will formally derive this using message passing algorithm
this using message passing algorithm sand
sand and the fact of the office and things
and the fact of the office and things like that but today I want to go rather
like that but today I want to go rather extreme and try to somehow we derive
extreme and try to somehow we derive this with the junction 3 algorithm so we
this with the junction 3 algorithm so we can just live the junction tree
can just live the junction tree algorithm behind us ok because it's you
algorithm behind us ok because it's you know it's a complicated topic it's it's
know it's a complicated topic it's it's much better to have it to cover it
much better to have it to cover it earlier on today I'm going to give you
earlier on today I'm going to give you another block force algorithm that
another block force algorithm that somehow if you don't see often in in you
somehow if you don't see often in in you know in references but we will see
know in references but we will see somehow that it's natural backwards
somehow that it's natural backwards approach basically to whole period
approach basically to whole period actually done the beta messages and
actually done the beta messages and these are what we call the dominant
these are what we call the dominant cities so there are no messages so this
cities so there are no messages so this is the probability of QT given all the
is the probability of QT given all the data y0 y1 to write it ok so hopefully I
data y0 y1 to write it ok so hopefully I wrote this correctly right ok so now I
wrote this correctly right ok so now I need to know why is this a backwards
need to know why is this a backwards message well if you do the algebra right
message well if you do the algebra right and nothing else for conditional
and nothing else for conditional independence relations you can see that
independence relations you can see that this one of grammar sweetie don't their
this one of grammar sweetie don't their attention to the denominator is really a
attention to the denominator is really a normalizing factor but it involves the
normalizing factor but it involves the family it involves the calculation of
family it involves the calculation of the Alpha message which remember it's
the Alpha message which remember it's for good but involves function of
for good but involves function of anomalous is that this computer time T
anomalous is that this computer time T plus 1 so to be able to calculate gamma
plus 1 so to be able to calculate gamma time DT at time T you need start
time DT at time T you need start backwards from the end of the chain but
backwards from the end of the chain but you need also to do the first
you need also to do the first development step to calculate the Alpha
development step to calculate the Alpha message right so you work forward you
message right so you work forward you finish with the Alpha relation and then
finish with the Alpha relation and then once you have those you can start going
once you have those you can start going backwards starting with the gamut
backwards starting with the gamut to capital P and then keep updating this
to capital P and then keep updating this as you go backwards okay and there is a
as you go backwards okay and there is a boundary condition of course at time
boundary condition of course at time capital T so you can so this works okay
capital T so you can so this works okay and don't need to give you this so let's
and don't need to give you this so let's look at the junction tree in exactly
look at the junction tree in exactly what the junction tree algorithm is
what the junction tree algorithm is going to do for us
remember in the junction tree we have to put we have to find the maximal cliques
put we have to find the maximal cliques and you notice here the maximal cliques
and you notice here the maximal cliques involve to knowledge others that click
involve to knowledge others that click here to see what you want you want you
here to see what you want you want you to etcetera this I have this clicks so
to etcetera this I have this clicks so this potential while chopping the
this potential while chopping the potential subside q1 q2 is the
potential subside q1 q2 is the probability of T 2 given Q on this the
probability of T 2 given Q on this the probability of q1 given to 0 these are
probability of q1 given to 0 these are my transition probabilities this is high
my transition probabilities this is high potentials across the tain and then we
potentials across the tain and then we have the observation clicks that involve
have the observation clicks that involve Q 1 y 1 y 2 y 2 and this will be
Q 1 y 1 y 2 y 2 and this will be observation clicks alright so this for
observation clicks alright so this for example is the probability of y 1 given
example is the probability of y 1 given 2 our probability of Y 2 given T 2 etc
2 our probability of Y 2 given T 2 etc and we take this up to time capital T in
and we take this up to time capital T in a suppose at time 0 you want because you
a suppose at time 0 you want because you want to make this a 3 right so we can
want to make this a 3 right so we can define this to be the probability of to
define this to be the probability of to 0 times the observation of y 0 given to
0 times the observation of y 0 given to 0 so really this is the Joint
0 so really this is the Joint Distribution of Q 0 y 0 you see that I
Distribution of Q 0 y 0 you see that I mean a time 0 right I'm gonna have I'm
mean a time 0 right I'm gonna have I'm going to start I'm going to sample to 0
going to start I'm going to sample to 0 from the initial distribution P of Q 0
from the initial distribution P of Q 0 and then given to 0 then I'm going to
and then given to 0 then I'm going to say what's the probability of y 0 given
say what's the probability of y 0 given to 0 so I put the two things together
to 0 so I put the two things together and I define them as this potential okay
and I define them as this potential okay just to make things easy so my junction
just to make things easy so my junction 3 loops I gotten and what you also see
3 loops I gotten and what you also see is the separators that you can see here
is the separators that you can see here these two nodes and one thing in common
these two nodes and one thing in common which is to 0 these two knowledge get
which is to 0 these two knowledge get one thing in common which is Q 1 so I
one thing in common which is Q 1 so I give different a lots of Greek symbols
give different a lots of Greek symbols here if you can pronounce them from
here if you can pronounce them from you're gonna get an extra bonus point in
you're gonna get an extra bonus point in your homework by Subic okay so this is
your homework by Subic okay so this is again Q to P of Q on etcetera
so so we introduce this right through this potentials are these transition
this potentials are these transition probabilities these are the observation
probabilities these are the observation models all right so we initialize all
models all right so we initialize all the potentials to one right so we start
the potentials to one right so we start we put every potential to be called
we put every potential to be called every separator to be the potential
every separator to be the potential survives be equal to 1 I have to wait to
survives be equal to 1 I have to wait to know what its life has right but don't
know what its life has right but don't read this and we will explain this
read this and we will explain this graphically ok ok
graphically ok ok from the clique 50 YP so maybe from this
from the clique 50 YP so maybe from this click here to - ok
click here to - ok again we are getting the same messages
again we are getting the same messages from this clicked up to this trick so
from this clicked up to this trick so remember when you services are right you
remember when you services are right you are going to have to update the
are going to have to update the separator and then once you have take
separator and then once you have take the separator then you have to abate the
the separator then you have to abate the potential side to one key to the
potential side to one key to the election but right now I'm going to take
election but right now I'm going to take messages propagating from here up all
messages propagating from here up all the way so from side petrol right to
the way so from side petrol right to subside - auntie - alright can you tell
subside - auntie - alright can you tell me traumatically right so we don't need
me traumatically right so we don't need the questions based on the junction tree
the questions based on the junction tree algorithm so we start with one what is
algorithm so we start with one what is the new separator potential which is a
the new separator potential which is a function of t2
I see something on the computers like that you know it was like and I went to
that you know it was like and I went to some high place they don't like myself
some high place they don't like myself cup you know right so must be something
cup you know right so must be something like that everything is in the computer
like that everything is in the computer all right so that's why I'm not gonna be
all right so that's why I'm not gonna be posting anything anymore you know it's
posting anything anymore you know it's too tiring try this blood so what is
too tiring try this blood so what is that benefit separate the potential you
that benefit separate the potential you remember to find the updated potential
remember to find the updated potential maybe we have to do this potential here
maybe we have to do this potential here we have integrated with respect to what
we have integrated with respect to what variable at this point okay okay because
variable at this point okay okay because clearly with exactly the junction tree
clearly with exactly the junction tree algorithm knows best
algorithm knows best so we don't otherwise right so you tell
so we don't otherwise right so you tell me when I integrate this with respect to
me when I integrate this with respect to Y to change the relative and tell me
Y to change the relative and tell me what that will give you
so when I integrate this potential we discover this potential is to respect to
discover this potential is to respect to Y 2
Y 2 what will the Z star be what is this
what will the Z star be what is this potential
you have to think again our original problem right
problem right what is that potential here here I can
what is that potential here here I can say is it's the king of you so when you
say is it's the king of you so when you named the greatest returns with respect
named the greatest returns with respect to what bhari maang
to what bhari maang we said why son I'll observe right now
we said why son I'll observe right now so with respect to how much is that so
so with respect to how much is that so the separation potential then will not
the separation potential then will not change all right how about this
change all right how about this potential here so the message now from
potential here so the message now from the superlative was in there
the superlative was in there so we have made this form of this
so we have made this form of this potential will be there is a potential
potential will be there is a potential times we have delegates of electric
times we have delegates of electric potential divided by the original
potential divided by the original potential separator potential which is
potential separator potential which is relative motion so this potential we
relative motion so this potential we should not say so when messages with
should not say so when messages with wise being an observed when messages are
wise being an observed when messages are sent from this critics upwards the this
sent from this critics upwards the this potential sigh of q0 q1 q1 q2 etc do not
potential sigh of q0 q1 q1 q2 etc do not change so the junction tree algorithm
change so the junction tree algorithm does nothing ok all right so let's see
does nothing ok all right so let's see [Applause]
[Applause] so now let's do the following thing
so now let's do the following thing let's send messages from from k0 y 0 to
let's send messages from from k0 y 0 to p 0 qm messages hmm so we're going to
p 0 qm messages hmm so we're going to send messages from here to there from
send messages from here to there from there to there and of course from here
there to there and of course from here to there so if this message what is so
to there so if this message what is so best to make is going to send messages
best to make is going to send messages to this plea can you tell me what is the
to this plea can you tell me what is the objective value is going to be of P star
objective value is going to be of P star to 0
using the main idea of the algorithm start to calculate the new value fish
start to calculate the new value fish this time to zero what do we have to do
this time to zero what do we have to do to this potential interview with respect
to this potential interview with respect my body my body will do zero so remember
my body my body will do zero so remember this potential he had told me it was the
this potential he had told me it was the joint distribution of Q zero Y zero
joint distribution of Q zero Y zero remember because it included the it
remember because it included the it included the prior of K 0 and also the
included the prior of K 0 and also the observation of y 0 into 0 since we know
observation of y 0 into 0 since we know joint okay Broadway so the reason
joint okay Broadway so the reason potentially with the joint circle
potentially with the joint circle integrative respect to y 0 you get P of
integrative respect to y 0 you get P of Q 0 so immediately you can see that this
Q 0 so immediately you can see that this peak potential becomes a marginal so
peak potential becomes a marginal so suddenly has a meaning it's nothing else
suddenly has a meaning it's nothing else but the marginal of to 0 so let's see
but the marginal of to 0 so let's see what's going to happen the prop dated we
what's going to happen the prop dated we will take the or potential which is the
will take the or potential which is the probability you are given to 0 and this
probability you are given to 0 and this we told is the marginal so this this
we told is the marginal so this this product is the joint of proceeding QR so
product is the joint of proceeding QR so the clinic potentials now become
the clinic potentials now become marginal social so maybe I should call
marginal social so maybe I should call this potential now becomes 2 marginally
this potential now becomes 2 marginally maybe this becomes a remember when we
maybe this becomes a remember when we said that the joint probability
said that the joint probability distribution is the product of the
distribution is the product of the maximal clique potentials divided by the
maximal clique potentials divided by the separators can you actually visualize
separators can you actually visualize now about what because it first becomes
now about what because it first becomes this marginal so the other one to become
this marginal so the other one to become the submariners maybe that works really
the submariners maybe that works really okay and you can guys do the algebra and
okay and you can guys do the algebra and you can see that which works fine
so when you send message from here to there alright and and from there to
there alright and and from there to there okay
there okay well this becomes this marginal and I
well this becomes this marginal and I remind you the message from here upwards
remind you the message from here upwards does not fit so now what we will need to
does not fit so now what we will need to do is we will need to send the message
do is we will need to send the message from here down to the click Q 1 yr so
from here down to the click Q 1 yr so you have to tell me what is the new
you have to tell me what is the new variant does it understand of going to
variant does it understand of going to be sure it is the degree of this no
be sure it is the degree of this no potential when the message comes from
potential when the message comes from here and it's going down so how do I
here and it's going down so how do I calculate this staff does it ever stop
calculate this staff does it ever stop now
now [Music]
with respect and tell me that this potential list is P of Q 0 Q 1 so 0 0 of
potential list is P of Q 0 Q 1 so 0 0 of acumen becomes what becomes a 0 now do
acumen becomes what becomes a 0 now do you say becomes P of pure refers to this
you say becomes P of pure refers to this potential originally because you never
potential originally because you never changed what if you reverse the
changed what if you reverse the probability of y 1 given Q 1 x now the
probability of y 1 given Q 1 x now the new potential Z that will start and we
new potential Z that will start and we told me was what B if you are divided by
told me was what B if you are divided by 1 so the new potential is going to be
1 so the new potential is going to be what now
so easily it was pure white women q1 and then you multiplied by P a few ones so
then you multiplied by P a few ones so that gives you a circle of why you want
that gives you a circle of why you want so you can see now that even this you
so you can see now that even this you know potentials also become marginal so
know potentials also become marginal so happy the only the peak potentials
happy the only the peak potentials become arsenals and then effectively the
become arsenals and then effectively the separators becomes her marginal or even
separators becomes her marginal or even you may say what's going on where is the
you may say what's going on where is the other message where's the bigger message
other message where's the bigger message I'm confused right so okay so let's see
I'm confused right so okay so let's see so this is just a schematic again of the
so this is just a schematic again of the what the other if like we presented
what the other if like we presented right so we start sending messages from
right so we start sending messages from these clips by just completing the
these clips by just completing the separators all right and then using this
separators all right and then using this product which we've updated separator
product which we've updated separator potential divided by the originals we
potential divided by the originals we update this Creek potential and the only
update this Creek potential and the only difference on this schematic from what
difference on this schematic from what we had before here this node has
we had before here this node has multiple children so we have taken
multiple children so we have taken further the same way we do with message
further the same way we do with message passing and then on the reverse step we
passing and then on the reverse step we distribute the information from this
distribute the information from this node to the children so we applied the
node to the children so we applied the separators alright so we calculate the
separators alright so we calculate the separators the way we did before and
separators the way we did before and then we multiplied with the double style
then we multiplied with the double style which we trying to update the potentials
which we trying to update the potentials of this now right that's what we did
okay
you know right so think of this so this can be represented as a well-defined
can be represented as a well-defined table okay so the difference because
table okay so the difference because this y star given is I am going to take
this y star given is I am going to take these two positive potentials to be the
these two positive potentials to be the conditional of YT given 50 so if I look
conditional of YT given 50 so if I look here I'm going to fake this to start
here I'm going to fake this to start with that is the condition of y2 given Q
with that is the condition of y2 given Q - okay in case you know you know you can
- okay in case you know you know you can come up to this you know with
come up to this you know with forgiveness but let's say I am going to
forgiveness but let's say I am going to use the separator potential to be the
use the separator potential to be the probability of YJ given kitty
probability of YJ given kitty fortunately what happens to the alpha
fortunately what happens to the alpha messages to the bigger messages etc
messages to the bigger messages etc let's figure out investors that is
let's figure out investors that is propagating in this case flow from here
propagating in this case flow from here to this click alright and then down
to this click alright and then down there so how to update using the
there so how to update using the junction tree algorithm this joint
junction tree algorithm this joint potential of 50 and 50 plus one
potential of 50 and 50 plus one so remember messages are going to be
so remember messages are going to be coming from this separator and they're
coming from this separator and they're gonna be coming from this separator and
gonna be coming from this separator and we are actually start with that this
we are actually start with that this message is coming from the separators
message is coming from the separators have no all right because my name is
have no all right because my name is Raquel should be so we have to start you
Raquel should be so we have to start you know with this messages from the leeches
know with this messages from the leeches let's say that they're known and we want
let's say that they're known and we want to update this potential emotion we want
to update this potential emotion we want to update this operator potential there
to update this operator potential there so this operator sends a message and we
so this operator sends a message and we want to see how this potential changes
want to see how this potential changes so look at this equation the first line
so look at this equation the first line and told me it could be the junction to
and told me it could be the junction to algorithm members mistake
what we're supposed to be the new potential of this potential the new
potential of this potential the new potential supposed to be the new
potential supposed to be the new potential which is this times the
potential which is this times the product of the Feist and demanded money
product of the Feist and demanded money originally we and the original three
originally we and the original three senses we take them equal to 1 so the
senses we take them equal to 1 so the show the product here will be of this
show the product here will be of this part of QT and the product of this part
part of QT and the product of this part of QT plus 1 and I told you that there
of QT plus 1 and I told you that there takes the start of KP plus 1 to make the
takes the start of KP plus 1 to make the probability of YT plus 1 given QT plus 1
probability of YT plus 1 given QT plus 1 so basically the only thing that I am
so basically the only thing that I am this here that doesn't literally divide
this here that doesn't literally divide right something from the separated
right something from the separated potential from k plus 1 ways by
potential from k plus 1 ways by marginalizing this potential because
marginalizing this potential because this click potential the members is not
this click potential the members is not a distribution as environment variables
a distribution as environment variables because we always observed so in
because we always observed so in principle I am using this by calculating
principle I am using this by calculating from the case that we had before where
from the case that we had before where this thing was the new potential child
this thing was the new potential child is the or potential times P star times
is the or potential times P star times the separator potential Z star so this
the separator potential Z star so this is my transition model this is this
is my transition model this is this power of U star and this is my
power of U star and this is my observation model and let's calculate
observation model and let's calculate now so this is the new update can give
now so this is the new update can give in a question to calculate this time 50
in a question to calculate this time 50 plus 1 what would be so we were moving
plus 1 what would be so we were moving forward on the chain what will be the
forward on the chain what will be the new simulator potential fist R of Q T
new simulator potential fist R of Q T plus 1
plus 1 what's my definition of calculating you
what's my definition of calculating you know the forward a page of them of the
know the forward a page of them of the separator potential when we need to come
separator potential when we need to come to do to calculate this kind of TP plus
to do to calculate this kind of TP plus one we need to start with what potential
remember the crystals are calculated if we have strictly potential and the
we have strictly potential and the message propagate right to the separator
message propagate right to the separator we technically potential finally the way
we technically potential finally the way the various materials from the separator
the various materials from the separator so that potential do you take we take
so that potential do you take we take the Tristar QT QT plus 1 that was just a
the Tristar QT QT plus 1 that was just a blanket this is the potential we just
blanket this is the potential we just have a few things here so we're going to
have a few things here so we're going to take this and we're going to integrate
take this and we're going to integrate what kind of allowed completely all
what kind of allowed completely all right so to define crystal 50 plus 1
right so to define crystal 50 plus 1 we're going to have this size star of QT
we're going to have this size star of QT QT plus 1 which is this expression from
QT plus 1 which is this expression from the slide before and we're going to
the slide before and we're going to integrate this with QT if you convinced
integrate this with QT if you convinced you know what the Alpha mess is at 50
you know what the Alpha mess is at 50 plus 1 and this is the Alpha messed up
plus 1 and this is the Alpha messed up UT this equation is identical the
UT this equation is identical the equation that you derived with the
equation that you derived with the conditional independence relations that
conditional independence relations that I gave you earlier
I gave you earlier so the junction tree hug with basically
so the junction tree hug with basically discovered a well-known recursive
discovered a well-known recursive equation for updating the correlations
equation for updating the correlations okay
and it is sort of a very nice I mean to me that's the best example to
me that's the best example to demonstrate how the junction tree
demonstrate how the junction tree algorithm works because it gives you an
algorithm works because it gives you an answer that
answer that you know it is not obvious but you will
you know it is not obvious but you will get it but you know but if you don't
get it but you know but if you don't have it you know that there's a problem
have it you know that there's a problem so this is a welcome basically proof of
so this is a welcome basically proof of consistency and the working ability of
consistency and the working ability of the or reduction tree algorithm ok so
the or reduction tree algorithm ok so this is the alpha message and so when
this is the alpha message and so when you propagate the message is all the way
you propagate the message is all the way to the you know to the location you vote
to the you know to the location you vote from the leaves all the way to the root
from the leaves all the way to the root at the end of the day if you calculate
at the end of the day if you calculate the updated the final updating potential
the updated the final updating potential your sandwich here the size part of Q
your sandwich here the size part of Q capital P and Q capital t minus 1 all
capital P and Q capital t minus 1 all right this is I am using the equation we
right this is I am using the equation we had on the previous slide when I apply
had on the previous slide when I apply this to the root effectively you can
this to the root effectively you can show that this gives you the joint
show that this gives you the joint distribution of y 0 to y capital T and
distribution of y 0 to y capital T and QT minus 1 to P P so actually when you
QT minus 1 to P P so actually when you integrate these two variables out on
integrate these two variables out on this final update of size star you can
this final update of size star you can get the marginal aptitude with a forward
get the marginal aptitude with a forward calculation ok
calculation ok so effectively the calculation of the
so effectively the calculation of the marginal likelihood from the calculation
marginal likelihood from the calculation that takes them to apparent complexity
that takes them to apparent complexity now it becomes something much easier
now it becomes something much easier because you only have to integrate two
because you only have to integrate two variables with the assumption of course
variables with the assumption of course that this alpha messages can be computed
that this alpha messages can be computed recursively
recursively from this equation at which appear
from this equation at which appear that's basically you know there are
that's basically you know there are multiplications here of this K by K
multiplications here of this K by K matrix with a k-dimensional vector so
matrix with a k-dimensional vector so the complexity of this is balance of all
the complexity of this is balance of all basically right
basically right you know it's not too complicated so
you know it's not too complicated so this correlation was not going backwards
this correlation was not going backwards can somebody help me to say when we get
can somebody help me to say when we get the beta messages or we get this wheel
the beta messages or we get this wheel dominus disease but usually you don't
dominus disease but usually you don't see them when you talk about
okay because so we need to point t double star of kitty can you help me on
double star of kitty can you help me on how the population may look like just so
how the population may look like just so you know remember to update you know if
you know remember to update you know if you have this separate the right and
you have this separate the right and strength semesters right so the
strength semesters right so the potentials basically would be the
potentials basically would be the original potentials x divided by T star
original potentials x divided by T star all right and then when you integrate
all right and then when you integrate everything out apparently actually from
everything out apparently actually from this message that comes from below when
this message that comes from below when you integrate out to tea you'll be able
you integrate out to tea you'll be able to get switched double style 50 so what
to get switched double style 50 so what should I write
in anticipation does this we agree on this
this the psystar novel style of QT QT + 1 is
the psystar novel style of QT QT + 1 is the previous potential knowledge P
the previous potential knowledge P double star divided by Q prime what
double star divided by Q prime what happened to the previous model no there
happened to the previous model no there is a picture here okay so so look at
is a picture here okay so so look at this equation is this the next sensor
this equation is this the next sensor you do a papist
you do a papist I think the on potential I multiplied
I think the on potential I multiplied with the double star and I'm going to do
with the double star and I'm going to do my starting from them until I won't find
my starting from them until I won't find that recursive relation for this divided
that recursive relation for this divided by the original message 3 star which was
by the original message 3 star which was my initial message we've never from the
my initial message we've never from the forward algorithm all right so this is
forward algorithm all right so this is the potential okay now how do we get all
the potential okay now how do we get all right
right so how do we get feedback we start with
so how do we get feedback we start with kitty
so what is dissipation tell you what
basically what I do is I take I stop all right because from what I say this is
right because from what I say this is try start or a freestyle times P double
try start or a freestyle times P double prime and then I integrate out to T plus
prime and then I integrate out to T plus one
one now I don't see anything coming from
now I don't see anything coming from below is that the we monitored nothing -
below is that the we monitored nothing - from below
knowing that the equations correct seems to me nothing comes from below right
to me nothing comes from below right what you guys were going to be in in
what you guys were going to be in in terrible
terrible so let's assuming that nothing comes
so let's assuming that nothing comes from this all right so what sending
from this all right so what sending message is so this is actually you know
message is so this is actually you know what this is of the distributive step so
what this is of the distributive step so the idea here is you are going to have
the idea here is you are going to have this message sending you a message this
this message sending you a message this way and a message that way so we will
way and a message that way so we will update this we will update that but
update this we will update that but right now we're looking on the back
right now we're looking on the back wants to distribute there where this
wants to distribute there where this double star potential will update this
double star potential will update this will update out and then we'll update
will update out and then we'll update that this is the new message to double
that this is the new message to double star and if you rent it okay explicitly
star and if you rent it okay explicitly and you crave this will double star to
and you crave this will double star to be a real message this equation that you
be a real message this equation that you get is identical to the gamma backwards
get is identical to the gamma backwards propagation message that you can get
propagation message that you can get directly with conditional independence
directly with conditional independence relations so the idea here is rather
relations so the idea here is rather than doing a forward step where you find
than doing a forward step where you find the outcome essence and apocryphal
the outcome essence and apocryphal define the beta messages you can reform
define the beta messages you can reform unless you define the alpha messages
unless you define the alpha messages change the Alpha messages and then you
change the Alpha messages and then you do ma quad step because we need the
do ma quad step because we need the alchemist is here to update the data
alchemist is here to update the data messages and once you have the a
messages and once you have the a question there are no messages you can
question there are no messages you can basically compute any quantity of
basically compute any quantity of interest directly so you can do the
interest directly so you can do the filtering you know the smoothing
filtering you know the smoothing distributions predictions
distributions predictions etc directly using this miss messages so
etc directly using this miss messages so that's how the algorithm looks basically
that's how the algorithm looks basically for Junction tree okay and while suggest
for Junction tree okay and while suggest us you know spend some time doing the
us you know spend some time doing the answer Rob I can't write because we made
answer Rob I can't write because we made the the a page a list
actually even closer I said we have them a nice plot this does really do anything
a nice plot this does really do anything you need to know alright this is the
you need to know alright this is the junction 300 okay so you collect
junction 300 okay so you collect messages from the children how do you do
messages from the children how do you do this marginalizing this potential
this marginalizing this potential eliminating all but the bottom was
eliminating all but the bottom was involved in the separators then form the
involved in the separators then form the product of the new separators divided by
product of the new separators divided by the old ones multiplying with the
the old ones multiplying with the current potential you update the
current potential you update the potential that's the phonograph step
potential that's the phonograph step down and if you want meant to go
down and if you want meant to go backwards and distribute information to
backwards and distribute information to the children effectively what you need
the children effectively what you need to do is find a new supply of
to do is find a new supply of pretentious integrating everything out
pretentious integrating everything out except the separator variables and then
except the separator variables and then update basically the new potentials as
update basically the new potentials as the old ones
the old ones times the product of the new separator
times the product of the new separator potentials this P double star divided by
potentials this P double star divided by the previous ones and the previous ones
the previous ones and the previous ones remember there would be one that you
remember there would be one that you computed in the forward step so you can
computed in the forward step so you can actually appreciate here for something
actually appreciate here for something you can say if this were the alpha
you can say if this were the alpha messages right you can see here you need
messages right you can see here you need to keep track of the other messages to
to keep track of the other messages to be able to do the distribution of
be able to do the distribution of information for fairness to the children
so this iWitness is basically as powerful as you can get with
powerful as you can get with probabilistic graphical models and you
probabilistic graphical models and you know there are sort of different type of
know there are sort of different type of ways of implementing this that I think
ways of implementing this that I think we highlighted on the lecture on
we highlighted on the lecture on Thursday but - what you see this is what
Thursday but - what you see this is what you get okay and it's nice because in
you get okay and it's nice because in essence the algorithm is really doing
essence the algorithm is really doing inference on a tree but the tree is a
inference on a tree but the tree is a tree of cliques so basically we to be
tree of cliques so basically we to be able to use all these ideas we transform
able to use all these ideas we transform the original glass right the rafter all
the original glass right the rafter all of the left--it to a junction tree which
of the left--it to a junction tree which is you know a tree basically potentials
is you know a tree basically potentials that are clicked and we notice when you
that are clicked and we notice when you implement this algorithm basically at
implement this algorithm basically at least with no evidence the potentials
least with no evidence the potentials come to be marginals the separators come
come to be marginals the separators come to be sub master what evidence is a wee
to be sub master what evidence is a wee bit more complicated than that any
bit more complicated than that any questions about the junction tree
questions about the junction tree algorithm you need to at least you know
algorithm you need to at least you know I would suggest this you know maybe take
I would suggest this you know maybe take you have not even you know the hmm
you have not even you know the hmm mobile same model I only have leaves you
mobile same model I only have leaves you know the dynamic you know the transition
know the dynamic you know the transition of states and apply this and see if you
of states and apply this and see if you get you know the Alpha and the beta
get you know the Alpha and the beta messages exactly as we did before and
messages exactly as we did before and then of course repeat these calculations
then of course repeat these calculations try to some propagating messages from
try to some propagating messages from the leaves to the rope the root path and
the leaves to the rope the root path and take what you get and see what you get
take what you get and see what you get is what's listed in the book
is what's listed in the book on forward and backward propagation 136
on forward and backward propagation 136 art with a lot of time but we can now
art with a lot of time but we can now relax
relax really and going another presentation
okay
so I really want to you know do good backflips and discuss about the
backflips and discuss about the elementary thinks about Markov models
elementary thinks about Markov models and in the process of course discussing
and in the process of course discussing the sentimental things we receive
the sentimental things we receive different implementations of this
different implementations of this forward and market messages but they
forward and market messages but they want the precision of this lectures as
want the precision of this lectures as part of for doing you know built a
part of for doing you know built a simulation using probabilistic graphical
simulation using probabilistic graphical models and actually some of you are
models and actually some of you are interested on on projects right you can
interested on on projects right you can see welcome to slice and start your own
see welcome to slice and start your own works then they can be lots of very
works then they can be lots of very complicated see the map of northern
complicated see the map of northern shore state-space models with multiple
shore state-space models with multiple change that they are interacting with
change that they are interacting with each other with a lot of complexity with
each other with a lot of complexity with observation notice that there the
observation notice that there the likelihood mods are nonlinear so if you
likelihood mods are nonlinear so if you can do lots of fancy things with it
can do lots of fancy things with it alright so not only ambition when I try
alright so not only ambition when I try to do through the very elementary things
to do through the very elementary things when something will only have
when something will only have discussions I'm going to bypass it but
discussions I'm going to bypass it but you have an opportunity to to leave that
you have an opportunity to to leave that again but when there's something in this
again but when there's something in this one that we haven't seen it even if it's
one that we haven't seen it even if it's trivial we would spend something
trivial we would spend something sometime
all right so you may ask me why do we go this
so you may ask me why do we go this backwards now to do these things you
backwards now to do these things you know because we have the luxury I finish
know because we have the luxury I finish covering the course so now I can just
covering the course so now I can just have fun right that's all because if we
have fun right that's all because if we go other ways and we do Junction tree
go other ways and we do Junction tree algorithm in May then you say what is
algorithm in May then you say what is going on here right there yeah all right
maybe you should record the yes right so you can play recorder say yeah what
you can play recorder say yeah what basically considering a collection of
basically considering a collection of random variables for the index L in the
random variables for the index L in the corner angle systems means time okay but
corner angle systems means time okay but many other things where you have
many other things where you have sequences of random variables has
sequences of random variables has nothing to do with time okay it's not in
nothing to do with time okay it's not in the spatial location you know each other
the spatial location you know each other so we are assuming that somehow in our
so we are assuming that somehow in our model we have the cumulative
model we have the cumulative distribution okay and here in this place
distribution okay and here in this place I'm interested on a finite joint
I'm interested on a finite joint cumulative distribution I'm not pushing
cumulative distribution I'm not pushing this train basically to infinity because
this train basically to infinity because not they bring other issues that we
not they bring other issues that we don't want to deal at this point so the
don't want to deal at this point so the first quantity of interest is to define
first quantity of interest is to define what we call a stationary process and
what we call a stationary process and the ability is if we already have
the ability is if we already have defined the CDF like this a stationary
defined the CDF like this a stationary process is the one called this joint
process is the one called this joint distribution is equal to this where
distribution is equal to this where instead of 1 I have 1 plus tau
instead of 1 I have 1 plus tau sort of - 2 plus tau etc so basically as
sort of - 2 plus tau etc so basically as I stretch the whole thing by tau I can
I stretch the whole thing by tau I can still get the same joint cumulative
still get the same joint cumulative distribution function
distribution function now the familiar model that we used in
now the familiar model that we used in the class of now is involved about
the class of now is involved about convey an assumption that tastes
convey an assumption that tastes basically the probability of xn plus 1
basically the probability of xn plus 1 depends only on the values of xn and not
depends only on the values of xn and not on the previous values ok and many books
on the previous values ok and many books have been written on this topic in the
have been written on this topic in the context of optimistic modeling you know
context of optimistic modeling you know molecular simulations financial
molecular simulations financial engineering etc but I can tell you that
engineering etc but I can tell you that everyone recent sort of research paper
everyone recent sort of research paper you sell the topic they say now this is
you sell the topic they say now this is not very good ok so somehow you need to
not very good ok so somehow you need to get rid of this assumption we get rid of
get rid of this assumption we get rid of it for now
it for now ok so now we are going to basically from
ok so now we are going to basically from natural - processing and actually you
natural - processing and actually you will see when you read back is book one
will see when you read back is book one of the things you can do is if you take
of the things you can do is if you take a text and the sequence of words in the
a text and the sequence of words in the text right you can think of that as the
text right you can think of that as the dynamical system and in essence you can
dynamical system and in essence you can write an essay you can write the
write an essay you can write the homework with a computer program where
homework with a computer program where you know it randomly selects words from
you know it randomly selects words from the dictionary using the previous words
the dictionary using the previous words and you submit a whole paper but it's a
and you submit a whole paper but it's a computer mate right and and I am sure
computer mate right and and I am sure lots of people do that ok this day so
lots of people do that ok this day so that is interesting is if you use a Mac
that is interesting is if you use a Mac avianna function and the product rule
avianna function and the product rule you can see the immediate simplification
you can see the immediate simplification right so you can see here giving X 3
right so you can see here giving X 3 depending on X 1 and X 2 you have only X
depending on X 1 and X 2 you have only X 3 depending on X 2 X 2 and XT minus 12
3 depending on X 2 X 2 and XT minus 12 so the variables that you need to keep
so the variables that you need to keep track of if each of this is
track of if each of this is gay values you know you only have just a
gay values you know you only have just a stage for its XP this time matrices of
stage for its XP this time matrices of the order of K square right so this is
the order of K square right so this is way much less complexity to be done it
way much less complexity to be done it without them Markovian assumption okay
without them Markovian assumption okay [Applause]
[Applause] so we are sure that this problem is the
so we are sure that this problem is the mode of the gives me the evolution of
mode of the gives me the evolution of the state
the state if you expressly parametrically then we
if you expressly parametrically then we assume that but then the parameters to
assume that but then the parameters to that model don't change with time okay
that model don't change with time okay and generally speaking trying to compute
and generally speaking trying to compute the parameters in this model is known as
the parameters in this model is known as certainly a trivial problem so you know
certainly a trivial problem so you know when you have you try to model something
when you have you try to model something with a Markov chain for example and if
with a Markov chain for example and if you make this amount I only distribution
you make this amount I only distribution for example something like that you know
for example something like that you know you are going to have a lot of unknowns
you are going to have a lot of unknowns in defining this distribution and the
in defining this distribution and the only way to compute them is by using
only way to compute them is by using data alright so if you know you can do
data alright so if you know you can do much more active with estimation what as
much more active with estimation what as we consider implemented through the EM
we consider implemented through the EM algorithm or maybe do a mapping but then
algorithm or maybe do a mapping but then assume that you start with it no you
assume that you start with it no you have to learn this and then cook is not
have to learn this and then cook is not being predictions influence of the rat
being predictions influence of the rat okay so we only assume that xn plus 1
okay so we only assume that xn plus 1 differential xn but in which way you
differential xn but in which way you know what is this table that's something
know what is this table that's something to do
for HIV so what you see here is basically what we described for the this
basically what we described for the this is this impression you see on the bottom
is this impression you see on the bottom is basically the Cleary's out what the
is basically the Cleary's out what the Montpellier assumption is used right and
Montpellier assumption is used right and this is what allow us to go from and the
this is what allow us to go from and the composition that depends for XP depends
composition that depends for XP depends on all the previous variables to extent
on all the previous variables to extent it depends only on X 3 minus 1 okay you
it depends only on X 3 minus 1 okay you can a better way since we're talking
can a better way since we're talking about published graphical models you can
about published graphical models you can see immediately that given X 2 X 1 and X
see immediately that given X 2 X 1 and X 3 are independent right so when you
3 are independent right so when you write the probability of X 3 given X 1
write the probability of X 3 given X 1 and X 2 that you get here you can get
and X 2 that you get here you can get rid of X 1 given X 2 right because they
rid of X 1 given X 2 right because they are independent I think because of the
are independent I think because of the separation okay so you know will be 2 so
separation okay so you know will be 2 so we like us rhabdo
we like us rhabdo this this graphical model immediately
this this graphical model immediately implies that the question ok all right
implies that the question ok all right so given X 2 X 1 and X 3 are independent
so given X 2 X 1 and X 3 are independent you can all right so let me keep going
you can all right so let me keep going so this matrix you know assuming that
so this matrix you know assuming that the states of the script we are going to
the states of the script we are going to call this an ALJ matrix right and
call this an ALJ matrix right and eventually we have to find some way to
eventually we have to find some way to compute from data ok so this is sort of
compute from data ok so this is sort of our state transition diagram that you
our state transition diagram that you can demonstrate basically this
can demonstrate basically this probabilities circuit with some
probabilities circuit with some schematic that looks like that so you
schematic that looks like that so you know here there is a self transition
know here there is a self transition probability from state 1 back to state 1
probability from state 1 back to state 1 transition state 2 but no to state 3 and
transition state 2 but no to state 3 and notice in state 3 basically there is no
notice in state 3 basically there is no way you can escape because the
way you can escape because the probability of being back to state 3 is
probability of being back to state 3 is 1 right so this is sort of an
1 right so this is sort of an interesting case in this diagram you
interesting case in this diagram you will not be
will not be from three to escape and go back to one
from three to escape and go back to one and two okay all right
and two okay all right so the transition matrix in this case is
so the transition matrix in this case is a 1 1 a 1 2 A 2 2 a 2 3 and 1
a 1 1 a 1 2 A 2 2 a 2 3 and 1 well that's a choice and more
well that's a choice and more interesting transition matrix square we
interesting transition matrix square we have self transition okay and so this is
have self transition okay and so this is best in transition from state 1 the
best in transition from state 1 the first roll to map to state 1 state 2
first roll to map to state 1 state 2 state 3 so this probabilities have to
state 3 so this probabilities have to sum to 1 you notice every loss how to do
sum to 1 you notice every loss how to do one and in this case that say we are
one and in this case that say we are skewing that the probability of initial
skewing that the probability of initial state is given as 1 3 1 3 1 3 so if best
state is given as 1 3 1 3 1 3 so if best an equal chance of being in any other
an equal chance of being in any other state thank you
state thank you you start with the state with this
you start with the state with this probability this is your initial
probability this is your initial probability and I ask you to tell me
probability and I ask you to tell me what's going to happen long term to
what's going to happen long term to calculate the probability of being at
calculate the probability of being at the given state after into a time how
the given state after into a time how are you going to implement this just in
are you going to implement this just in three lines quote so let me give you
three lines quote so let me give you this and I give you this transition
this and I give you this transition matrix and I'm asked them to compute for
matrix and I'm asked them to compute for me what we you know the probability of
me what we you know the probability of being in state 1 state 2 state 3 is
being in state 1 state 2 state 3 is going to be at time infinity
going to be at time infinity assuming that have somehow this chain
assuming that have somehow this chain converges okay so how do i implement
converges okay so how do i implement this we may struggle a little but it's
this we may struggle a little but it's been online that does this
step rather than
you're gonna start moving on this on different states right with the
different states right with the dynamical model apply by a so I'm gonna
dynamical model apply by a so I'm gonna write the software to do that so what do
write the software to do that so what do you have to do the first step
exactly yeah very good excellent
I have to give feedback right so they think am i responding to the class okay
think am i responding to the class okay so what do we do
so we basically have to select with this probabilities something to start and
probabilities something to start and then assuming that say we select the
then assuming that say we select the second state then we're going to have to
second state then we're going to have to select with this probabilities to what's
select with this probabilities to what's a good transition from state one and we
a good transition from state one and we make transition with this to take one
make transition with this to take one backward to take two of state three and
backward to take two of state three and then keep repeating this with the hope
then keep repeating this with the hope that somehow at the end of the day we're
that somehow at the end of the day we're gonna reach some stationary distribution
gonna reach some stationary distribution and we will introduce twelve only one
and we will introduce twelve only one stationary distribution for this Markov
stationary distribution for this Markov chains exist now can you tell me I mean
chains exist now can you tell me I mean this is something we are keenly covered
this is something we are keenly covered on lectures in hope maybe but if
on lectures in hope maybe but if somebody gives you this distribution and
somebody gives you this distribution and say sample from this distribution how do
say sample from this distribution how do we do this how do something from a given
we do this how do something from a given distribution and you know that you are
distribution and you know that you are on screen so you should have suffered
on screen so you should have suffered from this can you tell exactly what will
from this can you tell exactly what will lead you to say among state for your
lead you to say among state for your state to
are we gonna do up in online
so the original sample from this distribution some of the distribution
I mean how do you sample from discrete distribution that's what I'm asking
distribution that's what I'm asking that's the single thing to sample from
that's the single thing to sample from discrete distribution
see there's something from a uniform and let's say from zero to one and if it
let's say from zero to one and if it happens to be let's say hi and then
happens to be let's say hi and then point six six or something then you say
point six six or something then you say you are now on state three all right
you are now on state three all right similarly if you are higher than point
similarly if you are higher than point three three but less than that then your
three three but less than that then your state 2 etc okay so this is how you
state 2 etc okay so this is how you sample from discrete distribution since
sample from discrete distribution since we defined this transition probability a
we defined this transition probability a I J what we often use and the location
I J what we often use and the location is also a LJ for this transition
is also a LJ for this transition probability basically transition is from
probability basically transition is from I to J
I to J but in n steps the idea being is that
but in n steps the idea being is that you start at time T at state I and after
you start at time T at state I and after n steps even and yourself in state Z so
n steps even and yourself in state Z so this is the N step transition
this is the N step transition probability and effectively this
probability and effectively this satisfies the Commonwealth equation that
satisfies the Commonwealth equation that what you have seen it in many different
what you have seen it in many different contexts in LD in this course so you can
contexts in LD in this course so you can think if you want transition in M plus n
think if you want transition in M plus n steps from I to J that you can do is you
steps from I to J that you can do is you can transition them steps decay for a
can transition them steps decay for a possible case and then in the remaining
possible case and then in the remaining n steps transition from K today
n steps transition from K today so the Commonwealth equation basically
so the Commonwealth equation basically looks like that ok and increased for
looks like that ok and increased for this allows you to write you know this n
this allows you to write you know this n step transition matrix the way that you
step transition matrix the way that you see here okay so don't sort of the
see here okay so don't sort of the liberal interpretation of this because
liberal interpretation of this because the interpretation of this for is
the interpretation of this for is basically the Commonwealth equation that
basically the Commonwealth equation that which is there
I think this problems are very difficult but you can see in on the picture on the
but you can see in on the picture on the bottom for example that you know after a
bottom for example that you know after a few steps because we need to initialize
few steps because we need to initialize things the state explored now depends on
things the state explored now depends on X 3 but also depends on X 2 and X 1 so
X 3 but also depends on X 2 and X 1 so this is the Markov chain basically or
this is the Markov chain basically or thanks flow so this is a way a little
thanks flow so this is a way a little bit more complicated problem and so you
bit more complicated problem and so you keep track dependence is basically that
keep track dependence is basically that the grab back from X for X 1
well it said you know what myself now I want to do this example
want to do this example so he just described and we will
so he just described and we will continue on this next week and I will
continue on this next week and I will put the notes played tomorrow so you can
put the notes played tomorrow so you can read it all right so the notes is
read it all right so the notes is basically to try to build a probability
basically to try to build a probability model for writing a language speaking
model for writing a language speaking language okay so the idea is you know
language okay so the idea is you know we're going to have to assign some
we're going to have to assign some probability for each word and you can
probability for each word and you can take it to be beautiful some probability
take it to be beautiful some probability from transition from one world to
from transition from one world to another this is the bigram probability
another this is the bigram probability and then a transition from two previous
and then a transition from two previous words to a third world okay so you can
words to a third world okay so you can actually use this if you build model for
actually use this if you build model for this which means you have to learn the
this which means you have to learn the parameters from this from given spoken
parameters from this from given spoken English or text you can actually use
English or text you can actually use this to complete the sentence and this
this to complete the sentence and this Barry I was told when I was young it's
Barry I was told when I was young it's very polite to complete the sentence or
very polite to complete the sentence or Father's right it seems when I teach I
Father's right it seems when I teach I do that all the time remember
do that all the time remember I just complete the sentence that I say
I just complete the sentence that I say thank you so that's not very polite okay
thank you so that's not very polite okay and not a joke you can actually use this
and not a joke you can actually use this to write document you know once you
to write document you know once you start it and it learns this transition
start it and it learns this transition probabilities you can start picking up a
probabilities you can start picking up a random words using the previous ones
random words using the previous ones arranging you have a whole document and
arranging you have a whole document and and maybe you will like that okay so
and maybe you will like that okay so this have how these transition
this have how these transition probabilities would look like so this is
probabilities would look like so this is for the probabilities of different
for the probabilities of different letters in the alphabet
letters in the alphabet okay
okay and the system this has been computed by
and the system this has been computed by using a given a textbook and these are
using a given a textbook and these are the Biograph probabilities that gives
the Biograph probabilities that gives you the transition from one letter to
you the transition from one letter to another this is like a human diagram
another this is like a human diagram that maybe you have seen it in
that maybe you have seen it in presentation of this vibro probability
presentation of this vibro probability in other contexts so the bigger this Y
in other contexts so the bigger this Y dot the higher the probability so
dot the higher the probability so obviously you're not going to go from a
obviously you're not going to go from a to a writer has very low probability
to a writer has very low probability from a 12 you know and if you look from
from a 12 you know and if you look from n2i that's significant
n2i that's significant okay because they have too many nicolas
okay because they have too many nicolas around right Nick all right okay so what
around right Nick all right okay so what I want to tell you and we just thing is
I want to tell you and we just thing is there I want you to tell how we're
there I want you to tell how we're actually going to use a document to
actually going to use a document to compute this transition probabilities
compute this transition probabilities and we're gonna use maximum likelihood
and we're gonna use maximum likelihood to do that all right
to do that all right so effectively the calculation will be
so effectively the calculation will be sort of an elementary introduction to
sort of an elementary introduction to the way we're going to be map estimation
the way we're going to be map estimation for state space model so we're going to
for state space model so we're going to achieve this in the Delta national
achieve this in the Delta national velocity what is the effect of this type
velocity what is the effect of this type of Emily estimate when you have limited
of Emily estimate when you have limited data so because moisturisers I don't
data so because moisturisers I don't have more than two