in the introduction without the microphone so we're gonna start going
microphone so we're gonna start going back to the liquor obligation as an
back to the liquor obligation as an example basically to see how the
example basically to see how the equations look like for an undirected
equations look like for an undirected graph particularly for photography
graph particularly for photography okay so we're going to see how to delete
okay so we're going to see how to delete propagation algorithm loops for animal F
propagation algorithm loops for animal F that has these cell potentials the way
that has these cell potentials the way you have seen in the past and then it
you have seen in the past and then it has this pair of potentials with receipt
has this pair of potentials with receipt here okay so we are the number of nodes
here okay so we are the number of nodes okay
okay SOT our edges in the graph so this term
SOT our edges in the graph so this term vs potential square potentials and Z is
vs potential square potentials and Z is the normalization factor all right so
the normalization factor all right so the the presentation it looks like a
the the presentation it looks like a slightly different but you know if you
slightly different but you know if you got the idea of message passing
got the idea of message passing effectively they are the same things
effectively they are the same things okay so what we're gonna do is we are
okay so what we're gonna do is we are going to assume a general basically
going to assume a general basically Markov random field so and we're gonna
Markov random field so and we're gonna use the same ideas we did for to it so
use the same ideas we did for to it so you know you can take the mountain from
you know you can take the mountain from the whole thing and say you know and
the whole thing and say you know and whatever is from the bottom which are
whatever is from the bottom which are the leaves and in some sense stop
the leaves and in some sense stop sending messages from the leaves to the
sending messages from the leaves to the root that's the collect evidence step
root that's the collect evidence step and then going from the roots all the
and then going from the roots all the way to the link before we are ready to
way to the link before we are ready to calculate marginal can do inference
so because I need to do this in the belief propagation sort of concept I'm
belief propagation sort of concept I'm going to define what belief propagation
going to define what belief propagation is so let's take a note - I mean a note
is so let's take a note - I mean a note P but just silver Nessun you even though
P but just silver Nessun you even though this to not you know a directed graph
this to not you know a directed graph but you can think of this if you found
but you can think of this if you found it again from T these are the neighbors
it again from T these are the neighbors directly connected with lists of the of
directly connected with lists of the of the children so we define that is called
the children so we define that is called the bottom half belief state of the node
the bottom half belief state of the node T to be the probability of XT given the
T to be the probability of XT given the evidence from below all right
evidence from below all right so the idea is that you notice the
so the idea is that you notice the phrase the grafton this is the evidence
phrase the grafton this is the evidence coming from below right this is very
coming from below right this is very important so this is what is called the
important so this is what is called the bottom-up belief state as you go from
bottom-up belief state as you go from the leaves to the rope to define the
the leaves to the rope to define the belief state of every node and it
belief state of every node and it represents the probability of XT given
represents the probability of XT given the evidence below alright now the idea
the evidence below alright now the idea is somehow the way we have done in the
is somehow the way we have done in the past we have learned how to propagate
past we have learned how to propagate vestiges from the tape from the timber
vestiges from the tape from the timber last few and especially as charged
last few and especially as charged right and so effectively this message
right and so effectively this message that you see here is the probability of
that you see here is the probability of XT given this evidence and from the
XT given this evidence and from the graph can you tell me what the words
graph can you tell me what the words what evidence did I mean we did this in
what evidence did I mean we did this in principle when we work with trees and
principle when we work with trees and poly trees so this message is from s to
poly trees so this message is from s to P is really the probability of P and it
P is really the probability of P and it is this you know the belief basically
is this you know the belief basically given what evidence
given what evidence what do you think this evidence is it
what do you think this evidence is it says V subscript s and T and then - so
says V subscript s and T and then - so what's the idea here
what's the idea here if I have an edge
if I have an edge let this be a speed - is the evidence
let this be a speed - is the evidence comment from what part of the graph from
comment from what part of the graph from Mouse thing or plot gives noticed the
Mouse thing or plot gives noticed the HST
HST you remember if you take espy right this
you remember if you take espy right this is subtree and the evidence of comes
is subtree and the evidence of comes from that it's really this message so
from that it's really this message so this master summarizes all the
this master summarizes all the information the evidence that you see
information the evidence that you see here below this blue coastline provides
here below this blue coastline provides you know T okay and so similarly to this
you know T okay and so similarly to this message we also have the message to the
message we also have the message to the beauty etc so the bottom-up belief state
beauty etc so the bottom-up belief state of the know T it is nothing else but the
of the know T it is nothing else but the potential of the node X P times all the
potential of the node X P times all the messages that are coming from below
messages that are coming from below alright so in this case two example this
alright so in this case two example this graph from s and Q because this vest is
graph from s and Q because this vest is progressing you summarized all the
progressing you summarized all the belief that we get from the bottom down
belief that we get from the bottom down okay so these are the children of T and
okay so these are the children of T and again I'm using this in a liberal sense
again I'm using this in a liberal sense because this is not a directed graph
because this is not a directed graph where I have a definition of children
where I have a definition of children but you can see what this implies from
but you can see what this implies from this graph so we propagate messages and
this graph so we propagate messages and the question is how do we compute this
the question is how do we compute this messages and we compute this messages
messages and we compute this messages recursively the way we have done before
recursively the way we have done before but now this is written slightly
but now this is written slightly different so the message from below from
different so the message from below from s to T it is a maximization s of the
s to T it is a maximization s of the joint potential of the non certainty
joint potential of the non certainty exactly as we have done before
exactly as we have done before times the belief of first - the belief
times the belief of first - the belief of no - coming communal so what is
of no - coming communal so what is really the belief subscript s -
really the belief subscript s - is evidence of comes from the no
is evidence of comes from the no s-tronic service you can think of this
s-tronic service you can think of this for example the all the message is
for example the all the message is coming to us from its children but now
coming to us from its children but now what I have done is I've written because
what I have done is I've written because I define explicitly what this is for any
I define explicitly what this is for any now I am using the belief from below for
now I am using the belief from below for now to write this equation in a slightly
now to write this equation in a slightly different manner
different manner so actually spelling cannabis lists how
so actually spelling cannabis lists how things were written right but if you
things were written right but if you don't like this definition you can go
don't like this definition you can go back to the old way I mean the way with
back to the old way I mean the way with discussions with messages but in the
discussions with messages but in the context of belief propagation this
context of belief propagation this equation is written like a so if you
equation is written like a so if you propagate beliefs basically from
propagate beliefs basically from evidence from below all the way to the
evidence from below all the way to the written once you reach the route
written once you reach the route effectively you have the probability of
effectively you have the probability of the route given all the evidence below
the route given all the evidence below and effectively that according to our
and effectively that according to our skin is the marginal of Nordics our
skin is the marginal of Nordics our times the product of all the messages
times the product of all the messages coming from the children of the root to
coming from the children of the root to the okay but the messages are coming
the okay but the messages are coming from below or population basically is
from below or population basically is the products of this normalization
the products of this normalization factor CP and the mystical Z becomes Z T
factor CP and the mystical Z becomes Z T basically is the normalization factor
basically is the normalization factor for each of this belief phase from below
for each of this belief phase from below you know what actually just produced
you know what actually just produced upon one line compilation to convince
upon one line compilation to convince yourselves that it could take all of
yourselves that it could take all of this is a taste and you multiply them
this is a taste and you multiply them together from the leaves to the road you
together from the leaves to the road you basically get the evidence
basically get the evidence the Maserati could make a pelvic
the Maserati could make a pelvic there's an extra sort of car bombs from
there's an extra sort of car bombs from this hopeless okay so here is and now
this hopeless okay so here is and now you're ready to start distributing
you're ready to start distributing informational downwards to the same way
informational downwards to the same way we have done with message passing so now
we have done with message passing so now as we start sending messages that say
as we start sending messages that say from T to s we are going to update us
from T to s we are going to update us then you notice now because when you
then you notice now because when you stop message sending message from T to s
stop message sending message from T to s actually with no accessories which is
actually with no accessories which is the probability of access given all the
the probability of access given all the evidence because we accounted evidence
evidence because we accounted evidence from banila and some accounting evidence
from banila and some accounting evidence from Abed all right so we the the belief
from Abed all right so we the the belief of X s is T of X s given V and it is
of X s is T of X s given V and it is very simple is the belief you know it's
very simple is the belief you know it's from the bottom up this is from the
from the bottom up this is from the first page of the algorithm finds all
first page of the algorithm finds all the messages that are coming from the
the messages that are coming from the parents but know this you agree in this
parents but know this you agree in this case the Jaypee and something else there
case the Jaypee and something else there okay so you know what we're doing
okay so you know what we're doing masters passing we have some scallion
masters passing we have some scallion like they actually we're exactly how
like they actually we're exactly how this equation on looking like before the
this equation on looking like before the messages when we didn't have this
messages when we didn't have this concept of belief so obviously we have
concept of belief so obviously we have the messages coming from above from the
the messages coming from above from the parents and here we did we have so if
parents and here we did we have so if you look at any node all right there's
you look at any node all right there's no not only receives messages from team
no not only receives messages from team but also receives message from what
you have to include the messages from the whole then of those messages now
the whole then of those messages now they're inside the belief - of now
they're inside the belief - of now effector some toothpaste the
effector some toothpaste the parameterization of the same Estes
parameterization of the same Estes fasting a questions would have doubt
fasting a questions would have doubt there's really nothing you yep
you know social location we win over the our price we passed the retailers and
our price we passed the retailers and now we need to start replicating belief
now we need to start replicating belief from there it all the way down because a
from there it all the way down because a lot of these notes have not yet received
lot of these notes have not yet received information from without going up and
information from without going up and down and actually you can do that the
down and actually you can do that the only thing you have to do is you have to
only thing you have to do is you have to initialize the message to be one so
initialize the message to be one so there is something to send right and
there is something to send right and after that you don't really have to go
after that you don't really have to go up you don't have to go down strong this
up you don't have to go down strong this came out good
came out good and this is sort of what you know using
and this is sort of what you know using sort of an idea of listening
sort of an idea of listening you can't respond same with messages
you can't respond same with messages anymore we can send messages send
anymore we can send messages send messages all right but right now we are
messages all right but right now we are looking for forward and backward
looking for forward and backward propagation and we writing this in terms
propagation and we writing this in terms of the list so the final belief of not
of the list so the final belief of not exist having received information from
exist having received information from above and below is to believe that we
above and below is to believe that we calculate this in as we went from the
calculate this in as we went from the links to the route and all the times all
links to the route and all the times all the products of the messages that
the products of the messages that basically comes from the parlance of no
basically comes from the parlance of no they're all right
they're all right and here's another equation now that the
and here's another equation now that the waves from the
from the message passing algorithm you have seen so you may say and what's the
have seen so you may say and what's the message that this sends to us now right
message that this sends to us now right as we go down goes from the root to the
as we go down goes from the root to the lives so that message is basically this
lives so that message is basically this is the definition right is the
is the definition right is the probability of XT given the upstream
probability of XT given the upstream evidence on the edge of T and it's given
evidence on the edge of T and it's given by marginalizing so this is the
by marginalizing so this is the information distance to ask right
information distance to ask right distance press does this look elect to
distance press does this look elect to you these term stress so it seems I am
you these term stress so it seems I am messed up the summation here okay so the
messed up the summation here okay so the information Teamsters crest will be the
information Teamsters crest will be the potential of the sphere and look at this
potential of the sphere and look at this now in many circumstances you know
now in many circumstances you know whether we have so if you look at the
whether we have so if you look at the message from T to s right so you have to
message from T to s right so you have to include the messages that arrived from
include the messages that arrived from above to ask all right my function you
above to ask all right my function you have to include all the messages are
have to include all the messages are coming from below so look at this
coming from below so look at this equation and tell me what exact is this
equation and tell me what exact is this  there's no - on this belief so what
there's no - on this belief so what exactly is this thing that we see this
exactly is this thing that we see this fraction
I mean stupid water when looking the messes from repeat to ask okay going
messes from repeat to ask okay going downwards so what is this distance
downwards so what is this distance dressed this misbelief state mr. Zhu -
dressed this misbelief state mr. Zhu - search maybe if you want addresses from
search maybe if you want addresses from above and below
above and below but here I'm dividing it by the message
but here I'm dividing it by the message that that sends the tip from below
that that sends the tip from below shall I stop you remember when you
shall I stop you remember when you update right I know there's the message
update right I know there's the message coming from below and the message coming
coming from below and the message coming from above all of this really this
from above all of this really this message will give you the belief of
message will give you the belief of Nordics fee but I'm dividing it by the
Nordics fee but I'm dividing it by the message that essence today from below so
message that essence today from below so what is that because they are not gonna
what is that because they are not gonna circular knowledge a mess is not an
circular knowledge a mess is not an alternative
life is the same way remember when we don't so that's an early privatization
don't so that's an early privatization of the equations the way originally
of the equations the way originally belief propagation was introduced in
belief propagation was introduced in principle really I mean if you correctly
principle really I mean if you correctly both ways you will get the same answer
both ways you will get the same answer so one way to look is this way another
so one way to look is this way another way is with a message passing passing as
way is with a message passing passing as we did before so it's the same story all
we did before so it's the same story all right now the migration and well you do
right now the migration and well you do this division as a song here is called
this division as a song here is called belief updating the Russian will be
belief updating the Russian will be multiplied messages the way we have done
multiplied messages the way we have done in the earlier lectures is really the
in the earlier lectures is really the sum-product algorithm so that's what we
sum-product algorithm so that's what we already have stained and with this new
already have stained and with this new parameterization you get this concept of
parameterization you get this concept of belief updating no messages update okay
belief updating no messages update okay all right so this is it can happen that
all right so this is it can happen that the Southwick
the Southwick you know you are operate on a tree the
you know you are operate on a tree the situation is very simple you know if
situation is very simple you know if you're going to camp you know so let me
you're going to camp you know so let me look here it says
actually let me let me because this was in earlier slides okay so we are looking
in earlier slides okay so we are looking now from the messages from top down all
now from the messages from top down all right from feet west okay so we just
right from feet west okay so we just noticed equation okay and we sent the
noticed equation okay and we sent the message from feet west is given with
message from feet west is given with these potential times the belief of node
these potential times the belief of node X T divided by the message that comes
X T divided by the message that comes from below from load test so to update
from below from load test so to update this message this from above you need to
this message this from above you need to know investors coming from below so you
know investors coming from below so you need is not the sufficient to only keep
need is not the sufficient to only keep top of the beliefs of the nodes you need
top of the beliefs of the nodes you need to keep track of the messages coming
to keep track of the messages coming from below and that's why this message
from below and that's why this message is from above if you would see lots of
is from above if you would see lots of books interpret the test conditional
books interpret the test conditional posterior probability and actually in
posterior probability and actually in the slides that I gave you for directed
the slides that I gave you for directed graphs and written this is like a cell
graphs and written this is like a cell sample a posterior probability here is
sample a posterior probability here is you are ready considering evidence from
you are ready considering evidence from below in computing these messages with
below in computing these messages with this parametrization so you can put sort
this parametrization so you can put sort of the meaning of this being a
of the meaning of this being a conditional posterior probability but
conditional posterior probability but the old way that we did right if you
the old way that we did right if you cannot do that right so the
cannot do that right so the interpretation is basically these
interpretation is basically these messages are like likelihoods vesicle
messages are like likelihoods vesicle conditional likelihood
I mean you can see in for example this is written for a piece here there's no
is written for a piece here there's no message from below alright so you cannot
message from below alright so you cannot call it the conditional probability so
call it the conditional probability so the protocol basically in simple terms
the protocol basically in simple terms right so we'll explain if you go from to
right so we'll explain if you go from to the list and then you can calculate any
the list and then you can calculate any sort of marginal stuff of interest and
sort of marginal stuff of interest and you can calculate the dictates but
you can calculate the dictates but actually what you can do is you can
actually what you can do is you can initialize all the messages to something
initialize all the messages to something and that can be arbitrary let's say
and that can be arbitrary let's say equal to 1 and it's really basically to
equal to 1 and it's really basically to take messages from all of its neighbors
take messages from all of its neighbors so you have they directly the belief of
so you have they directly the belief of every node as the cell potential times
every node as the cell potential times the product of all the messages coming
the product of all the messages coming from all of its neighbors
from all of its neighbors there's no anymore above and below you
there's no anymore above and below you know downstream and upstream sort of
know downstream and upstream sort of belief you can actually start updating
belief you can actually start updating the belief of all the nodes this way and
the belief of all the nodes this way and when are you going to convert when
when are you going to convert when basically the message that you've
basically the message that you've converted and the message have converged
converted and the message have converged when effectively information from every
when effectively information from every other node so the number of steps
other node so the number of steps basically that you have to drag this
basically that you have to drag this would be as large as the size of your
would be as large as the size of your graph ok so so they basically converges
graph ok so so they basically converges linearly with the size of the graph
linearly with the size of the graph which is proportional to the number
which is proportional to the number in the gun right and if you check the
in the gun right and if you check the Nicollet sure that you will find too
Nicollet sure that you will find too much of different algorithms for doing
much of different algorithms for doing finalization of this okay and there are
finalization of this okay and there are extremely fast
extremely fast and keep in mind this all gonna start
and keep in mind this all gonna start exactly
exactly there's no approximation there example
there's no approximation there example okay so so they're very nice okay
okay so so they're very nice okay I think so they gave you homework you
I think so they gave you homework you know that if I remember if you're
know that if I remember if you're supposed to implement a marker a magic
supposed to implement a marker a magic marker marker on appeal okay something
marker marker on appeal okay something like that not exactly
it was undirected block
okay okay I haven't questioned was homework 3 if I
I haven't questioned was homework 3 if I remember so here is a Gaussian Markov
remember so here is a Gaussian Markov random field where the cell potential
random field where the cell potential basically a Gaussian this is sort of a
basically a Gaussian this is sort of a normalized Gaussian
normalized Gaussian all right you close the square you get
all right you close the square you get the Gaussian and then you have their
the Gaussian and then you have their potentials to define Phi of s and T so
potentials to define Phi of s and T so when you put all of this together the
when you put all of this together the joint probability of X is really
joint probability of X is really Gaussian and here I'm reading it I'm
Gaussian and here I'm reading it I'm writing it in sort of an immobilized
writing it in sort of an immobilized fall okay so the minima nausea if you
fall okay so the minima nausea if you close the square you're going to have to
close the square you're going to have to invert this matrix a minus 1 B and this
invert this matrix a minus 1 B and this is a very costly calculation right
is a very costly calculation right important metrics it goes to the cube of
important metrics it goes to the cube of the size of this matrix but if you do
the size of this matrix but if you do this calculation using this belief
this calculation using this belief propagation now what it means you can do
propagation now what it means you can do it you have you with the size of the
it you have you with the size of the graph so we need to see how we can do
graph so we need to see how we can do the propagation with Gaussian with
the propagation with Gaussian with Gaussian distribution so here is the
Gaussian distribution so here is the advance for the cell potential but I out
advance for the cell potential but I out here if you pull of the square
here if you pull of the square it is a Gaussian so the mean and the
it is a Gaussian so the mean and the precision are written here explicitly
precision are written here explicitly all right the the procedure the
all right the the procedure the marginals at every known country one
marginals at every known country one should be Gaussian right because you can
should be Gaussian right because you can sleep on clearly if the joint is a
sleep on clearly if the joint is a Gaussian obviously all the margins will
Gaussian obviously all the margins will be Gaussian strong of interest will be
be Gaussian strong of interest will be to calculate near T and lambda T okay
to calculate near T and lambda T okay and you need to do this at the cost that
and you need to do this at the cost that is not the same as inverting that matrix
is not the same as inverting that matrix a but something way more efficient to be
a but something way more efficient to be able to do that we need to manipulate
able to do that we need to manipulate the audience and it sounds like a
the audience and it sounds like a right when especially in one dimension
right when especially in one dimension but this can be very complicated if you
but this can be very complicated if you can have an explosion of calculation
can have an explosion of calculation says especially if you try to explain
says especially if you try to explain this to you know just gaussians but
this to you know just gaussians but mixture of gaussians so what you need to
mixture of gaussians so what you need to know sir one simple formula or pill one
know sir one simple formula or pill one is the format of gaussians and you have
is the format of gaussians and you have to write on what is called an
to write on what is called an information form share to use
information form share to use Precision's rather than very insist
Precision's rather than very insist divide this product in a nice form so if
divide this product in a nice form so if you like this with prestigious level two
you like this with prestigious level two one laughter - the product of two
one laughter - the product of two gaussians has a precision which the sum
gaussians has a precision which the sum of the two Precision's and I mean that
of the two Precision's and I mean that is given like that the normalization
is given like that the normalization postulate is not important even like
postulate is not important even like this
this I mean lot of the times right an
I mean lot of the times right an organization you know it is of no
organization you know it is of no interest really you an interest rate so
interest really you an interest rate so that we need to do is we need to compute
that we need to do is we need to compute to be able to apply the different
to be able to apply the different valuation right so if you look at the
valuation right so if you look at the belief of state note that first is the
belief of state note that first is the potential of access times all the
potential of access times all the messages arriving from its neighbors so
messages arriving from its neighbors so you need to be able to compute this in a
you need to be able to compute this in a closed form as a Gaussian and then
closed form as a Gaussian and then together with this product is another
together with this product is another closed out for Gaussian so you can write
closed out for Gaussian so you can write the belief of no excess as a stupid
the belief of no excess as a stupid thousand and this is what this
thousand and this is what this compression is done if you write the
compression is done if you write the messages to have a name USP and
messages to have a name USP and precision lambda is 3 and you multiply
precision lambda is 3 and you multiply all of this then you get a nice formula
all of this then you get a nice formula for the belief of know the test to be
for the belief of know the test to be long passed right one pass I remind you
long passed right one pass I remind you comes from the the precision of this
comes from the the precision of this single node potential plus the sum of
single node potential plus the sum of the Precision's of all the masses
the Precision's of all the masses from the neighbors of s to militate okay
from the neighbors of s to militate okay so the very nice 12 minutes a big dollar
so the very nice 12 minutes a big dollar must exist
must exist all right nothing and if you don't
all right nothing and if you don't update if you want to do message passing
update if you want to do message passing and you want update a message from st p
and you want update a message from st p you know this Bella right here
you know this Bella right here I don't assume things coming from above
I don't assume things coming from above and below because the idea is I am
and below because the idea is I am initializing everything with one or with
initializing everything with one or with some vouchers that you like and then I
some vouchers that you like and then I mystic messages with every note from
mystic messages with every note from other neighbors so the metas promise to
other neighbors so the metas promise to think much realized in excess of a
think much realized in excess of a mysterious in an integral form you have
mysterious in an integral form you have the senior potential access the
the senior potential access the potential of access honesty and then all
potential of access honesty and then all the messages that arrive from the
the messages that arrive from the neighbors of the no vest except nullity
neighbors of the no vest except nullity okay now I want to go through the
okay now I want to go through the algebra but effectively we just have
algebra but effectively we just have seen that this are Gaussian this to a
seen that this are Gaussian this to a social Gaussian this was also Gaussian
social Gaussian this was also Gaussian then there's a ssin in excess so
then there's a ssin in excess so technically at the end of the day you
technically at the end of the day you can have a recursive equation that gives
can have a recursive equation that gives you this messages as a clothespin
you this messages as a clothespin Gaussian with the given mean in a given
Gaussian with the given mean in a given procedure long term so effectively you
procedure long term so effectively you have this problem of scandi the program
have this problem of scandi the program to did the propagation called Gaussian
to did the propagation called Gaussian market on the fins it's really you know
market on the fins it's really you know the two lines
this is okay you should people not that you gave this homework okay all right so
you gave this homework okay all right so this is really all right now he realized
this is really all right now he realized yes to solve it - okay all right any
yes to solve it - okay all right any questions on this child now the only
questions on this child now the only thing I want to say right when you look
thing I want to say right when you look at these formulas for the way
at these formulas for the way dating messages somebody would stay but
dating messages somebody would stay but messages on a Gaussian right nothing is
messages on a Gaussian right nothing is so you're going to do tons of
so you're going to do tons of nonparametric early and then the idea is
nonparametric early and then the idea is can I give you a burst Gaussian matrix
can I give you a burst Gaussian matrix so you know what the problem will be
so you know what the problem will be when every message everything is a
when every message everything is a Gaussian mixture what happens when you
Gaussian mixture what happens when you want to apply a mixed in component with
want to apply a mixed in component with a lot of needs to go for it so multiply
a lot of needs to go for it so multiply you mix the three components with
you mix the three components with another mixtape let's ignacio components
another mixtape let's ignacio components how many components you get $30 a
how many components you get $30 a mixture with a lot of three browsers
mixture with a lot of three browsers what do you get nine and then humans
what do you get nine and then humans blind with another three all right
blind with another three all right or the Northern Line and it keeps going
or the Northern Line and it keeps going and going and so you get an explosion of
and going and so you get an explosion of thousand components so usually what
thousand components so usually what people do is they survive they take a
people do is they survive they take a mixture than genetic component and then
mixture than genetic component and then they project it to a mixture with three
they project it to a mixture with three components but again so you know some
components but again so you know some information okay and so the
information okay and so the probabilities even that try to you you
probabilities even that try to you you should for these five things don't
should for these five things don't automatically they are not necessarily
automatically they are not necessarily the exact right because you're gonna
the exact right because you're gonna listen information if you go from nine
listen information if you go from nine components two three you won't be able
components two three you won't be able to do this exactly okay buddy has been
to do this exactly okay buddy has been that it has been not for many years
that it has been not for many years almost 20 plus years people know how to
almost 20 plus years people know how to do this with Gaussian
all right
so mr. Higgs board with the name of nonparametric belief propagation
nonparametric belief propagation especially if you've used a mixed with
especially if you've used a mixed with nonparametric you know you're going to
nonparametric you know you're going to say I have a Gaussian mixture well but
say I have a Gaussian mixture well but you know you're not assuming any
you know you're not assuming any parametric form especially if the gods
parametric form especially if the gods are mixed you can there is many
are mixed you can there is many components as you wish right but also
components as you wish right but also nonparametric can imply distributions
nonparametric can imply distributions that you represent agree with some hopes
that you represent agree with some hopes well I cannot sort of a very nice way of
well I cannot sort of a very nice way of doing it message calculation so rather
doing it message calculation so rather than trying to fit them in some
than trying to fit them in some distribution for what you do is you
distribution for what you do is you represent them with particles and then
represent them with particles and then when you calculate the message updates
when you calculate the message updates you calculate the new particle
you calculate the new particle distribution to represent the questions
distribution to represent the questions okay so what's techniques actually have
okay so what's techniques actually have been extremely successful in in many
been extremely successful in in many dimension and I would say most only they
dimension and I would say most only they are the state of the art for this type
are the state of the art for this type of calculation and another way to do
of calculation and another way to do this
this nonparametric array is to give
nonparametric array is to give additional approximation okay so you
additional approximation okay so you vaccinate the distributions with some
vaccinate the distributions with some variation approximations and then the
variation approximations and then the question is how do you compute this new
question is how do you compute this new variation or approximation that's
variation or approximation that's something we will discuss later in the
something we will discuss later in the course we will spend maybe do a few
course we will spend maybe do a few lectures on the topic
by the way if the scoutship problem that I briefly went through and you will do
I briefly went through and you will do it in the home or if your mobile is sort
it in the home or if your mobile is sort of a linear dynamical system the
of a linear dynamical system the questions that you get with masters
questions that you get with masters passing etc become actually to be
passing etc become actually to be identical to thermal printer II so you
identical to thermal printer II so you know this message passing algorithm will
know this message passing algorithm will give you exactly the same answers that
give you exactly the same answers that come the printer does the questions will
come the printer does the questions will more complicated you know and
more complicated you know and conceptually but actually much way much
conceptually but actually much way much much more elegant than the derivation of
much more elegant than the derivation of the Kalman filter equations okay and so
the Kalman filter equations okay and so we will actually review and lots of
we will actually review and lots of these things because data simulation is
these things because data simulation is important so I worship to get this
important so I worship to get this concept in detail as we go through the
concept in detail as we go through the course
course okay so we have 25 minutes to finish the
okay so we have 25 minutes to finish the junction 3 algorithm that we discussed
junction 3 algorithm that we discussed and basically I'm not going to do
and basically I'm not going to do anything you know some very
anything you know some very parameterization of the Albert and then
parameterization of the Albert and then one cute example of applying the
one cute example of applying the junction tree algorithm to the hidden
junction tree algorithm to the hidden Markov models and into the head of so if
Markov models and into the head of so if you start let's say with a directed
you start let's say with a directed graph to get a junction tree the first
graph to get a junction tree the first thing you have to do is marelize and
thing you have to do is marelize and once you realize you replace all the
once you realize you replace all the directed edges with undirected edges so
directed edges with undirected edges so here is organization making the path
here is organization making the path Tektronix Plagne this red line this is
Tektronix Plagne this red line this is the factorization of the direction graph
the factorization of the direction graph and this is where they have from the
and this is where they have from the undirected graph so you can the color
undirected graph so you can the color supposed to represent we want one
supposed to represent we want one correspondence I mean really that's not
correspondence I mean really that's not an issue but this probability here is
an issue but this probability here is nice high potential
nice high potential etcetera etcetera
this is a bit more complicated example export history planet so basically have
export history planet so basically have to marry all of them straights not
to marry all of them straights not sufficient to marry actually x2 and you
sufficient to marry actually x2 and you say x1 is the husband of you and excuse
say x1 is the husband of you and excuse the hospital of extreme that x1 is a car
the hospital of extreme that x1 is a car politics the daily right no they have to
politics the daily right no they have to have an individual certificate of
have an individual certificate of marriage here so we need to connect x1
marriage here so we need to connect x1 x3 also okay then so this is how the
x3 also okay then so this is how the undirected graph will look like if you
undirected graph will look like if you have evidence we want to discuss this
have evidence we want to discuss this really there is nothing specific you
really there is nothing specific you need to do but take slices of these
need to do but take slices of these potentials okay
potentials okay by fixing to the given values whatever
by fixing to the given values whatever known to travelers you have so in this
known to travelers you have so in this case it's a 4 X 3 and X 4 are given
case it's a 4 X 3 and X 4 are given effectively you take a two-dimensional
effectively you take a two-dimensional slice from let's say this one dimension
slice from let's say this one dimension table human dimensions lines etc and in
table human dimensions lines etc and in principle the plane nodes in this
principle the plane nodes in this problem become X 1 X 2 X 5 X 6 and
problem become X 1 X 2 X 5 X 6 and excedrin and literally you can think of
excedrin and literally you can think of this equation X 1 X 2 I'll separate it
this equation X 1 X 2 I'll separate it from X 5 X 6 and X 7
from X 5 X 6 and X 7 so maybe you can do this sort of
so maybe you can do this sort of inference short opener in a very trivial
inference short opener in a very trivial manner you don't really have to mix
manner you don't really have to mix things together that don't depend on
things together that don't depend on each other the next step was to let me
each other the next step was to let me see this written here already for
see this written here already for buildin well so there was another
buildin well so there was another Stefan's maybe going to come in the next
Stefan's maybe going to come in the next slide because it's not a problem on this
slide because it's not a problem on this pictograph what was the other step that
pictograph what was the other step that was very essential
was very essential after modernization what do we have to
after modernization what do we have to do to create clicks that they are not
do to create clicks that they are not you know they don't lead to you just
you know they don't lead to you just basically then was the best word we use
basically then was the best word we use to get a junction tree we have to do
to get a junction tree we have to do what to the graph so example let's say
what to the graph so example let's say in my undirected graph if this was not
in my undirected graph if this was not there when you're going to be happy if
there when you're going to be happy if you had today was not there that was
you had today was not there that was what is the step you have to do
what is the step you have to do basically before you start getting you
basically before you start getting you know your junction tree yep
no cartographer dr. Graf left them behind us
behind us what's the war I said not supplying us
what's the war I said not supplying us here
you know one of them which was much more plates okay and the possibilities
plates okay and the possibilities basically as we wish I think in okay
increasing this this we have to satisfy a fundamental property to make this
a fundamental property to make this problem consistent and we will discuss
problem consistent and we will discuss this with examples today so what was the
this with examples today so what was the exact property that we need to satisfy
exact property that we need to satisfy to make this sort of car to work crops
when I look at this tree here I noticed this first node with a click a VD in
this first node with a click a VD in common so what did we say needs to
common so what did we say needs to happen in between this node and that
happen in between this node and that node if they serve no be the whoever of
node if they serve no be the whoever of no change in the junction tree to
no change in the junction tree to subscribe well you need to have what D
subscribe well you need to have what D ok whenever I receive information going
ok whenever I receive information going to propagate
to propagate from here to there to a baby it's going
from here to there to a baby it's going to mediate notes having no idea they
to mediate notes having no idea they don't care about this okay so you need
don't care about this okay so you need basically when you cancel you need to
basically when you cancel you need to satisfy that property of what you've
satisfy that property of what you've been taught now we actually reduce the
been taught now we actually reduce the concept of the separatist and the
concept of the separatist and the Cifaretto sphere are the squares
Cifaretto sphere are the squares knowledge that contain the Kuna notes
knowledge that contain the Kuna notes between the Terra Mystica VD and the
between the Terra Mystica VD and the click this again in this case are the
click this again in this case are the notes B and D and the converse operators
notes B and D and the converse operators and don't oppress them will come out or
and don't oppress them will come out or anything like that because clear every
anything like that because clear every note including the separator subjects
note including the separator subjects basically right I'm sorry mmm these are
basically right I'm sorry mmm these are the common laws between those two clicks
the common laws between those two clicks but basically there is no factor so
but basically there is no factor so anything like that the way we did in
anything like that the way we did in fact or not
fact or not now may say well but racist if it's a
now may say well but racist if it's a great comes with a potential right so
great comes with a potential right so that sense you can think representation
that sense you can think representation on the photograph but I'm not going to
on the photograph but I'm not going to use the concept today because you know
use the concept today because you know the junction tree as a tree of with
the junction tree as a tree of with white nodes immediately comes with its
white nodes immediately comes with its potential all right so these are the
potential all right so these are the separators alright and then you know
separators alright and then you know basically let's say without discussing
basically let's say without discussing about how we do inference right let's
about how we do inference right let's look at this know the conflict and this
look at this know the conflict and this note that self notes beardy
note that self notes beardy what do you think the importance of the
what do you think the importance of the parameter in this case what does it is
parameter in this case what does it is going to help us to remind us at least
going to help us to remind us at least walk but when the snake interact what
walk but when the snake interact what Lincoln updates information of this
Lincoln updates information of this click and the other way around
click and the other way around happens on what note
maybe the only notes that they're home to them so in other ways when this time
to them so in other ways when this time okay a masters only we see whether it
okay a masters only we see whether it means to this click this TV is no
means to this click this TV is no medicine to mess about every because be
medicine to mess about every because be stirred be doesn't care about it it has
stirred be doesn't care about it it has to be only on the notes that are in the
to be only on the notes that are in the separate okay
separate okay and there is a mathematical issue that
and there is a mathematical issue that we need to specify here and we will
we need to specify here and we will citizen in examples right somehow
citizen in examples right somehow I mean business this is let say a
I mean business this is let say a believer countries on potential the
believer countries on potential the separate on the logic on some potential
separate on the logic on some potential in a container you can guess maybe that
in a container you can guess maybe that invisible jurisdiction with respect to
invisible jurisdiction with respect to any of the potential of the trickery be
any of the potential of the trickery be be finishing up I mean the potential of
be finishing up I mean the potential of the separator be they will be the
the separator be they will be the marginalization of the see but what is
marginalization of the see but what is the rational potential do not agree with
the rational potential do not agree with each other that's what the algorithm
each other that's what the algorithm actually try to obtain but consistency
actually try to obtain but consistency that makes the two organizations equal
that makes the two organizations equal to each other
to each other so in some sense having dissipators
so in some sense having dissipators that's what they will do so the sending
that's what they will do so the sending message is basically this two clicks to
message is basically this two clicks to each other in a way that when given two
each other in a way that when given two allies this with respect to a and you
allies this with respect to a and you marginalize this with respect to see
marginalize this with respect to see somehow you can get a consistent
somehow you can get a consistent calculate
calculate of the separator for then shall be in
of the separator for then shall be in the process yes absolutely and this is
the process yes absolutely and this is what we will discuss today yes so we
what we will discuss today yes so we think and then it was talking to rating
think and then it was talking to rating you sent me a message I sent you a
you sent me a message I sent you a message everybody sends messages to each
message everybody sends messages to each other until we're all happy okay so
other until we're all happy okay so where's my desk I told you way too much
where's my desk I told you way too much information so let's as the plots come
information so let's as the plots come again we will see this again so we get
again we will see this again so we get the main so then this is the Train on
the main so then this is the Train on directed and you can see the
directed and you can see the triangulation process all right so we
triangulation process all right so we connected this block if the edges are
connected this block if the edges are this is the definition of the trip and
this is the definition of the trip and effectively the message that I think we
effectively the message that I think we passed last lecture was that so there
passed last lecture was that so there are many ways we can pose some what we
are many ways we can pose some what we said we are going to choose the one that
said we are going to choose the one that maximizes something and what is the many
maximizes something and what is the many challenges which one should be used so
challenges which one should be used so in this case we have this trade that has
in this case we have this trade that has two separate first each of them has two
two separate first each of them has two elements and then we have this 3 which
elements and then we have this 3 which is 30 minute and he has one element of
is 30 minute and he has one element of this separator and turned out whatever
this separator and turned out whatever you like
we have to redefine the maximum spanning tree with you know we will call it the
tree with you know we will call it the junction tree and when we say the
junction tree and when we say the maximum spanning tree maximal with
maximum spanning tree maximal with respect to what he has too much my son
respect to what he has too much my son tree so if you look at verse days what
tree so if you look at verse days what is the time between the two three
well the answer is you have to look at the separator
what is littering the separators invest twit P and in this the number of no all
twit P and in this the number of no all right so here we have 2 + 10 + 2 + 2 is
right so here we have 2 + 10 + 2 + 2 is greater than 1 + 2 3 and these lots of
greater than 1 + 2 3 and these lots of heuristic algorithms on how to do this
heuristic algorithms on how to do this the actual calculation is a very hard
the actual calculation is a very hard one you know for a complex 3 but using
one you know for a complex 3 but using the empirical methods give a job ok so
the empirical methods give a job ok so the natural trick has the largest total
the natural trick has the largest total separator of cardinality in this case
separator of cardinality in this case for example you can notice here is the
for example you can notice here is the cardinality here is still so 10 plus 2
cardinality here is still so 10 plus 2 is greater than 1 plus I'm sorry 1 plus
is greater than 1 plus I'm sorry 1 plus plus 2 okay in the running intersection
plus 2 okay in the running intersection property is what we discussed before it
property is what we discussed before it you know this self between this and this
you know this self between this and this next it has to be stare constant but any
next it has to be stare constant but any other click in between on the path okay
other click in between on the path okay so I just copy this 3 seconds before I
so I just copy this 3 seconds before I came from the lecture you know I always
came from the lecture you know I always try to find links for you to read more
try to find links for you to read more about these things right but not sure if
about these things right but not sure if you actually do but so stratosphere is
you actually do but so stratosphere is an empirical law group on how to find
an empirical law group on how to find this maximal spanning tree and and the
this maximal spanning tree and and the algorithm is just under the name of this
algorithm is just under the name of this crystal stir algorithm that is really
crystal stir algorithm that is really sort of a heuristic algorithm that works
sort of a heuristic algorithm that works in not change not just for Junction
in not change not just for Junction trees but this is very useful in many
trees but this is very useful in many other contexts as well so you know if
other contexts as well so you know if you hit this you will come up to this
you hit this you will come up to this live animation and an example and region
live animation and an example and region of the problem now and revisit the
of the problem now and revisit the junction tree algorithm using the
junction tree algorithm using the separated potentials so I'm going to
separated potentials so I'm going to cross paths with a parameterization that
cross paths with a parameterization that of the Joint Distribution that looks
of the Joint Distribution that looks like this relation that you see here
like this relation that you see here that is the product of the potentials of
that is the product of the potentials of for the maximal cliques
for the maximal cliques on my junction tree divided by the
on my junction tree divided by the product of the potentials of the
product of the potentials of the separators and in conceptual and please
separators and in conceptual and please does this make sense right why you
does this make sense right why you develop here by the potential of the
develop here by the potential of the separators
doesn't look like this I gave you a preview way to start defining the
preview way to start defining the superlative the different one so these
superlative the different one so these potentials you take know from the simple
potentials you take know from the simple interpretation equals one discussion
interpretation equals one discussion here basically first operators are one
here basically first operators are one and you can affiliate the connect
and you can affiliate the connect potentials in your original undirected
potentials in your original undirected graph with the clip potentials that you
graph with the clip potentials that you used in the junction 3 then the
used in the junction 3 then the numerator in that expression is actually
numerator in that expression is actually the joint probability bution of all the
the joint probability bution of all the variables all right so mr. very general
variables all right so mr. very general expression I'm going to use if you are
expression I'm going to use if you are confused as to why is that consider that
confused as to why is that consider that I'm starting with the denominator to be
I'm starting with the denominator to be equal to answer there's no issue ok and
equal to answer there's no issue ok and then we would see what happens as we go
then we would see what happens as we go along okay you know the parameterization
along okay you know the parameterization we discussed on the last lecture but the
we discussed on the last lecture but the equations are identical in other ways if
equations are identical in other ways if you put the two x's next to each other
you put the two x's next to each other and you look at the equations they plan
and you look at the equations they plan to start with but then you know with
to start with but then you know with some thinking they're identical so here
some thinking they're identical so here we have separator right everywhere okay
we have separator right everywhere okay we do not have this in the previous
we do not have this in the previous lecture so let's so we're going to start
lecture so let's so we're going to start planting messages basically from the
planting messages basically from the links to vary
links to vary to tell you the way we have done it in
to tell you the way we have done it in the past and so let's tell the message
the past and so let's tell the message from a curriculum die to click no J did
from a curriculum die to click no J did we stay by the initial mr. political
we stay by the initial mr. political potential that no information no the
potential that no information no the eyes consent today is about which no so
eyes consent today is about which no so if I understand some information from
if I understand some information from right answer if your information a
right answer if your information a consent is the information related to an
consent is the information related to an updated the knowledge that are shared by
updated the knowledge that are shared by CI n CJ I am going to send two giant
CI n CJ I am going to send two giant firm ation what some knows this click
firm ation what some knows this click contains blood I'm not contain is to say
contains blood I'm not contain is to say because that's your anyone so not only
because that's your anyone so not only are going to sent information that is
are going to sent information that is related with the current variables
related with the current variables effectively what I need to do is the
effectively what I need to do is the message I'm gonna sell to my today will
message I'm gonna sell to my today will be the potential of you know I defined
be the potential of you know I defined by the flick of NotI where I integrate
by the flick of NotI where I integrate all the variables about the variables
all the variables about the variables that are involved in the separator
extent so we sent information contained here but this point to the local
here but this point to the local potentials for each of these nodes and
potentials for each of these nodes and the ideas well you know take the old
the ideas well you know take the old potentials time if this is propagation
potentials time if this is propagation from the list of nodes times are the
from the list of nodes times are the messages that are coming from the times
messages that are coming from the times of Pi I mean on the side
well so let me say this just for update all right you know the picture let me
all right you know the picture let me see again
so this okay Charlie they things to I all right maybe this
they things to I all right maybe this picture is know that proper to general
picture is know that proper to general dating see I actually you know was it
dating see I actually you know was it thank you here actually thinking if it's
thank you here actually thinking if it's because me from business out scare okay
because me from business out scare okay so basically all the messages of the
so basically all the messages of the propagated from the children of no guy
propagated from the children of no guy okay so basically you know I had one
okay so basically you know I had one graphing they have to use it you can use
graphing they have to use it you can use the industries and give them the right
the industries and give them the right interpretation of the way you wanted a
interpretation of the way you wanted a physical IJ and because mister natality
physical IJ and because mister natality processed what we need to do is we need
processed what we need to do is we need to update the messages without basically
to update the messages without basically separate the potential okay and so look
separate the potential okay and so look at this equation carefully and and
at this equation carefully and and trying to give some personal meaning to
trying to give some personal meaning to what it takes
so this is sort of a definition right but this you can think of this being the
but this you can think of this being the amazing potential of the separator s9j
so what this equation says the other information of the fast from Lodi today
information of the fast from Lodi today we have to integrate over modernist
we have to integrate over modernist except the ones contain a separate them
except the ones contain a separate them but the notice here there's a division
but the notice here there's a division from surprise
and again this is related to what your concept
I'm gonna convince you with a precise calculation why this works right but
calculation why this works right but shared this division is very similar to
shared this division is very similar to the division who has the belief
the division who has the belief propagation algorithm respectively why
propagation algorithm respectively why do we have this in the denominator
you didn't tell Commonwealth my message from Jake are we no one can doubt
from Jake are we no one can doubt melancholy the message that basically
melancholy the message that basically the Bison taste of chains so this
the Bison taste of chains so this calculation
okay okay all right
everything from very acceptable semester project so then I'm gonna days once I
project so then I'm gonna days once I have updated this operator potential I
have updated this operator potential I am going to update the potential of the
am going to update the potential of the Qaddafi and the real dated is the old
Qaddafi and the real dated is the old potential of trig W times the abated
potential of trig W times the abated separated people potential divided by
separated people potential divided by the original separated potential okay
the original separated potential okay that sounds good
that sounds good we will show right what obviously
we will show right what obviously passing messages can wait to battle you
passing messages can wait to battle you so the potential if there's no way to
so the potential if there's no way to change to another man exactly so let's
change to another man exactly so let's see how we're gonna send those Mexican
see how we're gonna send those Mexican value T to V so we're gonna have to
value T to V so we're gonna have to update the potential of the separator
update the potential of the separator how do we do this by taking the
how do we do this by taking the potential of W which remember was update
potential of W which remember was update me to this and we're going to integrate
me to this and we're going to integrate all the vitamins buffers in the
all the vitamins buffers in the separator and then we are going to
separator and then we are going to update the potential of V which remember
update the potential of V which remember was this and how we're going to update
was this and how we're going to update there may be potential of the separator
there may be potential of the separator divided by the previous value of the
divided by the previous value of the potential of the separators times try
potential of the separators times try the star which is this and the potential
the star which is this and the potential of Gavi will remain the updated to start
of Gavi will remain the updated to start swimming with what it was before so
swimming with what it was before so messages from V to W and I'm updating
messages from V to W and I'm updating the separator potential the davia
the separator potential the davia potential the V potential really doesn't
potential the V potential really doesn't change and then messages from EE here to
change and then messages from EE here to me
me I am updating the separation it separate
I am updating the separation it separate the potential the potential of V and the
the potential the potential of V and the potential now he doesn't say why this
potential now he doesn't say why this works most - those that belong in ask so
works most - those that belong in ask so well so this is probably double stars
well so this is probably double stars try plant-eating right this is this this
try plant-eating right this is this this comes outside the summation sign
comes outside the summation sign hispanist IV and what is this this is pH
hispanist IV and what is this this is pH are you still at the discount of tau
are you still at the discount of tau this is the second half length of the
this is the second half length of the separator potential which is what is the
separator potential which is what is the summation of all the nodes but as from
summation of all the nodes but as from darling you
[Applause]
the potential of the separator is the same regardless my completed my
same regardless my completed my marginalization of the potential on the
marginalization of the potential on the left or the potential overall so
left or the potential overall so basically by you can think of this you
basically by you can think of this you know a forward and a mess disgusting I
know a forward and a mess disgusting I have achieved basically with some
have achieved basically with some consistency which is exactly what I work
is based on the papers this consistency between the potentials defined by the
between the potentials defined by the clicks if you don't have this sort of
clicks if you don't have this sort of explicitly you know somehow still you
explicitly you know somehow still you will need to satisfy some consistency
will need to satisfy some consistency relations but here they are sort of
relations but here they are sort of straightforward basically for the
straightforward basically for the previous picture this the slide because
previous picture this the slide because I'm not going to repeat them again the
you cannot say you sent messages from here to there so we have to update
here to there so we have to update basically the potential of the separator
basically the potential of the separator this is what we did then we have to
this is what we did then we have to update the potential of this click by
update the potential of this click by multiplying the previous values of the
multiplying the previous values of the potential with size start dividing
potential with size start dividing lifestyle and you remember we start with
lifestyle and you remember we start with the separator potential to be equal to 1
the separator potential to be equal to 1 and then we do the markers
and then we do the markers so he marginalised say I start for
so he marginalised say I start for everything except mr. Perret embody most
everything except mr. Perret embody most and then you have take as we spend Isis
and then you have take as we spend Isis provide to jail you update the potential
provide to jail you update the potential of J this factor and at the end of the
of J this factor and at the end of the day if you actually consistency and when
day if you actually consistency and when you know doing all of these calculations
you know doing all of these calculations the marginal distribution and you know
the marginal distribution and you know the variables remains unchanged okay and
the variables remains unchanged okay and I think there is some put in the slides
I think there is some put in the slides that shows that but basically very we
that shows that but basically very we don't play with the joint probability
don't play with the joint probability distribution with all these local
distribution with all these local updates because the local updates
updates because the local updates maintain the joyful of in distribution
maintain the joyful of in distribution to be to be the same during iterations
to be to be the same during iterations and actually chemists you know I am I
and actually chemists you know I am I just said with the trivial example that
just said with the trivial example that perfect does not change basically in
perfect does not change basically in either the forward of the backwards that
either the forward of the backwards that it remains the same okay I have 30
it remains the same okay I have 30 minutes and I'm going to do one example
minutes and I'm going to do one example the struggles it sounds like another
the struggles it sounds like another killed right but I wanted to show you
killed right but I wanted to show you how you can actually apply this to real
how you can actually apply this to real problems so this is cohesion Markov
problems so this is cohesion Markov models that I will start discussing
models that I will start discussing detail on Thursday but we're going to do
detail on Thursday but we're going to do the junction tree algorithm with the
the junction tree algorithm with the separators for the hmm model today
for those who have not seen it the hmm LD - can we have some sugar dynamics so
LD - can we have some sugar dynamics so there's notes that the shielded waffle
there's notes that the shielded waffle is the system state that evolves with
is the system state that evolves with some dynamics and right now we assumed
some dynamics and right now we assumed that the modern smart for bein so the
that the modern smart for bein so the probability of being on a given state
probability of being on a given state here depends only on the state that you
here depends only on the state that you were before and it's defined by this
were before and it's defined by this transition that you say hey and somehow
transition that you say hey and somehow you want to infer this hidden states by
you want to infer this hidden states by some large observations that I volunteer
some large observations that I volunteer y0 y1 white the white pocket empty or
y0 y1 white the white pocket empty or something like that so we want to do
something like that so we want to do sort of the junction 3 algorithm and in
sort of the junction 3 algorithm and in the process you can discover the
the process you can discover the probabilistic after matters all the
probabilistic after matters all the equations from you know you may not know
equations from you know you may not know about Kalman filtering in a show you can
about Kalman filtering in a show you can derive any sort of extensions to come a
derive any sort of extensions to come a filtering your interest rate for the
filtering your interest rate for the shuttle distribution I using a cure but
shuttle distribution I using a cure but somehow I have to change the slides so
somehow I have to change the slides so this parity scare the durations of Y so
this parity scare the durations of Y so the joint of a minute radiation of Q and
the joint of a minute radiation of Q and y is given by the probability of the
y is given by the probability of the initial stage which is the transition
initial stage which is the transition probabilities from - t2 t2 plus 1 and
probabilities from - t2 t2 plus 1 and this is the observation model many most
this is the observation model many most probably hoped
probably hoped without right some sort of just a little
without right some sort of just a little bit all right so again I want you as an
bit all right so again I want you as an overkill application right because you
overkill application right because you can't apply something that is very
can't apply something that is very general a trivial problem
general a trivial problem we know the answer they sound like
we know the answer they sound like another kid but it's a very good
position ethics AI J the in the join distribution
ethics AI J the in the join distribution here right I can write it's playable
here right I can write it's playable this is the probability of QT plus 1
this is the probability of QT plus 1 given Q T so we find all the metrics say
given Q T so we find all the metrics say which components a I'm very defined the
which components a I'm very defined the way is secure so I go from state I time
way is secure so I go from state I time step T you know state J on T plus 1 I
step T you know state J on T plus 1 I can write this as a IJ 250 I 50 plus 1 J
can write this as a IJ 250 I 50 plus 1 J from and I'm assuming here I have a
from and I'm assuming here I have a multinomial distribution so the values
multinomial distribution so the values of the states can be n different values
of the states can be n different values of its time then you should ask I mean
of its time then you should ask I mean isn't this triply eyes except you know
isn't this triply eyes except you know some of them would be 1 and that's what
some of them would be 1 and that's what we want they will give you the correct
we want they will give you the correct element for my transition matrix AI J
element for my transition matrix AI J there's nothing faster okay again the
there's nothing faster okay again the for identification state to ask this
for identification state to ask this transition probabilities from the
transition probabilities from the dynamics and times of the vegetable so
dynamics and times of the vegetable so the when we do states a state-space
the when we do states a state-space models in the next week or so the
models in the next week or so the fundamental problems in the context of
fundamental problems in the context of data simulation is basically if you're
data simulation is basically if you're given don't define P to estimate the
given don't define P to estimate the state of time T that's what is called
state of time T that's what is called the sintering problem the prediction
the sintering problem the prediction problem is if you are given data up to
problem is if you are given data up to time s to the predictions of habit
time s to the predictions of habit raishin but the prediction problem and
raishin but the prediction problem and then the smithing problem is if you are
then the smithing problem is if you are given observations from now on till
given observations from now on till tomorrow can we predict distributing
tomorrow can we predict distributing what the state is so here using a lot of
what the state is so here using a lot of data including future data to predict
data including future data to predict the state of the given value time and
the state of the given value time and suppose nothing obviously because this
suppose nothing obviously because this would be very smooth to answer than what
would be very smooth to answer than what you would get with printer various
you would get with printer various problems you can address them with
problems you can address them with probabilistic graphical models and
probabilistic graphical models and actually we talked on deeper messages
actually we talked on deeper messages the way we did for for changed but I
the way we did for for changed but I will again do another King today to use
will again do another King today to use the junction tree over to show this
the junction tree over to show this problem okay just think you can get the
problem okay just think you can get the Peconic if the junction tree thinking
Peconic if the junction tree thinking deeply so children for example to
deeply so children for example to calculate the marginal of the
calculate the marginal of the observations you can see the summation
observations you can see the summation here this challenge because if you have
here this challenge because if you have these steps and each day but you have to
these steps and each day but you have to some take some values this is M to the
some take some values this is M to the time m to Capitol Hill calculations so
time m to Capitol Hill calculations so this is very expensive we need to be
this is very expensive we need to be able to do this table for problems with
able to do this table for problems with well better than this exponential course
I don't think I would be able to proceed um realizing it but let's try to do our
um realizing it but let's try to do our best so if you reminders of some of the
best so if you reminders of some of the things beginning we will come and
things beginning we will come and discuss them slowly in front of lectures
discuss them slowly in front of lectures but I want to use okay if you see here
but I want to use okay if you see here is the smoothing problem I am well aware
is the smoothing problem I am well aware of the derivations because I don't have
of the derivations because I don't have the time and since we will repeat this
the time and since we will repeat this right let me just say that by using this
right let me just say that by using this basic probability was a no-show
basic probability was a no-show by using conditional independence
by using conditional independence relationships applied by this graph
relationships applied by this graph basically that which are given the node
basically that which are given the node P P Q P plus 1 is independent of QT
P P Q P plus 1 is independent of QT minus 1 right the type of Independence
minus 1 right the type of Independence relations you can show that this moving
relations you can show that this moving probability it's really the product of
probability it's really the product of the non semesters which is absolute
the non semesters which is absolute masters x 2 bar minus beta divided by P
masters x 2 bar minus beta divided by P of Y the marginal of Y and the
of Y the marginal of Y and the definition of the alpha methods is this
definition of the alpha methods is this entity here and the definition of the
entity here and the definition of the meta message just presented there if you
meta message just presented there if you look at this definition that comes
look at this definition that comes basically do the derivation is very
basically do the derivation is very simple is that is the probability that
simple is that is the probability that you will observe y0 y1 y3 and then in
you will observe y0 y1 y3 and then in the end of stage GT all right
the end of stage GT all right so alpha is merely something that
so alpha is merely something that accounts for all your observations of
accounts for all your observations of deterring TV sort of forward calculation
deterring TV sort of forward calculation but the trace is the joint probability
but the trace is the joint probability of
the observed date of to little T assuming that you've finished in state
assuming that you've finished in state 50 and you can show the first message is
50 and you can show the first message is that you have to calculate this
that you have to calculate this probability and this really can be
probability and this really can be calculated recursively we have been
calculated recursively we have been encouraged to the questions for the
encouraged to the questions for the Alpha method and the recursive equation
Alpha method and the recursive equation for the beta message noticed that the
for the beta message noticed that the updating of the Alpha message is
updating of the Alpha message is affirmative date so we reverse the
affirmative date so we reverse the message alpha Q T and the observation
message alpha Q T and the observation model of the dynamics to update so there
model of the dynamics to update so there is a marginalization if you take here
is a marginalization if you take here and the bigger message is the bathroom
and the bigger message is the bathroom message because you need to know the
message because you need to know the bigger masses of 350 plus one we've seen
bigger masses of 350 plus one we've seen this batch away yes when we change okay
this batch away yes when we change okay [Applause]
it's really that's what we did before but now we have this observation system
but now we have this observation system but literally this is the update
but literally this is the update equation this is a equation for the
equation this is a equation for the market
in mrs. Ballew constant and it is you know you're not still be remaining which
know you're not still be remaining which part are you expensive actually the the
part are you expensive actually the the automation of the death with the
automation of the death with the junction tree if you missed a map of
junction tree if you missed a map of propagation related to not to the
propagation related to not to the message beta but to this message gamma
message beta but to this message gamma and this message garlic you know what
and this message garlic you know what the pH is the posterior of QT given long
the pH is the posterior of QT given long terms of relations from y 0 to Y
terms of relations from y 0 to Y tropical T so this map of messed again
tropical T so this map of messed again is the posterior of should be given all
is the posterior of should be given all the observations of the capital T and
the observations of the capital T and you may say wife tomorrow message
you may say wife tomorrow message because if you do the calculations and
because if you do the calculations and they are simple to reveal the only gives
they are simple to reveal the only gives mister collation of the so to account
mister collation of the so to account for some conditional independence you
for some conditional independence you can show that the gamma Q T to complete
can show that the gamma Q T to complete each you have to compute the Masters
each you have to compute the Masters gamma 3 T plus 1 and then months analyze
gamma 3 T plus 1 and then months analyze with respect to K T plus one semester
with respect to K T plus one semester and I want you to right now to worry
and I want you to right now to worry about the details of the questions for
about the details of the questions for basically there is a data mess is
basically there is a data mess is propagating backwards but also is a
propagating backwards but also is a reminiscence
reminiscence if you like what's a little different ok
if you like what's a little different ok they have different definitions okay and
they have different definitions okay and their days if you know the sulfur masses
their days if you know the sulfur masses and the beta masters program a message
and the beta masters program a message effectively you can calculate there is
effectively you can calculate there is nothing probability distribution of QT
nothing probability distribution of QT given all the data so if you never
given all the data so if you never observe esters you say give me a nice
observe esters you say give me a nice smooth prediction of the state to take
smooth prediction of the state to take its effectively multiplying at least
its effectively multiplying at least knowledge the further than the marketing
knowledge the further than the marketing message the same way with an unequal
message the same way with an unequal training remember for the chain we need
training remember for the chain we need to calculate the posterior several types
to calculate the posterior several types of common measures the market message
of common measures the market message this is it do anything except to tell
this is it do anything except to tell you
this and the other and we will see the formulas we get to the junction 3 they
formulas we get to the junction 3 they are basically identical to the out
are basically identical to the out program updates that you get with the
program updates that you get with the classical length we put using
classical length we put using conditional okay the next homework
conditional okay the next homework project so make it a comma because
project so make it a comma because that's why you can learn something about
that's why you can learn something about data assimilation alright so so perfect