I wish they can say that the cluster's League because the weather is nice then
League because the weather is nice then that would be a very reasonable excuse
that would be a very reasonable excuse but as the semester progresses
but as the semester progresses everybody's coming later and later later
everybody's coming later and later later I don't even bring my watch anymore but
I don't even bring my watch anymore but unfortunately I can see the time there
so if you remember we were talking we start talking actually about doing
start talking actually about doing maximum likelihood estimation for the
maximum likelihood estimation for the parameters in undirected graphical
parameters in undirected graphical models so I'm going to continue that
models so I'm going to continue that topic but I realized that some of the
topic but I realized that some of the the you know the algorithm is a little
the you know the algorithm is a little bit more complicated than you guys are
bit more complicated than you guys are ready to take on a sunny day so I'm
ready to take on a sunny day so I'm going to take sort of the box back today
going to take sort of the box back today and I I'm gonna review this parameter
and I I'm gonna review this parameter estimation for completely describe to
estimation for completely describe to observe graphical models first starting
observe graphical models first starting with the under with directed graphs and
with the under with directed graphs and then I'm going to give you some
then I'm going to give you some introduction for undirected graph so
introduction for undirected graph so when we come on the next lecture we can
when we come on the next lecture we can complete the the previous notes from
complete the the previous notes from last Tuesday right like sometimes the
last Tuesday right like sometimes the lecture today is elementary on some
lecture today is elementary on some other point of view it's actually more
other point of view it's actually more complicated because it involves concepts
complicated because it involves concepts that we have already seen in the
that we have already seen in the homework yet
well interested basically to learn the parameters of directed undirected
parameters of directed undirected graphical models where we assume that we
graphical models where we assume that we have all the data we need this
have all the data we need this non-observable
non-observable so somebody gives you the recognizer
so somebody gives you the recognizer calmodulin space you know what I have
calmodulin space you know what I have data on all nodes in the graph can you
data on all nodes in the graph can you go and estimate the parameters
go and estimate the parameters and we're interested to go back to the
and we're interested to go back to the problem we discussed on Tuesday which is
problem we discussed on Tuesday which is maximum likelihood estimation so I can
maximum likelihood estimation so I can tell you what the outcome of the lecture
tell you what the outcome of the lecture today is going to be but for the referee
today is going to be but for the referee graphical models the parameter
graphical models the parameter estimation decouples as one little Emily
estimation decouples as one little Emily problem of this node so basically you
problem of this node so basically you can calculate the parameters locally in
can calculate the parameters locally in the graph so this is very trivial very
the graph so this is very trivial very attractive to do for undirected
attractive to do for undirected graphical mode for undirected graphical
graphical mode for undirected graphical model for Montecarlo fields we're ready
model for Montecarlo fields we're ready started discussing this on Tuesday
started discussing this on Tuesday because of the normalization factors D
because of the normalization factors D you cannot really be couple it this
you cannot really be couple it this nicely so the whole problem needs to
nicely so the whole problem needs to come together and compute all the
come together and compute all the parameters for all the tricks because
parameters for all the tricks because this G factor includes all the
this G factor includes all the information so this does not allow the
information so this does not allow the coffee now there is a very special type
coffee now there is a very special type of undirected graphical models that is
of undirected graphical models that is called the composable models where
called the composable models where somehow we can do a many locally and
somehow we can do a many locally and this is what I want to discuss today and
this is what I want to discuss today and so there is some relative that complete
so there is some relative that complete the Emily solution and this algorithms
the Emily solution and this algorithms are local okay so for dialectic
are local okay so for dialectic graphical models we're going to see the
graphical models we're going to see the problem is really trivial if we have a
problem is really trivial if we have a completely observed model for the record
completely observed model for the record graphical models it becomes an easy
graphical models it becomes an easy thing for what is called the composable
thing for what is called the composable bundle otherwise still you can do some
bundle otherwise still you can do some iterations and we will see what type of
iterations and we will see what type of file would we have
file would we have to discuss them much I'm gonna take a
to discuss them much I'm gonna take a step backwards and discuss the trivial
step backwards and discuss the trivial problem first of directed graphical
problem first of directed graphical models and see why this is sort of a
models and see why this is sort of a trivial situation I realize she's
trivial situation I realize she's getting hot
so we consider a very simple directive graphical fondant and you notice all the
graphical fondant and you notice all the notes are observed right and so if you
notes are observed right and so if you try to write the joint probability
try to write the joint probability distribution of course you may have P of
distribution of course you may have P of x1 given to that one so this is the
x1 given to that one so this is the transfer ominous theta one then you have
transfer ominous theta one then you have P of x2 given x1 its own parameters and
P of x2 given x1 its own parameters and finally P of X for given x2 and x3 with
finally P of X for given x2 and x3 with its own parameters 2 1 July will you
its own parameters 2 1 July will you write down the log life it looks like
write down the log life it looks like that so you can immediately see why this
that so you can immediately see why this is a trivial problem to discuss about
is a trivial problem to discuss about Emily estimation in the record graphs
Emily estimation in the record graphs when you have fully prescribed data
when you have fully prescribed data because if you look at theta 1 it only
because if you look at theta 1 it only comes in this term if you look at see
comes in this term if you look at see the two it only comes here etcetera
the two it only comes here etcetera etcetera so really if you want to
etcetera so really if you want to compute it along if you can do any many
compute it along if you can do any many problem on the first time if you want to
problem on the first time if you want to do to compute theta 2 or the second term
do to compute theta 2 or the second term etc so effectively the problem
etc so effectively the problem decomposes to little optimization
decomposes to little optimization problems defined in its node all right
problems defined in its node all right they need to know do you remember the
they need to know do you remember the probability involves the node and the
probability involves the node and the path of the node all right so
path of the node all right so information that for example if you try
information that for example if you try to compute theta 2 obviously the
to compute theta 2 obviously the observations X 1 and X 2 completely at
observations X 1 and X 2 completely at all so when we have to see at least four
all so when we have to see at least four discrete models how people get fitter to
discrete models how people get fitter to give an information
give an information x1 and x2 in essence what the Emily
x1 and x2 in essence what the Emily problem becomes becomes a bunch of
problem becomes becomes a bunch of separate Emily problems define for its
separate Emily problems define for its node and this little graph that you see
node and this little graph that you see involve to no than the parts okay so in
involve to no than the parts okay so in in many ways you can run this in
in many ways you can run this in parallel and it's as we received surveys
parallel and it's as we received surveys analytical solution eight sort of a
analytical solution eight sort of a trivial problem
trivial problem so let's because I'm gonna need the
so let's because I'm gonna need the notation in the context of Markov random
notation in the context of Markov random field so let's introduce this notation
field so let's introduce this notation for directed models so we have a graph
for directed models so we have a graph okay this is the number of notes a
okay this is the number of notes a number of edges xu is random variable
number of edges xu is random variable affiliated with a note you in the graph
affiliated with a note you in the graph the little xu is the realization of
the little xu is the realization of capital X of you capital X with
capital X of you capital X with subscript T is basically the random
subscript T is basically the random variables affiliation with a subset G of
variables affiliation with a subset G of the notes alright
the notes alright and this would be a very useful
and this would be a very useful important location actually today and
important location actually today and because we use X subscript C to describe
because we use X subscript C to describe the random variables on the subset say
the random variables on the subset say we're going instead of using X and
we're going instead of using X and scribe order on the volume which we're
scribe order on the volume which we're going to put X subscript V to describe
going to put X subscript V to describe other of the variables in the graph as
other of the variables in the graph as well okay so the distribution factorizes
well okay so the distribution factorizes basically this is the fundamental
basically this is the fundamental property of directed graphs as a product
property of directed graphs as a product of these local distributions for it's no
of these local distributions for it's no condition of the parlance and these are
condition of the parlance and these are the unknown parameters that we want to
the unknown parameters that we want to compute okay so basically this
compute okay so basically this parameters if the variables are discrete
parameters if the variables are discrete they are basically the values that the
they are basically the values that the XQ takes the tray value i given the
XQ takes the tray value i given the defines
defines take a value J
take a value J but we just denote the parameters now
but we just denote the parameters now asleep thank you but really for the
asleep thank you but really for the street models the parameters
street models the parameters v IQ is the table that gives you the
v IQ is the table that gives you the information about this conditional
information about this conditional distribution where can we have n
distribution where can we have n observations and sure that is
observations and sure that is interesting and observations means I
interesting and observations means I have n observations and each observation
have n observations and each observation involves values of all the nodes in the
involves values of all the nodes in the graph because everything is observed ok
graph because everything is observed ok so there is not hidden variables so
so there is not hidden variables so again in everything we have done up to
again in everything we have done up to now when we still have n observations we
now when we still have n observations we may have some variables in the graph
may have some variables in the graph here we apply all the the realizations
here we apply all the the realizations are given in the graph and we have n of
are given in the graph and we have n of those right n observations okay so let's
those right n observations okay so let's check how we are going to write this in
check how we are going to write this in some sense what we have is we have n
some sense what we have is we have n replicas or a 20 describe probabilistic
replicas or a 20 describe probabilistic directly graphical model you Bri so you
directly graphical model you Bri so you know if I say I give you all of these
know if I say I give you all of these nodes prescribed one realization I will
nodes prescribed one realization I will give you another one and another one and
give you another one and another one and another one really a heav n realizations
another one really a heav n realizations I have n different graphical models
I have n different graphical models obviously it's not convenient to think
obviously it's not convenient to think that you work with an graphical model so
that you work with an graphical model so somehow when we do the analysis we will
somehow when we do the analysis we will need sort of to take this information
need sort of to take this information and and somehow composited in a way that
and and somehow composited in a way that we can use these probability for one
we can use these probability for one stinking graph G ok but right now the
stinking graph G ok but right now the way that this looks like ok it's like
way that this looks like ok it's like that and so it's maybe back home to
that and so it's maybe back home to describe what is going on so I could
describe what is going on so I could describe if you want to describe the end
describe if you want to describe the end for this replicas of the twenty
for this replicas of the twenty described
described directly grout even have to write it as
directly grout even have to write it as xB which is all the notes or theoretical
xB which is all the notes or theoretical and what if you want to do this for a
and what if you want to do this for a subset of note C then you have to again
subset of note C then you have to again refer to some replicas and okay so it's
refer to some replicas and okay so it's a little bit awkward to do that so the
a little bit awkward to do that so the observed data set is the values of all
observed data set is the values of all the notes and we have this given n times
the notes and we have this given n times again I want you to be sure that you
again I want you to be sure that you understand this each of this are the
understand this each of this are the values of X's every cronograph alright
values of X's every cronograph alright and we have n realizations below
and we have n realizations below so the likelihood is written as the
so the likelihood is written as the product over each of this replicas of
product over each of this replicas of the likelihood for each graph and given
the likelihood for each graph and given the parameters so I have n data you know
the parameters so I have n data you know I have a product over with the data set
I have a product over with the data set and then the factorization of the Joint
and then the factorization of the Joint Distribution over each graph is over
Distribution over each graph is over nodes right and I put a subscript u
nodes right and I put a subscript u there and here clear precise that this
there and here clear precise that this refers to the replica and anybody
refers to the replica and anybody follows
right we're giving and number of observations and each observation
observations and each observation involves the values of for the notes in
involves the values of for the notes in a graph alright so what I want to write
a graph alright so what I want to write a likelihood I'm going to have first
a likelihood I'm going to have first over a product of the likelihood of this
over a product of the likelihood of this replicas here want to up to n right so
replicas here want to up to n right so this is a product and then I'm going to
this is a product and then I'm going to have to light the light with a picture
have to light the light with a picture of this graph I mean much of the course
of this graph I mean much of the course up to now has been the likelihood of a
up to now has been the likelihood of a single graph but now because fully
single graph but now because fully describe I have a likelihood over an
describe I have a likelihood over an elective s of the graph and it'd be
elective s of the graph and it'd be different okay so and this distribution
different okay so and this distribution for this replica end it is written in
for this replica end it is written in the classical way is the product of the
the classical way is the product of the Xu for every note you given the parents
Xu for every note you given the parents alright and peter view of the parameters
alright and peter view of the parameters but you know the defined that condition
but you know the defined that condition distribution so we take the log
distribution so we take the log likelihood right the public becomes
likelihood right the public becomes summations it looks like that can you
summations it looks like that can you see now immediately why this Emily
see now immediately why this Emily estimation the couple's can look at this
estimation the couple's can look at this equation I don't read anything in the
equation I don't read anything in the text etc so we can move faster today and
text etc so we can move faster today and tell me look at this equation what
tell me look at this equation what information from the observations do we
information from the observations do we need to compute the parameters theta you
need to compute the parameters theta you about having the conditional
about having the conditional distribution affectionately given its
distribution affectionately given its products so what information how do you
products so what information how do you you know maximize this with respect to
you know maximize this with respect to theta here for the given you
in how many firms invest a double summation of these are you comes in
summation of these are you comes in terms okay and only one of the
terms okay and only one of the summations on you so what are the
summations on you so what are the cetacean statistics basically from the
cetacean statistics basically from the data or at least what information looks
data or at least what information looks right now from all the data that it's
right now from all the data that it's going to be essential in computing
going to be essential in computing p-type you looking at this the
p-type you looking at this the observations of the non-text view in the
observations of the non-text view in the n electricals that we had and also the
n electricals that we had and also the information on the current review
information on the current review there's no return for these things
there's no return for these things coming in you see that if that he only
coming in you see that if that he only comes it is you know the parameters are
comes it is you know the parameters are coming in this distribution rights
coming in this distribution rights during installation of many of these
during installation of many of these distributions so today you will only be
distributions so today you will only be in all these terms 10 where we have the
in all these terms 10 where we have the youth here you and the parents of you
youth here you and the parents of you there on the couple okay the only cover
there on the couple okay the only cover all right now we will not tell me that
all right now we will not tell me that if this distribution is in the
if this distribution is in the exponential family right actually we can
exponential family right actually we can easily compute sufficient statistics all
easily compute sufficient statistics all right but for any and basically okay so
right but for any and basically okay so let's see how this is going to have
so inefficient I was going to get a little bit complicated and I need this
little bit complicated and I need this when throughout the lecture today so we
when throughout the lecture today so we have any observations at all the roads
have any observations at all the roads being the go ok so let me introduce the
being the go ok so let me introduce the following definition all right so the
following definition all right so the intellectual member is reinventions with
intellectual member is reinventions with a subscript retiarius the organization's
a subscript retiarius the organization's of all the variables so M affects V is
of all the variables so M affects V is the number of times that in my data set
the number of times that in my data set I escape this realization little extra
I escape this realization little extra subscript me I'm working with discrete
subscript me I'm working with discrete volume so it's every X takes a finite
volume so it's every X takes a finite number of values and I'm taking a
number of values and I'm taking a collection of all the variables and I'm
collection of all the variables and I'm asking for this collection little X's
asking for this collection little X's realization of all of our images mean
realization of all of our images mean how many counts how many times but
how many counts how many times but collection for the variables happens on
collection for the variables happens on the data set that I collected which is
the data set that I collected which is this n pint you ever and what the basis
this n pint you ever and what the basis is the summation of these Delta
is the summation of these Delta functions or indicator functions to do
functions or indicator functions to do once them even better and this gives me
once them even better and this gives me one every time XV coincides with X very
one every time XV coincides with X very subscript F do you agree this is what I
subscript F do you agree this is what I have observed so if you gave me amounts
have observed so if you gave me amounts of realizations who followed the axis
of realizations who followed the axis obviously the number of cows how many
obviously the number of cows how many times in my data set this happens is the
times in my data set this happens is the summation of this
you know sometimes I'm wonder if anybody sleeping and then I realized somebody
sleeping and then I realized somebody looks there they're so well okay yeah
yes
all right
okay so this again X subscript V is the realization of focus in the dark to give
realization of focus in the dark to give them a try on X 2 X 5 X 55 whatever you
them a try on X 2 X 5 X 55 whatever you have the number of times the number of
have the number of times the number of cows that you see this in your observed
cows that you see this in your observed observations is this time now I am going
observations is this time now I am going to introduce the notation for partial
to introduce the notation for partial accounts always subscripe of the
accounts always subscripe of the variables and I want you to look very
variables and I want you to look very carefully on this equation and convince
carefully on this equation and convince yourself that we understand it so we
yourself that we understand it so we introduce ffxv the number of accounts in
introduce ffxv the number of accounts in my data set of this observation section
my data set of this observation section 2 XV all right and now to define the
2 XV all right and now to define the partial count of a subset G unfold my
partial count of a subset G unfold my notes okay what I have to do is take
notes okay what I have to do is take this and sum it over all the
this and sum it over all the realizations in V minus T so I you know
realizations in V minus T so I you know I give the relationship C and I can
I give the relationship C and I can complete this partial tau all right
complete this partial tau all right by taking this and summing everything
by taking this and summing everything except X subscript C and you have a
except X subscript C and you have a value so you say understand all the
value so you say understand all the possible combinations for the other
possible combinations for the other variables enough to give me the count
variables enough to give me the count effective take for example if I share
effective take for example if I share three variables right and M of X 1 X 2 X
three variables right and M of X 1 X 2 X 3 is the number of times in my data set
3 is the number of times in my data set but capital X 1 takes the value little X
but capital X 1 takes the value little X 1 capital X 2 takes the value little X 2
1 capital X 2 takes the value little X 2 capital X 3 X 1 a little extreme to
capital X 3 X 1 a little extreme to define the number of times that in my
define the number of times that in my data stand I have a capital X 1 taking
data stand I have a capital X 1 taking divided leave electron and capital
divided leave electron and capital actually
actually let's do what I have to do is take the
let's do what I have to do is take the count or for all the variables and some
count or for all the variables and some extreme make sense yes all right so and
extreme make sense yes all right so and similarly mx1 I can comics to tear over
similarly mx1 I can comics to tear over I can some X 2 and X 3 or not okay so
I can some X 2 and X 3 or not okay so what I want you to remember is this is
what I want you to remember is this is the count M of X V for all the variables
the count M of X V for all the variables and this is a party account for a
and this is a party account for a success of the variables and this would
success of the variables and this would be an essential thing right because we
be an essential thing right because we will have the you see shortly why and we
will have the you see shortly why and we try to solve them really well now look
try to solve them really well now look at this equation and tell me this is for
at this equation and tell me this is for the example right but effectively if I
the example right but effectively if I take M effects V of all the variables
take M effects V of all the variables and I sound for possible combinations of
and I sound for possible combinations of X V and then I have to get particle and
X V and then I have to get particle and there
right
here I'm taking all possible realizations of my variables but they
realizations of my variables but they have only an observation so this sum has
have only an observation so this sum has to be equal to capital F okay so let me
to be equal to capital F okay so let me introduce the last notation basically
introduce the last notation basically then we're ready to go I'm going to
then we're ready to go I'm going to introduce a partial account for the
introduce a partial account for the comedy of the note you okay so the
comedy of the note you okay so the family of a note here is basically here
family of a note here is basically here in the palette right and I do notice as
in the palette right and I do notice as P of you okay so take some realizations
P of you okay so take some realizations of the notes that belong to this family
of the notes that belong to this family of note view obviously the number of
of note view obviously the number of times that you see this in your data set
times that you see this in your data set is the partial account which is
is the partial account which is completed if you take n of organizations
completed if you take n of organizations of X V and you sum for all values in
of X V and you sum for all values in these notes except the values that
these notes except the values that belong in the family of the note view
belong in the family of the note view you see that so this is the number of
you see that so this is the number of counts that you see and now do you take
counts that you see and now do you take some values and the Paris take some
some values and the Paris take some other value
other value okay you can compute this by taking the
okay you can compute this by taking the total count over all the notes and
total count over all the notes and summing everything but the notes that
summing everything but the notes that belong without stopping so let's turn I
belong without stopping so let's turn I don't have to go through all of this so
don't have to go through all of this so I'm looking on the equation of the
I'm looking on the equation of the bottom all right so we're looking for
bottom all right so we're looking for the likelihood of of
of the observations I have and I'm guessing they're absolute most probably
guessing they're absolute most probably it'd be okay
it'd be okay it's on slide 11 this is fine as it is
it's on slide 11 this is fine as it is but you know it's better to put the
but you know it's better to put the probability of the observation of given
probability of the observation of given the parameters suddenly you're late and
the parameters suddenly you're late and we're all this equation before that this
we're all this equation before that this is the product of the likely which over
is the product of the likely which over this and eléctricas remember anything
this and eléctricas remember anything else we can do so
else we can do so okay so I have the product basically
okay so I have the product basically over and graphs right so this listen to
over and graphs right so this listen to them and this is the likelihood for each
them and this is the likelihood for each graph end of observing the data that I
graph end of observing the data that I have given for the presentation okay so
have given for the presentation okay so now I'm going to do I won't be get rid
now I'm going to do I won't be get rid of this index ten and this product in n
of this index ten and this product in n so I'm going to start doing some algebra
so I'm going to start doing some algebra so I'm going to write this probability
so I'm going to write this probability for this replica and I'm gonna write it
for this replica and I'm gonna write it as this product and I want you to look
as this product and I want you to look and tell me that you understand
all right so what exactly have I done here remember in in this time all right
here remember in in this time all right I have a particular type of realization
I have a particular type of realization of all the variables right X subscript V
of all the variables right X subscript V comma n is from the unreplicated the
comma n is from the unreplicated the values of all the nodes in a lifeless as
values of all the nodes in a lifeless as the following take basically the
the following take basically the probability of observing little X
probability of observing little X subscript V rotational inertia flex V in
subscript V rotational inertia flex V in only converse bunch of experi cortex
only converse bunch of experi cortex become an we have all those tricks
become an we have all those tricks actually before okay all right
actually before okay all right that's this equation on middle and then
that's this equation on middle and then for notice that the probability
for notice that the probability basically of having the realizations of
basically of having the realizations of all the nodes okay given the parameters
all the nodes okay given the parameters is basically the product of the curve of
is basically the product of the curve of the probabilities of the parents given a
the probabilities of the parents given a mean of the knowledge given the parents
mean of the knowledge given the parents but with recent Anthony's notice that by
but with recent Anthony's notice that by doing this trick here the isness I only
doing this trick here the isness I only worked with the probability of one model
worked with the probability of one model this is very important the subscription
this is very important the subscription has been eliminated here right when we
has been eliminated here right when we start playing right so we have the
start playing right so we have the probability of X V comma n here there is
probability of X V comma n here there is no anymore end the end has gone up to
no anymore end the end has gone up to that delta function so we work with the
that delta function so we work with the probability the joint probability of one
probability the joint probability of one graphical model alone not of the n
graphical model alone not of the n replicas okay action
replicas okay action and what practically done I think with
and what practically done I think with this slide take the log of this so this
this slide take the log of this so this product is gonna become a summation all
product is gonna become a summation all right we don't like this gonna end there
right we don't like this gonna end there so this term is going to become a
so this term is going to become a summation
summation the delta function will come down and
the delta function will come down and then we're going to have log of V of X V
then we're going to have log of V of X V given theta this is nice because this is
given theta this is nice because this is the probability the love largely good
the probability the love largely good for our generic graph right does not
for our generic graph right does not involve any end and now notice if I take
involve any end and now notice if I take the summation here in n what is this
the summation here in n what is this summation giving me what is this
summation giving me what is this summation according to our definition
you know I go through basically okay so this is for possible configuration so
this is for possible configuration so then you know what I do is for each 6v I
then you know what I do is for each 6v I am checking how many times that
am checking how many times that exhibitions appear within my data set so
exhibitions appear within my data set so isn't it this the terms of M XP right
isn't it this the terms of M XP right okay
okay so basically if you look at this there
so basically if you look at this there is absolutely no end here now there's no
is absolutely no end here now there's no precursor of models etc I want to graph
precursor of models etc I want to graph alone but somehow the bank has been
alone but somehow the bank has been integrated in the number of cows of the
integrated in the number of cows of the observed X subscript V okay so let's put
observed X subscript V okay so let's put in here
in here right so the log likelihood of all my
right so the log likelihood of all my observations is this again and I write
observations is this again and I write this probability as long I factorize
this probability as long I factorize this over the conditional probabilities
this over the conditional probabilities of bits now given the parent and I
of bits now given the parent and I forgot to mention the condition
forgot to mention the condition probability I basically because we work
probability I basically because we work with discrete variables I liked it you
with discrete variables I liked it you know a parametric homeless parameters
know a parametric homeless parameters theta that belongs to the Lord V and
theta that belongs to the Lord V and their functions of the data at the node
their functions of the data at the node V and it's product
V and it's product mr. Stanner petitioner could have
mr. Stanner petitioner could have written explicitly this P of X V given X
written explicitly this P of X V given X of its parts comma theta V but for a
of its parts comma theta V but for a discrete distribution departments are
discrete distribution departments are really the values of a conditional
really the values of a conditional distribution given different values for
distribution given different values for the node V any tolerance all right so
the node V any tolerance all right so this is basically from the factorization
this is basically from the factorization of the directed
of the directed a bundle so okay there is the product
a bundle so okay there is the product becomes a summation the launch goes
becomes a summation the launch goes inside and I have been a frictional so
inside and I have been a frictional so let's see I take this donation and VA
let's see I take this donation and VA put it outside I pay I take a summation
put it outside I pay I take a summation over all the immunization for the notes
over all the immunization for the notes and I split it in estimation over the
and I split it in estimation over the realizations of the family and the
realizations of the family and the organization of all the notes - the
organization of all the notes - the problem
problem am I allowed to do it I split this right
am I allowed to do it I split this right this is estimation over all
this is estimation over all hospitalizations for the notes and I
hospitalizations for the notes and I split it over the family of node V and
split it over the family of node V and everything you know except the family of
everything you know except the family of notes V and all right look now at the
notes V and all right look now at the inside summation what is the summation
inside summation what is the summation of this on the total count of XV we
of this on the total count of XV we introduced and definition it was our
introduced and definition it was our second definition of towns so if I take
second definition of towns so if I take this summation here what is it
this summation here what is it if I take F of M that's me and I found
if I take F of M that's me and I found everything but the family of V what they
everything but the family of V what they get the personal contact the notes and
get the personal contact the notes and the harmony of V alright so now I can
the harmony of V alright so now I can you see why immediately the problem the
you see why immediately the problem the MLE estimate the couple's and why you
MLE estimate the couple's and why you can compute the parameters affiliated
can compute the parameters affiliated with the condition probability of not V
with the condition probability of not V independently of other parameters can
independently of other parameters can you see this decomposition here right
you see this decomposition here right okay separates this right this is for
okay separates this right this is for each node V and for each node V I have
each node V and for each node V I have this summation over all possible
this summation over all possible realizations of the varnish effects in
realizations of the varnish effects in the family of being
the family of being so basically you can immediately see
so basically you can immediately see that this parameterization only comes
that this parameterization only comes once for each node V the problem is
once for each node V the problem is convened a couple so we want to complete
convened a couple so we want to complete this parameter so obviously we're going
this parameter so obviously we're going to maximize this but to maximize it we
to maximize this but to maximize it we all should have so children we decouple
all should have so children we decouple it right we're gonna maximize this with
it right we're gonna maximize this with them separately okay because this
them separately okay because this parameters appear only in this term but
parameters appear only in this term but we need to be careful because since this
we need to be careful because since this is for habilities conditional
is for habilities conditional probability when you sang in XV you have
probability when you sang in XV you have to get equal to one when you have the
to get equal to one when you have the probability of X V given its powers and
probability of X V given its powers and you sominex three it better stands to up
you sominex three it better stands to up okay so basically you have to put a
okay so basically you have to put a Lagrange multiplier and you want to
Lagrange multiplier and you want to compute the Emily estimates for the
compute the Emily estimates for the parameters that define this conditional
parameters that define this conditional distribution you have to maximize that
distribution you have to maximize that and the answer is immediate and an int
and the answer is immediate and an int actually always it says that the Emily
actually always it says that the Emily estimate of theta subscript V and
estimate of theta subscript V and remember really this is the conditional
remember really this is the conditional distribution of X V given its parents to
distribution of X V given its parents to put some values for X P so values for
put some values for X P so values for the parents
the parents that's what we're looking here is the
that's what we're looking here is the partial count effects in the commonly
partial count effects in the commonly divided by the partial count okay of X
was fun to the parlance of V but that makes sense so basically the calculated
makes sense so basically the calculated safety of analytics one clinician let a
safety of analytics one clinician let a extreme condition and it's wrong and you
extreme condition and it's wrong and you won't obey the parameters of that so
won't obey the parameters of that so what you have here is you have an
what you have here is you have an electronic school and surpass muscles
electronic school and surpass muscles that the values have observed in your
that the values have observed in your data set for x1 and x2 divided by the
data set for x1 and x2 divided by the observations that you have or in the
observations that you have or in the particular case if x1 is the comment
particular case if x1 is the comment basically for the counts of x1 is that
basically for the counts of x1 is that sort of an expected answer right
I mean this is the obvious answer and usually if you don't get the obvious
usually if you don't get the obvious answer you're doing something wrong
answer you're doing something wrong again this is for discrete distributions
again this is for discrete distributions okay and this is what you get so the
okay and this is what you get so the bottom line is this
bottom line is this Emily estimate for direct graphical
Emily estimate for direct graphical models the couples okay and you can
models the couples okay and you can solve this problems basically for each
solve this problems basically for each node separately and these partial counts
node separately and these partial counts that you get is the sufficient
that you get is the sufficient statistics that you need and contain all
statistics that you need and contain all the information relevant to this local
the information relevant to this local estimation and Emily estimation problem
estimation and Emily estimation problem for long B so all this estimates are
for long B so all this estimates are independent for each node so this
independent for each node so this paradox now I know a definition in the
paradox now I know a definition in the class in in in the film so we will say
class in in in the film so we will say you know if you try to do this great
you know if you try to do this great models and this probabilities right now
models and this probabilities right now very high-dimensional so you basically
very high-dimensional so you basically the very high dimension of table to
the very high dimension of table to describe this obviously that is not
describe this obviously that is not going to be very practical
going to be very practical I mean if X we can take PI values this
I mean if X we can take PI values this can take 20 values you know you got lost
can take 20 values you know you got lost okay so what you usually do is you
okay so what you usually do is you approximate this with a generalized
approximate this with a generalized linear model so you could basically if
linear model so you could basically if you link this distribution with fewer
you link this distribution with fewer parameters in a generalized linear model
parameters in a generalized linear model and so in we have shown them you can go
and so in we have shown them you can go and visit one of the lectures from the
and visit one of the lectures from the fall semester I think Mary's book has
fall semester I think Mary's book has this as well as an example you can show
this as well as an example you can show so in this case this generalizing and
so in this case this generalizing and what is corresponding to each node we
what is corresponding to each node we are decoupled
are decoupled so you can complete the parameters of
so you can complete the parameters of each of these models separately for each
each of these models separately for each node
node and you didn't have a nice solution in
and you didn't have a nice solution in terms of counts the way that you see
terms of counts the way that you see here so you have to solve any therapy
here so you have to solve any therapy the way to discuss problem okay
the way to discuss problem okay so basically what you get is and where
so basically what you get is and where he describes problem that you solve
he describes problem that you solve iteratively but you can do this
iteratively but you can do this algorithm in parallel for its note so in
algorithm in parallel for its note so in in essence you know the total still
in essence you know the total still becomes even if you have a network of
becomes even if you have a network of the game of expression for this
the game of expression for this conditional distribution okay so the
conditional distribution okay so the only thing I want you to not forget here
only thing I want you to not forget here is right but it says for completely
is right but it says for completely observed data sets all right so you have
observed data sets all right so you have begun everything is prescribed in the
begun everything is prescribed in the drafter I'm not even body can you just
drafter I'm not even body can you just if you have hidden variables since I
if you have hidden variables since I start I said something intellectual last
start I said something intellectual last time and we're going to come back on it
time and we're going to come back on it next week but if you have hidden
next week but if you have hidden variables how do you you know do you
variables how do you you know do you have any algorithms of chance that you
have any algorithms of chance that you think the same idea can be applied
think the same idea can be applied so basically somehow you can do some
so basically somehow you can do some iterations and apply some of the same
iterations and apply some of the same algorithms which will be that will allow
algorithms which will be that will allow you to work with hidden variables and
you to work with hidden variables and observe all
but this is a value so how will you do a man live when you have hidden powers
man live when you have hidden powers which how do you do Emily when you have
which how do you do Emily when you have kid environments
how do you do Emily what he have to the particles there's only one algorithm you
particles there's only one algorithm you know and the guy who you know will be
know and the guy who you know will be happy that you don't all those outward
happy that you don't all those outward p.m. expectation maximization you don't
p.m. expectation maximization you don't remember expectation maximization no no
remember expectation maximization no no all right you know what is what it isn't
all right you know what is what it isn't you know and you move on okay
expectation maximization all right so you do expectation much choices all
you do expectation much choices all right okay so we're gonna move back to
right okay so we're gonna move back to the problem we were discussing on
Thursday and try to see how we're actually can do MLE more than directed
actually can do MLE more than directed graphical models we will say the problem
graphical models we will say the problem does not decompose okay and it is a
does not decompose okay and it is a little bit vertically bit complicated
little bit vertically bit complicated mainly because of this normalization
mainly because of this normalization factor see the capitana parameters in
factor see the capitana parameters in the graph okay so
again premiums and thank the senator Kaine we have any lefty custer's we
Kaine we have any lefty custer's we started before but somehow we would like
started before but somehow we would like to get rid of these replicas and work
to get rid of these replicas and work with the probability of one undirected
with the probability of one undirected more than so we will need to borrow some
more than so we will need to borrow some of the notation reviews from directed
of the notation reviews from directed graphs that's why I inserted those
graphs that's why I inserted those slides but this is the main difficult
slides but this is the main difficult problem we need others
problem we need others ok so to learn if you give me the
ok so to learn if you give me the realizations of all the variables in the
realizations of all the variables in the graph right this is basically one of the
graph right this is basically one of the normalization till the product of this
normalization till the product of this potential is defined over clicked and
potential is defined over clicked and for the discussion today actually I'm
for the discussion today actually I'm not assuming anything about this click
not assuming anything about this click so you can use whatever you want so they
so you can use whatever you want so they don't even have to be maximal okay so
don't even have to be maximal okay so these are potentials over clicks not
these are potentials over clicks not necessarily the normalization factor is
necessarily the normalization factor is basically the numerator here when you
basically the numerator here when you sum over all possible configurations of
sum over all possible configurations of extreme and magnification is identical
extreme and magnification is identical to what I used before sure let's go
to what I used before sure let's go again all right please ask again it
again all right please ask again it doesn't make any sense the probability
doesn't make any sense the probability for the observations is the product of
for the observations is the product of the likelihood police really described
the likelihood police really described block right exiting a comma n is the
block right exiting a comma n is the data for the analeptic of the graph
data for the analeptic of the graph where I given all the realizations right
where I given all the realizations right okay and I write each of this as the
okay and I write each of this as the product over all possible configurations
product over all possible configurations to find out now where is the generic
to find out now where is the generic graph G and I use the likelihood of that
graph G and I use the likelihood of that for some realizations explained and then
for some realizations explained and then to get the replica and I could event a
to get the replica and I could event a function of the exponent right so when X
function of the exponent right so when X vacant side next the end I'm in business
vacant side next the end I'm in business right but by doing this effectively I
right but by doing this effectively I don't have any more to deal with this
don't have any more to deal with this text become iron okay I'm going to deal
text become iron okay I'm going to deal with one probability model oh my god
with one probability model oh my god I mean why having an erect because this
I mean why having an erect because this is it this is what I want to work with
is it this is what I want to work with okay no twist there's no rule right I
okay no twist there's no rule right I mean they are the same but this is much
mean they are the same but this is much more elegant so the log of this is so
more elegant so the log of this is so I'm going to take logs here summation in
I'm going to take logs here summation in N and then I have X V so summation on
N and then I have X V so summation on all configurations of little V I have
all configurations of little V I have people and exponents of the Delta
people and exponents of the Delta function will come in there and again
function will come in there and again what is this this is my count of XV in
what is this this is my count of XV in my data step alright this is after now
my data step alright this is after now it's identical with before nothing else
it's identical with before nothing else so share is the difference and I think
so share is the difference and I think this is what we work for the finish and
this is what we work for the finish and cutely with slightly different notation
cutely with slightly different notation so now what we do is we'll plug in this
so now what we do is we'll plug in this optimization from my undirected graph so
optimization from my undirected graph so this is number one over Z over the
this is number one over Z over the clicks on my graph of the potential side
clicks on my graph of the potential side C and immediately you appreciate the
C and immediately you appreciate the problem yes you get the summation over
problem yes you get the summation over the logs of the potentials but also you
the logs of the potentials but also you get the log of Z and that's the main
get the log of Z and that's the main should make in all of the rest of
should make in all of the rest of graphical waters ok now you get to
graphical waters ok now you get to mission of mmm effectively and you
mission of mmm effectively and you remember what is this quantity equal to
remember what is this quantity equal to this book summation what is it if
this book summation what is it if you take the accounts of all the
you take the accounts of all the variables the limitations of all the
variables the limitations of all the nodes and you sum for all possible x
nodes and you sum for all possible x rays what do you get
rays what do you get and all right so this is what you get
and all right so this is what you get okay you get summation n XV summation
okay you get summation n XV summation over maybe a this is the set of all that
over maybe a this is the set of all that makes or maybe I should put here
makes or maybe I should put here estimation over say
estimation over say slide 16 so we hit the correct part and
slide 16 so we hit the correct part and so this is and then you know what I disc
so this is and then you know what I disc I am using magic and I write equation on
I am using magic and I write equation on the top in the question too and I want
the top in the question too and I want you to tell me how a question to came
you to tell me how a question to came there are you saying dear so partial
there are you saying dear so partial cows but you have to tell me half of
cows but you have to tell me half of that you went to that what have I done
obviously I haven't taught this summation over the click starts there
summation over the click starts there what if I dunno next week but summation
what if I dunno next week but summation Alex me
what have I download the servation XP I
mean I secured MXC so they spend on summation X be a multipass estimation
summation X be a multipass estimation illiteracy and another summation of X B
illiteracy and another summation of X B minus C and when I sum everything but
minus C and when I sum everything but okay this total content become the
okay this total content become the partial counts of XE
so basically why you might know this because I only want this trick to
because I only want this trick to isometric see alright so you can sit
isometric see alright so you can sit here if you have estimation over the
here if you have estimation over the click okay information over the
click okay information over the realizations of the volume of this click
realizations of the volume of this click here is the partial count of XE lava
here is the partial count of XE lava precisely mr. function of HC so
precisely mr. function of HC so immediately you can appreciate that the
immediately you can appreciate that the least some decomposition they are
least some decomposition they are similar to what we have for the record
similar to what we have for the record last but Z involves all the parameters
last but Z involves all the parameters in the model so we're rolling so that's
in the model so we're rolling so that's the main complication basically and it
the main complication basically and it is the problem very fundamental not just
is the problem very fundamental not just for machine learning but very
for machine learning but very fundamental in statistical mechanics and
fundamental in statistical mechanics and other areas okay all right so this list
other areas okay all right so this list what do we do all right
so we need to start doing some ads about to see what is going to come out of this
to see what is going to come out of this right and I am going to try to optimize
right and I am going to try to optimize with respect to its potentials I see
with respect to its potentials I see okay for its to exchange so here the
okay for its to exchange so here the idea is working for a guarantee
right and the configuration of Twix is
given okay so that we can maximize there is the potential choice Qi okay so we
is the potential choice Qi okay so we take belabor this with respect to C and
take belabor this with respect to C and immediately you can you know we this is
immediately you can you know we this is similar with the record graphs this
similar with the record graphs this decomposes so we're going to have the
decomposes so we're going to have the passer counts of exceed one / - I see
passer counts of exceed one / - I see remember when you look at this pair
remember when you look at this pair right the precisely concerning what
right the precisely concerning what they're writing comes on in Walter okay
they're writing comes on in Walter okay [Applause]
[Applause] so this X take here is speaks to take
so this X take here is speaks to take and support fixed realization of the
and support fixed realization of the matter will succeed we only have my
matter will succeed we only have my third choice G of X G and we take
third choice G of X G and we take derivatives with respect to that so M
derivatives with respect to that so M over 1 over C minus 10 times the
over 1 over C minus 10 times the derivative of the log and now we start
derivative of the log and now we start getting today's because log of Z the
getting today's because log of Z the derailleur would be 1 over is d times
derailleur would be 1 over is d times the derivative with respect to price G
the derivative with respect to price G of X 3 and Z is written
of X 3 and Z is written remember the Z is the normalization so
remember the Z is the normalization so it's written like that the potentials
it's written like that the potentials and then I stand all the variables and
and then I stand all the variables and because I don't want to confuse
because I don't want to confuse since I work with a given X P in Cyprus
since I work with a given X P in Cyprus the definition they put and externally
the definition they put and externally right because I some every for the
right because I some every for the access get out okay alright so let's
access get out okay alright so let's this is the equation that we started
this is the equation that we started with so Emirates I see now I have done a
with so Emirates I see now I have done a little bit today right so can be
little bit today right so can be appreciate what Rick has been done on
appreciate what Rick has been done on the second line I will need to move that
the second line I will need to move that summation which are DX outside just to
summation which are DX outside just to simplify my antibodies with so what's
simplify my antibodies with so what's the trick here to move this summation of
the trick here to move this summation of curly out I need to be sure that on this
curly out I need to be sure that on this term wait a second what happened yes
term wait a second what happened yes alright so I need to be sure you can
alright so I need to be sure you can vary care of its derivatives with
vary care of its derivatives with respect to precisely for a given X C so
respect to precisely for a given X C so I need to put a mental function they
I need to put a mental function they have to be sure that I don't agree in
have to be sure that I don't agree in fix remember in psyche Here I am
scarily different information outside I've never shared about the function
I've never shared about the function here to be sure that share a morning
here to be sure that share a morning differentiate with respect to price T of
differentiate with respect to price T of X G okay
X G okay right so this comes third minus N 1 over
right so this comes third minus N 1 over Z there's the function and now in stage
Z there's the function and now in stage here I have the para or for the ties on
here I have the para or for the ties on every click alright and you notice here
every click alright and you notice here this now became xfinity of C okay and
this now became xfinity of C okay and these are security
these are security so you remember if I have the folder
so you remember if I have the folder condition I think they know about this
condition I think they know about this with respect to on terror where I'm
with respect to on terror where I'm going to get these proposed that for
going to get these proposed that for focus potentials except potential Street
right that's an assumption of you depreciate one disappears and you get
depreciate one disappears and you get the product of everything but see in
the product of everything but see in obviously now what I'm gonna this I'm
obviously now what I'm gonna this I'm gonna multiply resistor and divide by
gonna multiply resistor and divide by got error
got error so what way inside this chair I am gonna
so what way inside this chair I am gonna get again my food distribution for X
get again my food distribution for X scale this is the rainbabies here I
scale this is the rainbabies here I would multiplied with twice tree of
would multiplied with twice tree of carry XP and divide by that so they
carry XP and divide by that so they terms of the multiplied together with
terms of the multiplied together with this will give me back all right so and
this will give me back all right so and now since I have done my accessible this
now since I have done my accessible this little trick I can push the summation
little trick I can push the summation inside plug in X trick here alright and
inside plug in X trick here alright and then what I get this I get from here and
then what I get this I get from here and we'll get the effects tell me right
we'll get the effects tell me right there is a function inside and I want
there is a function inside and I want you to tell me this summation what will
you to tell me this summation what will it give me so here this is all the
it give me so here this is all the variables in the graph right and you say
variables in the graph right and you say it's time for possible configurations
it's time for possible configurations but this show you from the very mission
but this show you from the very mission makes a systematic see because X is
makes a systematic see because X is fixed so what did we get out of it
fixed so what did we get out of it we'll give it here off me okay chin what
we'll give it here off me okay chin what is pfx cheating with words
what does people could see with what's what is the name I mean here this
what is the name I mean here this has big tables right position in service
has big tables right position in service in the ground
in the ground now I integrate all the Bible acceptance
now I integrate all the Bible acceptance on the clicks chain that I fixed them of
on the clicks chain that I fixed them of the injection XT so that this P of X C
the injection XT so that this P of X C is the marginal corresponding to the
is the marginal corresponding to the logistic state of the lights and click
logistic state of the lights and click see that's very nice
see that's very nice all right so this gives me the final
all right so this gives me the final result that looks as follows the
result that looks as follows the derivative of the log likelihood of all
derivative of the log likelihood of all my observations is the partial count in
my observations is the partial count in my data set of XT divided by this now
my data set of XT divided by this now optimized right need figure out what
optimized right need figure out what what would lead us the potential and
what would lead us the potential and click see completed of XT right after
click see completed of XT right after night XT is fixed minus n times 1 over
night XT is fixed minus n times 1 over PI C of X T and this is the marginal
PI C of X T and this is the marginal over the click complete aquatics tree
over the click complete aquatics tree some of this comes from childhood comes
some of this comes from childhood comes out and what I get is the this is this
out and what I get is the this is this is nested it is valued at still the MLE
is nested it is valued at still the MLE estimate so the an early estimate toward
estimate so the an early estimate toward the marginal over click shape computer
the marginal over click shape computer visualization extry is NH 3 divided by n
visualization extry is NH 3 divided by n an amazing without and what is M of XJ
an amazing without and what is M of XJ divided by n what what is on the right
divided by n what what is on the right hand side what what name will give you
hand side what what name will give you this this is the partial parent
this this is the partial parent effective T so M effects C divided by n
effective T so M effects C divided by n swap what they will you give it is you
swap what they will you give it is you can't how many times in realizations you
can't how many times in realizations you have seen the variable sex say capital
have seen the variable sex say capital extreme to take these values of
extreme to take these values of next e-service best best M divided by n
next e-service best best M divided by n which to name we should give to it you
which to name we should give to it you know datasets you have seen this
know datasets you have seen this combinations of expiry times so what
combinations of expiry times so what does anyone where end
we're discrete distributions how do you co-op
spell it I can see you're fighting with it so what's the war
frequency okay you're close right you know another word similar to frequency
and in the alphabet is very close 1000 left and other starts between empirical
left and other starts between empirical distribution right so basically the
distribution right so basically the optimal marginal is equal to the
optimal marginal is equal to the empirical distribution so basically what
empirical distribution so basically what we have done is the modal marginal
we have done is the modal marginal agrees with in political much the still
agrees with in political much the still amazing result if you think right we
amazing result if you think right we have done no sanctions anything not even
have done no sanctions anything not even we haven't even said that the clicks are
we haven't even said that the clicks are much more but the maximal active a
much more but the maximal active a destination for this functional sigh
implicitly implies that the the marginal for its place to the empirical model is
for its place to the empirical model is right objective is to find the potential
right objective is to find the potential side another information is given
side another information is given because
so they are devious it doesn't matter this algorithm this this the regression
this algorithm this this the regression tells you I don't know how they're going
tells you I don't know how they're going to compute this potentials but whatever
to compute this potentials but whatever it is know if you want to pull this
it is know if you want to pull this anomaly estimate this short of the model
anomaly estimate this short of the model marginal can start with the empirical
marginal can start with the empirical box it doesn't tell you where those
box it doesn't tell you where those choice would be there is no information
choice would be there is no information of this equation okay and why there's no
of this equation okay and why there's no information because unfortunately when
information because unfortunately when we took the million the steep side terms
we took the million the steep side terms cancel out don't worry this cycle
cancel out don't worry this cycle don't you think is contained inside the
don't you think is contained inside the marginal of pfx shape it's abusive area
marginal of pfx shape it's abusive area right
right marginal connection also click see and
marginal connection also click see and what is really the pencil existed the
what is really the pencil existed the potential is not a distribution all
potential is not a distribution all right so this is what you get so we will
right so this is what you get so we will obviously need to figure out a way to
obviously need to figure out a way to extract the potentials with some
extract the potentials with some algorithm in a way that satisfies this
algorithm in a way that satisfies this condition so we can call those estimates
condition so we can call those estimates and potentials particles for a very
and potentials particles for a very particular set of undirected graphs and
particular set of undirected graphs and then we will expect this to be trillion
then we will expect this to be trillion directed graphs I'm using a simple
directed graphs I'm using a simple example which were three nodes I am
example which were three nodes I am writing The Comedians videos one
writing The Comedians videos one potential of electronic spirit another
potential of electronic spirit another potential over X 2 X 3 so this two
potential over X 2 X 3 so this two potentials basically stare down x2 so
potentials basically stare down x2 so obviously there is an empirical
obviously there is an empirical counterfactual and X you remember the
counterfactual and X you remember the speaker needs a miracle gown so there is
speaker needs a miracle gown so there is an empirical count X 2 and X 3 and you
an empirical count X 2 and X 3 and you know what I am going to give you what
know what I am going to give you what the you know what the summation will
the you know what the summation will look like for the model for the
look like for the model for the underneath solution okay what's the
underneath solution okay what's the initial issue and you can tell me if I'm
initial issue and you can tell me if I'm right or wrong okay
right or wrong okay I mean nothing all right so I am going
I mean nothing all right so I am going to tell you that the MLE estimate okay
to tell you that the MLE estimate okay is given by this empirical marginal x 1
is given by this empirical marginal x 1 x 2 x this is physical marginal but
x 2 x this is physical marginal but divided by the physical model of extreme
divided by the physical model of extreme and can you do some checking and tell me
and can you do some checking and tell me that this is satisfies the condition
that this is satisfies the condition that we had before so really we can call
that we had before so really we can call it an Emily estimate
it an Emily estimate I say this is the solution and I want
I say this is the solution and I want you to tell me that that solution is
you to tell me that that solution is actually satisfying this so can you tell
actually satisfying this so can you tell me about the gate so remember the
me about the gate so remember the imminent question is not the mountain
imminent question is not the mountain Nancy that has to be equal to the
Nancy that has to be equal to the empirical module this is my mother
empirical module this is my mother i postulate this is the model take the
i postulate this is the model take the margin I would say of x1 and x2 all
margin I would say of x1 and x2 all right so take from this the margin of
right so take from this the margin of affection are x2 what do we need to do
affection are x2 what do we need to do to get a nonzero reflection on
to get a nonzero reflection on experience from this approximation here
experience from this approximation here but i postulate that maybe in my answer
but i postulate that maybe in my answer to get the mountain of x1 x2 what do I
to get the mountain of x1 x2 what do I need to do how do you not generalize
sonic 3 so when you sang on x3 what will you get here that will cancel out so you
you get here that will cancel out so you get that the modern marginal of x1 x2 is
get that the modern marginal of x1 x2 is the empirical module Flextronics to do
the empirical module Flextronics to do the same thing and marginalize the chain
the same thing and marginalize the chain on the on x1 if you mention illogical x1
on the on x1 if you mention illogical x1 this will give you the empirical
this will give you the empirical marginal of X 2 will cancel out the list
marginal of X 2 will cancel out the list and then you get the empirical version
and then you get the empirical version of X 2 and X 3 so this satisfies
of X 2 and X 3 so this satisfies actually all the properties there so it
actually all the properties there so it is the correct solution so how did I get
is the correct solution so how did I get this relation here is the trick what a
this relation here is the trick what a business I think the text of ahead of my
business I think the text of ahead of my problem like X 1 X 2 X 2 X 3
problem like X 1 X 2 X 2 X 3 I took the empirical couch over this
I took the empirical couch over this place so these are my empirical
place so these are my empirical knowledge not and because the splits
knowledge not and because the splits have another lost over this now the X 2
have another lost over this now the X 2 I divided by the marginal of now that
okay so the next wave you can actually do this type of things are called the
do this type of things are called the composable drops alright and so she's
composable drops alright and so she's right the composable glass right okay
right the composable glass right okay and here's one glass that is not
and here's one glass that is not decomposable for you won't be able to
decomposable for you won't be able to actually do this trick so this idea of
actually do this trick so this idea of starting with the pinnacle marginals and
starting with the pinnacle marginals and trying to guess where the solution will
trying to guess where the solution will not actually apply to this problem okay
not actually apply to this problem okay and and the reason is not because this
and and the reason is not because this has a look all right this is nothing to
has a look all right this is nothing to do out at the end of the day you have a
do out at the end of the day you have a look here but here's liver the fact that
look here but here's liver the fact that this what you see here is not a
this what you see here is not a decomposable drop so what's the
decomposable drop so what's the definition of a decomposable graph the
definition of a decomposable graph the glasses are become possible if we can
glasses are become possible if we can divide it into this joint into various
divide it into this joint into various joint cells adn s where s the parade a
joint cells adn s where s the parade a and B and s is complete
and B and s is complete chasuble knowledge genus are collective
chasuble knowledge genus are collective okay so if you look on this graph I can
okay so if you look on this graph I can divide you from this knowledge of this
divide you from this knowledge of this node and that node and obviously in this
node and that node and obviously in this S note here x2 separate sexual in
S note here x2 separate sexual in extreme right and I can do the same
extreme right and I can do the same thing here I can divide this to be the
thing here I can divide this to be the set a this node x4 to be the certainty
set a this node x4 to be the certainty and x2 and x3 that are connected they
and x2 and x3 that are connected they separate x2 and x4
separate x2 and x4 but if you move to this graph you can
but if you move to this graph you can try if you try to define how to define a
try if you try to define how to define a bns we are not going to succeed unless
bns we are not going to succeed unless you actually add extra edges from this
you actually add extra edges from this graph all right unless you had extra
graph all right unless you had extra edges to this graph
edges to this graph and let me tell you and you know I know
and let me tell you and you know I know what I'm going to be able to discuss
what I'm going to be able to discuss this in this course
this in this course remember when we do will the very early
remember when we do will the very early part of the course we were doing a graph
part of the course we were doing a graph elimination so nothing that you do graph
elimination so nothing that you do graph elimination here right and it's not
elimination here right and it's not eliminating any note it doesn't matter
eliminating any note it doesn't matter they're all symmetric so if you luminate
they're all symmetric so if you luminate explore what do you need to go to the
explore what do you need to go to the next step if you need to analyze this
next step if you need to analyze this idea the composability for this class it
idea the composability for this class it is directly linked with the graph
is directly linked with the graph elimination algorithm all right and to
elimination algorithm all right and to hell and actually at the end of the day
hell and actually at the end of the day they're directly linked with the
they're directly linked with the junction 3 output ok so if the graph is
junction 3 output ok so if the graph is the compulsive vote the solution is
the compulsive vote the solution is trivial all right and there is more
trivial all right and there is more discussion in the launch
discussion in the launch ok ok so it says if the graph is not
ok ok so it says if the graph is not become possible basically there's
become possible basically there's nothing you can do with the present
nothing you can do with the present curve of the immediate so we need to do
curve of the immediate so we need to do something better so since the time is
something better so since the time is clicking so let's see what we will do if
clicking so let's see what we will do if the algorithm if graph is a genetic
the algorithm if graph is a genetic graph and we cannot use this the
graph and we cannot use this the composition become possibility basically
composition become possibility basically of the graph so we're going to develop
of the graph so we're going to develop evaluate let's call it therapy
evaluate let's call it therapy proportional thinking part of this
proportional thinking part of this nozzle continuation be a lecture on
nozzle continuation be a lecture on Tuesday but we're going to come back so
Tuesday but we're going to come back so we can finish the course so let's see
we can finish the course so let's see what is our waitress remember when we
what is our waitress remember when we took the gradient of the log likelihood
took the gradient of the log likelihood we basically regret the use this pair -
we basically regret the use this pair - despair you remember we said that
despair you remember we said that child-sized cancel out so you know now
child-sized cancel out so you know now we're going guys
we're going guys ok this
ok this raishin site with more the likelihood
raishin site with more the likelihood implicitly right so then I guess I am
implicitly right so then I guess I am NOT going to get rid of precisely but
NOT going to get rid of precisely but I'm gonna plate and tell at the fixed
I'm gonna plate and tell at the fixed point algorithm using this equation as
point algorithm using this equation as follows
follows I am what I'm going to based I am going
I am what I'm going to based I am going to use so this is my empirical marginal
to use so this is my empirical marginal or a is there I am going to divide by my
or a is there I am going to divide by my previous guests as the modern marginal
previous guests as the modern marginal which is this but interracial tea I am
which is this but interracial tea I am going to multiply with my estimate for
going to multiply with my estimate for the potential of iteration of tea and
the potential of iteration of tea and then we all the term on the other side
then we all the term on the other side even when you update the time T plus 1
you should happen here right I took this to the right hand side they push
to the right hand side they push everything to the left all right
everything to the left all right so the this thing on the right hand side
so the this thing on the right hand side would be mighty plus small update based
would be mighty plus small update based on the estimate of the previous nine
on the estimate of the previous nine times the ratio of this empirical margin
times the ratio of this empirical margin divided by the previous estimated margin
divided by the previous estimated margin of clickstream now you know conventional
of clickstream now you know conventional have done this in numerical analysis you
have done this in numerical analysis you know it's not like you play trivia
know it's not like you play trivia question we divide by some unknown then
question we divide by some unknown then you do a fixed point iteration somehow
you do a fixed point iteration somehow this thing converts the assumption is no
this thing converts the assumption is no guarantee that this will actually makes
guarantee that this will actually makes any sense well in the notes and I don't
any sense well in the notes and I don't know how much time we have there is a
know how much time we have there is a propulsion unit only that this is
propulsion unit only that this is working the naturally maximizes them
working the naturally maximizes them they love likelihood so it's actually
they love likelihood so it's actually the more than the standard wave as well
the more than the standard wave as well okay and so let's see how this so this
okay and so let's see how this so this is how this thing works
is how this thing works all right I am NOT gonna go through the
all right I am NOT gonna go through the points because the drop is wanted before
points because the drop is wanted before but let me tell you two things that you
but let me tell you two things that you know they know she's actually
know they know she's actually there's just algebra there are two
there's just algebra there are two things that happen when you iterate with
things that happen when you iterate with this algorithm number one demands you
this algorithm number one demands you know at every iteration is equal to the
know at every iteration is equal to the empirical marginal so if it means as you
empirical marginal so if it means as you implement you subscribe in the liquor
implement you subscribe in the liquor trade show is like you keep going and
trade show is like you keep going and clapping the prevent you will suffice to
clapping the prevent you will suffice to say that the model module is equal to
say that the model module is equal to the empirical much stuff we position you
the empirical much stuff we position you satisfy them and the normalization
satisfy them and the normalization factor does not change okay and I want
factor does not change okay and I want to give you so basically this is the MLE
to give you so basically this is the MLE property right of all iterations the
property right of all iterations the more than marginal is equal to the
more than marginal is equal to the empirical milestone thus it doesn't
empirical milestone thus it doesn't change but I wanted to give you a
change but I wanted to give you a position of this time with it
position of this time with it this is what we derive you can actually
this is what we derive you can actually show this very important you can throw
show this very important you can throw from this equation you can show the
from this equation you can show the algorithm takes the form that you see on
algorithm takes the form that you see on just a question on the lingual okay and
just a question on the lingual okay and I'm going to rewrite this equation in a
I'm going to rewrite this equation in a form of the total fraud you can which
form of the total fraud you can which orientation you can come up with it
orientation you can come up with it without any mathematics okay so I mean
without any mathematics okay so I mean give you proof of this you can show the
give you proof of this you can show the proof is actually two lines but this
proof is actually two lines but this algorithm you can show that the
algorithm you can show that the probability of X being right on the
probability of X being right on the whole at iteration T plus one is your
whole at iteration T plus one is your estimated duration T times the empirical
estimated duration T times the empirical marginal
marginal clip state divided by the northern
clip state divided by the northern margin out at Creek stream I mean you
margin out at Creek stream I mean you can you know when you're working this
can you know when you're working this right you will operate on
right you will operate on Trixie so you can appreciate why I can
Trixie so you can appreciate why I can stop the disguise here with a whole
stop the disguise here with a whole probability distribution because
probability distribution because socialism doesn't change so it's not
socialism doesn't change so it's not like you go from P plus 1 to P and this
like you go from P plus 1 to P and this is going to ring you because they always
is going to ring you because they always can keep the second stop okay so let me
can keep the second stop okay so let me I'm going to take this equation and I'm
I'm going to take this equation and I'm gonna rewrite it
gonna rewrite it okay so whatever it is I am keeping this
okay so whatever it is I am keeping this in critical marginal there and I am
in critical marginal there and I am taking this divided by God and I'm going
taking this divided by God and I'm going to write this at iteration P and I'm
to write this at iteration P and I'm going to write it as the conditional of
going to write it as the conditional of X V minus T given XT you never played
X V minus T given XT you never played that risk / that is the conditional of
that risk / that is the conditional of XT minus T given extreme I mean if you
XT minus T given extreme I mean if you are going to expire right this would be
are going to expire right this would be the joint of this and that which is not
the joint of this and that which is not divided by the modal marginal extreme
divided by the modal marginal extreme nothing now why am i doing like this
nothing now why am i doing like this this is how the graph looks like
this is how the graph looks like all right and very intuition here what
all right and very intuition here what do you do you're actually changing the
do you do you're actually changing the potential conflict see you know of the
potential conflict see you know of the notes on click G so equation tells us
notes on click G so equation tells us you know math test to make the joint
you know math test to make the joint probability distribution of step T plus
probability distribution of step T plus 1 use the previous conditional where the
1 use the previous conditional where the body missions still are not updated and
body missions still are not updated and anything in first line of data marginal
anything in first line of data marginal on extreme
all right so you keep the previous again exit here
exit here this is the conditional from the
this is the conditional from the previous model times the new marginal
previous model times the new marginal which is basically it is so yeah
which is basically it is so yeah basically the marginal on XJ with
basically the marginal on XJ with empirical master very clearly allowed
empirical master very clearly allowed relief if you think about it and this
relief if you think about it and this algorithm is applicable sort of to any
algorithm is applicable sort of to any type of undirected graph it doesn't have
type of undirected graph it doesn't have to be you know become possible you know
to be you know become possible you know haven't really said anything about that
haven't really said anything about that the police have to be much small so it's
the police have to be much small so it's and again you can see miss nice the
and again you can see miss nice the details there is a profit rate that this
details there is a profit rate that this increases as you iterate a much more
increases as you iterate a much more likelihood and in even give you life
likelihood and in even give you life solution of the three iterations by the
solution of the three iterations by the way if the graph is like impossible I
way if the graph is like impossible I think you do this in one iteration
think you do this in one iteration converges to right answer yep
when people study before but the whole thing is of directly linked actually
thing is of directly linked actually yeah exactly
yeah exactly okay as an algorithm is basically the
okay as an algorithm is basically the most general a lot of good is right but
most general a lot of good is right but so the two things are directly linked
so the two things are directly linked here okay so the exact elimination
here okay so the exact elimination algorithm a junction tree algorithm and
algorithm a junction tree algorithm and what you see here have the same origin
is algorithm and I'm going to give you something that somehow when I was
something that somehow when I was looking at your Mike Jordans knows that
looking at your Mike Jordans knows that I gave you some time ago she has a
I gave you some time ago she has a derivation of this IPF algorithm that is
derivation of this IPF algorithm that is very interesting using short of one
very interesting using short of one identity we have never seen and most
identity we have never seen and most probably very few people use okay and
probably very few people use okay and and something we have discussed at least
and something we have discussed at least we discussed with us we took the course
we discussed with us we took the course in the fall
in the fall shall we give you that you can derive
shall we give you that you can derive all of these things using a minimization
all of these things using a minimization of an appropriate KL divergence distance
of an appropriate KL divergence distance and that you to minimize is basically
and that you to minimize is basically the distance between P of x given theta
the distance between P of x given theta and the empirical distribution P of X
and the empirical distribution P of X right and what you need to do is you can
right and what you need to do is you can show by the way
show by the way so let me say that things that you
so let me say that things that you should know by now if you want to
should know by now if you want to maximize the likelihood this is
maximize the likelihood this is equivalent to minimizing the distance of
equivalent to minimizing the distance of P of X from the empirical distribution
P of X from the empirical distribution picture via text that's the standard
picture via text that's the standard theory all right if you want to maximize
theory all right if you want to maximize the likelihood the derivation sphere is
the likelihood the derivation sphere is the same as minimize
the same as minimize distance from the empirical distribution
distance from the empirical distribution factor that's part one factor the cool
factor that's part one factor the cool but liberal distance D between some
but liberal distance D between some distribution P from another distribution
distribution P from another distribution Q when I split the variables in two sets
Q when I split the variables in two sets a and B can be written down in a in a
a and B can be written down in a in a sort of very nice decomposition that is
sort of very nice decomposition that is given by the second line here so if you
given by the second line here so if you need the distance between P of X a X B
need the distance between P of X a X B and Q of X or X B you can write this as
and Q of X or X B you can write this as the difference between the marginals and
the difference between the marginals and the distance between the conditionals
the distance between the conditionals after it's over let's say all right okay
after it's over let's say all right okay so what I'm gonna do is so this is not
so what I'm gonna do is so this is not something you see often but it comes
something you see often but it comes very handy in our problem because if you
very handy in our problem because if you use this idea but much maizing the
use this idea but much maizing the likelihood is the same as me imagine
likelihood is the same as me imagine this distance and it's life is this
this distance and it's life is this confusing this equation you're shall get
confusing this equation you're shall get the same answer as what you know
the same answer as what you know directly doing the algebra that I show
directly doing the algebra that I show you before and here is the how the scale
you before and here is the how the scale of distance manifests itself in our
of distance manifests itself in our problem so what are those two be noise
problem so what are those two be noise the distance between the model and the
the distance between the model and the empirical distribution is the same as
empirical distribution is the same as you know we have to write as distance as
you know we have to write as distance as the distance between the marginals and
the distance between the marginals and I'm using the potential to HC between
I'm using the potential to HC between the model and the empirical and then I
the model and the empirical and then I have this average that involves the
have this average that involves the conditionals as given exchange shall be
conditionals as given exchange shall be only further this equation that I want
only further this equation that I want to minimize with respect to X T is this
to minimize with respect to X T is this time this is not secure that ship has
time this is not secure that ship has been tomorrow
so how do you minimize the distance between this marginal and this and
between this marginal and this and critical Martina obviously this should
critical Martina obviously this should be equal to that and that's what we
be equal to that and that's what we proved before so there is a proofing on
proved before so there is a proofing on life right and again you never know
life right and again you never know where and how things will be useful but
where and how things will be useful but this not is the composition of the KL
this not is the composition of the KL it's actually very handy because it
it's actually very handy because it gives you an answer no need to the
gives you an answer no need to the gradient and you know you can use ideas
gradient and you know you can use ideas from a gradient descent so we can please
from a gradient descent so we can please so rather than doing this fixed point
so rather than doing this fixed point iteration algorithm you can introduce
iteration algorithm you can introduce some learning rate and a real life is a
some learning rate and a real life is a gradient equation is the gradient so you
gradient equation is the gradient so you can put some learning rate law and you
can put some learning rate law and you can keep doing update in a fantastic
can keep doing update in a fantastic regular sense if you apply the solver if
regular sense if you apply the solver if the discuss today the only thing is you
the discuss today the only thing is you need to just be careful because the
need to just be careful because the romanization cost from Z has to be
romanization cost from Z has to be recalculated at each iteration doesn't
recalculated at each iteration doesn't remain constant right and again if you
remain constant right and again if you have latent variables basically what you
have latent variables basically what you need to do is that for the rest of the
need to do is that for the rest of the wacky graphs you can apply exactly the
wacky graphs you can apply exactly the same that needs to discuss today but you
same that needs to discuss today but you apply them artistic iteration of the e/m
apply them artistic iteration of the e/m outwards so really you can do this for
outwards so really you can do this for any problem with hidden variables very
any problem with hidden variables very simple way to estimate the parameters
simple way to estimate the parameters assuming that you have complete data
assuming that you have complete data description all right if civics says no
description all right if civics says no we have noticed they know no lecture on
we have noticed they know no lecture on Friday okay and I'm going to maybe if we
Friday okay and I'm going to maybe if we have a lecture next Friday but there's
have a lecture next Friday but there's no lecture on Tuesday and Thursday okay
no lecture on Tuesday and Thursday okay all right
all right so and and and so we'll see you next
so and and and so we'll see you next week