right
so we're supposed to start a new topic that is not only applicable to
that is not only applicable to probabilistic graphical models but to
probabilistic graphical models but to any sort of Bayesian inference and that
any sort of Bayesian inference and that is with school variational method to
is with school variational method to approximate posterior distributions okay
approximate posterior distributions okay and we will do some elementary examples
and we will do some elementary examples today maybe some applied to
today maybe some applied to probabilistic graphical models and there
probabilistic graphical models and there is a lots of this topic store maybe we
is a lots of this topic store maybe we will spend another two lectures or three
will spend another two lectures or three lectures depending how exhausted you
lectures depending how exhausted you seem to be you know in the days ahead
seem to be you know in the days ahead so try not to sleep okay all right I
so try not to sleep okay all right I believe Subic sent you the notes but I
believe Subic sent you the notes but I will post them if you find any mistakes
will post them if you find any mistakes on this nas please email me so we're
on this nas please email me so we're back to the standard problem where we
back to the standard problem where we have some observed data that I denote
have some observed data that I denote here with text Z are the latent
here with text Z are the latent variables and we want to compute the
variables and we want to compute the posterior of the latent variables given
posterior of the latent variables given the data the light came on and it seems
the data the light came on and it seems the camera I am assuming should be
the camera I am assuming should be working okay it was not exactly when
working okay it was not exactly when it's supposed to be it was dead natural
it's supposed to be it was dead natural not with a miracle yes thank you guys
so so the probability of G of X Bayes rule basically is given like that so the
rule basically is given like that so the most of the machine learning subject
most of the machine learning subject area is to compute this posterior okay
area is to compute this posterior okay now in addition to G you may have all
now in addition to G you may have all the parameters the way we have seen up
the parameters the way we have seen up to now but and we will do some examples
to now but and we will do some examples but let's cross the credit MC so we are
but let's cross the credit MC so we are assuming that this post is not very easy
assuming that this post is not very easy to compute or you know it's not maybe
to compute or you know it's not maybe even given in any other litical form
even given in any other litical form maybe it's a computer code and somehow
maybe it's a computer code and somehow we're gonna try today to discuss
we're gonna try today to discuss methodology square we can have some
methodology square we can have some approximation of the posterior that they
approximation of the posterior that they have explicitly not sir so you can think
have explicitly not sir so you can think you know taking a general of course
you know taking a general of course tyranny approximating it as a Gaussian I
tyranny approximating it as a Gaussian I mean that can be in a simple example
mean that can be in a simple example maybe a Gaussian won't be enough
maybe a Gaussian won't be enough we don't be enough because maybe these
we don't be enough because maybe these very high dimensional so that you can
very high dimensional so that you can think this in the examples we did with
think this in the examples we did with graphs Z can involve many variables
graphs Z can involve many variables approximating the Joint Distribution of
approximating the Joint Distribution of C as a Gaussian wave is not a good idea
C as a Gaussian wave is not a good idea all right
so there are methods of doing this and
so one is basically to approximate the posterior with samples and in some sense
posterior with samples and in some sense we discuss this a little bit in the
we discuss this a little bit in the context of the previous lecture when I
context of the previous lecture when I refer to particle methods basically to
refer to particle methods basically to compute the predictive and the smoking
compute the predictive and the smoking distribution in in state-space models so
distribution in in state-space models so this is using on the counter
this is using on the counter attractively right and the method of
attractively right and the method of well are discuss today is basically a
well are discuss today is basically a deterministic method in many ways and
deterministic method in many ways and small service category of what we call
small service category of what we call various turn on the inference so we're
various turn on the inference so we're gonna try to approximate the posterior
gonna try to approximate the posterior with some form that is sort of
with some form that is sort of computational easy to work with and that
computational easy to work with and that prong is going to involve the
prong is going to involve the factorization so an approximation that
factorization so an approximation that factorizes this in distribution software
factorizes this in distribution software each of the variables to disease so
each of the variables to disease so let's say if Z is three variables we're
let's say if Z is three variables we're going to proximate this as q1 of Z 1 and
going to proximate this as q1 of Z 1 and Q 2 of Z 2 times 2 3 of Z 3 and then try
Q 2 of Z 2 times 2 3 of Z 3 and then try to persuade each of this Q I
to persuade each of this Q I distribution we will say that this
distribution we will say that this actually leads to methodologies already
actually leads to methodologies already known in statistical mechanics for you
known in statistical mechanics for you know centuries basically so in many ways
know centuries basically so in many ways these methods are coming directly from
these methods are coming directly from physics ok and and sort of the
physics ok and and sort of the techniques that they applied for simple
techniques that they applied for simple inference problems to probabilistic
inference problems to probabilistic graphical models to deep learning to
graphical models to deep learning to everything to they're very powerful
everything to they're very powerful methods what their approach metrics
methods what their approach metrics approximate method is you get what you
approximate method is you get what you approximated with right so you're not
approximated with right so you're not happy with it too much
happy with it too much okay so in some sense this is a good
okay so in some sense this is a good active area preserved if you want to
active area preserved if you want to come up with something better following
come up with something better following basically the ideas of a rational
basically the ideas of a rational inference all right so let's introduce
inference all right so let's introduce the some of the basic of the problems so
the some of the basic of the problems so we assume we have collected some data x1
we assume we have collected some data x1 to xn we are assuming that we have
to xn we are assuming that we have latent variables Z 1 to Z n so you know
latent variables Z 1 to Z n so you know this year the number of latent variables
this year the number of latent variables is the same as the number of data so you
is the same as the number of data so you can think of a problem where you know
can think of a problem where you know this is you know if this you are talking
this is you know if this you are talking let's say birth of a Gaussian mixture
let's say birth of a Gaussian mixture for its extra ZZ that tells you what
for its extra ZZ that tells you what from what component of the mixture this
from what component of the mixture this is coming so we have n data points and
is coming so we have n data points and and latent parameters but later on we
and latent parameters but later on we can enrich this with static parameters
can enrich this with static parameters beta but right now this is what we have
beta but right now this is what we have this is how Joint Distribution who have
this is how Joint Distribution who have played with it when we work with the e/m
played with it when we work with the e/m algorithm and we want to approximate the
algorithm and we want to approximate the posterior and also the model evidence ok
posterior and also the model evidence ok so we're going to denote the
so we're going to denote the approximation as qz so this is the exact
approximation as qz so this is the exact posterior and this is the approximation
posterior and this is the approximation of that posterior we're going to to try
of that posterior we're going to to try to compute we don't used usually in the
to compute we don't used usually in the notation Q of Z given X right so this is
notation Q of Z given X right so this is the distribution in Z but remember it's
the distribution in Z but remember it's an approximation of a posterior
an approximation of a posterior distribution ok the very fundamental a
distribution ok the very fundamental a question that I have to use today and
question that I have to use today and you need to remember it because it's
you need to remember it because it's essential every quality machine learning
essential every quality machine learning is the question that we see there that
is the question that we see there that it raised the long of the of the
it raised the long of the of the evidence so this is the likelihood of
evidence so this is the likelihood of the data so the log of the length of the
the data so the log of the length of the data is this lower bound which I will
data is this lower bound which I will define shortly the trolley function of Q
define shortly the trolley function of Q plus the cool but liberal distance
plus the cool but liberal distance between Q and P
between Q and P so P is the exact posterior cure is the
so P is the exact posterior cure is the approximation we try to model you may
approximation we try to model you may say if you know why is this useful well
say if you know why is this useful well you will see shortly why is this useful
you will see shortly why is this useful okay so let me define things the lower
okay so let me define things the lower bound is defined basically as the
bound is defined basically as the expectation with respect to the
expectation with respect to the distribution Q of the log of the joint
distribution Q of the log of the joint likelihood divided by Q of Z so this is
likelihood divided by Q of Z so this is the lower bound you may say why do I
the lower bound you may say why do I call it a lower bound we will see that
call it a lower bound we will see that shortly and the KL distance between Q
shortly and the KL distance between Q and P is defined this way so you may
and P is defined this way so you may want to memorize one of the two
want to memorize one of the two definitions with the sign so that you do
definitions with the sign so that you do this properly right so if you put a
this properly right so if you put a minus sign and this is the distance
minus sign and this is the distance between Q and P Q will come there and
between Q and P Q will come there and there and this would be the the exact
there and this would be the the exact distribution it rise approximate if you
distribution it rise approximate if you want to put the sign in tight and get
want to put the sign in tight and get rid of it basically you're going to have
rid of it basically you're going to have to reverse the order and have QC devices
to reverse the order and have QC devices by PLC effects
by PLC effects okay everybody familiar with the KL
okay everybody familiar with the KL distance of distributions okay it's not
distance of distributions okay it's not a real distance okay
a real distance okay it is a non-symmetric quantity we will
it is a non-symmetric quantity we will see actually today but if you have the
see actually today but if you have the distance between P and Q is not equal to
distance between P and Q is not equal to this so this is very important for this
this so this is very important for this the distance of Q from P not P from Q
the distance of Q from P not P from Q okay
okay this distance is zero when Q and P are
this distance is zero when Q and P are equal it is greater or equal to zero and
equal it is greater or equal to zero and because it's greater or equal to zero
because it's greater or equal to zero what you see here is greater or equal to
what you see here is greater or equal to 2l q
2l q and that's why we call L Q the lower
and that's why we call L Q the lower bound to the log-likelihood you select
bound to the log-likelihood you select because the KO distance is positive
because the KO distance is positive right so the M of Q is a lower bound
right so the M of Q is a lower bound basically to the log likelihood so if
basically to the log likelihood so if you want really an approximation of the
you want really an approximation of the log likelihood because this is
log likelihood because this is computationally the
computationally the to come thing to do what is very easy to
to come thing to do what is very easy to do is computer love you because it
do is computer love you because it involves the joining of log magnitude
involves the joining of log magnitude here okay and we only have seen in the
here okay and we only have seen in the contest of expectation maximization in
contest of expectation maximization in fact there is a reason you would like to
fact there is a reason you would like to work with the affection Z because for
work with the affection Z because for example if this joint distribution is
example if this joint distribution is Gaussian everything falls nicely and the
Gaussian everything falls nicely and the calculations is easy but working
calculations is easy but working directly with this it requires
directly with this it requires integration in Z and that's not
integration in Z and that's not convenient to do let's prove this
convenient to do let's prove this equation the proof is trivial
equation the proof is trivial so the we use the definition of L of Q
so the we use the definition of L of Q so a lot Q we define it to be like that
so a lot Q we define it to be like that so this is what it is so I'm expanding
so this is what it is so I'm expanding our Q Z log of T of Z of X plus Q of Z
our Q Z log of T of Z of X plus Q of Z log of T of X minus Q of Z log of Q of Z
log of T of X minus Q of Z log of Q of Z all right nice okay now longer effects
all right nice okay now longer effects does not depend on Z so I can put
does not depend on Z so I can put outside the integral and I am assuming Q
outside the integral and I am assuming Q the distribution huge normalize so the
the distribution huge normalize so the integral of Q DZ will give me 1 so what
integral of Q DZ will give me 1 so what I'm gonna get is from this term I'm
I'm gonna get is from this term I'm gonna get the log likelihood and then I
gonna get the log likelihood and then I have basically the rest of the terms
have basically the rest of the terms which is Q log of P of Z X okay this
which is Q log of P of Z X okay this term comes from here and then minus Q
term comes from here and then minus Q log of Q is there so this is minus the
log of Q is there so this is minus the cubot liberal distance this is the log
cubot liberal distance this is the log of the evidence so you can see that the
of the evidence so you can see that the love of the evidence is the lower bound
love of the evidence is the lower bound plus the KL distance of QP okay very
plus the KL distance of QP okay very simple derivation is extremely from the
simple derivation is extremely from the mental side prior to you know your head
mental side prior to you know your head spinning and you say to many equations
spinning and you say to many equations you know
well you know this is you will see it actually in publications this things
actually in publications this things used with zero explanation because you
used with zero explanation because you supposed to know it okay so you don't
supposed to know it okay so you don't explain things that you supposed to know
explain things that you supposed to know all right
all right so we explain why this is a lower bound
so we explain why this is a lower bound okay and this is the picture sort of you
okay and this is the picture sort of you want to remember like the only thing we
want to remember like the only thing we have when we have data is this evidence
have when we have data is this evidence so we're always trying to maximize the
so we're always trying to maximize the evidence of the data so whatever unknown
evidence of the data so whatever unknown parameters we care starts as Z or static
parameters we care starts as Z or static parameters theta the only really really
parameters theta the only really really we can in a Bayesian setting we can
we can in a Bayesian setting we can compute the unknowns is by maximizing
compute the unknowns is by maximizing the evidence okay and we just have seen
the evidence okay and we just have seen that the evidence yes two terms the
that the evidence yes two terms the killing of distance between Q and P and
killing of distance between Q and P and the lower bound so you can think the
the lower bound so you can think the problem in two ways one is you say I'm
problem in two ways one is you say I'm going to maximize the lower bound right
going to maximize the lower bound right if you maximize the lower about and to
if you maximize the lower about and to make it equal to that basically you
make it equal to that basically you minimize the KO distance you bring it to
minimize the KO distance you bring it to zero
zero or you can directly work with the K of
or you can directly work with the K of distance so whatever is computationally
distance so whatever is computationally profitable would be the way to go but as
profitable would be the way to go but as we will see only for trivial toy
we will see only for trivial toy problems we work with the KL distance
problems we work with the KL distance the lower bound is what we have to play
the lower bound is what we have to play with
in the literature depending what book you read you know - what community to
you read you know - what community to discuss things with the terminology for
discuss things with the terminology for the lower bound has different fiscal
the lower bound has different fiscal makes I'm going to give you one of them
makes I'm going to give you one of them in the context of 36 so we said the
in the context of 36 so we said the objective is to maximize the lower bound
objective is to maximize the lower bound you can think of this as minimizing -
you can think of this as minimizing - the lower bound so if you calculate -
the lower bound so if you calculate - the lower bound by the initiative plug
the lower bound by the initiative plug in a - there then you get minus Q over Q
in a - there then you get minus Q over Q that's the entropy of the distribution Q
that's the entropy of the distribution Q and then you have minus Q log of P of X
and then you have minus Q log of P of X and Z and the second term here alright
and Z and the second term here alright you can write it as the expectation with
you can write it as the expectation with respect to Q an energy function that I
respect to Q an energy function that I defined here to be minus the log of the
defined here to be minus the log of the drawing love like the joint likelihood
drawing love like the joint likelihood of X and C so this T here is minus Ln of
of X and C so this T here is minus Ln of P of X MC okay so basically what you
P of X MC okay so basically what you have here is you have this average you
have here is you have this average you know energy minus this entropy and this
know energy minus this entropy and this is basically what people in in physics
is basically what people in in physics called the Helmholtz free energy all
called the Helmholtz free energy all right so the problem really of computing
right so the problem really of computing Q is the same as minimizing the kelvins
Q is the same as minimizing the kelvins free energy okay and actually you know
free energy okay and actually you know you can play out with the definition of
you can play out with the definition of the energy and you can build the problem
the energy and you can build the problem to a form of imaging other sort of
to a form of imaging other sort of Pharisees like the Gibbs energy and the
Pharisees like the Gibbs energy and the like okay so you can immediately see the
like okay so you can immediately see the similarities with with the distal
similarities with with the distal mechanics
mechanics all right I have another interpretation
all right I have another interpretation we don't really need it so rather
we don't really need it so rather elementary a distribution a posterior of
elementary a distribution a posterior of Z given X and we want approximate it
Z given X and we want approximate it with Q of G so this you know high
with Q of G so this you know high dimension also have lots of this and
let's not worry about that parameter you know well actually these are not static
know well actually these are not static parameters so the way it is written here
parameters so the way it is written here it says if you approach babies let's say
it says if you approach babies let's say to be a Gaussian and Omega is the mean
to be a Gaussian and Omega is the mean and the variance of a Gaussian then
and the variance of a Gaussian then effectively you can think of the problem
effectively you can think of the problem of computing this parameter Omega the
of computing this parameter Omega the defining this distribution okay that's
defining this distribution okay that's all what I wanted to do but there is an
all what I wanted to do but there is an example basically that demonstrates this
example basically that demonstrates this before we go to the general of the food
before we go to the general of the food ology so let me show it to you
ology so let me show it to you this simple problem it's really not
this simple problem it's really not variational metal but it demonstrates
variational metal but it demonstrates what exactly we're going to be doing
what exactly we're going to be doing there in a general context so pimples we
there in a general context so pimples we have a distribution that is you know not
have a distribution that is you know not very easy to work with so there is an
very easy to work with so there is an exponential there like a Gaussian but
exponential there like a Gaussian but there is a sigmoid function and the
there is a sigmoid function and the distribution of suppose is this one okay
distribution of suppose is this one okay it looks like that and you say I want to
it looks like that and you say I want to fluctuate this with a nauseam okay now
fluctuate this with a nauseam okay now an obvious way to portray this with the
an obvious way to portray this with the Gaussian is using the Laplace expression
Gaussian is using the Laplace expression can use somebody the Miami with the
can use somebody the Miami with the Laplace approximation or maybe we'll
Laplace approximation or maybe we'll have a gives it two months in this class
have a gives it two months in this class but we use it last fall and it is found
but we use it last fall and it is found that the machine learning so and maybe
that the machine learning so and maybe you can guess from the picture what the
you can guess from the picture what the Laplace approximation is so what's the
Laplace approximation is so what's the Laplace approximation
okay but eventually it's a Gaussian with what mean where is the Gaussian Center
it's centered on the zero under the mean of the of the actual distribution on the
of the of the actual distribution on the main okay I mean it looks to be zero
main okay I mean it looks to be zero here and the covariance is defined using
here and the covariance is defined using what the curvature of the actual
what the curvature of the actual distribution that we should here on the
distribution that we should here on the main okay so basically this yes did you
main okay so basically this yes did you do a Taylor series expansion for
do a Taylor series expansion for expected mean and the second order term
expected mean and the second order term and and effectively you get a Gaussian
and and effectively you get a Gaussian center are out the mean with the correct
center are out the mean with the correct temperature that much is you know the
temperature that much is you know the cabbage is defined by the covariance I'm
cabbage is defined by the covariance I'm sorry the temperature of the the koala
sorry the temperature of the the koala is defined by the curvature of the
is defined by the curvature of the distribution you want to approximate now
distribution you want to approximate now if you see is and we will be discussing
if you see is and we will be discussing these ideas today is actually a
these ideas today is actually a variation approximation where in an
variation approximation where in an elementary way because this is a
elementary way because this is a distribution in a single variable Z you
distribution in a single variable Z you can tell the variation or explanation as
can tell the variation or explanation as one that minimizes the distance between
one that minimizes the distance between Q and P for if we take you to be
Q and P for if we take you to be Gaussian so you want the approachable
Gaussian so you want the approachable distribution to be Gaussian you say what
distribution to be Gaussian you say what is the Gaussian e mais de que el
is the Gaussian e mais de que el districts and noticed a big difference
districts and noticed a big difference you get from the Laplace of rocks which
you get from the Laplace of rocks which significant difference okay so not only
significant difference okay so not only basically there is a difference in the
basically there is a difference in the peak of the distribution but also you
peak of the distribution but also you can see the support of the distribution
can see the support of the distribution is very much different from the support
is very much different from the support of the Laplace props Meister but you
of the Laplace props Meister but you know what indulgence okay so Laplace
know what indulgence okay so Laplace approximation and here is the various
approximation and here is the various approaches and this I think the plot on
approaches and this I think the plot on the right shows what is that the
the right shows what is that the curvature
okay so this is I think is just the temperature of the two distributions
temperature of the two distributions basically showing if this is the Laplace
basically showing if this is the Laplace approximation you know this
approximation you know this it matches basically the the curvature
it matches basically the the curvature of the exact distribution okay and this
of the exact distribution okay and this is this is the variation all I'm
is this is the variation all I'm somebody with color skin oh sorry need
somebody with color skin oh sorry need to okay so this is the polyester
to okay so this is the polyester approximation again this is a bigger
approximation again this is a bigger problem right it gives you a sense of
problem right it gives you a sense of what the variational metals will do it
what the variational metals will do it in this case there's no point of forming
in this case there's no point of forming the you know lower bound because we only
the you know lower bound because we only have one variable basically and there's
have one variable basically and there's no need to go to join the minimization
no need to go to join the minimization of the curve of the distance between two
of the curve of the distance between two and three
so I stood there saying this without realizing that it was a few slides down
realizing that it was a few slides down let's take the real problem now and say
let's take the real problem now and say that G is high dimensional so we need to
that G is high dimensional so we need to approximate this so the first thing we
approximate this so the first thing we do in these variational methods we
do in these variational methods we factorize the distribution Q of Z as a
factorize the distribution Q of Z as a product of the distributions of Qi so
product of the distributions of Qi so each of the states so so if you think of
each of the states so so if you think of this you know if you have two variables
this you know if you have two variables Q 1 of Z 1 P 2 of Z 2 okay so if somehow
Q 1 of Z 1 P 2 of Z 2 okay so if somehow your punch made it to them to be imagine
your punch made it to them to be imagine you even have a product of gaussians in
you even have a product of gaussians in each variable right but it's a factorize
each variable right but it's a factorize product okay so this is the essential
product okay so this is the essential part to start with alright so we're
part to start with alright so we're going to use this limitation this
going to use this limitation this approximation on define Q of Z and then
approximation on define Q of Z and then somehow we're going to use the
somehow we're going to use the maximization of the lower bound to try
maximization of the lower bound to try to compute what is the form of this two
to compute what is the form of this two eyes and we're going to assume that
eyes and we're going to assume that there are generational about to start
there are generational about to start with so we will do this as general as
with so we will do this as general as possible and and after that we which
possible and and after that we which exactly with applications on if we need
exactly with applications on if we need any additional approximations so I can
any additional approximations so I can tell you again
tell you again this is nothing new in machine learning
this is nothing new in machine learning the machine learning people basically
the machine learning people basically stole the idea from statistical
stole the idea from statistical mechanics and the derivation we will do
mechanics and the derivation we will do basically leads to the classical mean
basically leads to the classical mean field theory from quantum mechanics okay
field theory from quantum mechanics okay so there's nothing you and actually
so there's nothing you and actually that's why a number of very smart
that's why a number of very smart machine learning people especially in
machine learning people especially in Europe actually they used to be forward
Europe actually they used to be forward physicists who switch to machine
physicists who switch to machine learning so they can make some money
learning so they can make some money okay and they are very successful
okay and they are very successful because their intuition pays off
because their intuition pays off alright if you work just with the
alright if you work just with the Christiane's you're missing reality and
Christiane's you're missing reality and these people know what reality is and
these people know what reality is and they have done some significant advances
they have done some significant advances in this area okay all right so this is
in this area okay all right so this is our ization all right so we plug in this
our ization all right so we plug in this to learn about and remember the lower
to learn about and remember the lower bound it was an expectation with respect
bound it was an expectation with respect with you there is Q and inside here we
with you there is Q and inside here we had the longer the joint likelihood
had the longer the joint likelihood divided by Q which Q was this product of
divided by Q which Q was this product of all of this and because I have a long
all of this and because I have a long the long the product the this product
the long the product the this product here becomes summations of the logs okay
here becomes summations of the logs okay you see
again the actual Miliband had few longer fear affects command C divided by Q of Z
fear affects command C divided by Q of Z cubes is that so you have longer bad so
cubes is that so you have longer bad so you get summation of the logs okay we're
you get summation of the logs okay we're going to try to do is we're going to try
going to try to do is we're going to try to approximate its time where
to approximate its time where fertilization one at a time right so to
fertilization one at a time right so to see if you know if that is possible and
see if you know if that is possible and foremost we have a physical intuition I
foremost we have a physical intuition I have taken a course in statistical
have taken a course in statistical mechanics or in quantum mechanics this
mechanics or in quantum mechanics this problem is going to be sort of solved to
problem is going to be sort of solved to such consistency now what that means is
such consistency now what that means is we're going to compute each of the
we're going to compute each of the factors that say the factor to j then
factors that say the factor to j then keeping the rest of the factors to some
keeping the rest of the factors to some values and then we will then update the
values and then we will then update the next factor keeping the rest constant
next factor keeping the rest constant until effectively as we play we iterate
until effectively as we play we iterate through the factors no further updates
through the factors no further updates are needed this is what's called
are needed this is what's called self-consistency
self-consistency the way we saw basically the Threadgill
the way we saw basically the Threadgill equations okay so i'm going to insulate
equations okay so i'm going to insulate the tactical jet so we're gonna compute
the tactical jet so we're gonna compute we're going to try to maximize this
we're going to try to maximize this lower bound with respect to QJ okay
lower bound with respect to QJ okay that's our objective because you know
that's our objective because you know it's from my direction here so we want
it's from my direction here so we want on this thing to have oniy QJ so let's
on this thing to have oniy QJ so let's look at this term when I have done
look at this term when I have done cherries there is a product of for the
cherries there is a product of for the two eyes so that I did is I put this
two eyes so that I did is I put this product inside the integral will include
product inside the integral will include all the terms modes a and then I do the
all the terms modes a and then I do the integration of juice apple tree
integration of juice apple tree nothing first you see that right I have
nothing first you see that right I have an integration
an integration disease but now I integrate in overseas
disease but now I integrate in overseas but today and then the integrations a
but today and then the integrations a separately so this then you get it like
separately so this then you get it like that right is basically the average of
that right is basically the average of the Journal of likelihood with respect
the Journal of likelihood with respect to the distribution of home of the other
to the distribution of home of the other variables but J okay all right
variables but J okay all right place this thing coming so I have some
place this thing coming so I have some looking on this there on everything
looking on this there on everything except J alright
except J alright everything except J and will you agree
everything except J and will you agree with me but here I'm only gonna have the
with me but here I'm only gonna have the product of the Q eyes at the Thames a
product of the Q eyes at the Thames a because the funds are you would be
because the funds are you would be integrated with 0 will give me loud
integrated with 0 will give me loud because there's no J there ZJ okay and
because there's no J there ZJ okay and then I'm gonna have an expert then when
then I'm gonna have an expert then when I pick up here the log of Q J and I'm
I pick up here the log of Q J and I'm going to keep here the longer the QJ
going to keep here the longer the QJ curve as well all the other terms will
curve as well all the other terms will be degraded to one well as a tory
be degraded to one well as a tory because the church shall have normalized
because the church shall have normalized okay
all right
so I am let me call this whole thing this whole parenthesis because is going
this whole parenthesis because is going to be a function of Z J because all the
to be a function of Z J because all the others this would be integrate now right
others this would be integrate now right some what I call this peak with a care
some what I call this peak with a care of X comma CJ okay and I'm claiming this
of X comma CJ okay and I'm claiming this longer this the wholly integral okay we
longer this the wholly integral okay we will see why it doesn't matter right now
will see why it doesn't matter right now just the I define this to be log of P P
just the I define this to be log of P P curve alright so this is Q J times that
curve alright so this is Q J times that okay and remember I only want to keep
okay and remember I only want to keep the times in Z J because I want to do a
the times in Z J because I want to do a maximization with respect to Q J okay so
maximization with respect to Q J okay so the only thing that I don't see any
the only thing that I don't see any future here do you see linkage a of the
future here do you see linkage a of the second time there is nothing there also
second time there is nothing there also we don't really care
we don't really care we call it constant and then we have the
we call it constant and then we have the entropy basically of DJ which is this
entropy basically of DJ which is this okay
okay the rest is basically functional
the rest is basically functional optimization and that's why these verbs
optimization and that's why these verbs are called variational you're going to
are called variational you're going to have to take derivatives of this with
have to take derivatives of this with respect to Q J alright and set this
respect to Q J alright and set this equal to zero but you know we can
equal to zero but you know we can immediately see also from this is the
immediately see also from this is the lower bound right we can see that
lower bound right we can see that without any calculations actually
without any calculations actually without any derivatives that this thing
without any derivatives that this thing here is minus the cool but liberal
here is minus the cool but liberal distance of Q J from this P curve we see
distance of Q J from this P curve we see that
you remember the courtly distance without the minus signs here right it
without the minus signs here right it would be the minus the integral of kids
would be the minus the integral of kids a this / cute a so you're going to get
a this / cute a so you're going to get there was a madness and this is in the
there was a madness and this is in the denominator another - disappearance and
denominator another - disappearance and with this thing we get here - which is
with this thing we get here - which is this okay so you can see what's the
this okay so you can see what's the optimal solution but maximize what is
optimal solution but maximize what is the Q J that much lies the lower bound L
the Q J that much lies the lower bound L of Q where we are scum again we do the
of Q where we are scum again we do the optimization one time at the time that
optimization one time at the time that the rest of the terms have to be left
the rest of the terms have to be left alone okay so that is the optimal QJ we
alone okay so that is the optimal QJ we want to maximize this with the - time we
want to maximize this with the - time we want to minimize the KL distance what's
want to minimize the KL distance what's the minimum Athenian distance
you have an evidence because I haven't
zero thank you
that's the minuend wins the minimum company for what values of QJ linkages
company for what values of QJ linkages become equal to what
become equal to what take care and so all right all right so
take care and so all right all right so k QJ will become equal to this okay and
k QJ will become equal to this okay and all right and and let me just write down
all right and and let me just write down so we defined us to be this picture to
so we defined us to be this picture to be I'm sorry little picture right so
be I'm sorry little picture right so what I'm writing here the longer picture
what I'm writing here the longer picture is this is my definition right this is
is this is my definition right this is what they have so when you agree with me
what they have so when you agree with me that the longer picture is the
that the longer picture is the expectation with respect to other
expectation with respect to other distributions except say of the joint
distributions except say of the joint ability could you say this right it's an
ability could you say this right it's an expectation with respect to all the kids
expectation with respect to all the kids but J all right this is the expectation
but J all right this is the expectation of you know with respect to all the Q
of you know with respect to all the Q eyes but J okay and you told me that QJ
eyes but J okay and you told me that QJ this optimal going to becomes equal to
this optimal going to becomes equal to PQ all right come on I'm looking for
PQ all right come on I'm looking for that equation okay so what did you tell
that equation okay so what did you tell me that this is optimal when this
me that this is optimal when this becomes equal to that so which means my
becomes equal to that so which means my take the logs the run up to j is equal
take the logs the run up to j is equal to log of p KL and lower peak oil was
to log of p KL and lower peak oil was this alright and if I write this if I
this alright and if I write this if I normalize it this is the optimal
normalize it this is the optimal distribution project project
distribution project project look at it very carefully okay all right
look at it very carefully okay all right usually an easier way to remember is
usually an easier way to remember is this equation here okay
this equation here okay rather than this so the reason I should
rather than this so the reason I should say is these words with respect to the
say is these words with respect to the other this that the longer joint of
other this that the longer joint of likelihood okay
likelihood okay now obviously if you take an average
now obviously if you take an average with respect to all the other cues right
with respect to all the other cues right you have to iterate this that's why I
you have to iterate this that's why I said you have to assume this to
said you have to assume this to self-consistency so if you start with
self-consistency so if you start with say and you approximate you define the
say and you approximate you define the optimal for q1 keeping all the other
optimal for q1 keeping all the other cues fixed then you go to optimal of
cues fixed then you go to optimal of people to think you won and the rest are
people to think you won and the rest are fixed and you keep iterating until
fixed and you keep iterating until basically you're happy that they are not
basically you're happy that they are not changes that's what's that consistency
changes that's what's that consistency means and now why do they call this the
means and now why do they call this the Menken approximation what is the method
Menken approximation what is the method that makes this to sort of be a mean
that makes this to sort of be a mean field of main field I mean what you know
field of main field I mean what you know you can extrapolate from the research
you can extrapolate from the research what is main main field
expectation right so to come you know to calculate this right you are using the
calculate this right you are using the expectation of the log likelihood of the
expectation of the log likelihood of the join of likelihood where you are with
join of likelihood where you are with respect to the distributions so this is
respect to the distributions so this is sort of you know if you say have many
sort of you know if you say have many electrons moving around and you want
electrons moving around and you want light in a question for a one-electron
light in a question for a one-electron you know we are doing the computation in
you know we are doing the computation in the average speed of electrons and then
the average speed of electrons and then we get there was a political sort of the
we get there was a political sort of the question in this case we get an equation
question in this case we get an equation for the distribution through J in the
for the distribution through J in the average distribution of the other of all
average distribution of the other of all the other guys all right so that's where
the other guys all right so that's where the mean field approximation yeah so you
the mean field approximation yeah so you can feel for example I mean and we may
can feel for example I mean and we may see an example later on let's say this
see an example later on let's say this factorized distributions come to be a
factorized distributions come to be a Gaussian in essence in this expectation
Gaussian in essence in this expectation here you can think possibly that they
here you can think possibly that they may come up that in certain cases what
may come up that in certain cases what you do is you may have to fix the
you do is you may have to fix the results to their mean values right to
results to their mean values right to their mean values
I don't think so I don't think so
but I can I know one case that there is a relation between what you see here
a relation between what you see here when you use particle approximations but
when you use particle approximations but installation of the car love this you
installation of the car love this you know it's very different
know it's very different okay it's very different okay
now remember so we went we did this right with tick all the late and by the
right with tick all the late and by the most pure of Z and we wrote them as a
most pure of Z and we wrote them as a product of tax rise you know we
product of tax rise you know we factorize the Montero at the time
factorize the Montero at the time Kinnock you one of Z 1 Z 2 Z 2 etc so
Kinnock you one of Z 1 Z 2 Z 2 etc so it's now this mission cubes this serves
it's now this mission cubes this serves again you know the distribution tables
again you know the distribution tables on the market blanket so in this case
on the market blanket so in this case for example when you apply these
for example when you apply these programs this is the summation Bishop
programs this is the summation Bishop with the market blanket and updates one
with the market blanket and updates one variable at the time one distribution at
variable at the time one distribution at a time keeping the rest basically to
a time keeping the rest basically to convey our okay so this is sort of our
convey our okay so this is sort of our you can see how this may be applied to
you can see how this may be applied to you in the context of classical modules
right
so let's do an approximation of this okay a very easy example then selects
okay a very easy example then selects the slides contain a lot of details so
the slides contain a lot of details so they were written by one of my master's
they were written by one of my master's students okay who was willing and
students okay who was willing and capable to do all these deviations and
capable to do all these deviations and provide all the computer programs I'm
provide all the computer programs I'm going with this lecture okay so what she
going with this lecture okay so what she did is she yeah she started with a
did is she yeah she started with a multivariate Gaussian in this case we
multivariate Gaussian in this case we have two variables only with this mean
have two variables only with this mean and quiet looking like that and he says
and quiet looking like that and he says you know what I am going to use this
you know what I am going to use this mini field approximation to approximate
mini field approximation to approximate this Gaussian over two variables as a
this Gaussian over two variables as a product of gaussians over its body more
product of gaussians over its body more separate so it's a vectorized proper
separate so it's a vectorized proper size of two univariate gaussians okay
size of two univariate gaussians okay you may say let me destroy a bubble to
you may say let me destroy a bubble to do this well you know it's interesting
do this well you know it's interesting right I mean can you actually take you
right I mean can you actually take you know this guy's on two variables and
know this guy's on two variables and write is the product of thousands in in
write is the product of thousands in in one dimension for each of the variables
one dimension for each of the variables and it'll be interesting
and it'll be interesting okay so no donation but actually it's a
okay so no donation but actually it's a very good way for you to learn exactly
very good way for you to learn exactly how this variation all right so remember
how this variation all right so remember in space the optimal Q line the normal
in space the optimal Q line the normal qrz one so this now means optimal it is
qrz one so this now means optimal it is the expectation whatever value was
the expectation whatever value was higher here Z 2 there is no hidden body
higher here Z 2 there is no hidden body or anything that zone is zip here so
or anything that zone is zip here so number P of Z so what I'm doing is I'm
number P of Z so what I'm doing is I'm expanding the love of pure silver by
expanding the love of pure silver by body of Gaussian all right clipping
body of Gaussian all right clipping anything that doesn't depend on
anything that doesn't depend on basically on on the Z one out of the
basically on on the Z one out of the picture okay because we're in interest
picture okay because we're in interest on the distribution of Z 1
whatever result we did we're gonna have to normalize it to be sure that this is
to normalize it to be sure that this is integrates to on so keep that in mind so
integrates to on so keep that in mind so you expand this write this term
you expand this write this term ultraviolet Gaussian you expand and and
ultraviolet Gaussian you expand and and then you have to take its protections
then you have to take its protections with respect to Z 2 so every time that
with respect to Z 2 so every time that has C - where is it - you can have the
has C - where is it - you can have the expectation of Z 2 respectively - okay
expectation of Z 2 respectively - okay there is nothing else and how do we
there is nothing else and how do we extract this distribution from this
extract this distribution from this expression what is the most rules that
expression what is the most rules that we have to do this is distribution in g1
we have to do this is distribution in g1 I see g1 here I see C 1 versus u 1
I see g1 here I see C 1 versus u 1 square so what do we need to do to come
square so what do we need to do to come up with the a nice expression what's the
up with the a nice expression what's the password
no I'm like I said Foursquare and somebody sent to complete the square I
somebody sent to complete the square I and I you know square square I left the
and I you know square square I left the square I was going to say closing the
square I was going to say closing the square or completing the square or you
square or completing the square or you know whatever so you basically have to
know whatever so you basically have to write this you know the three - some
write this you know the three - some mean right mr. matrix times D - Ameen
mean right mr. matrix times D - Ameen all right so you can get the form of a
all right so you can get the form of a Gaussian distribution you have to close
Gaussian distribution you have to close the square on c1 okay so you can be
the square on c1 okay so you can be missed in a Trinity of reading and if
missed in a Trinity of reading and if you do this in a trivial way it comes
you do this in a trivial way it comes that the optimal distribution for zero
that the optimal distribution for zero is and again the Vice here so you don't
is and again the Vice here so you don't have to move a finger the moon comes to
have to move a finger the moon comes to be what you see here okay and the
be what you see here okay and the optimal t2 by symmetry comes to look
optimal t2 by symmetry comes to look like that so I remind you me I am you
like that so I remind you me I am you two are the means but they're coming
two are the means but they're coming from the bivariate Gaussian and so if
from the bivariate Gaussian and so if security of z1 the means of the
security of z1 the means of the univariate gaussians in the
univariate gaussians in the factorization alright so there is an
factorization alright so there is an issue here you can nothing issue it this
issue here you can nothing issue it this is exactly what we discussed about
is exactly what we discussed about self-consistency to find kill one of z1
self-consistency to find kill one of z1 you need to know lipids to remain as
you need to know lipids to remain as they keep we have z2 and to find you 12
they keep we have z2 and to find you 12 G - you need to know what is the mean of
G - you need to know what is the mean of q1 of z1 thanks mate let's say this main
q1 of z1 thanks mate let's say this main and you complete this and then you
and you complete this and then you complete its meaning you are you planet
complete its meaning you are you planet in here calculate this you can't make a
in here calculate this you can't make a new mean of this you plug it in and get
new mean of this you plug it in and get irate and feel convergence okay it's
irate and feel convergence okay it's actually contact but this problem has
actually contact but this problem has I really like it is the fix point
I really like it is the fix point solution okay and so the fix point
solution okay and so the fix point solution basically at the end of the day
solution basically at the end of the day gives you the chances of you secure all
gives you the chances of you secure all right so when you iterate this you can
right so when you iterate this you can do it but you know gives the answer okay
do it but you know gives the answer okay so the mean of q1 z1 is actually new one
so the mean of q1 z1 is actually new one and the you know the precision is lambda
and the you know the precision is lambda 1 1 and here the Precision's love with
1 1 and here the Precision's love with you too and I mean me too alright so
you too and I mean me too alright so let's I do not have time to check I'm
let's I do not have time to check I'm gonna post this right but there is a
gonna post this right but there is a product on problems actually the plan
product on problems actually the plan and get you the pixels of your seat here
and get you the pixels of your seat here so I'm gonna show you how the results
so I'm gonna show you how the results look like so this is this is the
look like so this is this is the multivariate Gaussian that to bivariate
multivariate Gaussian that to bivariate Gaussian P of Z and you try to
Gaussian P of Z and you try to approximate it with this factorized
approximate it with this factorized variational distribution Q of Z alright
variational distribution Q of Z alright so so notice okay so this is what you
so so notice okay so this is what you get all right so this is the product of
get all right so this is the product of two univariate gaussians and you notice
two univariate gaussians and you notice that in in the direction of the maximal
that in in the direction of the maximal variance of P of Z basically your
variance of P of Z basically your underestimate X okay so basically here
underestimate X okay so basically here you're doing good but you know you're
you're doing good but you know you're missing what's going on in there
missing what's going on in there so this is basically the support the
so this is basically the support the solution that you get this multiple path
solution that you get this multiple path than the actual P of Z so basically your
than the actual P of Z so basically your cube Z is over confident approximation
cube Z is over confident approximation of the procedure
okay alternative approximate interesting we don't need to know this right
we don't need to know this right basically the same derivation I gave you
basically the same derivation I gave you I see here when we did the optimization
I see here when we did the optimization problem and crossing the constrain but
problem and crossing the constrain but the distribution future is normalized so
the distribution future is normalized so if you do absolutely this you get the
if you do absolutely this you get the right solution right away so there's
right solution right away so there's nothing you really on this think I know
nothing you really on this think I know actually Wireless came out of sequence
okay it doesn't matter so let me continue this approximation of the
continue this approximation of the Gaussian think this is what Winston's
Gaussian think this is what Winston's we're getting okay so we mentioned that
we're getting okay so we mentioned that maximizing the lower bound right is the
maximizing the lower bound right is the same as minimizing the Cooper clip or
same as minimizing the Cooper clip or distance between Q and P so it just to
distance between Q and P so it just to make things interesting you know what we
make things interesting you know what we do here is promote instead of minimizing
do here is promote instead of minimizing risk QM between Q and P that comes
risk QM between Q and P that comes directly from the is a variation of
directly from the is a variation of Principles if we try to minimize instead
Principles if we try to minimize instead the distance between P and Q for I can
the distance between P and Q for I can remember the cubot liberal distance is
remember the cubot liberal distance is not symmetric so you know anticipate
not symmetric so you know anticipate that this will give you the same results
that this will give you the same results as this so this is the valuation
as this so this is the valuation approximation this is what were
approximation this is what were discussing in this Q lectures this is
discussing in this Q lectures this is not a variation approximation we
not a variation approximation we minimize the KL distance between P and Q
minimize the KL distance between P and Q all right big difference so this is what
all right big difference so this is what you get
you get so K here look at the so the Q is all
so K here look at the so the Q is all over the space this is P of Z so P of Z
over the space this is P of Z so P of Z is 0 there right so in cubes if you can
is 0 there right so in cubes if you can see when you minimize the distance
see when you minimize the distance between P and Q it fits for community
between P and Q it fits for community mass where the section values of P of Z
mass where the section values of P of Z are very small okay so before we had
are very small okay so before we had another confident solution that
another confident solution that underestimates the variance in this
underestimates the variance in this direction here we have a solution has
direction here we have a solution has very high support and non zero mass in
very high support and non zero mass in areas for P of Z is equal to zero
areas for P of Z is equal to zero so again be sure to write analytical
so again be sure to write analytical problems you minimizing Cal differences
problems you minimizing Cal differences yes this to be conserve how big
yes this to be conserve how big differences you get when you memorize Q
differences you get when you memorize Q and Q the distance of U from P versus
and Q the distance of U from P versus the distance of P from Q and you can
the distance of P from Q and you can actually sort of you know you can expect
actually sort of you know you can expect many of this results right so you know
many of this results right so you know so let's do one of these cases just for
so let's do one of these cases just for demonstration so in this case we
demonstration so in this case we minimize the distance between Q and P
minimize the distance between Q and P and this is what this distance is right
and this is what this distance is right so let's consider regions of the actual
so let's consider regions of the actual distribution that P of Z given X is zero
distribution that P of Z given X is zero all right so it's observers cannot what
all right so it's observers cannot what this is insane it's me
this is insane it's me okay very big it's really crucial big we
okay very big it's really crucial big we actually are going to member of 50s need
actually are going to member of 50s need that most probably
that most probably so this is big Lee okay TMZ given X is
so this is big Lee okay TMZ given X is big okay
big okay if you get basically you get an infinite
if you get basically you get an infinite contribution assuming what that cube Z
contribution assuming what that cube Z is not 0 all right assuming a huge list
is not 0 all right assuming a huge list of 0 7 doesn't mean that in regions
of 0 7 doesn't mean that in regions where remember to minimize this distance
dispersed awareness Israel you can confusion over here so in regions that P
confusion over here so in regions that P of Z is 0 she seems to be what
look at this expression right and considering regions were fields is zero
considering regions were fields is zero alright
alright to avoid getting the above zero what is
to avoid getting the above zero what is the only option that will lead to an
the only option that will lead to an envelope for the distance of 20
the presses do have the only way that you get not infinite is when when cubes
you get not infinite is when when cubes that have become zero and this is what's
that have become zero and this is what's called zero forcing for Q of Z and you
called zero forcing for Q of Z and you can take care P of Z is zero right and
can take care P of Z is zero right and curves is supposed to go to zero okay in
curves is supposed to go to zero okay in this case and the discussions of the
this case and the discussions of the next slide that you can read you
next slide that you can read you basically get the opposite effectively
basically get the opposite effectively what you get in regions where P of Z is
what you get in regions where P of Z is 0 Q has positive master Fisto okay right
0 Q has positive master Fisto okay right the opposite effect you can see the
the opposite effect you can see the actual distribution is a becauseum right
actual distribution is a becauseum right and believe this means in the prop swish
and believe this means in the prop swish right that's a kind of an interesting
right that's a kind of an interesting problem so this is this let me see what
problem so this is this let me see what is the actual distribution so the video
is the actual distribution so the video I the motion of the you say is the
I the motion of the you say is the mixture of gaussians and we try to
mixture of gaussians and we try to compute factorize approximation of mm
compute factorize approximation of mm factorized
factorized product for basically of univariate
product for basically of univariate gaussians okay so with your situation
gaussians okay so with your situation starting from the minimization of the
starting from the minimization of the total distance between P and Q again I'm
total distance between P and Q again I'm going to this is nationals
going to this is nationals okay again this okay this is not
okay again this okay this is not variational methods is not maximizing
variational methods is not maximizing the lower bound and but so this is how
the lower bound and but so this is how the approximation of loops you get
the approximation of loops you get basically the right approximation here
basically the right approximation here is is univariate is the product of this
is is univariate is the product of this you know you get basically this Gaussian
you know you get basically this Gaussian what you see here okay and you know it
what you see here okay and you know it basically contains the point of the two
basically contains the point of the two modes in the Gaussian mixture if you go
modes in the Gaussian mixture if you go however and you
however and you made you do the very National methyl and
made you do the very National methyl and you approximate the you minimize the
you approximate the you minimize the care of distance between Q and P you
care of distance between Q and P you will get either a list or either that so
will get either a list or either that so basically the variational method web
basically the variational method web browsers it collapses to all of the
browsers it collapses to all of the modes of the Gaussian Mexico okay so
modes of the Gaussian Mexico okay so this is your standard mode collapse
this is your standard mode collapse problem and of course whether Sigma
problem and of course whether Sigma necrosis I mean is this number it you
necrosis I mean is this number it you know how is it possible to give you two
know how is it possible to give you two solutions well you know you start with
solutions well you know you start with something about your so for some initial
something about your so for some initial guess here would converge there for
guess here would converge there for something else will converge there now
something else will converge there now if you know the initial basis you can
if you know the initial basis you can immediately say fifty percent of the
immediately say fifty percent of the time you may get this and fifty percent
time you may get this and fifty percent of the time you may get done but to the
of the time you may get done but to the right so this is the you know minimizing
right so this is the you know minimizing the distance between P and Q this
the distance between P and Q this corresponds the minimization of Q and P
corresponds the minimization of Q and P which is our variational techniques
which is our variational techniques discussed today okay if we have time
discussed today okay if we have time maybe in a week or two we will discuss
maybe in a week or two we will discuss basically the whole huge set of
basically the whole huge set of methodologies include the expectation
methodologies include the expectation propagation basically does lead to this
propagation basically does lead to this type of approximations with which we
type of approximations with which we obscure but the variational methods they
obscure but the variational methods they have this problem with multiple lost
okay
I can utilize this actually this problem with you know well there's a lot of
with you know well there's a lot of things that can be asking it here but
things that can be asking it here but you know in this slide basically and I'm
you know in this slide basically and I'm rubber and walk through it because it's
rubber and walk through it because it's elementary if somebody gives you an
elementary if somebody gives you an arbitrary distribution P of X in high
arbitrary distribution P of X in high dimensions and says find using
dimensions and says find using variational methods a Gaussian
variational methods a Gaussian approximation you know the simple
approximation you know the simple example to demonstrate the difference
example to demonstrate the difference from the Laplace approximation but you
from the Laplace approximation but you may wonder is there any action the
may wonder is there any action the organization of this to multivariate
organization of this to multivariate distribution can I get the variation of
distribution can I get the variation of expression of the Gaussian and it comes
expression of the Gaussian and it comes apart so if you do the algebra and I
apart so if you do the algebra and I have everything here and I know if you
have everything here and I know if you are not gonna bother to look at it but
are not gonna bother to look at it but somebody bother to type it so out of
somebody bother to type it so out of respect for him you may want to actually
respect for him you may want to actually read it all right because there is
read it all right because there is pretty much to learn you know there is a
pretty much to learn you know there is a little trick that you do suspender trick
little trick that you do suspender trick in machine learning with with this term
in machine learning with with this term here I am NOT going to discuss it since
here I am NOT going to discuss it since you need to take derivatives with
you need to take derivatives with respect to me here in Sigma to find the
respect to me here in Sigma to find the optimal Q of X you need to know how to
optimal Q of X you need to know how to do this derivatives but here's the
do this derivatives but here's the answer the answer comes to be that the
answer the answer comes to be that the mean in the variation force ratio is
mean in the variation force ratio is naturally the expectation of X and the
naturally the expectation of X and the violence is actually the covariance of X
violence is actually the covariance of X okay so Sigma is exactly the covariance
okay so Sigma is exactly the covariance of X so really there is no factorization
of X so really there is no factorization here right so this is a multivariate
here right so this is a multivariate Gaussian okay so if you want to do this
Gaussian okay so if you want to do this you can use variational methods this is
you can use variational methods this is not the result is very much different
not the result is very much different from the Laplace approximation
from the Laplace approximation okay very much different
can you generalize this metal to sort of different type of distributions because
different type of distributions because kill distance you know not typically
kill distance you know not typically decides it I remember you know I once
decides it I remember you know I once upon a time I gave a seminar in a
upon a time I gave a seminar in a British University and one of my
British University and one of my colleagues decided you know it's very
colleagues decided you know it's very bad and not a good distance and since
bad and not a good distance and since then she owned 25 papers using the km
then she owned 25 papers using the km distance for some trivial 1d problems
distance for some trivial 1d problems hopefully and so lots of people
hopefully and so lots of people including ourselves right we use the km
including ourselves right we use the km distance because convenient we know
distance because convenient we know everybody knows the deficient this ok
everybody knows the deficient this ok but it's all about you know mathematical
but it's all about you know mathematical simplicity and knowing exactly when
simplicity and knowing exactly when things work and when things don't work
things work and when things don't work ok so you can internalize this K of
ok so you can internalize this K of distance to what's called the family of
distance to what's called the family of divergence okay
divergence okay and this is the definition of this
and this is the definition of this distance with parameter right it looks
distance with parameter right it looks very much different from the KL distant
very much different from the KL distant okay so this problem is alpha is 2 minus
okay so this problem is alpha is 2 minus R into infinity and it is obviously
R into infinity and it is obviously greater or equal to 0 equal to 0 when P
greater or equal to 0 equal to 0 when P and Q are equal if you want to actually
and Q are equal if you want to actually read everything about calculations with
read everything about calculations with this type of alpha distances memcache is
this type of alpha distances memcache is a very nice report okay that you can
a very nice report okay that you can download from Microsoft website with all
download from Microsoft website with all the derivations are in the appendices so
the derivations are in the appendices so you can still have a very interesting
you can still have a very interesting type of extensions of the K of distance
type of extensions of the K of distance so the let me see if I need to tell you
so the let me see if I need to tell you anything here
so basically we're having the next two slides is to show you some limiting
slides is to show you some limiting values of this alpha distances when
values of this alpha distances when alpha takes various doors to one
alpha takes various doors to one basically what exactly you are getting
basically what exactly you are getting and so if you define this coefficient 1
and so if you define this coefficient 1 plus alpha over the fewest gamma P and
plus alpha over the fewest gamma P and this coefficient as gamma Q arise the
this coefficient as gamma Q arise the exponent of the Judis to be the Q
exponent of the Judis to be the Q distribution obviously gamma P a gamma Q
distribution obviously gamma P a gamma Q equal to 1 so if you take the limit at
equal to 1 so if you take the limit at this gamez when alpha goes to 1 you can
this gamez when alpha goes to 1 you can see this goes to zero this goes to 1 and
see this goes to zero this goes to 1 and what you can do is actually you can take
what you can do is actually you can take these powers in the definition of this
these powers in the definition of this alpha distances and use first of all the
alpha distances and use first of all the Taylor expansions the results are
Taylor expansions the results are actually previous I'm not gonna go
actually previous I'm not gonna go through everything here okay so for
through everything here okay so for example if you take the distribution Q
example if you take the distribution Q to gamma Q you can write this as the
to gamma Q you can write this as the exponential of gamma Q log of Q and then
exponential of gamma Q log of Q and then you can use the turtle data since its
you can use the turtle data since its function in gamma cubed because gamma Q
function in gamma cubed because gamma Q goes to 0 as alpha goes to 1 so you can
goes to 0 as alpha goes to 1 so you can write this as exponential is 1 plus X
write this as exponential is 1 plus X plus x squared over 2 so the first term
plus x squared over 2 so the first term is 1 plus gamma log of Q this is to
is 1 plus gamma log of Q this is to limit what Ricky but it's nothing major
limit what Ricky but it's nothing major you can approximate this B minus gamma Q
you can approximate this B minus gamma Q P of log of P and it comes out that this
P of log of P and it comes out that this integral it gives you a very nice form
integral it gives you a very nice form that maybe some of you have seen it in
that maybe some of you have seen it in different contexts in machine learning
different contexts in machine learning so if you take this asymptotic value and
so if you take this asymptotic value and we plug them in there if you get
we plug them in there if you get basically you recover from the self of
basically you recover from the self of distances the KL Vista
distances the KL Vista okay so as a matter fact when alpha we
okay so as a matter fact when alpha we set out from goes to z/2 on right
set out from goes to z/2 on right without reverse to 1 this becomes equal
without reverse to 1 this becomes equal to answer you get the K of distance okay
to answer you get the K of distance okay and so this has some limiting values
and so this has some limiting values okay so when alpha worst one you get the
okay so when alpha worst one you get the KL distance and actually here yeah so
KL distance and actually here yeah so this correct and you can get the reverse
this correct and you can get the reverse key and distance when alpha goes to
key and distance when alpha goes to minus 1 in even further you can get out
minus 1 in even further you can get out of this
of this even the Shannon give distance but some
even the Shannon give distance but some people in network theory goes right so
people in network theory goes right so this is recovered by taking after equal
this is recovered by taking after equal to 0
let me see if I am going to tell you brothers
right so let's say okay let me see how we're going to define this problem so in
we're going to define this problem so in everything we did like one will apply
everything we did like one will apply expectation maximization right do you
expectation maximization right do you remember we had a set of latent variable
remember we had a set of latent variable Z but also we have a set of parameters
Z but also we have a set of parameters okay and in the expectation step what we
okay and in the expectation step what we did is we computed the efficient
did is we computed the efficient statistics that they were effectively
statistics that they were effectively expectations with respect to the Z
expectations with respect to the Z variable for fixed parameters and then
variable for fixed parameters and then we since we completed the sufficient
we since we completed the sufficient statistics then we much mize all right
statistics then we much mize all right so here can I do a body astral
so here can I do a body astral approximation what is not going to give
approximation what is not going to give me when the Joint Distribution of the
me when the Joint Distribution of the unknown Nathan variables Z and the
unknown Nathan variables Z and the parameters theta fertilizes has what you
parameters theta fertilizes has what you see here I should have put there cure
see here I should have put there cure see that comma theta all right now if
see that comma theta all right now if you want to keep the the parameters
you want to keep the the parameters theta to a fixed value all right and you
theta to a fixed value all right and you don't want to bother basically bistro3
don't want to bother basically bistro3 that becomes a delta function okay and
that becomes a delta function okay and so let's see what case this is
so let's see what case this is considered here so the maximization of
considered here so the maximization of the lower bound is the same as the
the lower bound is the same as the minimization of the distance between qlp
minimization of the distance between qlp so the distance between Q and P is
so the distance between Q and P is written minus Q of theta Q of Z this the
written minus Q of theta Q of Z this the authorization I use this is the log of
authorization I use this is the log of joint log likelihood you have Z Q theta
joint log likelihood you have Z Q theta just the definition okay so anyways if I
just the definition okay so anyways if I say let's fix the parameters the value
say let's fix the parameters the value theta 0 expectation step all right so
theta 0 expectation step all right so actually does the expectations that has
actually does the expectations that has anything to do with wanna show that
anything to do with wanna show that right so we're going to keep paper
right so we're going to keep paper tricks to 0 so the calculation that
tricks to 0 so the calculation that involves basically the numerator there
involves basically the numerator there all right theta is the Delta function so
all right theta is the Delta function so you believe that I'm going to get their
you believe that I'm going to get their number physique of P of Z comma theta 0
number physique of P of Z comma theta 0 all right but basically we think that we
all right but basically we think that we don't really care because I am looking
don't really care because I am looking down on 0 date 3 so out here minus Q of
down on 0 date 3 so out here minus Q of Z log of p 0 0 so minus P of Z ok some
Z log of p 0 0 so minus P of Z ok some thinking
thinking here is the join little Hydra put this
here is the join little Hydra put this is what we use in expectation
is what we use in expectation maximization and I like this as the
maximization and I like this as the posterior of Z given the parameters
posterior of Z given the parameters times the probability of theta 0 the
times the probability of theta 0 the posterior of theta 0 basically
posterior of theta 0 basically okay so he just doesn't matter for this
okay so he just doesn't matter for this I get rid of it so minus Q of Z log of
I get rid of it so minus Q of Z log of this divided by Q C ok and which is the
this divided by Q C ok and which is the the minimization so we need to minimize
the minimization so we need to minimize K this K of distance all right
K this K of distance all right all right so when is the minimization
all right so when is the minimization happening when Q of Z equal to P of Z
happening when Q of Z equal to P of Z given theta 0 comma X this is what
given theta 0 comma X this is what actually we did from the expectation
actually we did from the expectation step right we fix the parameters all
step right we fix the parameters all right and you remember what we did this
right and you remember what we did this we computed the average of the join
we computed the average of the join locally with respect to the distribution
what was the distribution and then step that we averaged with because the
that we averaged with because the custodian of Z given the parameter ETA
custodian of Z given the parameter ETA is the first
is the first she given because 0 so this step
she given because 0 so this step actually does come from it's the small
actually does come from it's the small part of the variational methods okay
part of the variational methods okay then you may ask I have a maximization
then you may ask I have a maximization step well so so maybe now Q of Z equal
step well so so maybe now Q of Z equal to that and we want to compute Q theta
to that and we want to compute Q theta shall we go back to again to the right
shall we go back to again to the right okay so we remember if this Q theta Q of
okay so we remember if this Q theta Q of Z the giant everything data and announce
Z the giant everything data and announce okay and in this case remember the this
okay and in this case remember the this fixed now okay so I put cubes inside and
fixed now okay so I put cubes inside and with a latest this 10 times that is the
with a latest this 10 times that is the expectation with respect to Q of Zeta of
expectation with respect to Q of Zeta of the joining of livelihood all right okay
the joining of livelihood all right okay and I have Q then I have an average with
and I have Q then I have an average with respect to Q theta and then of the
respect to Q theta and then of the denominator basically I'm going to get
denominator basically I'm going to get the entropy of the distribution theta
the entropy of the distribution theta and how do you find how do you update to
and how do you find how do you update to theta you basically need to maximize
theta you basically need to maximize look at this right how are you going to
look at this right how are you going to maximize this
you're verifying the thickness no overmuch Mises the joined up likelihood
overmuch Mises the joined up likelihood and actually yeah I was going to
and actually yeah I was going to thinking they're just having a
thinking they're just having a genetically Delavan theta zero for the
genetically Delavan theta zero for the suppose we have to take we update theta
suppose we have to take we update theta 0 here so this is their step
0 here so this is their step alright you only have computing the
alright you only have computing the sufficient statistics with respect to
sufficient statistics with respect to the distribution cubes if we complete it
the distribution cubes if we complete it and then you maximize the joint of
and then you maximize the joint of likelihood with respect to the
likelihood with respect to the parameters bottom line is you know when
parameters bottom line is you know when you applied this term this variation
you applied this term this variation electron from the distribution that
electron from the distribution that factorizes the latent variables and the
factorizes the latent variables and the parameters like that basically you
parameters like that basically you discover as you have a Z first and then
discover as you have a Z first and then you update theta you discover the E&amp;M
you update theta you discover the E&amp;M steps of the expectation maximization
steps of the expectation maximization algorithm as a matter of fact they am
algorithm as a matter of fact they am aware if I remember historically was
aware if I remember historically was developed way because people must in
developed way because people must in have Inc have it using the variational
have Inc have it using the variational methods but now you can see sort of the
methods but now you can see sort of the TM algorithm is really the variational
TM algorithm is really the variational approximation substance okay you missed
approximation substance okay you missed and maybe some of you have not seen this
and maybe some of you have not seen this example but please and I think we gave
example but please and I think we gave you did we give them a homework on this
you did we give them a homework on this this semester all right so you have seen
this semester all right so you have seen it okay so this is the denoising of an
it okay so this is the denoising of an image problem well you can think of this
image problem well you can think of this being the pixels in an image this of the
being the pixels in an image this of the noisy bodies an extra you know the
noisy bodies an extra you know the original image but here we take it to be
original image but here we take it to be a binary black or white okay plus one or
a binary black or white okay plus one or minus one okay
the joint distributions of X Y is protects
protects times the likelihood of
P of Y given X okay so I am going to do some manipulation of the algebra okay
some manipulation of the algebra okay just to make things to generalize things
just to make things to generalize things so the first thing I'm going to assume
so the first thing I'm going to assume the prior so we're going to compute X
the prior so we're going to compute X right we want to compute what the
right we want to compute what the original image this if you have some
original image this if you have some noisy red surveillance most web
noisy red surveillance most web denoising is so the primary are X I'm
denoising is so the primary are X I'm going to assume it will have an
going to assume it will have an exponential prominent distribution would
exponential prominent distribution would be e to the minus some energy and this
be e to the minus some energy and this energy functional I write it like that
energy functional I write it like that where I account
where I account interactions between neighbors so this
interactions between neighbors so this is sort of a journal is a nesting model
is sort of a journal is a nesting model okay so I put some weights between
okay so I put some weights between pixels I and J but the only account for
pixels I and J but the only account for this interaction science a if I and J is
this interaction science a if I and J is unable okay so a business my so this is
unable okay so a business my so this is a very standard way you know to
a very standard way you know to introduce basically the dependencies
introduce basically the dependencies between the X pixels okay so again there
between the X pixels okay so again there is a regional writing uses into the - II
is a regional writing uses into the - II like it gives distribution and this is
like it gives distribution and this is my energy and let's see what the
my energy and let's see what the likelihood is going to be like so the
likelihood is going to be like so the likelihood is a progress of x for its I
likelihood is a progress of x for its I right so it is the probability of Y
right so it is the probability of Y given X I so you can think of this sort
given X I so you can think of this sort of being a Gaussian with some describe
of being a Gaussian with some describe noise so I'm gonna do is I'm gonna write
noise so I'm gonna do is I'm gonna write each of these terms to follow this
each of these terms to follow this format is into some energy life all
format is into some energy life all right
right so because it's products of
so because it's products of Exponential's then I'm going to get the
Exponential's then I'm going to get the expectation of the summation of all the
expectation of the summation of all the alarms and this allows can be Gaussian
alarms and this allows can be Gaussian right with some noise step okay all
right with some noise step okay all right
right easy
easy if I compute the joint you know if you
if I compute the joint you know if you forgive the organization or the the
forgive the organization or the the posterior of X given Y I get e to the
posterior of X given Y I get e to the minus the energy equal the energy is e 0
minus the energy equal the energy is e 0 minus restoration of audiologic ok so my
minus restoration of audiologic ok so my energy in my giant log likelihood this
energy in my giant log likelihood this is what we need from the variational
is what we need from the variational methods is e to the minus this energy so
methods is e to the minus this energy so multinational approximation now because
multinational approximation now because this looks complicated ok in this is the
because to simplify this calculation because an exponential I am going to
because an exponential I am going to define
so I do not put the rice here right but this is you can think of this is the
this is you can think of this is the giant okay this is what it is okay so
giant okay this is what it is okay so the giant under that liquid is so the
the giant under that liquid is so the Journal article will disconnect this
Journal article will disconnect this exponential to disappear and it will be
exponential to disappear and it will be there's a minus sign there so it will be
there's a minus sign there so it will be X I times the summation over the
X I times the summation over the neighborhoods of Na VI j xj all right
neighborhoods of Na VI j xj all right plus Li of X I this person's so ravenous
plus Li of X I this person's so ravenous I am writing the joint of liquid but
I am writing the joint of liquid but because I'm interested only calculate
because I'm interested only calculate one factor at the time I am making the
one factor at the time I am making the terms that contain X I nothing else
terms that contain X I nothing else so there's many other terms like there
so there's many other terms like there is actual on here x all the neighbor
is actual on here x all the neighbor selector I only want to see X I because
selector I only want to see X I because effectively this is what I'm interested
effectively this is what I'm interested to to compute in in some iterative
to to compute in in some iterative manner so the jury will be happy who is
manner so the jury will be happy who is this okay so all right nice distribution
this okay so all right nice distribution is you know that the log of the optimal
is you know that the log of the optimal right is remember it is the expectation
right is remember it is the expectation with the cures and here is not all right
with the cures and here is not all right so the Qi is the expectation okay of X I
so the Qi is the expectation okay of X I times this where I substance that
because Qi is expectation of this disguise the exponential of the
disguise the exponential of the expectation of this and what is the
expectation of this and what is the expectation of X J because the binary
expectation of X J because the binary variable
variable it's men so actively in this trivial
it's men so actively in this trivial model - you can try to access to that
model - you can try to access to that average value very nice
average value very nice all right you know extremely is the
all right you know extremely is the completion so you don't really have to
completion so you don't really have to calculate any sufficient statistics and
calculate any sufficient statistics and complicated expectations you just fix XA
complicated expectations you just fix XA with the mean right because you need to
with the mean right because you need to break expectations okay
break expectations okay and I want you to interests right but we
and I want you to interests right but we are you know we're calling the stems
are you know we're calling the stems here Mui okay and we define the values
here Mui okay and we define the values of shall I and I plus an ally - okay I'm
of shall I and I plus an ally - okay I'm gonna finish all right so I'm going to
gonna finish all right so I'm going to come back to this example
come back to this example so maybe sakali at the end of the day
so maybe sakali at the end of the day you can derive the UI to get a very nice
you can derive the UI to get a very nice cloth solution okay - solution so mr.
cloth solution okay - solution so mr. right around would be one line and if
right around would be one line and if you apply the mean field approximation
you apply the mean field approximation in a self consistent manner few images
in a self consistent manner few images you can see you know with